<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:18:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tartisan Nickel Launches 3,600m Drill Program at Kenbridge</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/TTSRF/tartisan-nickel-corp-engages-rodren-drilling-ltd-for-drill-program-nclylbqzyjeu.html</link><description>Tartisan Nickel Corp. has initiated a 3,600-meter diamond drilling program at its 100% owned Kenbridge Nickel-Copper-Cobalt Deposit. The program aims to convert inferred mineral resources into measured and indicated categories and support an updated Mineral Resource Estimate and a forthcoming Pre-Feasibility Study. Mobilization is scheduled for December 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Major Chinese Steelmaker Signs Landmark Contract with Primetals Technologies</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/38255/</link><description>A major Chinese steelmaker signed a landmark contract with Primetals Technologies to supply two continuous slab casters, indicating ongoing investment in steel production capacity and modernization in China.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Surge Copper digs deep: Berg project PFS underway</title><link>https://www.mining.com/surge-copper-digs-deep-berg-project-pfs-underway/</link><description>Surge Copper is advancing a pre-feasibility study (PFS) for its Berg project in British Columbia, aiming for completion in mid-2026. The project promises large-scale copper production alongside molybdenum and precious metals, building on a 2023 preliminary economic assessment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Plunge Sharply on November 21 as Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cut Weaken</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103633277</link><description>Nickel prices dropped sharply on November 21, 2025, with SMM #1 refined nickel averaging 116,700 yuan/mt, down 1,500 yuan/mt from the previous day. The decline was driven by weaker expectations for a US Federal Reserve interest rate cut amid strong US non-farm payroll data and rising unemployment, creating macroeconomic pressure and high inventory levels that weighed on nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel inches down ahead of Fed's decision</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-inches-down-ahead-of-feds-decision-47634</link><description>Nickel prices edged lower as the US dollar strengthened and market sentiment was bearish ahead of the US Federal Reserve's interest rate decision. The price movement reflects cautious investor positioning amid macroeconomic uncertainty.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian shares rise as Italian cable maker seen as winner amid US copper tariffs</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/prysmian-shares-rise-as-italian-cable-maker-seen-as-winner-amid-us-copper-tariffs-4127785</link><description>Prysmian's shares rose nearly 4% due to expectations that its large US business will benefit from US copper tariffs. The company’s vertically integrated copper sourcing and production in the US gives it a competitive edge, especially in the low-voltage cable sector, strengthening margins despite tariff impacts on demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Industry Mulls Unveiled CBAM Benchmarks, Default Values</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/aluminum-industry-mulls-unveiled-cbam-benchmarks-default-values/</link><description>Aluminum producers are reviewing the preliminary benchmarks and default values for the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM), which could impact trade and pricing in the sector. The industry is assessing how these new standards will affect competitiveness and compliance.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Falls on Nov 21</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103632229/SMM-Flash-News:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Falls-on-Nov-21</link><description>Social inventory of secondary aluminum ingots declined on November 21, according to SMM statistics. The market saw a slight recovery in aluminum prices, with ADC12 alloy prices stabilizing at 21,450 yuan/mt.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices fell to 4.92 USD/lb on November 21, 2025, down 0.63% from the previous day. The price has declined 0.79% over the past month but remains 20.73% higher than the same time last year. Market sentiment has been affected by uncertainty over Federal Reserve rate cuts, reducing expectations for a December cut.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper demand set to soar amid supply crunch</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/11/21/copper-demand-set-to-soar-amid-supply-crunch/</link><description>Copper demand is expected to surge due to global electrification, electric vehicles, renewables, and grid upgrades, while supply constraints persist across mining, refining, and smelting. Analysts warn that new supply additions and recycling will not be enough to close the widening supply-demand gap by 2035.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Widening Supply-Demand Gap to Drive Copper Prices to New Heights</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/commodity-news/petail-28158.html</link><description>Global copper mine output dropped 4.7% year-on-year in Q3 2025 due to disruptions in major producing regions, including Peru, DRC, and Indonesia. The supply-demand gap is projected to widen to 300,000 tons in 2026, supporting expectations for copper prices to reach new highs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price Update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103632922/</link><description>On November 21, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 114,400-119,000 yuan/mt, with an average price of 116,700 yuan/mt. This represents a decline of 1,500 yuan/mt from the previous trading session, marking nickel prices breaking below the 118,000–123,000 yuan/mt range that had persisted for nearly four months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alaska, Montana projects added to FAST-41</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/11/21/news/alaska-montana-projects-added-to-fast-41/9367.html</link><description>Alaska Energy Metals' Nickolai nickel project and US Critical Materials' Sheep Creek gallium-rare earths project have been added to the FAST-41 dashboard. This designation aims to expedite permitting for critical mineral projects.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alaska, Montana projects added to FAST-41</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/11/21/news/alaska-montana-projects-added-to-fast-41/9367.html</link><description>Alaska Energy Metals' Nickolai nickel project and US Critical Materials' Sheep Creek gallium-rare earths projects have been added to the FAST-41 dashboard. This represents progress in developing North American critical mineral infrastructure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Market Dominance: Supply Chain Control</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/indonesian-nickel-dominance-global-market-2025/</link><description>Indonesia's nickel market dominance is transforming global supply chains and driving innovation in battery technology, including accelerated research into nickel-free batteries, recycling technologies, and alternative chemistry scaling like LFP batteries. Supply chain concentration risk is spurring investment in alternative technologies and substitution materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Raises Annual Targets After Record Q3 Performance</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/prysmian-raises-annual-targets-after-record-q3-performance/</link><description>Prysmian has raised its full-year 2025 guidance following a record-breaking third quarter. The company’s strong financial performance reflects its leadership in the cable industry, including copper cables, and its strategic focus on innovation and growth in Italy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 4-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to $2,792.50 per ton on November 21, 2025, down 0.72% from the previous day, marking a 4-week low. Despite the recent decline, aluminum prices remain nearly 6% higher than a year ago, reflecting ongoing market volatility influenced by supply and demand factors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>GACC: China's alumina imports soar 216% MoM in October</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/list-all/latest-updates/aluminum/</link><description>China's alumina imports reached 189,326 tonnes in October 2025, marking the highest monthly volume this year and a 215.6% increase from September. This surge reflects strong demand in China's aluminum production sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AIP to sell or list French aluminum plant, union claims</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/11/21/aip-to-sell-or-list-french-aluminum-plant-union-claims</link><description>AIP is reportedly planning to sell or list its French aluminum plant as part of a strategy to increase aluminum recycling capacity to 15 million tonnes per year by 2027. This move is seen in the context of global competition, especially from China in secondary aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel fell to 3,057 CNY/T on November 21, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China fell slightly by 0.33% to 3,057 CNY per tonne on November 21, 2025. Despite a small monthly increase of 0.20%, steel prices remain about 7.53% lower than a year ago. The market shows some short-term fluctuations but overall remains below last year's levels.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Shagang holds list prices for steel longs for late-Nov sales</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5104914-shagang-holds-list-prices-for-steel-longs-for-late-nov-sales</link><description>Shagang Group, a leading Chinese steelmaker, decided to maintain its list prices for long steel products for sales in late November 2025. This move reflects a cautious approach amid current market conditions and price stability in the steel longs segment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Price on Trade: Changes to USMCA needed to support American steelmaking</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/21/price-on-trade-changes-to-usmca-needed-to-support-american-steelmaking/</link><description>Since Canada and Mexico were brought back under the Section 232 steel program in 2025, U.S. domestic raw steel production increased nearly one-to-one with the decrease in steel imports from these countries. From January to September 2025, U.S. production rose by approximately 1.4 million short tons while imports from Canada and Mexico decreased by about 1.5 million short tons, reflecting the impact of trade policy on domestic steelmaking.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Federal Steel Systems Reaffirms Commitment to Quality Standards and Transparent Building Delivery</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/pressadvantage-2025-11-22-federal-steel-systems-reaffirms-commitment-to-quality-standards-and-transparent-building-delivery</link><description>Federal Steel Systems reaffirmed its commitment to maintaining high-quality standards and transparency in building delivery. The company emphasized its dedication to customer satisfaction and adherence to industry best practices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper prices fall on firm dollar, as traders evaluate US employment data</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/11/21/copper-prices-fall-on-firm-dollar-as-traders-evaluate-us-employment-data</link><description>Copper prices declined on November 21, 2025, with the London Metal Exchange benchmark three-month price falling 0.62% to $10,671.5 per ton amid a strong US dollar and cautious investor sentiment ahead of the Federal Reserve's interest rate decision. China's weak demand further pressured prices, with Shanghai Futures Exchange copper contracts down 0.83%, marking a weekly decline of 1.43%. Traders are closely watching US employment data and Fed rate cut probabilities, which have increased to 70%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices fall on week-end dollar firm as traders evaluate US employment data</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/11/21/copper-prices-fall-on-weekend-dollar-firm-as-traders-evaluate-us-employment-data</link><description>Copper prices dropped 0.39% to $10,696.5 per ton on the London Metal Exchange, expected to close the week with a 1.41% loss. The strong US dollar and hawkish Fed officials weighed on commodity prices, making them costlier for investors using other currencies. Despite high prices this year, demand from China remains weak, contributing to the price decline. Other metals like lead, nickel, and tin also saw price drops.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Grasberg Mine Suspension Creates Major Copper Production Crisis</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/grasberg-underground-catastrophe-copper-supply-2025/</link><description>The Grasberg mine suspension following a tragic underground incident has caused a significant disruption in copper production. Freeport McMoRan's Q3 2025 copper output dropped 13.2% quarter-on-quarter, with a projected 35% decrease in 2025 production, reducing output by approximately 262,000 metric tons. This event impacts global copper supply amid rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CRML Secures One of the Largest Strategic Stockpiles of Ultra-High-Purity Copper Powder in a US$20M All-Share Acquisition</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/21/3192887/0/en/CRML-Secures-One-of-the-Largest-Strategic-Stockpiles-of-Ultra-High-Purity-Copper-Powder-in-a-US-20M-All-Share-Acquisition-Issued-at-a-40-Premium-to-Market.html</link><description>CRML has acquired one of the largest strategic stockpiles of ultra-high-purity copper powder through a US$20 million all-share acquisition, issued at a 40% premium to market. This move aims to strengthen supply chain security for critical copper materials in the US.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Amid Expectations of Copper Concentrate Shortages, How Are Smelters Adjusting Their Operating Strategies?</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103634470/amid-expectations-of-copper-concentrate-shortages-how-are-smelters-adjusting-their-operating-strategies</link><description>Copper concentrate shortages are expected to persist through 2025, with spot treatment charges remaining negative. Smelters are adjusting their operating strategies to cope with the tight supply, reflecting ongoing challenges in copper concentrate availability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP's Copper Boom: Sustainable Mining to Meet Soaring Global Demand</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/bhps-copper-boom-sustainable-mining-to-meet-soaring-global-demand/</link><description>BHP reported record copper production with a 28% increase since FY22, emphasizing copper's role in energy transition technologies and urban development. The company is advancing sustainable mining by reducing greenhouse gas emissions, electrifying operations, expanding renewable energy use, and minimizing methane emissions, aiming for net zero by 2050. BHP expects global copper demand to rise by about 70% by 2050.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Mining 2025: Innovative Sustainable Solutions</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-mining-2025-innovative-sustainable-solutions</link><description>This article explores innovations in copper mining that reduce water usage by up to 30% per ton of copper produced and integrate blockchain for traceability and transparency in the supply chain. It highlights environmental and social considerations and the use of satellite technology to improve resource management, aligning copper mining with climate action targets and sustainable development.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Energy Efficiency in Copper Processing Plants 2025 - Technology, Sustainability &amp; Innovation</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/energy-efficiency-in-copper-processing-plants-2025</link><description>Energy-efficient copper processing plants in 2025 are cutting emissions by up to 30% through automation, digitization, smelting improvements, thermal recovery, and renewable energy integration. These innovations reduce fossil fuel reliance, lower operational costs, and support renewable infrastructure, reinforcing the copper sector's commitment to a green circular economy. Blockchain-based traceability ensures supply chain authenticity and transparency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CRML Secures One of the Largest Strategic Stockpiles of Ultra-High-Purity Copper Powder in a US$20M All-Share Acquisition</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/21/3192887/0/en/CRML-Secures-One-of-the-Largest-Strategic-Stockpiles-of-Ultra-High-Purity-Copper-Powder-in-a-US-20M-All-Share-Acquisition-Issued-at-a-40-Premium-to-Market.html</link><description>CRML acquired a large strategic stockpile of ultra-high-purity copper powder, securing a G7/EU-origin, fully traceable resource to support Western industrial resilience. This acquisition enhances CRML's ability to support R&amp;D and production for advanced manufacturing and defense, central to innovation in these sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>UNCTAD urges smarter copper trade as bottlenecks threaten global transition</title><link>https://unctad.org/news/unctad-urges-smarter-copper-trade-bottlenecks-threaten-global-transition</link><description>UNCTAD warns that a looming copper shortfall could stall the global shift to clean energy and digital infrastructure. The organization calls for smarter copper trade policies to address supply bottlenecks critical for the energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's role in the energy transition grows as demand surges</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_us/insights/mining-metals/coppers-role-in-the-energy-transition-grows-as-demand-surges</link><description>With intensifying supply pressures, copper companies are increasing production while embracing sustainability and digital innovations. The article discusses copper's expanding role in the energy transition and the industry's efforts to meet rising demand responsibly.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel rose to 14,420.75 USD/T on November 21, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices rose slightly to 14,420.75 USD per metric ton on November 21, up 0.11% from the previous day. However, prices are down 4.75% over the past month and 9.05% compared to the same time last year, reflecting ongoing market weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Sumitomo Metal Mining's Q3 nickel production rises 3.31% Year-on-Year</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103772-flash-sumitomo-metal-minings-q3-nickel-production-rises-331-year-on-year</link><description>Sumitomo Metal Mining reported nickel production of 22,900 tonnes for Q3 2025, a 5.32% increase from the previous quarter and a 3.31% rise compared to the same period last year. Production included electrolytic nickel, nickel sulfate, and ferronickel, while nickel-cobalt sulfide production at the Nickel Asia Corporation project in the Philippines declined.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Implats Q3 2025 nickel production rises 15.35% Year-on-Year</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103774-flash-implats-q3-2025-nickel-production-rises-1535-year-on-year</link><description>South Africa's Implats reported nickel production of 4,531 tonnes in briquette form for Q3 2025, a 19.43% increase from the previous quarter and 15.35% higher than the same period last year. The nickel was produced as a by-product of platinum group metals refining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Antitrust opens an investigation against the main producers of copper cables in Italy, accused of fixing prices since 2005</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/tag/prysmian/</link><description>The Italian antitrust authority has launched an investigation into the main producers of copper cables in Italy, including Prysmian, for alleged price-fixing practices dating back to 2005. This probe targets the copper cable market in Italy, potentially impacting Prysmian's operations and market behavior.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Italy's Prysmian sees stronger U.S. pricing, margins after new copper tariff scheme</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3TS0GY:0-italy-s-prysmian-sees-stronger-u-s-pricing-margins-after-new-copper-tariff-scheme/</link><description>Prysmian Group expects improved pricing and margins in the U.S. market following the implementation of a new copper tariff scheme. The company projects full-year adjusted EBITDA between 2.3 and 2.375 billion euros, reflecting positive financial impacts from tariff adjustments on copper cables.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Price Falls Slightly to $2,805.70/ton on November 21, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped 0.25% to $2,805.70 per ton on November 21, 2025, but remain elevated compared to previous months. The market has seen overall upward pressure due to trade tariffs and supply chain dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Historical Prices: November 18–21, 2025</title><link>https://www.investing.com/commodities/aluminum-historical-data</link><description>Recent data shows aluminum prices fluctuating between $2,783.80 and $2,863.30 per ton over the past week. The market remains volatile, reflecting ongoing global supply and demand shifts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium News: Market Updates and Price Movements</title><link>https://www.investing.com/commodities/aluminum-news</link><description>Latest headlines cover ongoing price changes and market developments in the aluminum sector, including impacts from tariffs and evolving demand patterns.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Edge Up in China, Close Above 21,405 Yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103467156/</link><description>Chinese aluminum prices pulled back from intraday highs but closed above 21,405 yuan per metric ton, reflecting sustained demand and regional market strength.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum industry mulls unveiled CBAM benchmarks, default values</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/aluminum-industry-mulls-unveiled-cbam-benchmarks-default-values/</link><description>Aluminum producers are reviewing the newly released CBAM (Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism) benchmarks and default values, which could have significant implications for trade and compliance in the European market. The industry is assessing how these benchmarks will affect costs and competitiveness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Rebounds to Highest in November</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China climbed to CNY 3,090 per tonne, the highest since early November, driven by Beijing's anti-involution policy reducing supply. Crude steel output in China fell 12% year-on-year in October, contributing to the price rebound despite a slight daily decline.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>CRU: APAC steel prices continued to decline amid weak demand</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/21/cru-apac-steel-prices-continued-to-decline-amid-weak-demand/</link><description>Chinese steel export prices declined due to weak domestic demand and tax-evading shipments, pulling down wider Asia-Pacific markets. In contrast, European sheet prices rose on import supply concerns related to trade policies, while US sheet prices increased significantly, surpassing landed import prices for the first time since July.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 4.99 USD/Lbs on November 21, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices increased by 0.86% from the previous day to $4.99 per pound, showing a 0.69% rise over the past month and a 22.54% increase compared to the same time last year. The metal reached an all-time high of $5.94 in July 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper futures fell below $4.95 per pound on Friday amid soft demand and supply concerns</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures dropped to a two-week low due to weak demand in China, affected by a property sector slump and slower power grid spending. Supply concerns persist with Freeport McMoRan planning to resume production at Indonesia’s Grasberg mine by July 2026 after a flood halted operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Amid Expectations of Copper Concentrate Shortages, How Are Smelters Adjusting Their Operating Strategies</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103634470/amid-expectations-of-copper-concentrate-shortages-how-are-smelters-adjusting-their-operating-strategies</link><description>Global copper smelters are aggressively adjusting to worsening concentrate shortages by locking in processing margins early and raising prepayment ratios. Chinese smelters are expanding exports to Southeast Asia and the Middle East to hedge against pricing losses, while refined copper smelting capacity growth is focused in China, Africa, and Indonesia.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel rose to 14,620 USD/T on November 21, 2025, up 1.14% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices increased by 1.14% to 14,620 USD per tonne on November 21, 2025, despite a 3.43% decline over the past month and a 7.80% drop compared to the previous year. The market remains volatile with fluctuations influenced by global economic factors and supply-demand dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Nornickel, a leading nickel producer, maintained its 2025 nickel production forecast at 196,000-204,000 metric tons. Production rose 18% in Q3 2025 due to higher volumes of processed raw materials, despite challenges from seasonal flooding and equipment replacement impacting output earlier in the year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Russia’s Nornickel reported an 18% increase in nickel production to 54,000 metric tons in Q3 2025 compared to the previous quarter. The company maintained its 2025 nickel production forecast at 196,000-204,000 metric tons despite earlier declines caused by equipment replacement and seasonal disruptions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,805.70 USD/T on November 21, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell 0.25% to $2,805.70 per tonne on November 21, 2025. Despite a slight monthly decline of 0.15%, prices remain 6.48% higher than a year ago, reflecting ongoing market fluctuations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,805.70 USD/T on November 21, 2025, down 0.25% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>China reaffirmed its focus on curbing overcapacity in metal production to ease deflationary pressures, with the aluminum output ceiling of 45 million tons expected to be exceeded next year. Supply pressures were compounded by disruptions such as the suspension of a potline at Iceland’s Grundartangi smelter and Alcoa's planned closure of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia due to deteriorating bauxite ore grades.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CoinCover Joins Digital Asset's Copper-based Disaster Recovery Setup at Canton Treasury</title><link>https://smbtech.au/news/coincover-joins-digital-assets-copper-based-disaster-recovery-setup-at-canton-treasury/</link><description>Digital Asset strengthened its treasury operations by integrating CoinCover into its Copper-based custody and disaster recovery setup. This move enhances security and operational resilience for digital asset management using Copper's technology platform.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices on Nov 22 climb to two-week high amid tightened supply</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/NewsItem/151442</link><description>Nickel futures at the London Metal Exchange surged by $256/ton to close at $15,970/ton on November 22, reaching a two-week high due to tightened supply conditions. The sharp increase reflects recent market volatility and supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Price Today</title><link>https://www.investing.com/commodities/nickel</link><description>The nickel price today is reported at 14,526.13 USD per metric ton. The market continues to show volatility, with prices fluctuating amid macroeconomic uncertainty and supply-demand dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 22 Nov 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/11/22/the-market-in-numbers-22-nov-2025/</link><description>Nickel prices declined by 2.59% on November 22, continuing a downward trend amid broader market pressures. The article highlights recent price movements and their implications for the metals sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (November 17, 2025 - November 21, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-november-17-2025-a-november-21-2025-on-the-ce7d5edfd189f422</link><description>Tenaris reported holding 37,359,848 ordinary shares in treasury, representing 3.49% of its total issued share capital as of November 21, 2025. The company remains a leading global supplier of steel tubes and related services for the energy industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Steel Production Ticked Higher in October</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/22/global-steel-production-ticked-higher-in-october/</link><description>After four consecutive monthly declines, global crude steel output increased by 1% from September to October 2025, reaching an estimated 143.3 million metric tons. China accounted for 50% of global production in October, producing 72.0 million metric tons, down 2% from September. Production outside China rose to a five-month high, increasing 4% from September.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>India's Power Ministry Honors M.P.K. Steels for Pioneering Energy-Efficient Manufacturing Technology</title><link>https://www.taxtmi.com/news?id=62456</link><description>M.P.K. Steels has been recognized by India's Power Ministry for implementing advanced energy-efficient technologies in its steel production facilities. The award highlights the company's leadership in sustainable manufacturing and sets a new benchmark for energy conservation in the industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 0.81% Lower at $5.0085 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511216592/comex-copper-ends-the-week-081-lower-at-50085-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for November delivery closed the week down 0.81% at $5.0085 per pound, marking a decline in three of the past four weeks. Despite the weekly drop, copper is up 25.65% year-to-date and remains well above its 52-week low.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Jubilee Metals Group reports 65% increase in copper production in first quarter</title><link>https://iol.co.za/business-report/companies/2025-11-22-jubilee-metals-group-reports-65-increase-in-copper-production-in-first-quarter/</link><description>Jubilee Metals Group announced a significant 65% rise in copper production for the first quarter of the 2026 financial year, reflecting strong operational performance and capacity expansion.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Harum Energy Q3 2025 nickel production rises 18.4% Year on Year</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5104917-flash-harum-energy-q3-2025-nickel-production-rises-184-year-on-year</link><description>PT Harum Energy Tbk reported a 18.4% year-on-year increase in nickel pig iron production to 19,249 tonnes in Q3 2025, with sales up 13.11% quarter-on-quarter. The company’s RKEF utilization rate improved to 89% in the first nine months of 2025, and its HPAL project is over 90% complete, with commissioning planned for early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>EV Nickel acquires unpatented mining claim over high-grade Langmuir South and Langmuir #2 nickel zones</title><link>https://www.webdisclosure.com/press-release/ev-nickel-inc-cve-evni-ev-nickel-acquires-unpatented-mining-claim-over-high-grade-langmuir-south-and-langmuir-2-nickel-zones-w2mIvSO5ihM</link><description>EV Nickel Inc. announced the issuance of an unpatented mining claim near Timmins, Ontario, advancing exploration of high-grade nickel mineralization. The company plans diamond drilling pending permit approval expected before the end of 2025, aiming to expand its nickel assets to support North American clean critical mineral supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit 3-Year High: Is It the Next Key Metal in the Clean Energy Shift?</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-hit-3-year-high-is-it-the-next-key-metal-in-the-clean-energy-shift/</link><description>Aluminum prices have reached a three-year high, driven by strong demand from electric vehicles, solar installations, and grid upgrades. The surge is reshaping supply chains as the metal becomes increasingly important for the transition to a low-carbon economy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Mining Methods 2025: Innovations &amp; Sustainability</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-mining-methods-2025-innovations-sustainability</link><description>The copper mining industry is advancing with innovations such as autonomous equipment, digital transformation, and sustainable extraction methods like in-situ leaching. These technologies are improving efficiency, reducing environmental impact, and supporting responsible resource extraction in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Energy Efficiency in Copper Processing Plants 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/energy-efficiency-in-copper-processing-plants-2025</link><description>In 2025, copper processing plants are achieving up to 30% lower emissions through automation, digitization, and integration of renewable energy. Innovations in thermal recovery and blockchain-based traceability are enhancing both sustainability and supply chain transparency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer drops to $2,765.5/t while opening stock climbs to 548,000t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-drops-to-2-765-5-t-while-opening-stock-climbs-to-548-000t-116302</link><description>LME aluminium prices eased on November 21 with cash and three-month contracts declining modestly. Exchange inventories increased, with opening stock rising to 548,000 tonnes. Forward values also weakened amid a slight drop in cash and three-month bids and offers.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price falls to one-month low in wider commodity slump</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-falls-to-one-month-low-in-wider-commodity-slump/</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped as much as 1.6% to $2,526 a ton on the London Metal Exchange, the lowest since November 14, amid a broad commodity pullback. The decline followed data showing record-high Chinese output in November, driven by booming exports and the end of export tax discounts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Manual Processing Profit Narrowed in October, Short-Term Primary Aluminum Imports Expected to Decrease [SMM Analysis]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635112/Manual-Processing-Profit-Narrowed-in-October-Short-Term-Primary-Aluminum-Imports-Expected-to-Decrease-%5BSMM-Analysis%5D</link><description>Profit margins for manual processing of aluminum narrowed in October, with expectations of decreased primary aluminum imports in the short term. Production cuts at an Icelandic smelter and tightening overseas supply have pushed LME aluminum prices higher, while high premiums in Europe and the US may divert supply away from China.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Manual Processing Profit Narrowed in October, Short-Term Primary Aluminum Imports Expected to Decrease [SMM Analysis]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635112/Manual-Processing-Profit-Narrowed-in-October-Short-Term-Primary-Aluminum-Imports-Expected-to-Decrease-%5BSMM-Analysis%5D</link><description>China's primary aluminum imports in October 2025 rose slightly by 0.6% month-on-month and 42.1% year-on-year, while exports decreased 15.2% MoM but increased 54.2% YoY. Production cuts at an Icelandic smelter and expectations of overseas supply tightening pushed LME aluminum prices higher, though SHFE prices lagged, narrowing profit margins for manual processing and likely reducing imports under handbook processing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Limited Commissioning of New Projects Leads to Slow Growth in Aluminum Production in 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635148/limited-commissioning-of-new-projects-leads-to-slow-growth-in-aluminum-production-in-2025-</link><description>China's operating aluminum capacity in 2025 approached the ceiling of compliant capacity with limited new project commissioning, resulting in slow capacity growth. Production cuts due to losses and technological transformation projects resuming contributed to an expected 1.7% year-on-year production growth. Regional capacity increases include resumed production in Sichuan and Guangxi provinces, with overall operating capacity up by 538,000 mt compared to 2024.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer drops to $2,765.5/t while opening stock climbs to 548,000t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-drops-to-2-765-5-t-while-opening-stock-climbs-to-548-000t-116302</link><description>LME aluminum prices eased on November 21, 2025, with the cash bid and offer both dropping by approximately 0.47%. Meanwhile, exchange inventories increased, with opening stock climbing to 548,000 tonnes, indicating a slight softening in market prices amid rising stock levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ITRI Wins Three R&amp;D 100 Awards for Breakthroughs in Regenerative Medicine and Sustainable Technologies</title><link>https://themalaysianreserve.com/2025/11/24/itri-wins-three-rd-100-awards-for-breakthroughs-in-regenerative-medicine-and-sustainable-technologies/</link><description>ITRI has been recognized with three R&amp;D 100 Awards for innovations in regenerative medicine and sustainable technologies, highlighting advancements that could impact aluminum sustainability and industrial processes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Enter Downward Channel as Weakening Costs Keep Stainless Steel Under Pressure</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28192.html</link><description>Nickel prices are trending downward due to weakening costs, which is putting pressure on stainless steel prices. The article highlights ongoing market dynamics affecting stainless steel and related commodities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Stock prices of US' steel industry skyrocket on Nov 24</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/NewsItem/122655</link><description>US steel industry stock prices surged on November 24, driven by acute supply shortages. The article notes strong market reactions to limited steel availability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 24, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/tata-steel-ltd-24-nov-2025-500470</link><description>Tata Steel Ltd shares declined by 0.15% on November 24, trading at ₹167.75 per share. Investors are closely watching the stock amid ongoing market volatility.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US steel shipments lifted by tariffs in Q3</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/us-steel-shipments-lifted-by-tariffs-in-q3/</link><description>US steel producers reported record shipments in Q3 as tariffs reduced imports. The article discusses how trade policies are influencing domestic steel market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ENR November 24, 2025: CONSTRUCTION ECONOMICS</title><link>https://digital.bnpmedia.com/article/CONSTRUCTION+ECONOMICS/5074480/857075/article.html</link><description>Monthly prices for reinforcing bars fell 0.1%, while yearly prices are down 15.1%. The article covers recent trends in construction steel prices and the producer price index for sheet metal.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global steel production ticked higher in October</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/22/global-steel-production-ticked-higher-in-october/</link><description>World crude steel output rose 1% from September to October, reaching 143.3 million metric tons, after four consecutive monthly declines. China's output fell 12% year-on-year, while the rest of the world saw a 1% increase, with daily production at a 22-month low.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Crude Steel Production Declines by 5.9% in October 2025</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/38272/</link><description>Global crude steel production declined 5.9% in October 2025 compared to the same month last year, with Asia and Oceania down 8.2% and Africa up 0.8%. The drop was mainly driven by continued weakness in China.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany increased steel production by 5.1% m/m in October</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Germany's steel production rose 5.1% month-on-month in October 2025, reflecting a regional uptick amid global production declines. The increase highlights ongoing shifts in European steelmaking capacity and output.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Global Steel Industry 2025: At a Pivotal Crossroads</title><link>https://www.steel-technology.com/articles/the-global-steel-industry-2025-at-a-pivotal-crossroads</link><description>The steel industry is undergoing a significant transformation driven by AI, hydrogen-based methods, automation, and sustainability. Green steel production is gaining momentum as demand for low-carbon materials rises, with hydrogen playing a key role in decarbonizing steelmaking processes. Supply chain challenges are also pushing the industry toward tech-driven solutions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Processing Industry Faces Pricing Stress Test</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/24/copper-processing-industry-faces-pricing-stress-test/</link><description>The global copper processing industry is expected to face a significant stress test in pricing mechanisms this week, reflecting ongoing market volatility and supply-demand imbalances. This could impact pricing stability and industry profitability in the near term.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's Grip on Copper Sets Scene for Make-or-Break Supply Talks</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2025/november/china-s-grip-on-copper-sets-scene-for-make-or-break-supply-talks/</link><description>The global copper-processing industry is facing a critical stress test as negotiations intensify amid China's dominance in securing copper concentrate supply and driving down processing fees. Chinese smelters continue to expand, crowding out international competitors and prompting concerns about the viability of the benchmark pricing system.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's Grip on Copper Sets Scene for Make-or-Break Supply Talks</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/chinas-grip-copper-sets-scene-make-or-break-supply-talks</link><description>Geopolitical tensions and China's growing control over copper concentrate supply are putting pressure on the global benchmark pricing mechanism. The expansion of Chinese smelting capacity has led to plummeting processing fees and increased struggles for smelters outside China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Processing Industry Faces Pricing Stress Test</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/24/copper-processing-industry-faces-pricing-stress-test/</link><description>The global copper processing industry is experiencing a major stress test due to China's dominance, constrained metal supplies, and the rapid expansion of processing capacity outpacing mined production. This is raising questions about the sustainability of the current benchmarking structure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Australian Mining Giant BHP Drops Anglo American Takeover Bid</title><link>https://www.macaubusiness.com/australian-mining-giant-bhp-drops-anglo-american-takeover-bid/</link><description>BHP, a major Australian mining company, has withdrawn its takeover bid for Anglo American, which could impact future copper production and capacity expansion plans in the sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's Grip on Copper Sets Scene for Make-or-Break Supply Talks</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2025/november/china-s-grip-on-copper-sets-scene-for-make-or-break-supply-talks/</link><description>China's dominant position in copper supply is influencing critical supply talks, with the country deploying digital tools to drive efficiency in copper production. This dynamic is shaping the global copper market amid rising demand and supply challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Enter Downward Channel as Weakening Costs Keep Stainless Steel Under Pressure</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28192.html</link><description>Nickel prices have entered a downward channel due to weakening costs and increased production capacity in China and Indonesia. The oversupply and weak demand are keeping stainless steel prices under pressure, with little room for a near-term rebound in nickel prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices have dropped to 14,532.00 USD/ton, the lowest since April 2025, losing 4.57% over the past four weeks and 8.05% over the past year. The market remains bearish due to persistent oversupply and weak demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in November period I</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103862-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-november-period-i</link><description>Indonesia's Nickel Miners Association (APNI) set the benchmark price for nickel ore at $15,075.33/wmt for the first half of November 2025, a slight decrease from October. Prices for various grades of nickel ore also declined marginally.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 24, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635765/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price was reported at 115,400–120,100 yuan/mt on November 24, with an average price of 117,750 yuan/mt, up 1,050 yuan/mt from the previous day. The market saw a slight rebound amid ongoing oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Rebound Slightly on November 24 as US-Ukraine Talks Make Significant Progress</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635953/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Rebound-Slightly-on-November-24-as-US-Ukraine-Talks-Make-Significant-Progress</link><description>Nickel prices rebounded slightly on November 24, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 117,750 yuan/mt, up 1,050 yuan/mt from the previous day. The rebound was attributed to progress in US-Ukraine talks, but oversupply remains a concern.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>MMG's deal to buy Anglo American's Brazil nickel assets faces EU regulatory delay</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/mmgs-deal-to-buy-anglo-americans-brazil-nickel-assets-faces-eu-regulatory-delay-2025-11-24</link><description>MMG's acquisition of Anglo American's Brazilian nickel assets is facing delays due to regulatory scrutiny from the European Commission, which is concerned the deal could divert ferronickel supplies away from Europe and negatively impact the European stainless steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in November (Period I)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103862-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-november-period-i</link><description>The Indonesia Nickel Miners Association (APNI) has announced the benchmark prices for nickel ore for the first half of November 2025, providing updated guidance for the domestic market amid ongoing supply and pricing volatility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Ore Port Inventory</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/102492700/</link><description>On November 24, 2025, the national port nickel ore inventory in China increased by 97,000 wet tons, reaching a total of 10.106 million wet tons, reflecting continued high supply levels and inventory buildup.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to $14,549.75 per tonne on November 24, 2025, down 0.48% from the previous day, continuing a downward trend as global supply outpaces demand and inventories remain elevated.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>