<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:16:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Persistent Supply Disruptions Sustain Upward Pressure on LME Nickel Prices</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-27046.html</link><description>Ongoing supply disruptions in the nickel market continue to exert upward pressure on London Metal Exchange (LME) nickel prices. These disruptions contribute to market volatility and reflect tight supply conditions in the global nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia emerging as strategic hub in critical minerals supply chain</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/icc-indonesia-emerging-as-strategic-hub-in-critical-minerals-supply-chain</link><description>Indonesia is increasingly recognized as a strategic hub in the global critical minerals supply chain, particularly for nickel. The country's role is expanding due to its large reserves and government policies supporting the sector, which impacts global nickel production capacity and supply security.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises Toward 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,769.80 per tonne on October 13, 2025, up 0.74% from the previous day, marking a 2.44% increase over the past month and a 6.61% rise year-on-year. The price increase is driven by expectations of lower supply, with Chinese authorities cutting their annual output growth targets for base metals, tightening the market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Soars to 52-Week High Amidst Robust Market and Strategic Expansion</title><link>http://business.times-online.com/times-online/article/marketminute-2025-10-13-century-aluminum-soars-to-52-week-high-amidst-robust-market-and-strategic-expansion</link><description>Century Aluminum's stock hit a 52-week high driven by rising aluminum prices and constrained global supply. The company’s strategic expansion and focus on sustainability, including renewable energy use, have bolstered investor confidence amid tight global aluminum markets and ongoing trade policy challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alumobility to Present Lightweighting Study at EuroCarBody 2025</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/alumobility-to-present-lightweighting-study-at-eurocarbody-2025-302581652.html</link><description>Alumobility will present a study at the EuroCarBody 2025 conference showing that converting key vehicle systems from steel to aluminum can reduce the weight of a crossover BEV by 20% without increasing cost or manufacturing complexity. The study highlights aluminum's role in sustainable automotive design and lightweighting, supporting more efficient and cost-effective vehicle architectures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Green Steel Markets Near EU Emissions Policies Emerge</title><link>https://bioengineer.org/green-steel-markets-near-eu-emissions-policies-emerge/</link><description>Emerging green steel markets are being shaped by EU emissions policies, including the Emissions Trading System and Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism. Increased consumer and corporate demand for low-carbon steel is driving supply chain changes, with sustainability becoming a key competitive factor in the industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU seeks US trade concessions by doubling steel tariffs</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/eu-seeks-us-trade-concessions-by-doubling-steel-tariffs/</link><description>The EU Commission announced it will double tariffs on steel imports above a tariff-free quota to 50%, aiming to secure trade concessions from the US. This move reflects ongoing trade tensions and could impact global steel trade flows.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Price of Aluminum: Mill Fire Adds Fuel to in U.S. Prices</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/10/13/mill-fire-fuela-price-of-aluminum/</link><description>European aluminum plate and sheet prices increased significantly in early October, with the 5083 aluminum plate rising 3.79% and the 1050 aluminum sheet up 3.74%. LME primary three-month aluminum prices also rose by 2.61%, while some Korean aluminum prices declined, reflecting mixed regional market trends influenced by supply disruptions such as mill fires.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Rally Soars on China's 2025 Demand Amidst Escalating Trade Tensions</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-13-copper-rally-soars-on-chinas-2025-demand-amidst-escalating-trade-tensions</link><description>Copper prices have surged due to strong demand from China driven by electric vehicles, renewable energy, and data centers. Supply constraints and geopolitical tensions are intensifying market tightness, with forecasts indicating potential supply deficits and increased activity in mining and supply chain sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Daily Social Inventory of Secondary Aluminum Ingots Drops by 31 mt on Oct 14</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103566577/SMM-Flash-News:-Daily-Social-Inventory-of-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingots-Drops-by-31-mt-on-Oct-14</link><description>Secondary aluminum markets mostly lowered prices by 100 yuan/mt on October 14, 2025, although some enterprises remain optimistic about future price trends. This indicates a short-term price adjustment in the secondary aluminum ingot market amid ongoing market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Ripple Effects of Steel and Aluminum Tariffs on HVAC</title><link>https://www.achrnews.com/articles/164158-the-ripple-effects-of-steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-on-hvac</link><description>The article discusses the economic impact of re-imposing 25% tariffs on steel and aluminum imports, highlighting concerns from the Coalition of American Metal Manufacturers and Users (CAMMU) about harm to U.S. manufacturers. It includes insights from Stan Kolbe of the Sheet Metal and Air Conditioning Contractors' National Association on how tariffs affect the HVAC industry and broader economic challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>National Security Investigation: Section 232 Opportunities for U.S. Factories</title><link>https://www.bipc.com/national-security-investigation-section-232-opportunities-for-u.s.-factories</link><description>The U.S. Department of Commerce’s Bureau of Industry and Security has opened inclusion windows for Section 232 tariffs affecting steel and aluminum products. This process offers U.S. factories opportunities to request product inclusions to benefit from tariffs designed to protect domestic manufacturers, particularly in the automotive sector, with specific guidance on tariff stacking.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Latest Tariff Developments - RVIA</title><link>https://www.rvia.org/news-insights/latest-tariff-developments</link><description>The article provides updates on ongoing tariff developments, including the continuation of Section 232 tariffs on steel and aluminum products. It notes recent inclusion requests for additional steel and aluminum derivative products to be subject to these tariffs, with rates set at 50% on the metal portion, reflecting ongoing trade policy enforcement.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>【SMM Flash News】According to SMM statistics, on October 14 ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103566577/SMM-Flash-News:-Daily-Social-Inventory-of-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingots-Drops-by-31-mt-on-Oct-14</link><description>SMM reports a daily social inventory drop of secondary aluminum ingots by 31 metric tons on October 14, 2025. The news also highlights challenges faced by Indonesia in its strategic shift from bauxite exporter to integrated aluminum producer amid significant headwinds this year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weekly Recap: Aluminium's low-carbon revolution in action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminium industry is undergoing a transformation towards sustainability, focusing on low-carbon production and innovative recycling technologies. Companies like RUSAL are developing technologies to turn off-grade aluminium scrap into high-purity metal. Taural India is also implementing sustainable practices to reduce emissions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US government launches new aluminum recycling technology</title><link>https://www.rinnovabili.net/draft/aluminum-recycling-technology-us/</link><description>The Pacific Northwest National Laboratory has developed the Shear Assisted Processing and Extrusion Process (ShAPE), which transforms 100% of aluminum scrap into construction-ready extrusions. This technology reduces energy consumption and eliminates impurities, making it more efficient than traditional methods.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>How green aluminium is transforming the metal industry</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/how-green-aluminium-is-transforming-the-metal-industry/</link><description>Green aluminium production involves low-carbon smelting and recycling, significantly reducing the carbon footprint of aluminium production. The industry is shifting towards maximizing recycled content, which requires only 5% of the energy needed for new aluminium production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Update: Chinese Steel Falls Further, Down 11% Year-on-Year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China dropped to 3,041 CNY/T on October 14, 2025, down 0.59% from the previous day and 11.08% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect prices to remain under pressure, with forecasts suggesting a further decline to 2,917.81 CNY/T over the next 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Prices Decline, But Remain Up Year-on-Year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel prices fell to 803.07 USD/T on October 13, 2025, down 1.34% from the previous day, but still 15.05% higher than a year ago. Forecasts indicate a potential rebound, with prices expected to reach 831.44 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 894.34 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Steel Demand Forecasted to Remain Flat in 2025</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/14/global-steel-demand-forecasted-to-remain-flat/</link><description>Worldsteel projects global steel demand will remain flat in 2025 at about 1,750 million tonnes, mirroring 2024 levels, with a modest rebound of 1.3% expected in 2026. China’s steel demand is forecast to decline by 2% in 2025, driven by a weak housing market, with risks weighted to the downside due to trade tensions and financial pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU Seeks US Trade Concessions by Doubling Steel Tariffs</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/eu-seeks-us-trade-concessions-by-doubling-steel-tariffs/</link><description>The EU Commission announced it will double duties to 50% for steel imports above a tariff-free quota, a move aimed at securing trade concessions from the US. This policy shift reflects ongoing trade tensions and could impact global steel trade flows.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iran's steel export increases 26% in H1</title><link>https://www.tehrantimes.com/news/519083/Iran-s-steel-export-increases-26-in-H1</link><description>Iran's steel exports rose by 26% in the first half of 2025, according to the Iranian Steel Producers Association. Despite a 5.3% year-on-year drop in production from January to May, output in May alone increased by 4.5%, and Iran now ranks ninth globally in steel production, just behind Germany.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Steel Demand Forecasted to Remain Flat</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/14/global-steel-demand-forecasted-to-remain-flat/</link><description>Worldsteel forecasts global steel demand will remain flat in 2025 at about 1,750 million tonnes, with a modest rebound of 1.3% expected in 2026. China's steel demand is projected to decline by 2% in 2025, mainly due to a downturn in the housing market, while global manufacturing faces elevated costs and trade tensions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>VinFast and the Quiet Power of Integration: Building a Greener Future from the Ground Up</title><link>https://themalaysianreserve.com/2025/10/14/vinfast-and-the-quiet-power-of-integration-building-a-greener-future-from-the-ground-up/</link><description>VinFast has announced VinMetal, a new high-tech steel manufacturer, as part of its broader strategy to build a sustainable, integrated ecosystem for greener manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed interest rate cuts heat up, LME copper surges overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103566505/Expectations-for-US-Fed-interest-rate-cuts-heat-up-LME-copper-surges-overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper futures surged overnight amid expectations of U.S. Fed interest rate cuts. The price movement reflects ongoing supply disruptions and market dynamics. Spot prices in Shanghai and Guangdong showed mixed trends, with some premiums increasing while others decreased.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Accelerates Copper Production to Meet Global Demand</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/rio-tinto-copper-production-expansion-2025-market-impact/</link><description>Rio Tinto has reported a significant increase in copper production, reaching 204,000 tonnes in Q3 2025, a 10% rise from the previous year. This growth is part of the company's strategic expansion to capitalize on rising global demand for copper. The strong performance reflects Rio Tinto's commitment to its copper business segment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed interest rate cuts heat up, LME copper surges overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103566505/Expectations-for-US-Fed-interest-rate-cuts-heat-up-LME-copper-surges-overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices surged overnight amid expectations of US Fed interest rate cuts. The futures opened at $10,648.5/mt, reflecting ongoing market volatility. Copper prices remain high despite slight pullbacks in some regions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Sharp divide between copper bulls and bears at industry gathering</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/lmeweek-sharp-divide-between-copper-bulls-and-bears-at-industry-gathering/</link><description>The copper market is experiencing a sharp divide between bullish and bearish outlooks. Bulls predict price increases due to mine disruptions, while bears argue the market is oversupplied. The LME three-month copper price has gained significantly this year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Bulls vs Bears: The Sharp Divide in Copper Industry</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-market-divide-bulls-bears-industry-2025/</link><description>The copper market is divided between those expecting price increases due to supply disruptions and those seeing a surplus. The LME three-month copper contract has risen significantly year-to-date. Industry experts are debating whether this trend is sustainable.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Supply Shocks Set the Stage For Shortages</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-bulls-lme-week-party-clouded-by-trumps-china-threats/copper-supply-shocks-set-the-stage-for-shortages-morgan-stanley-expects-the-biggest-deficit-in-22-years-next-year/</link><description>Morgan Stanley expects a significant copper deficit next year, driven by supply shocks. Mine disruptions have already impacted global supply, leading to price increases. Analysts predict further shortages in the coming years.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco joins mining giants backing Friedland's I-Pulse's technology</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/codelco-joins-mining-giants-backing-friedlands-i-pulses-technology-2025-10-14</link><description>Codelco and other mining giants are supporting Friedland's I-Pulse technology, which aims to reduce energy consumption in drilling, rock crushing, and underground mining. This innovation is expected to contribute significantly to sustainability by lowering the environmental footprint of mining operations.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Approach 120,000 Yuan Again Amid Ongoing US-China Trade Tensions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103567756/</link><description>Nickel prices have been fluctuating, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranging from 120,700 to 123,500 yuan/mt on October 14. This reflects ongoing market dynamics influenced by trade tensions and other global factors. The average price was 122,100 yuan/mt, down 350 yuan/mt from previous levels.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Extend Gains as Weaker Dollar &amp; Fed Rate Cut Expectations Boost Market</title><link>https://yieh.com/es/News/nickel-prices-extend-gains-as-weaker-dollar-fed-rate-cut-expectations-boost-market/157126</link><description>Nickel prices have increased due to a weaker U.S. dollar and expectations of a Fed rate cut. The spot price rose by $120.5/ton to reach $15,257/ton. These factors have contributed to a boost in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Fathom Nickel's three-year journey to full project ownership</title><link>https://mining.com.au/fathom-nickels-three-year-journey-to-full-project-ownership/</link><description>Fathom Nickel has completed a 100% earn-in at the Gochager Lake Nickel Project in Saskatchewan, expanding the project area significantly. Recent wildfires revealed new outcrops and high-priority drill targets, supporting the development of a high-grade nickel camp in Canada.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Legacy Minerals Strengthens Nickel-Cobalt Ambitions with Strategic MoU</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/stocks/metal-and-mining/legacy-minerals-strengthens-nickel-cobalt-ambitions-with-strategic-mou</link><description>Legacy Minerals announced a strategic Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) to strengthen its nickel-cobalt ambitions, signaling increased focus on expanding its footprint in these critical minerals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Approach 120,000 Yuan Again on October 14 Amid Ongoing US-China Trade Tensions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103567756/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Approach-120000-Yuan-Again-on-October-14-Amid-Ongoing-US-China-Trade-Tensions</link><description>Nickel prices on October 14 hovered between 120,700 and 123,500 yuan per metric ton, with an average price of 122,100 yuan/mt, slightly down by 350 yuan/mt. The market remains influenced by ongoing US-China trade tensions impacting supply and demand dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy's Antitrust Authority has opened an investigation into major low voltage copper cable manufacturers, including Prysmian, over alleged price-fixing and anti-competitive practices since 2005. The probe was triggered by a clemency request from one company, leading to inspections at several firms and industry associations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,744.60 USD/T on October 14, 2025, down 0.91% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices declined slightly to 2,744.60 USD per tonne on October 14, 2025, down 0.91% from the previous day. Despite this drop, prices have risen 1.51% over the past month and are up 6.67% compared to the same time last year. Aluminum futures recently reached a three-year high amid tight supply and bullish demand expectations, with Chinese authorities lowering their base metals output growth targets for 2025 and 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Design for Sustainability: New Design Principles for Reducing IT Hardware Emissions</title><link>https://engineering.fb.com/2025/10/14/data-center-engineering/design-for-sustainability-new-design-principles-for-reducing-it-hardware-emissions/</link><description>Facebook Engineering introduces new technical design principles aimed at reducing emissions and costs in IT hardware, emphasizing sustainability in the development of new products.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Falls Slightly to 813 USD/T on October 14, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>The price of Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel fell marginally by 0.12% to 813 USD per ton on October 14, 2025. Despite the slight daily decline, HRC steel prices have risen 0.62% over the past month and are up 16.48% compared to the same period last year. Analysts expect prices to reach 831.44 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 894.34 USD/T within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AISI: Raw steel production drops to multi-month low</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/14/aisi-raw-steel-production-drops-to-multi-month-low/</link><description>US raw steel production declined for the second consecutive week, falling to the lowest weekly rate since May. Domestic mills produced an estimated 1,722,000 short tons of raw steel in the week ending October 11, with a 1.5% decrease from the previous week, though year-to-date production remains 2.5% higher than last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Swedish Green Steel Firm Stegra Launches $1B Round to Finish Hydrogen Steel Plant</title><link>https://esgnews.com/swedish-green-steel-firm-stegra-launches-1b-round-to-finish-hydrogen-steel-plant/</link><description>Stegra, formerly H2 Green Steel, has opened a €975 million ($1.1 billion) financing round to complete its green steel plant in Boden, Sweden. The plant will use renewable-powered hydrogen to replace coal in steelmaking, aiming to be one of Europe's flagship industrial decarbonisation projects, with over €6.5 billion already secured.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron and steelmaking account for around one-tenth of all CO2 emissions. Here’s how they could be greener</title><link>https://www.unsw.edu.au/newsroom/news/2025/10/Green-iron-steel-reduce-CO2-emissions</link><description>Current iron and steelmaking methods contribute approximately 7-9% of global CO2 emissions. UNSW Professor Yansong Shen leads research into low-cost, low-emission ironmaking technologies aimed at eliminating coal use to achieve greener steel production and support global net zero goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Swedish Green Steel Firm Stegra Launches $1B Round to Finish Hydrogen Steel Plant</title><link>https://esgnews.com/swedish-green-steel-firm-stegra-launches-1b-round-to-finish-hydrogen-steel-plant/</link><description>Stegra, a Swedish green steel firm, has launched a $1 billion financing round to complete its hydrogen steel plant in Boden. This project aims to significantly reduce emissions from traditional steel production by using hydrogen. The financing will also cover infrastructure costs and ensure greater control over critical assets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Freeport to Break Away from Copper Benchmark System in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/freeport-copper-pricing-2025-transformation-strategy/</link><description>Freeport-McMoRan plans to abandon the longstanding copper benchmark pricing system due to record-low treatment and refining charges (TC/RCs) that threaten smelter profitability globally. The 2025 benchmark TC/RC rates have dropped to historic lows, with some spot market offers even showing negative rates, a situation described as unsustainable by industry experts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper falls on US-China trade tensions</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-falls-on-us-china-trade-tensions/</link><description>Copper prices declined as US-China trade tensions impacted market sentiment. The premium for cash copper over the three-month contract dropped to $45 per ton after peaking at $227, its highest since June, reflecting volatility linked to geopolitical concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Golden Decade: Global Market Set to Soar Beyond $450 Billion by 2034, Fueling Green Transition and Industrial Evolution</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-10-14-coppers-golden-decade-global-market-set-to-soar-beyond-450-billion-by-2034-fueling-green-transition-and-industrial-evolution</link><description>The global copper market is projected to exceed $450 billion by 2034, driven by the green energy transition, electrification, and surging demand from electric vehicles and renewable infrastructure. Despite robust demand, the industry faces supply challenges due to declining ore grades and slow new mine development, which are expected to keep prices elevated.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP Resolution Copper Mine: 7 Innovations For 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/bhp-resolution-copper-mine-7-innovations-for-2025</link><description>BHP's Resolution Copper Mine is implementing seven major innovations in 2025, including automated drilling, advanced ore processing, intelligent mine management, water recycling, sustainable land reclamation, renewable energy integration, and enhanced community engagement. These technologies aim to boost efficiency, reduce CO₂ emissions, and increase copper output while improving sustainability and local relations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP Copper Mine: Hot Copper BHP Innovation 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/bhp-copper-mine-hot-copper-bhp-innovation-2025</link><description>BHP copper mines are deploying cutting-edge automation, AI, energy management, and blockchain traceability to enhance productivity and sustainability. These innovations have led to significant CO₂ reductions, lower water use, and greater supply chain transparency, setting new industry benchmarks for responsible copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel declines on negative price outlook for next year</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-declines-on-negative-price-outlook-for-next-year-47532</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts nickel prices to fall 6% to $14,500 per metric ton by December 2026, citing the need for Indonesian producer margins to decline to curb supply growth. The report highlights a persistent surplus and weak demand outlook, influenced by trade tensions and supply dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ardea positioned for growth from KNP launch pad</title><link>https://mining.com.au/ardea-positioned-for-growth-from-knp-launch-pad/</link><description>Ardea Resources is advancing the Kalgoorlie Nickel Project (KNP) with a 40-year mine life and 4 million tonnes of contained nickel in the Goongarrie Hub. The project is designed for modular expansion to reduce capital expenditure and accelerate future growth phases, with additional upside potential from the Kalpini hub and other mineral resources.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Meeting with Norilsk Nickel CEO Vladimir Potanin</title><link>http://en.kremlin.ru/events/president/news/78199</link><description>Norilsk Nickel, led by CEO Vladimir Potanin, produces nickel along with platinum group metals, gold, and rare metals, meeting domestic needs and exporting surplus. The company is reducing emissions through new technologies and predictive modeling, enhancing environmental performance despite sanctions pressures.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Discusses Maximizing Hydrogen Storage Vessel Lifecycle in Tech Talk</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-discusses-maximizing-hydrogen-storage-vessel-lifecycle-in-tech-talk-ce7d5ad9d08ff527</link><description>Tenaris recently discussed strategies for maximizing the lifecycle of hydrogen storage vessels in a Tech Talk event. The focus was on optimizing these vessels for sustainable energy applications. This aligns with Tenaris's broader commitment to supporting the energy transition.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Drift Upward Despite Stock Surplus</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/10/14/copper-prices-drift-up-despite-surplus/</link><description>Copper prices have risen 3.7% from September to October, with Comex prices surpassing $11,000 per metric ton. Despite a surplus in stocks and global economic headwinds, bullish fundamentals such as data center demand and raw material constraints support the upward trend, although some softness in renewables forecasts tempers the outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Rises by 26 mt on Oct 15</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103568852/SMM-Flash-News:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Rises-by-26-mt-on-Oct-15</link><description>On October 15, secondary aluminum markets mostly lowered prices by 100 yuan/mt, although some enterprises remain optimistic about future demand. The social inventory of secondary aluminum ingots increased by 26 metric tons, indicating shifts in supply dynamics within the recycled aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Fed Month-End Interest Rate Cut Signals Strengthen, Consumption Underpins Aluminum Market</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>On October 14, SHFE aluminum prices closed slightly lower under short-term pressure but maintained a medium to long-term upward trend. Market activity was low with reduced trading volume, and technical indicators showed mixed momentum. The aluminum market remained rangebound with key resistance and support zones identified, while consumption fundamentals continue to support the market amid recent US Federal Reserve interest rate cuts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Rises by 26 mt on Oct 15</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103568852/SMM-Flash-News:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Rises-by-26-mt-on-Oct-15</link><description>According to SMM statistics, domestic aluminum ingot inventory in 2025 increased by 57,000 mt, a 9.6% rise, while aluminum billet inventory also saw an increase. The latest data shows a daily rise of 26 mt in secondary aluminum ingot social inventory on October 15.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Al Yamamah Steel commissions operations at new wind tower factory in Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://powerline.net.in/2025/10/15/al-yamamah-steel-commissions-operations-at-new-wind-tower-factory-in-saudi-arabia/</link><description>Al Yamamah Steel Industries Company has started commercial operations at its new wind energy systems factory in Yanbu Industrial City, Saudi Arabia. The factory has an annual production capacity of 50,000 tonnes of steel towers designed for modern wind turbines, with towers exceeding 130 meters in height.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SPD floats partial nationalisation as last resort to save Germany's steel industry</title><link>https://www.cleanenergywire.org/news/spd-floats-partial-nationalisation-last-resort-step-save-germanys-steel-industry</link><description>Germany's Social Democrats (SPD) have proposed taking stakes in struggling steel companies as a last-resort measure to rescue the crisis-ridden steel industry amid ongoing challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Scientists Create Wood 10 Times Stronger Than Steel</title><link>https://greekreporter.com/2025/10/15/scientists-create-wood-ten-times-stronger-steel/</link><description>Researchers have developed a new type of wood, known as Superwood, which is ten times stronger than steel and six times lighter. This innovation could revolutionize construction by offering a sustainable alternative to steel. The production process has a lower carbon footprint compared to steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>IEA Issues Warning on Oil Supply Surplus, LME Copper Plunged Sharply Last Night</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103568754/</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated significantly overnight, closing at $10,598.5/mt, down 1.88%. The trading volume reached 29,000 lots. This volatility comes amid broader market concerns about supply disruptions and global economic uncertainties.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Producer Aurubis Held Talks with US on Support for New Smelter</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-producer-aurubis-held-talks-with-us-on-support-for-new-smelter-ceo-says/</link><description>Aurubis, a German copper producer, has engaged in preliminary discussions with the US regarding support for a new smelter. This move reflects ongoing efforts to enhance copper production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices remained in the doldrums on October 15 as the US Fed may cut interest rates again in October</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103569973/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-remained-in-the-doldrums-on-October-15-as-the-US-Fed-may-cut-interest-rates-again-in-October</link><description>On October 15, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,300 yuan/mt, slightly up from the previous day. Market sentiment is cautious due to risks like a potential US government shutdown and Sino-US trade tensions, with nickel prices expected to remain subdued in the short term amid weak fundamentals and uncertain Fed policy.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>NPI smelters caught between rising costs and tepid demand, while October prices have upside potential</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103560694/npi-smelters-caught-between-rising-costs-and-tepid-demand-while-october-prices-have-upside-potential-</link><description>Nickel Pig Iron (NPI) smelters face challenges from rising costs and weak demand, with prices declining slightly after the National Day holiday in China. Market participants are cautious, awaiting October consumption and price trends to determine future direction, as stainless steel prices remain subdued, limiting NPI price increases.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Institute seminar and cocktail reception - 2025</title><link>https://nickelinstitute.org/en/resources/articles/nickel-institute-seminar-and-cocktail-reception-2025</link><description>The Nickel Institute is hosting a seminar and cocktail reception focused on how circularity, evolving recycling practices, and sustainability frameworks are reshaping the future of nickel. The event highlights innovations in nickel technology and sustainability efforts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>'A blind spot at COPs': NGOs call for equity in transition minerals ahead of COP30</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/news/a-blind-spot-at-cops-ngos-call-for-equity-in-transition-minerals-ahead-of-cop30/</link><description>NGOs urge governments to recognize human rights, environmental protection, and equity in mineral value chains, including nickel, during climate negotiations at COP30. They emphasize the importance of just transition frameworks to ensure sustainable development and local job creation in the mining sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,747.05 per tonne on October 15, 2025, marking a 0.03% increase from the previous day and reaching the highest level in over three years. The price has increased 1.20% over the past month and 6.15% year-over-year, driven by tight supply and bullish demand expectations, with Chinese authorities lowering their base metals output growth targets.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CPI Rebound Coupled with Inventory Drawdown, Aluminum Prices Hold Up Well in the Short Term</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>Technical analysis of SHFE aluminum contracts shows limited price fluctuations with short-term pressure but a medium to long-term bullish trend supported by inventory drawdowns and CPI rebound. Market participation remains low with a wait-and-see sentiment prevailing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Surge Approaches Record Highs in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-price-surge-market-indicators-2025/</link><description>Copper prices have surged toward record highs, reaching $10,866.25 per tonne and approaching the previous peak of $11,400 per tonne from May 2024. The market shows strong institutional interest and technical momentum, driven by structural supply deficits, declining ore grades, and growing demand linked to the global energy transition and electric vehicle adoption.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Export Avalanche Reshapes Global Markets Amidst Arbitrage Frenzy</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-10-15-chinese-copper-export-avalanche-reshapes-global-markets-amidst-arbitrage-frenzy</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are exporting unprecedented volumes due to arbitrage opportunities between international and domestic prices, reshaping global supply chains. This export surge comes amid persistent global supply deficits and strong demand from the energy transition, temporarily easing LME inventory shortages but not resolving underlying structural tightness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Commodity Radar: Copper prices cool off after Monday's sharp rally</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/commodity-radar-copper-prices-cool-off-after-mondays-sharp-rally-time-to-buy-on-dips-for-16-potential-gains-says-religare-expert/articleshow/124548572.cms</link><description>Copper prices fell sharply on Tuesday after a strong rally on Monday, with MCX October futures dropping 2.4% amid profit taking and international price declines. Supply disruptions in major mines and expectations of US interest rate cuts had previously pushed prices to a 16-month high near $11,000 per ton, supported by robust demand from green energy and electric vehicles.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Weaker dollar, Fed cut bets drive copper up</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40387650</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.9% to $10,675 per metric ton, supported by a weaker US dollar and expectations of Federal Reserve interest rate cuts. These macroeconomic factors are contributing to upward pressure on copper prices amid ongoing supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Export Avalanche Reshapes Global Markets Amidst Arbitrage Frenzy</title><link>http://markets.chroniclejournal.com/chroniclejournal/article/marketminute-2025-10-15-chinese-copper-export-avalanche-reshapes-global-markets-amidst-arbitrage-frenzy</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are capitalizing on near-record LME prices and a premium for immediate delivery outside China, causing an unprecedented surge in exports. This export wave temporarily replenishes LME inventories but does not resolve underlying supply deficits caused by mine disruptions and strong long-term demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Japan, Spain and South Korea warn over unsustainable copper processing fees</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/japan-spain-and-south-korea-warn-over-unsustainable-copper-processing-fees/</link><description>Japan, Spain, and South Korea issued a joint statement expressing concern over falling copper treatment and refining charges (TC/RCs), which threaten the sustainability of copper smelting operations. The decline in fees, partly due to expanding Chinese smelting capacity and tight concentrate supply, is causing some smelters to consider scaling back or exiting the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel mine using smelting and leaching processes to extract nickel</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/mining-innovation-takes-centre-stage-during-sudbury-mining-week/attachment/nickel-mine-using-smelting-and-leaching-processes-to-extract-nickel/</link><description>A nickel mine is utilizing both smelting and leaching processes to extract nickel, highlighting innovation in mining techniques. The article does not provide specific details about new production capacities but emphasizes the use of advanced extraction methods. This approach can improve efficiency and reduce environmental impact.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Releases Positive Results from Crawford Nickel Project Economic Impact Study</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/pr-newswire/20251015to98247/canada-nickel-releases-positive-results-from-crawford-nickel-project-economic-impact-study</link><description>Canada Nickel Company announced positive results from an economic impact study for its Crawford Nickel Project. The project is expected to contribute significantly to Canada's GDP and generate substantial tax revenues and employment opportunities. While not directly addressing current production capacity, it highlights future potential.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, northern Italy, marking a significant step in replacing fossil natural gas with green hydrogen in its industrial heat treatment process. This initiative aims to reduce CO₂ emissions substantially and supports the company's commitment to climate-neutral industrial processes.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne, located in Aosta, has entered a new period in steel production with a green hydrogen facility</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/haber/cogne-located-in-aosta-has-entered-a-new-period-in-steel-production-with-a-green-hydrogen-facility/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is pioneering the use of green hydrogen in steel production by replacing fossil natural gas in its heat treatment process. The company also develops specialized stainless steels designed for hydrogen transport infrastructure, contributing to the energy transition and climate neutrality goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Drops by 1,600 mt to 54,800 mt on Oct 16</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103572172/SMM-Flash-News:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Drops-by-1600-mt-to-54800-mt-on-Oct-16</link><description>China's domestic secondary aluminum ingot inventory decreased by 1,600 metric tons to 54,800 metric tons as of October 16, 2025, according to SMM data. This reflects ongoing adjustments in secondary aluminum supply within the Chinese market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Gov't invites feedback on $2B plan to support green aluminium manufacturing</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/govt-invites-feedback-on-2b-plan-to-support-green-aluminium-manufacturing/</link><description>The Australian Government has launched a public consultation for its $2 billion Green Aluminium Production Credit to boost domestic aluminium manufacturing and support the transition to renewable energy. The initiative aims to help aluminium smelters shift to renewable electricity, reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and strengthen Australia's position in sustainable aluminium production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Dutch Nouryon completes metal alkyls capacity expansion in China</title><link>https://www.icis.com/explore/resources/news/2025/10/16/11146273/dutch-nouryon-completes-metal-alkyls-capacity-expansion-in-china</link><description>Nouryon has doubled its production capacity of triethyl aluminum (TEAL), a metal alkyl used in plastics manufacturing, at its Jiaxing facility in China. The company also plans to start producing modified methylaluminoxane (MMAO) in China by 2027, a catalyst used in solar panel materials, reflecting Nouryon's commitment to innovation in polymer specialties.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Can circular aluminium provide a blueprint for a post-plastic world?</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/can-circular-aluminium-provide-a-blueprint-for-a-post-plastic-world/61691/</link><description>This article explores the sustainability benefits of circular aluminium, highlighting its infinite recyclability and low energy requirements for remanufacturing compared to virgin aluminium. It discusses aluminium's potential to reduce reliance on plastics and support a circular economy, emphasizing the need for increased recycling infrastructure and stakeholder engagement to drive adoption.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Recycled aluminium for sustainable shipbuilding</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/recycled-aluminium-for-sustainable-shipbuilding/54273/</link><description>Speira’s VIA Maris recycled aluminium alloys offer improved mechanical properties and a lower CO2 footprint, making them ideal for maritime and offshore applications. London-based yacht builder Arksen is using these marine-grade recycled aluminium alloys for its new hybrid propulsion yachts, advancing sustainability in shipbuilding.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>Chinese buyers are seeking alternative sources, leading to increased price premiums for non-BHP cargoes. There is growing volatility in spot market prices and inventory movements as traders reposition their stocks. Chinese steel producers face the urgent task of securing alternative supply sources, potentially benefiting other major iron ore producers like Vale and Rio Tinto.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Kallanish Global Flat Steel 2025 Conference</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/announcement-kallanish-global-flat-steel-2025/</link><description>The Kallanish Global Flat Steel 2025 conference will discuss current issues affecting the global flat steel market. The event addresses concerns over US tariffs and their impact on global trade, as well as rising Chinese exports and potential trade cases. The EU is reviewing its safeguard measures and adjusting the CBAM ahead of its full launch in 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>InfraBuild wins Innovation of the Year at World Steel Association awards</title><link>https://www.aumanufacturing.com.au/infrabuild-wins-innovation-of-the-year-at-world-steel-association-awards</link><description>InfraBuild was recognized for its innovative contributions to steel technology at the World Steel Association awards, highlighting advancements that support sustainable steel production and industry transformation.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Smelters Plan Exports After Surge in LME Prices</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/utilities/2025/october/chinese-copper-smelters-plan-exports-after-surge-in-lme-prices/</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are increasing exports due to near-record London Metal Exchange (LME) prices, arranging up to 25,000 tons of spot shipments to bonded warehouses and Asian depots. This surge follows global mine disruptions and US monetary easing, which have boosted copper prices, while domestic Chinese demand slows amid higher costs and weaker margins.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Saudi Aramco Expands into Metal Trading, LME Copper Edged Down Slightly Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103570980/Saudi-Aramco-Expands-into-Metal-Trading-LME-Copper-Edged-Down-Slightly-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Saudi Aramco is entering the metal trading market by hiring copper traders, signaling a strategic diversification amid the energy transition. Meanwhile, LME copper prices showed volatility, opening at $10,681/mt and closing slightly down at $10,576/mt, reflecting mixed market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Smelters Plan Exports After Surge in LME Prices</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/utilities/2025/october/chinese-copper-smelters-plan-exports-after-surge-in-lme-prices/</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are increasing exports due to near-record London Metal Exchange (LME) prices, arranging up to 25,000 tons of spot shipments to bonded warehouses and Asian depots. This surge is driven by a rally in copper prices following global mine disruptions and US monetary easing, despite weakening domestic demand in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Smelters Export Surge: Global Impact</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/chinese-copper-exports-surge-2025-investment-arbitrage/</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are exporting over 25,000 tons of copper in spot shipments, with monthly volumes potentially reaching 50,000 tons. The surge is due to softening domestic demand amid rising production costs and a significant decline in the Yangshan copper premium, making foreign sales more attractive.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper demand to rise 24% by 2035, says Wood Mackenzie</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-india.com/2025/10/16/copper-demand-to-rise-24-by-2035-says-wood-mackenzie/</link><description>Wood Mackenzie forecasts a 24% increase in global copper demand by 2035, driven by economic development and structural demand from electrification and digitalization. The energy transition is a key factor, with electric vehicle-related copper demand expected to double by 2035, highlighting copper's critical role in the global energy shift.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mining innovation takes centre stage during Sudbury Mining Week</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/mining-innovation-takes-centre-stage-during-sudbury-mining-week/</link><description>Sudbury Mining Week 2025 focuses on innovation and sustainability in mining, featuring industry leaders and educational events. The event promotes mining's role in modern society and sustainable development, with interactive exhibits and workshops aimed at inspiring youth and strengthening industry-community partnerships.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices continued to fluctuate on October 16</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103572103/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-continued-to-fluctuate-on-October-16-with-broad-money-M2-up-84-YoY-in-September</link><description>Nickel prices continued to fluctuate due to broad money supply increases and ongoing market uncertainties. The SMM #1 refined nickel price was between 120,700-123,600 yuan/mt. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract edged higher during the session.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 4-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel decreased to 15,151.00 USD/T, marking a four-week low. Over the past month, nickel's price has fallen 1.68%, and it is down 10.86% compared to the same time last year. Nickel futures previously rose to an eleven-week high due to supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market Trends</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/commodity-insights/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/101425-trade-review-global-nickel-market-eyes-oversupply-in-q4-as-shifting-trade-policy-feeds-uncertainty</link><description>The global nickel market is expected to face oversupply in Q4 due to shifting trade policies and increased inventory levels. Despite this, African mining projects continue to advance. Nickel prices have fallen significantly since 2022 due to supply outpacing demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103572103/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-continued-to-fluctuate-on-October-16-with-broad-money-M2-up-84-YoY-in-September</link><description>Nickel prices continued to fluctuate, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 122,150 yuan/mt. The market is influenced by broader economic factors, including changes in social financing and money supply. However, there is no specific mention of new production capacities in this report.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Queensland university $2.2 million grant win promises boost to battery supply chain</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/2025/10/16/queensland-university-2-2-million-grant-win-promises-boost-to-battery-supply-chain/</link><description>Researchers at the Queensland University of Technology have secured a $2.2 million grant to develop a more efficient process for manufacturing battery cathode materials using Australian critical minerals like nickel. The project aims to reduce costs and emissions in cathode production. This innovation could enhance energy security in the Indo-Pacific region.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Africa-Europe Power Bridge Moves Ahead As Contract Awarded for Submarine Cable</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news/0110-49154-first-africa-europe-power-bridge-moves-ahead-as-contract-awarded-for-submarine-cable</link><description>Prysmian has won the contract to build a high-voltage submarine power cable connecting Italy and Tunisia, marking the first interconnector between Europe and North Africa. The 220 km cable will have a capacity of 600 MW and is a key component of the ELMED project.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian wins 460 mln euros power cable deal connecting Italy to Tunisia</title><link>https://newsprobe.io/news/01d389a9-75b1-47df-aaa5-b71d2cd2da23/prysmian-wins-460-mln-euros-power-cable-deal-connecting-italy-to-tunisia</link><description>Prysmian has secured a €460 million contract to build a submarine power cable linking Italy and Tunisia, advancing energy interconnection between the two countries.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>