<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:40:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DMCI Mining says nickel output up 33% in 2025; Long Point mine set to start operations</title><link>https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2026/02/09/729139/dmci-mining-says-nickel-output-up-33-in-2025-long-point-mine-set-to-start-operations/</link><description>DMCI Mining Corp. achieved 33% higher nickel ore production at 2 million WMT in 2025, with shipments up 31% to 1.9 million WMT, fueled by Zambales mines and initial Long Point project in Palawan. The Long Point mine awaits final permits and could start within weeks, supporting a target of 3 million WMT shipments in 2026 amid strong prices. The company has rehabilitated areas at its Quezon mine ahead of schedule.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Announces US$32 Million Bridge Loan Facility with Auramet International Inc.</title><link>https://www.newswire.ca/news-releases/canada-nickel-announces-us-32-million-bridge-loan-facility-with-auramet-international-inc--806231615.html</link><description>Canada Nickel secured a US$32 million bridge loan from Auramet, closing by February 9, 2026, to fund its Crawford Nickel Sulphide Project, due May 2026 with 1% monthly interest. The project features robust economics from a prior PEA, including a 120,000 tonnes/day plant for nickel and magnetite concentrates. This supports advancement amid strong nickel demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Signs €2.3 Billion Contract for UK Power Link Project</title><link>https://ca.investing.com/news/company-news/prysmian-signs-23-billion-contract-for-uk-power-link-project-93CH-4432135</link><description>Italian cable maker Prysmian signed a contract worth over €2.3 billion with SP Energy Networks and National Grid to build the Eastern Green Link 4 power transmission link connecting the electrical grids of Scotland and England.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>World's Top Cable Maker Sees US Copper Tariff as Opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Prysmian, which acquired Texas-based Encore Wire for $4 billion, expressed support for President Trump's planned 50% copper tariff, stating it will bolster the American supply chain. The company believes its vertical integration and domestic copper sourcing position it favorably relative to competitors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian, Versalis Launch Chemical Recycling Chain for Plastic Cable Waste in Italy</title><link>https://esgnews.com/prysmian-versalis-launch-chemical-recycling-chain-for-plastic-cable-waste-in-italy/</link><description>Prysmian and Versalis established a strategic partnership for chemical recycling of end-of-life and production cable plastics in Italy. Using Versalis's Hoop® technology, the initiative will recover up to 60% of difficult-to-recycle XLPE insulation, with pilot operations scheduled to begin in the second half of 2026.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminium price rallies sharply as LME cash offer spikes to 3,083.5 per tonne</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminium-price-rallies-sharply-as-lme-cash-offer-spikes-to-3-083-5-per-tonne-117222</link><description>On February 9, 2026, LME aluminium prices surged with the cash bid and offer rising by USD 38.5 per tonne or 1.3%, reaching USD 3,083 to 3,083.5 per tonne. Three-month forward contracts also increased by USD 44.5 per tonne or 1.5%. This reflects declining inventory amid market rally.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Seasonal weakness pressure dominates aluminium prices in the doldrums</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/seasonal-weakness-pressure-dominates-aluminium-prices-in-the-doldrums-117221</link><description>SHFE aluminium closed at RMB 23,525 per tonne, down 0.06%, while LME aluminium settled at USD 3,109 per tonne, down 0.67%. Spot A00 aluminium rose to RMB 23,400 per tonne amid slowing transactions before Chinese New Year. Secondary aluminium enterprises are suspending operations, leading to weaker demand and fluctuating prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bechtel to lead preparatory engineering work on Oklahoma aluminum project</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2026/02/09/3234698/0/en/Bechtel-to-lead-preparatory-engineering-work-on-Oklahoma-aluminum-project.html</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium (EGA) and Century Aluminum have selected Bechtel to conduct preparatory engineering for a new primary aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, the first in the US since 1980. The project aims to double US primary aluminum production using EGA's advanced EX technology, creating 1,000 permanent jobs and 4,000 construction jobs. Bechtel's work focuses on value improvement, modularization, and preparing for a final investment decision and construction start by end-2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bechtel to lead preparatory engineering work on Oklahoma aluminum project</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/bechtel-to-lead-preparatory-engineering-work-on-oklahoma-aluminum-project-117223</link><description>EGA and Century Aluminum announced Bechtel will handle preparatory engineering for their planned aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, targeting doubled US primary production. The facility will employ EGA's efficient EX reduction technology and generate significant jobs during construction and operation. Bechtel is also addressing infrastructure, logistics, and modular construction to support local growth.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum taps Bechtel for Oklahoma smelter plan</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CENX/bechtel-to-lead-preparatory-engineering-work-on-oklahoma-aluminum-yzf9wbxb7teo.html</link><description>Century Aluminum and EGA (60%/40% ownership) have engaged Bechtel for engineering on a new Oklahoma smelter using EX technology, set to double US primary aluminum output. The project includes 1,000 permanent and 4,000 construction jobs, with preparatory work targeting construction by end-2026. It builds on prior announcements for a 750,000-tonne-per-year facility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bechtel to Lead Engineering for New US Primary Aluminum Smelter in Oklahoma</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103763081-Bechtel-to-Lead-Engineering-for-New-US-Primary-Aluminum-Smelter-in-Oklahoma</link><description>Bechtel has been selected to lead engineering for a new primary aluminum smelter in Oklahoma by EGA and Century Aluminum, potentially doubling US production capacity. The project incorporates advanced technology and sustainability efforts. It marks a significant expansion in American aluminum manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AISI: Raw steel production increases to 5-month high</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/02/09/aisi-raw-steel-production-increases-to-5-month-high/</link><description>US mills produced an estimated 1,783,000 short tons of raw steel in the week ending Feb. 7, up 1.4% from the previous week and marking a five-month high. Year-to-date production totals 9,557,000 short tons, up 3.7% from last year, with mill capability utilization at 77.1%. Production increased in four of five AISI regions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures rose to around $17,200-$17,400 per tonne, supported by concerns over Indonesian supply constraints as smelters fail to submit reports, potentially disrupting exports. Indonesia confirmed cutting mining permits to 260 million wet tons in 2026 from 379 million last year. Philippine DMCI Mining targets 3 million WMT output in 2026 after record 2025 production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market Eyes $20,000 as Supply Discipline Meets Surging ...</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gb7bxSSP58c</link><description>The nickel market shows a constructive outlook in early 2026, backed by Indonesia's 250-260 million ton ore production targets and strong demand. Prices trade in $16,500-$18,500 range after hitting $19,000. Canada Nickel advances Crawford project with engineering and financing milestones for 2026 construction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum at the Centre of Global Industrial Transformation AICE 2026</title><link>https://highways.today/2026/02/09/aluminum-aice-2026/</link><description>The AICE 2026 expo positions recycling on equal footing with primary aluminum production, reflecting growing economic and environmental significance. The event addresses industry challenges including energy-intensive primary production, supply chain carbon scrutiny, and the development of closed-loop systems for construction, automotive, and packaging applications with improved quality control and traceability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Slides to 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures fell to around CNY 3,070 per ton, hitting a one-month low as Chinese steel mills trimmed production ahead of the Lunar New Year holiday. Several blast furnaces and electric-arc furnaces paused operations for planned maintenance, weighing on near-term demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Rise from 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures rebounded to around $17,400 per tonne from a one-month low, driven by supply concerns linked to Indonesia's confirmed mining permit cuts to 260 million wet tons in 2026. The reduction signals tighter availability of nickel feedstock for stainless steel and battery production, with enforcement against illegal mining adding to supply uncertainty.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>NMDC Price Hike Amidst Soaring Costs Sparks Investor Scrutiny</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/Commodities/NMDC-Price-Hike-Amidst-Soaring-Costs-Sparks-Investor-Scrutiny/698ab3d9757d40c78184d329</link><description>NMDC raised iron ore prices by ₹100 per tonne for lumps and fines effective February 10, 2026, to ₹4,700 and ₹4,000 per tonne respectively, responding to higher steel prices and rupee depreciation. EBITDA margins contracted from 36.1% to 28.2%, amid India's steel demand growth projection of 8% in FY2025/2026. Analyst views are mixed, with upgrades to 'Strong Buy' alongside 'Sell' ratings.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Ltd Hits Intraday High with 3.56% Surge on 10 Feb 2026</title><link>https://www.marketsmojo.com/news/stocks-in-action/tata-steel-ltd-hits-intraday-high-with-356-surge-on-10-feb-2026-3830506</link><description>Tata Steel's share price hit a 52-week high of Rs 208.15, up 3.56% intraday and 2.99% from previous close, outperforming the Ferrous Metals sector. The stock stayed above key moving averages, showing bullish momentum amid a positive market with Sensex up 0.3%. This follows two days of gains totaling 5.56%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel consolidated steel production declines 2% to 24.75 lakh tonne in January</title><link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/jsw-steel-share-price-january-business-update-consolidated-production-india-operations-ohio-us-19846305.htm</link><description>JSW Steel's consolidated crude steel production for January 2026 fell 2% to 24.75 lakh tonnes year-over-year. US Ohio operations saw a 74% decline to 0.17 lakh tonnes due to a scheduled outage for caster upgrades from December 15, 2025, to January 11, 2026. Capacity utilization for Indian operations was 85%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vietnam's 2025 crude steel output hits 5-year high</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/vietnams-2025-crude-steel-output-hits-5-year-high-2026-2-10/98437</link><description>Vietnam’s crude steel output in 2025 reached 24.7 million tons, a 12% year-on-year increase and a five-year high. The Vietnam Steel Association forecasts 8-10% growth in 2026, with finished steel output at 33-34.5 million tons and domestic consumption at 26 million tons. Challenges include green standards and anti-dumping cases.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Ministry signs MOUs for 85 projects under PLI</title><link>https://industrialeconomist.com/steel-ministry-signs-mous-for-85-projects-under-pli/</link><description>The Union Ministry of Steel signed Memorandums of Understanding for 85 projects under the Production Linked Incentive scheme. These initiatives aim to boost steel production capacity in India.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price forecast for 2026: Goldman Sachs</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/02/10/copper-price-forecast-for-2026-goldman-sachs/</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts copper prices to stay around $13,000 per tonne in the first half of 2026 before declining to $11,200 by year-end, assuming a US 15% tariff on refined copper by mid-2026. The price recently rebounded to $13,117 per tonne after a sell-off triggered by US dollar strength. ASX copper shares and ETFs rose today amid ongoing recovery and uncertainty supporting current levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price forecast for 2026: Goldman Sachs</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/02/10/copper-price-forecast-for-2026-goldman-sachs/</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts copper prices to remain around $13,000 per tonne in early 2026 before declining to $11,200 by year-end, citing a short-term 600 kilotonne surplus in 2025 but long-term supply constraints due to lengthy mine development times and declining ore grades in Chile. Demand is driven by grid infrastructure, EVs, renewables, China's building sector, and data centers. The article notes restricted supply amid rising demand from energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices fell to 5.91 USD/Lbs on February 10, 2026, amid supply challenges from power outages at major mines and conservative production guidance. The China Nonferrous Metals Industry Association projects refined copper output to rise about 5% in 2026, half the 2025 growth rate. Global demand remains robust from energy transition and data-center expansion despite short-term pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel prices edged lower on February 10 with market trading turning sluggish</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103764127-SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-prices-edged-lower-on-February-10-with-market-trading-turning-sluggish</link><description>On February 10, SMM #1 refined nickel prices ranged from 133,400-144,500 yuan/mt, averaging 138,950 yuan/mt, down 500 yuan/mt from the previous day. Market trading turned sluggish ahead of the Chinese New Year holiday, with futures prices fluctuating lower and spot prices weakening due to stagnant demand. Post-holiday focus will be on Indonesia's nickel ore quota policy implementation.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel News</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103763647-SMM-Nickel-News</link><description>SMM reports #1 refined nickel prices on February 10 at 133,400–144,500 yuan/mt, averaging 138,950 yuan/mt, a decline of 500 yuan/mt from the prior session. The update highlights ongoing spot market assessments amid broader nickel market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Top Fiber Laser Cutting Machine Manufacturers Driving Innovation in Metal Fabrication</title><link>https://natlawreview.com/press-releases/top-fiber-laser-cutting-machine-manufacturers-driving-innovation-metal</link><description>Fiber laser technology is replacing traditional CO2 systems in metal fabrication with superior efficiency (25-40% wall-plug efficiency versus 10-15%), particularly benefiting electric vehicle and aerospace manufacturing. The technology offers lower energy consumption, reduced maintenance requirements, and decreased environmental impact while enabling precision cutting of aluminum and other materials.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel prices surged significantly on February 11, with new progress on Indonesia's RKAB quotas</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103766423--SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-prices-surged-significantly-on-February-11-with-new-progress-on-Indonesias-RKAB-quotas</link><description>Nickel prices surged on February 11 due to progress on Indonesia's 2026 nickel ore RKAB production target of 260-270 million mt, aligning with market expectations and boosting sentiment. Spot prices for SMM #1 refined nickel reached an average of 142,600 yuan/mt, up significantly, while SHFE nickel futures rose 4.31%. Prices are expected to remain supported in the short term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Closes the Acquisition of ACSM</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en</link><description>Prysmian has completed its acquisition of Spain-based ACSM, a submarine cable installation company, for €169 million ($198 million). The acquisition brings subsea surveying, seabed preparation, and installation capabilities in-house, strengthening Prysmian's position in the submarine cable sector.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Shagang Group keeps local rebar price stable for mid-February 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-prices/steel-prices-market-analyses/longs-and-billet/shaganggroup-keeps-local-rebar-price-stable-for-mid-february-2026-1435380.htm</link><description>Shagang Group maintained stable rebar pricing for mid-February 2026, with Shanghai Futures Exchange rebar futures at RMB 3,052/mt ($439/mt) as of February 10. Global steel markets showed mixed signals, with some products declining slightly while others remained stable amid weak demand conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Decarbonising to Compete: pathways to unlock investment and strengthen Brazil's low-carbon cement and steel industries</title><link>https://www.climatebonds.net/news-events/press-room/press-releases/decarbonising-compete-pathways-unlock-investment-strengthen-brazils-low-carbon-cement-steel-industries</link><description>A new report analyzes technological, policy, and investment pathways for decarbonizing Brazil's cement and steel industries, which together represent 18% of global greenhouse gas emissions. The report identifies Brazil's renewable electricity matrix and biomass use as comparative advantages, while assessing both short-term solutions like energy efficiency and longer-term approaches including electrification, low-carbon hydrogen, and carbon capture and storage.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: ESDM approves nickel ore mining quotas up to 260-270 million tonnes for 2026</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5113201-flash-esdm-approves-nickel-ore-mining-quotas-up-to-260-270-million-tonnes-for-2026</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources (ESDM) announced the 2026 Nickel Work Plan and Budget, approving a nickel ore production quota between 260-270 million tonnes. This represents a significant cut from the previous year's 379 million tonnes, aligning with the Indonesian Nickel Miners Association's earlier disclosures.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Our Power, Our Planet: Novelis' Commitment to Renewable and Clean Energy</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/our-power-our-planet-novelis-commitment-to-renewable-and-clean-energy-302433614.html</link><description>Novelis is advancing aluminum sustainability through multiple initiatives including building onsite solar parks, conducting industrial-scale hydrogen testing in recycling furnaces, and targeting 75% recycled content in products by 2030. The company emphasizes that recycled aluminum production requires 95% less energy than primary aluminum production, making circular economy practices central to their business model.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Iran elevates its crude steel production in early 2026</title><link>https://www.trend.az/business/4151742.html</link><description>Iran's crude steel production increased by 8.1% during the first 10 months of the current Iranian year (from March 21). Production of steel derivatives, sponge iron, iron ore pellets, and concentrate also rose compared to the previous year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A-State to receive $2.1 million to expand steel research</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/a-state-to-receive-2.1-million-to-expand-steel-research-2026-2-11/98448</link><description>Arkansas State University has secured $2.1 million in federal funding to expand steel research, testing capabilities, and advanced manufacturing initiatives related to steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper and aluminum prices drop as gains peter out before China break</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-and-aluminum-prices-drop-as-gains-peter-out-before-china-break/</link><description>Copper prices consolidated around $5.90 per pound in New York and dropped toward $13,000 per ton in London as a rally stalled ahead of China's Lunar New Year holiday. Chinese copper buyers are expected to extend their break as elevated prices curb industrial demand, with total warehouse stockpiles now exceeding 970,000 tons—the highest since 2003.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Feb. 11</title><link>http://www.china.org.cn/world/Off_the_Wire/2026-02-11/content_118328408.shtml</link><description>Copper was trading at $5.90 USD per pound as of 0200 GMT on February 11, 2026, according to London Stock Exchange Group data. This brief update provides current commodity pricing across multiple metals including gold, iron ore, palladium, and platinum.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hitting 1 million tonnes of copper will be easy this year – Kabuswe</title><link>https://diggers.news/local/2026/02/11/hitting-1-million-tonnes-of-copper-will-be-easy-this-year-kabuswe/</link><description>Zambian official Kabuswe indicates that achieving 1 million tonnes of copper production in 2026 will be straightforward. The statement reflects optimism about the country's copper output capacity for the year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel prices surged significantly on February 11, with new progress on Indonesia's RKAB quotas</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103766423--SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-prices-surged-significantly-on-February-11-with-new-progress-on-Indonesias-RKAB-quotas</link><description>Nickel prices surged significantly on February 11, with the SMM #1 refined nickel average price at 142,600 yuan/mt, up 3,650 yuan/mt from the previous day. The SHFE nickel contract (2603) rose 4.31% to 139,760 yuan/mt amid positive market sentiment from Indonesia's 2026 nickel ore RKAB production target of 260-270 million mt. Prices are expected to hold up well in the short term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel extends gains as Indonesia reaffirms sharp mining cuts</title><link>https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/business/2026/02/11/nickel-extends-gains-as-indonesia-reaffirms-sharp-mining-cuts</link><description>Nickel rose for a fourth straight day to US$17,780 a tonne after Indonesia reaffirmed 2026 production quotas of 260-270 million tonnes of nickel ore, down from 379 million in 2025. The cuts aim to boost prices amid a persistent surplus, with LME nickel up as much as 1.7%. Macquarie raised its 2026 forecast to US$17,750 a tonne due to quota constraints.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Metals 2026 outlook: recent sell-off provide further upside on gold/nickel miners</title><link>https://ipotnews.com/ipotnews/newsDetail.php?jdl=Metals___2026_outlook__recent_sell_off_provide_further_upside_on_gold_nickel_miners&amp;news_id=213283&amp;group_news=IPOTNEWS&amp;taging_subtype=LOGAMDANMINERAL&amp;name=&amp;search=y_general&amp;q=Sector+Update%2C%C2%A0Metals%2C+%28EMAS%29%2C+%28ANTM%29%2C+%28INCO%29%2C+%28MBMA%29%2C+RKAB%2C+gold+price%2C&amp;halaman=1</link><description>The outlook sets LME nickel price forecast at US$17k/t for 2026, up from US$15k/t in 2025. This reflects expectations of further upside for nickel miners amid recent market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel extends gains as Indonesia reaffirms sharp mining cuts</title><link>https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/business/2026/02/11/nickel-extends-gains-as-indonesia-reaffirms-sharp-mining-cuts</link><description>Nickel prices rose to US$17,780/t for a fourth straight day after Indonesia confirmed 2026 production quotas of 260-270 million tonnes of ore, down sharply from 379 million in 2025, to boost prices amid surplus. Quota issuance is expected by March, viewed as bullish by analysts. The metal has surged over 20% since mid-December amid broader metals rally.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's Biggest Nickel Mine in Indonesia Told to Slash Output</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kGjoT_z37-0</link><description>PT Weda Bay Nickel, the world's largest nickel mine, has been notified of a drastic production quota cut to 12 million tons in 2026, down from 42 million tons in 2025. The Indonesian government is implementing these cuts to boost global prices of its largest export commodity. Nickel prices climbed following the announcement, as the metal is essential for both stainless steel and electric-vehicle batteries.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium prices recover with cash offers at $3098/t while inventories follow a declining trend</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-prices-recover-with-cash-offers-at-3-098-t-while-inventories-follow-a-declining-trend-117249</link><description>LME aluminium cash bid prices increased by 1.09% to USD 3,096 per tonne on February 11, with cash offers rising 1.14% to USD 3,098 per tonne. Three-month bids and offers also saw similar gains of around 1.1-1.13%. Inventories continued a declining trend, indicating potential global supply shortages.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Price Today: China Trading Curbs Stall Rally Amid Supply Constraints</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-price-today-analysis/</link><description>Aluminum prices stand at $3,159.93 USD, down 0.12% over the past seven days but up 7.16% in the last 30 days amid a strong uptrend. China's curbs on high-frequency trading have stalled the rally, though supply disruptions in regions like Iceland and Mozambique provide support. Technicals show consolidation near $3,200 with key support at $3,130.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Indian Alumina Price Rises to $311.5/mt in Overseas Trade, Up from $308/mt in January</title><link>https://news.metal.com/vn/newscontent/103768396-Indian-Alumina-Price-Rises-to-3115mt-in-Overseas-Trade-Up-from-308mt-in-January</link><description>Overseas alumina transactions saw Indian prices rise to $311.5/mt on February 12, 2026, up from $308/mt in January. This reflects tightening supply dynamics in the alumina market linked to aluminum production. Related news mentions Arconic seeking spot aluminum amid US supply tightness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Large Steel Mills' Guiding Prices for Various Series on February 12 - SMM Steel Mill Guiding Prices</title><link>https://news.metal.com/ru/newscontent/103173385-Domestic-Large-Steel-Mills-Guiding-Prices-for-Various-Series-on-February-12-SMM-Steel-Mill-Guiding-Prices</link><description>Large domestic steel mills in China released guiding prices for various steel series on February 12. This update from SMM provides insights into current pricing trends amid ongoing market dynamics. Specific price adjustments reflect daily market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ArcelorMittal upgraded as tighter EU imports to lift steel prices</title><link>https://au.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/arcelormittal-upgraded-as-tighter-eu-imports-to-lift-steel-prices-4254321</link><description>Jefferies upgraded ArcelorMittal to Buy from Hold, raising the price target to €62 from €44, citing tighter EU import restrictions that will boost steel prices. This reflects expectations of improved market conditions due to trade protection measures. The upgrade highlights positive outlook for the steel giant amid policy changes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Edges Higher on Weaker Dollar, but China Demand Softens Ahead of Lunar New Year</title><link>https://www.kiwoom.co.id/internationalnews/detailInternationalNewsMain?id=493</link><description>Copper prices rose modestly on February 11, 2026, supported by a weaker U.S. dollar, though China demand slowed ahead of the Lunar New Year holiday. The SHFE most-active contract closed up 0.31% at 102,180 yuan per ton, while LME three-month copper gained 0.31% to $13,155 per ton. SHFE inventories surged to their highest since March, and COMEX stocks hit a record 536,563 tons.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Peel Mining Announces Landmark Sale of South Cobar Copper Project to Aeris Resources</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/02/12/peel-mining-announces-landmark-sale-of-south-cobar-copper-project-to-aeris-resources/</link><description>Peel Mining Limited has agreed to sell its South Cobar Copper Project, including the Mallee Bull and Wirlong deposits, to Aeris Resources for $214 million via a Scheme of Arrangement. The deal involves demerging Peel's remaining Cobar Basin assets into a new ASX-listed entity, NewCo, for shareholders. The transaction accelerates development using Aeris' expertise and is recommended by Peel's board, pending approvals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Headed to $20,000 as Indonesia Limits Production, EV Demand Surges</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-headed-to-20-000-as-indonesia-limits-production-ev-demand-surges</link><description>Nickel prices bounced between $16,500-$18,500/ton in January after briefly exceeding $19,000, supported by Indonesia's commitment to flat-to-down ore production targets of 250-260 million tons for 2026. EV demand remains robust with 20% underlying growth continuing, with analysts expecting nickel to move toward $20,000 per ton within the near term as production discipline is verified.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Cuts Weda Bay Nickel Mining Quota, Prices Rise</title><link>https://chinaglobalsouth.com/2026/02/12/indonesia-cuts-weda-bay-nickel-mining-quota-prices-rise/</link><description>Indonesia sharply cut PT Weda Bay Nickel's 2026 mining quota to 12 million wet metric tons from 32 million wet tons in 2025, causing nickel prices to climb. The LME benchmark three-month nickel contract rose 0.70% to $17,990 a ton, with the Shanghai Futures Exchange contract climbing 2.49% to 140,570 yuan per metric ton.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Weda Bay Nickel Receives Sharply Reduced 2026 Quota</title><link>https://projectblue.com/blue/news-analysis/1422/weda-bay-nickel-receives-sharply-reduced-2026-quota</link><description>Indonesia revised its total nickel ore production target to 260-270 million tons for 2026, down from 379 million tons in 2025, with the objective to support LME nickel prices within a stable $19,000-20,000/ton range. Project Blue forecasts a nickel market surplus of 249kt Ni in 2026, though higher prices may face resistance from downstream consumers due to structural shifts in EV battery markets and weak stainless steel demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Crude Oil Rises, Nickel Prices Extend Gains for Fourth Day, Silver Surges</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-30578.html</link><description>Nickel prices rose for a fourth consecutive day, hitting a two-week high after Indonesia signaled significant production cuts. LME nickel futures climbed 2.23% to $17,880.0 per ton as market sentiment strengthened on expectations of constrained Indonesian supply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel Prices Continue to Rise on February 12</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103768521-SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-Prices-Continue-to-Rise-on-February-12-January-US-Non-Farm-Payrolls-Data-Strongly-Exceed</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices were quoted at 140,200-150,500 yuan/mt with an average price of 145,350 yuan/mt, up 2,750 yuan/mt on the day. Prices continued their upward momentum following Indonesia's production quota announcements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Mining Quota Cut Impacts Market</title><link>https://chinaglobalsouth.com/2026/02/12/indonesia-cuts-weda-bay-nickel-mining-quota-prices-rise/</link><description>Following Indonesia's sharp cut to PT Weda Bay Nickel's mining quota, nickel prices climbed with the Shanghai Futures Exchange contract rising 2.49% to 140,570 yuan per metric ton and the London Metal Exchange benchmark rising 0.70% to $17,990 per ton. Analysts note that while prices are supported in the short term, Indonesia historically prevents prices from rising sustainably above $18,000 per tonne to protect domestic EV sector competitiveness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum fell to 3,097.15 USD/T on February 12, 2026, down 0.73% from the previous day and 2.92% over the past month, though still 18.64% higher year-over-year. It hit a 4-week low of 3031 USD/T on February 9. Earlier in February, prices fell from a three-year high amid base metals pullback.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices: Wuxi (Feb 12, 2026 19:36)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/daily-prices/6912405-aluminum-prices-wuxi</link><description>Mysteel reported spot aluminum prices in Wuxi, China, including updates for Gongyi, Shanghai, Shenyang, Tianjin, and Linyi as of February 13 morning local time. Prices include 13% VAT for A00 aluminum (Al≥99.7%). Full details require a subscription.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Macro sentiment still shows no significant improvement, aluminum prices remain in the doldrums [SMM Aluminum Weekly Review]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103769380/Macro-sentiment-still-shows-no-significant-improvement,-aluminum-prices-remain-in-the-doldrums-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Weekly-Review%5D/</link><description>Macro sentiment lacks improvement, keeping aluminum prices subdued in the latest SMM weekly review. Broader market pressures continue to weigh on the metal.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>What happened to gold, silver, platinum and copper today? Why are precious metal prices crashing sharply today? Gold, silver, platinum and copper price plunge: Is this the end of the bull run for metals?</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/what-happened-to-gold-silver-platinum-and-copper-today-why-are-precious-metal-prices-crashing-sharply-today-gold-silver-platinum-and-copper-price-plunge-is-this-the-end-of-the-bull-run-for-metals/articleshow/128271333.cms</link><description>Copper prices slid 2.78% to $5.80 per pound on February 12, 2026, amid a broader plunge in precious and industrial metals. The drop reflects technical pressure, macro uncertainty including slowing Chinese manufacturing signals, stronger US data, and anticipation of tighter financial conditions. Traders note this as a potential delayed reaction to strong nonfarm payrolls, with tomorrow's CPI report as the next volatility catalyst.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Henkel showcases new material innovations, sustainability concept and partner ecosystem at LOPEC 2026</title><link>https://www.henkel.com/press-and-media/press-releases-and-kits/2026-02-12-henkel-showcases-new-material-innovations-sustainability-concept-and-partner-ecosystem-at-lopec-2026-2122326</link><description>Henkel introduces silver-plated copper (SPC) ink technology at LOPEC 2026 to counter high silver prices, offering cost efficiency and performance for printed electronics while emphasizing sustainability through recycled silver materials. The innovations include high-conductivity inks, self-regulating PTC inks for thermal management in batteries and wearables, and solutions for connectivity, mobility, and healthcare applications.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review - Nickel Prices Continue to Rise on February 12</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103768521-SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-Prices-Continue-to-Rise-on-February-12-January-US-Non-Farm-Payrolls-Data-Strongly-Exceed</link><description>Nickel prices continued their upward trend on February 12, supported by strong January US Non-Farm Payrolls data that exceeded expectations. The positive labor market data influenced commodity markets and contributed to nickel price gains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale posts $3.8 billion Q4 loss on nickel assets impairment</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/business/vale-posts-3-8-billion-q4-loss-on-nickel-assets-impairment-170094/</link><description>Brazilian mining company Vale reported a $3.8 billion net loss in Q4 2025, primarily due to a $3.5 billion impairment on nickel assets in Canada triggered by downward revisions in long-term nickel price assumptions. The loss reflects broader market challenges in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 23-month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel increased to 970.00 USD/T, the highest since January 2024. Over the past 4 weeks, Hot-Rolled Coil Steel gained 3.3%, and in the last 12 months, it increased 31.83%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>What happened to gold, silver, platinum and copper today? Why are precious metal prices crashing sharply today?</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/what-happened-to-gold-silver-platinum-and-copper-today-why-are-precious-metal-prices-crashing-sharply-today-gold-silver-platinum-and-copper-price-plunge-is-this-the-end-of-the-bull-run-for-metals/articleshow/128271333.cms</link><description>Copper slid 2.78% to $5.80 per pound on February 12, 2026, amid a broader plunge in metal prices including gold, silver, and platinum. The drop reflects technical pressure, macro uncertainty, slowing Chinese manufacturing signals, and reactions to strong US data. Traders eye upcoming CPI data for potential volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Nickel Report</title><link>https://www.hunton.com/the-nickel-report/</link><description>The report covers regulatory updates from PHMSA regarding hazardous materials shipping standards, including new regulations for sodium ion batteries aligned with lithium ion battery standards. It also discusses companies reconsidering sustainability targets due to economic pressures and challenges in meeting interim decarbonization goals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Prices Soar as Tariffs and Energy Costs Reshape the Market</title><link>https://www.investing.com/analysis/aluminium-prices-soar-as-tariffs-and-energy-costs-reshape-the-market-200674422</link><description>Aluminium prices reached nearly four-year highs on LME, with U.S. premiums hitting a record above $1/pound due to high energy costs, capacity closures, trade disputes, and rising demand. Goldman Sachs raised its H1 2026 forecast to $3,150/ton from $2,575/ton. This benefits producers like Alcoa and Century Aluminum but pressures downstream sectors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Why are aluminium, copper, nickel and tin prices going down today and will base metals continue to fall or rise again?</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/why-are-aluminium-copper-nickel-and-tin-prices-going-down-today-and-will-base-metals-continue-to-fall-or-rise-again-global-metals-market-fall-analysts-insights-and-market-outlook-explained-heres-what-should-investors-do-now/articleshow/128275875.cms</link><description>Base metals prices on LME fell despite early aluminum strength, with aluminum down 0.1% to $3,100/ton by late trading due to position squaring, weaker sentiment, U.S. data, and pre-Lunar New Year China demand slowdown. Other metals like nickel, zinc, lead, and tin also declined. Future direction hinges on post-holiday China demand and tight supply.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump plans to roll back tariffs on metal and aluminium goods, FT reports</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/commodities-news/trump-plans-to-roll-back-tariffs-on-metal-and-aluminiumgoods-ft-reports-4504332</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump is planning to scale back tariffs on steel and aluminium goods, per Financial Times and Reuters. This development occurs amid recent aluminum price volatility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Backs New U.S. Smelter Built Around Next-Generation Smelting Technology</title><link>https://www.heattreattoday.com/century-aluminum-backs-new-u-s-smelter-built-around-next-generation-smelting-technology/</link><description>Century Aluminum Company and Emirates Global Aluminum (EGA) are partnering to build an advanced primary aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, using next-generation EX smelting technology. The facility is expected to produce up to 750,000 metric tons of aluminum annually, more than doubling current U.S. capacity, while reducing energy consumption and emissions. Construction is expected to begin as early as 2026, with commercial production anticipated before the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Metals Innovation Initiative Appoints Sustainability Project Coordinator</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/metals-innovation-initiative-appoints-sustainability-project-coordinator/</link><description>The Metals Innovation Initiative (MI2) has appointed Laura Haury as sustainability project coordinator to focus on aluminum recycling efforts, environmental education, and outreach programs. Haury brings decades of environmental engineering and manufacturing sustainability experience, and will work to increase aluminum recycling rates across Kentucky and beyond through partnerships with The Recycling Society.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Decarbonisation and Raw Material Independence at Stake</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/decarbonisation-and-raw-material-independence-at-stake-117254</link><description>Speira, a European aluminum recycler, urges EU action to boost competitiveness and protect aluminum recycling, noting that recycling processes can avoid up to 95 percent of CO2 emissions compared to primary production. The company has joined the Antwerp Declaration to advocate for sustainable steps toward European competitiveness and future-proof planning security in the circular economy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Update</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel fell to $980.05/ton on February 13, 2026, down 0.10% from the previous day, though prices have risen 4.37% over the past month and are up 27.58% compared to the same time last year. The commodity has shown volatility, reaching a 36-week high of $941/ton on January 28, 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A new way to make steel could reduce America's reliance on imports</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2026/new-way-make-steel-could-reduce-americas-reliance-imports-0213</link><description>Hertha Metals is advancing a novel single-step steelmaking process using natural gas and electricity on molten iron oxide, operating a 1-tonne-per-day pilot plant near Houston since late 2024. The company plans to build a 10,000-ton-per-year plant this year, reaching full capacity by end-2027, also producing high-purity iron for magnets to onshore critical materials. This innovation aims to outcompete traditional methods and integrate with existing U.S. steel infrastructure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A new way to make steel could reduce America's reliance on imports</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2026/new-way-make-steel-could-reduce-americas-reliance-imports-0213</link><description>Hertha Metals has developed a new steel production system using natural gas and electricity that reduces iron ore to molten steel in a single step, eliminating the need for coking and sintering plants. The process uses 30 percent less energy and is 25 percent more cost-competitive than conventional American steel mills while reducing emissions. The company is scaling from its current 1-tonne-per-day pilot plant to a 10,000-ton-per-year facility expected to reach full capacity by end of 2027.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Border States Commodity Update: February 2026</title><link>https://tedmag.com/border-states-commodity-update-february-2026/</link><description>Major copper miners reported strong 2025 fourth-quarter production results. Rio Tinto achieved an 11% increase in copper production, exceeding 800,000 metric tons, driven by the Oyu Tolgoi mine in Mongolia with a 5% year-over-year rise in Q4 output. Freeport-McMoRan posted better-than-expected results despite a production decline at Indonesia’s Grasberg mine due to a natural disaster, expecting 85% recovery by mid-2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Wants to Further U.S. Copper Investment Amid Tariffs</title><link>https://www.industrialinfo.com/iirenergy/industry-news/article/rio-tinto-wants-to-further-us-copper-investment-amid-tariffs--343839</link><description>Rio Tinto is advancing the Resolution copper mine project in the U.S., potentially producing up to 500,000 tons of copper concentrate annually from 43.2 million tons of ore over 40 years, with permitting estimated for completion by February 13, 2026. The company is also investing in Bingham Canyon mine expansions, including a $1.5 billion Phase II project to extend life to 2032 and add 1 million tons of refined copper, plus a $500 million North Rim Skarn development for additional capacity by end-2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Sulphate Daily Review - February 13: Trading Sluggish Before the Holiday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103771216-SMM-Nickel-Sulphate-Daily-Review-February-13-Trading-Sluggish-Before-the-Holiday-Nickel-Salt-Prices-Remain-Stable</link><description>Battery-grade nickel sulphate prices remained stable at 31,635 yuan/mt on February 13, with trading activity slowing ahead of the Lunar New Year holiday. Market activity is expected to remain subdued during the holiday period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale reports $3.8 billion loss in Q4 due to nickel asset impairment</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/vale-reports-38-billion-loss-in-q4-due-to-nickel-asset-impairment-93CH-4504294</link><description>Mining giant Vale reported a $3.8 billion fourth-quarter loss, primarily driven by a $3.5 billion impairment on its nickel assets in Canada due to expectations of lower nickel prices. The impairment reflects broader concerns about the nickel market outlook.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale posts $3.8bn loss on nickel impairment; analysts welcome core profit</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/vale-posts-3-8bn-loss-on-nickel-impairment-analysts-welcome-core-profit-2026-02-13</link><description>Vale recorded a $3.5 billion impairment on nickel assets in its Base Metals division, contributing to a $3.8 billion quarterly loss that significantly exceeded analyst expectations of a $2.7 billion profit. The impairment reflects declining nickel price forecasts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's biggest nickel mine in Indonesia told to cut output</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/international/asean/worlds-biggest-nickel-mine-indonesia-told-cut-output</link><description>PT Weda Bay Nickel, the world's largest nickel mine, has been ordered to reduce its 2026 production quota to 12 million tonnes of ore, down from 42 million tonnes in 2025—a 71% reduction. This cut is part of Indonesia's broader strategy to restrict nickel supply, as the country produces approximately 65% of global nickel.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's Weda Bay Nickel facing quota cut by 70%, causing nickel prices to surge</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/indonesias-weda-bay-nickel-facing-quota-cut-by-70-causing-nickel-prices-to-surge/159215</link><description>The Indonesian government has drastically cut the production quota for PT Weda Bay Nickel to 12 million tonnes, triggering significant price movements in global nickel markets. The reduction reflects Indonesia's effort to tighten supply and support prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia risks oversupply in Class 2 nickel: Expert</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-risks-oversupply-in-class-2-nickel-expert</link><description>An expert analysis suggests that Indonesia's plan to sharply reduce its nickel ore production quota may paradoxically create oversupply risks in Class 2 nickel markets. The article discusses potential market implications of the production cuts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Trump signals rollback on 50% steel and aluminum tariffs – what it means for solar</title><link>https://pv-magazine-usa.com/2026/02/13/trump-signals-rollback-on-50-steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-what-it-means-for-solar/</link><description>The Trump administration is preparing to scale back up to 50% tariffs on imported steel and aluminum to address an affordability crisis. This could significantly lower costs for the US solar industry, where aluminum frames now represent 14% of solar panel manufacturing costs. The rollback may ease Balance of System costs for utility-scale and residential solar projects.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Metals retreat on reports Trump may soften aluminium tariffs</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/business/2026/02/13/metals-retreat-on-reports-trump-may-soften-aluminium-tariffs</link><description>Metals prices retreated on the London Metal Exchange after reports that Trump may soften aluminum tariffs. The benchmark three-month aluminum contract slipped more than 2.5% to $2,965.75 a tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump signals rollback on 50% steel and aluminum tariffs: What it means for solar</title><link>https://pv-magazine-usa.com/2026/02/13/trump-signals-rollback-on-50-steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-what-it-means-for-solar/</link><description>The Trump administration is reportedly preparing to scale back up to 50% tariffs on imported steel and aluminum to address affordability concerns. The shift toward 'targeted' metal duties could significantly impact the solar supply chain, where aluminum frames have become the costliest component in panel production at 14% of manufacturing costs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Construction steel prices: Yining (Feb 13, 2026 19:05)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/daily-prices/6913922-construction-steel-prices-yining</link><description>Mysteel reports construction steel prices in Yining, China, collected on February 13, 2026, including round bar and other products with 13% VAT. Similar daily price updates were issued for other regions like Kuitun, Kumul, Urumchi, and Zhuhai on February 14. These reflect ongoing market monitoring amid rangebound expectations for February.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper scrap prices: Baoding (Feb 13, 2026 17:40)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/daily-prices/6913632-copper-scrap-prices-baoding</link><description>Mysteel reports copper scrap prices in Baoding, China, including grades like brass (Cu:98%), low-voltage cable (Cu≥99.5%), and others with low, high, and mid prices in Yuan/tonne including 13% VAT. Prices were updated as of February 13, 2026, 17:40, reflecting regional market activity. Similar updates available for other Chinese cities like Foshan and Shanghai on February 14.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 16,995 USD/T on February 13, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell 1.48% to $16,995 per tonne on February 13, declining 9.53% over the past month despite remaining 9.96% higher than a year ago.[1] Nickel futures had surged to $17,900 per tonne earlier in February following Indonesia's announcement of production quota cuts to 270 million tonnes for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Falls on Likely US Tariff Slash</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/aluminum-falls-on-likely-us-tariff-slash/</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK fell to $3,050 per tonne, continuing the pullback from a three-year high. The decline follows reports of a likely US tariff reduction on aluminum imports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>February 14: Aluminum Prices Strong While Downstream Orders Remain Weak; Aluminum Billet Processing Fees in Three Regions Remain Flat Compared to Yesterday - Daily Review of Spot Aluminum Billets</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103177818-february-14-aluminum-prices-strong-while-downstream-orders-remain-weak-aluminum-billet-processing-fees-in-three-regions-remain-flat-compared-to-yesterday-daily-review-of-spot-aluminum-billets</link><description>Aluminum prices remained strong on February 14 despite weak downstream orders. Aluminum billet processing fees in three regions stayed flat compared to the previous day.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price rises as looming smelter closure adds to supply strains</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-rises-as-looming-smelter-closure-adds-to-supply-strains/</link><description>South32 Ltd. is proceeding with plans to mothball its Mozal smelter in Mozambique next month, a major supplier to the European market. The closure adds to growing supply constraints as Chinese smelters near government-imposed production capacity caps and 50% US tariffs have caused imports to slump, with aluminum prices rallying 17% last year and 5.5% so far in 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bessent discusses possible narrowing of steel, aluminum tariffs</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2026-02-14/business/industry/Bessent-discusses-possible-narrowing-of-steel-aluminum-tariffs/2524445</link><description>Treasury Secretary Bessent commented on reports of potential tariff rollbacks, stating that any changes would likely involve clarification on incidental objects rather than broad scaling back. The Trump administration has imposed 50% tariffs on steel and aluminum imports, with discussions ongoing about possible modifications.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bessent discusses possible narrowing of steel, aluminum tariffs</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2026-02-14/business/industry/Bessent-discusses-possible-narrowing-of-steel-aluminum-tariffs/2524445</link><description>U.S. Treasury Secretary Bessent discussed the Trump administration's potential plan to scale back 50 percent tariffs on steel and aluminum imports to address rising affordability issues. Officials believe the tariffs are hurting consumers by raising prices for goods including pie tins and food-and-drink cans.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump plans to roll back some tariffs on steel, aluminium goods</title><link>https://www.thenews.pk/print/1398950-trump-plans-to-roll-back-some-tariffs-on-steel-aluminium-goods-ft-reports</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump plans to scale back some tariffs on steel and aluminum goods, according to Financial Times reporting. The move comes as Commerce Department and trade officials believe the tariffs are hurting consumers, with shares of major steelmakers declining following the announcement.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bessent discusses possible narrowing of steel, aluminum tariffs</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2026-02-14/business/industry/Bessent-discusses-possible-narrowing-of-steel-aluminum-tariffs/2524445</link><description>US Treasury Secretary Bessent discussed potential narrowing of 50% tariffs on steel and aluminum imports and derivatives like appliances in a CNBC interview. The Trump administration imposed these tariffs, but changes may clarify incidental items ahead of midterm elections. He noted it would be the president's decision after consulting the US Trade Rep.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Prices Inched Lower in February</title><link>http://news.metal.com/newscontent/102143337-Nickel-Futures-Prices-Inched-Lower-in-February</link><description>Nickel prices declined in February amid macroeconomic headwinds including higher-than-expected CPI (6.4%) and PPI (6%) data, along with hawkish Federal Reserve commentary raising interest rate concerns. The LME announced on February 23 that Asian nickel trading would resume on March 20, which also contributed to price declines.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Philippine nickel sales to Indonesia to jump after Jakarta curbs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/philippine-nickel-sales-to-indonesia-to-jump-after-jakarta-curbs/</link><description>Philippine nickel ore shipments to Indonesia could double to 30 million tons in 2026 following Indonesia's production cuts. Philippine miners see this as an opportunity to fill the supply gap created by Indonesia's domestic output reduction, though expansion may be limited by aging mines and slow approval processes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>