<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 05:17:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>China will promote value-added steel production</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/china-will-promote-value-added-steel-production/</link><description>China's annual steel production is expected to fall below 1 billion tons for the first time in six years by the end of 2025, driven by declining demand. The country plans to focus on promoting value-added steel production to adapt to changing market conditions and improve product quality.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>USWC's Rare November Bulk Scrap Cargo Sale to Turkey</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/scrap-metal-trade-anomaly-2025-rare-cargo-turkey/</link><description>The U.S. West Coast (USWC) sold a rare bulk scrap cargo to Turkey amid disruptions in Asian scrap markets, creating a unique arbitrage opportunity. Turkey remains a major scrap importer with strong demand for premium scrap grades, benefiting from geographic advantages and electric arc furnace technology adoption.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Falls on Fed Policy, Codelco Supply</title><link>https://www.miningreporters.com/noticia/news/2025/11/copper-price-falls-fed-policy-codelco-supply</link><description>Copper extended losses as renewed uncertainty over US interest rates and positive production signals from Chile's Codelco eased supply fears, with LME three-month copper around $10,855/tonne and COMEX near $5.013/lb. The US dollar's strength and mixed signals from Fed officials further pressured prices, though copper remains up over 20% in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Set for Weekly Drop</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/500126</link><description>Copper futures steadied around $4.95/lb but were set for a weekly loss amid a global risk-off mood, weak Chinese trade data, and speculation about Beijing curbing copper refining overcapacity. Concerns over AI valuations and a prolonged US government shutdown added to the cautious market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 15020 USD/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.23% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices decreased to 15,020 USD per tonne on November 7, 2025, marking a 0.23% drop from the previous day. Over the past month, nickel prices fell by 2.40%, and are down 8.01% compared to the same time last year, reflecting ongoing oversupply concerns and muted momentum in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The world nickel market in 2025 – a growing surplus in an uncertain global landscape</title><link>https://stainless-steel-world.net/the-world-nickel-market-in-2025-a-growing-surplus-in-an-uncertain-global-landscape/</link><description>Global primary nickel production is projected to grow by 5.9% in 2025, contributing to a growing surplus amid record-high EV sales and rising stainless steel production. LME and SHFE nickel inventories have been rising steadily, surpassing 230,000 tonnes in early 2025, reflecting ongoing oversupply despite geopolitical uncertainties.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Woes: Innovations Steering a Sustainable EV Future</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-supply-woes-innovations-steering-a-sustainable-ev-future-aemc/</link><description>This article discusses the critical role of nickel in battery technology for electric vehicles (EVs) and highlights innovations such as low-nickel or nickel-free battery chemistries, advanced battery recycling, and smaller battery sizes to ensure sustainability. It also emphasizes financial incentives and policies like the U.S. Inflation Reduction Act and the EU’s Battery Fund to boost domestic battery production and mining capacities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Greening nickel extraction requires institutional and financial support</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-01811-8</link><description>The article highlights the environmental challenges of nickel mining, particularly the greenhouse gas emissions from clearing carbon-rich forests. It stresses the need for institutional and financial backing to scale up low-carbon nickel extraction technologies to reduce the industry's carbon footprint.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,856.95 per tonne on November 7, 2025, marking a 0.45% daily increase and an 8.63% rise year-over-year. Prices are expected to reach $2,918.78 by the end of the quarter and $3,053.09 in 12 months, driven by tight supply and China's output caps.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever launch first consumer packaging using carbon-free ELYSIS aluminum</title><link>https://esgpost.com/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-launch-first-consumer-packaging-using-carbon-free-elysis-aluminum/</link><description>Alcoa Corporation, Ball Corporation, and Unilever PLC announced the first commercial use of ELYSIS® carbon-free smelting technology in consumer packaging. This innovation eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions from aluminum smelting by generating oxygen instead of CO2, producing aerosol cans with 50% ELYSIS primary aluminum and 50% recycled content, representing one of the lowest-carbon packaging solutions available.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Pioneering Sustainable Practices: Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever Lead with Carbon-Free Smelting Technology</title><link>https://csimarket.com/news/pioneering-sustainable-practices-alcoa-ball-and-unilever-lead-with-carbon-free-smelting-technology2025-11-07140104</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever are leading sustainable aluminum production by adopting ELYSIS technology that eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions during smelting. This breakthrough aligns with global decarbonization goals and demonstrates how cross-sector collaboration can scale low-carbon innovations in industrial supply chains.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Billions at stake: Chancellor Merz backs European patriotism for steel</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/business/2025/11/07/billions-at-stake-chancellor-merz-backs-european-patriotism-for-steel</link><description>German steel production faces challenges due to Chinese subsidies and US tariffs, with EU steel output declining and major producers like Thyssenkrupp cutting jobs. The EU is proposing stricter trade measures, including tighter import quotas and higher tariffs, to protect its steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper prices soars due to mine closures!</title><link>https://www.xtb.com/int/market-analysis/news-and-research/copper-prices-soars-due-to-mine-closures</link><description>Copper prices surged to their highest levels since May last year following a serious accident at the Grasberg Block Cave mine in Indonesia and mine closures in Peru. These supply disruptions, combined with rising demand from the energy transition, have increased market uncertainty and pushed prices closer to record highs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Electrification Fuels Unprecedented Demand and Market Volatility</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-11-7-coppers-green-revolution-electrification-fuels-unprecedented-demand-and-market-volatility</link><description>Copper demand is surging due to the global energy transition, driven by electric vehicles, renewable energy infrastructure, and grid modernization. Technological advances like AI, data centers, and 5G networks further increase copper consumption, with emerging markets such as India becoming significant demand drivers alongside China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer eases to $2,841/t as opening stock edges up to 549,225t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-eases-to-2-841-t-as-opening-stock-edges-up-to-549-225t-116132</link><description>LME aluminium prices declined slightly on November 7, with the cash bid slipping to $2,840/t and the cash offer easing to $2,841/t. Stocks showed a marginal increase, with opening stock rising to 549,225 tonnes and live warrants up 0.51%. The 3-month Asian Reference Price was $2,848/t.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Stainless Steel Daily Review: Stainless Steel Market Faces Year-End Off-Season, Low Spot Prices Fail to Boost Demand</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Finished-Steel</link><description>Stainless steel futures and spot prices remain weak due to the year-end off-season and tepid demand, despite active discounting by mills. Social inventory increased slightly, and major steel mills lowered list prices, keeping the market sluggish.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vedanta spins off Konkola Copper Mines into US-domiciled CopperTech Metals Inc.</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2025/11/07/vedanta-spins-off-konkola-copper-mines-into-us-domiciled-coppertech-metals-inc/</link><description>Vedanta Resources has spun off Konkola Copper Mines into a US-based company, CopperTech Metals Inc., to meet US copper resource security needs. CopperTech plans to invest an additional $1.5 billion on top of Vedanta's existing $3 billion investment in the Konkola mine.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] On November 7, nickel prices moved ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103609730</link><description>Nickel prices declined after a higher opening on November 7, 2025, as the US dollar index continued to fall. The market showed signs of weakness despite some early gains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Russia’s Nornickel, one of the largest nickel producers globally, maintained its 2025 nickel production outlook at 196,000-204,000 metric tons. Nickel production rose 18% to 54,000 metric tons in Q3 2025, attributed to higher volumes of processed raw materials, despite earlier shipment cuts due to seasonal flooding.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel Upgrades Catalyst in Sulphur Program</title><link>https://nornickel.com/news-and-media/press-releases-and-news/nornickel-upgrades-catalyst-in-sulphur-program/</link><description>Nornickel has begun replacing the vanadium catalyst in its Sulphur Program at the Nadezhda Smelter, aiming to improve efficiency and reduce environmental impact. This upgrade is part of ongoing efforts to enhance the sustainability of nickel production processes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Green steel revolution: navigating a new frontier in 2025</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/green-steel-revolution-navigating-a-new-frontier-in-2025/</link><description>Sweden is set to produce the world's first zero-carbon emission steel in 2025, marking a historic milestone for the industry. The shift to green steel, driven by hydrogen-based direct reduction iron and scrap-based electric arc furnace technologies, will reshape pricing, markets, and supply chains, though challenges remain around energy costs and infrastructure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Coarse Particle Flotation: Mining Recovery Revolution</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/coarse-particle-flotation-technology-2025-benefits/</link><description>Coarse particle flotation (CPF) technology is transforming mineral processing by enabling efficient recovery of valuable minerals from larger particles, improving sustainability and operational efficiency in mining. The technology reduces energy and water use, minimizes tailings, and is gaining rapid adoption across major mining operations.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Strengthens as Trade Tensions Ease</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-strengthens-as-trade-tensions-ease/</link><description>Copper prices rose on Friday, supported by signs of easing trade tensions between major economies, providing some relief after recent declines driven by Fed uncertainty and supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Maxus Mining Announces Closing of Flow Through Private Placement</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/6239431</link><description>Maxus Mining closed a flow-through private placement, supporting exploration at its Penny Copper Project in British Columbia. The project has returned high copper values in grab samples, indicating potential for future copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM News Flash: High-Nickel Pig Iron Prices Decline on November 8</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103030296/SMM-News-Flash:-High-Nickel-Pig-Iron-Prices-Decline-on-November-8</link><description>SMM reported that the price range for 8-12% high-nickel pig iron (ex-factory price) declined to 1005~1025 yuan/nickel on November 8, 2025. The drop reflects ongoing market pressures and subdued demand in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Q3 2025 slides: Sequential growth amid missed expectations</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/company-news/century-aluminum-q3-2025-slides-sequential-growth-amid-missed-expectations-93CH-4340937</link><description>Century Aluminum reported sequential progress in Q3 2025 despite missing expectations. The company is advancing a new smelter project expected to take 4-6 years and create over 6,500 jobs, which will help address the U.S. aluminum deficit. For 2025, Century projects total aluminum shipments of 660,000 tonnes and anticipates improved EBITDA in Q4.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Record Bull Bets Signal a New Era for Industrial Metals</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-11-8-aluminums-unprecedented-ascent-record-bull-bets-signal-a-new-era-for-industrial-metals</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged past $2,900 per metric ton, driven by a forecasted supply shortfall growing from 8,000 tons in 2025 to 365,000 tons in 2026. Primary producers like Alcoa stand to benefit from higher margins and potential capacity expansions, while downstream industries face cost pressures and supply challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Environmental Engineering Researchers are Using Plants to Extract Nickel for Sustainable Mining</title><link>https://www.stevens.edu/news/environmental-engineering-plants-nickel-mining</link><description>Researchers at Stevens are developing phytomining technology that uses hyperaccumulator plants to extract nickel from ultramafic mine tailings and serpentine barren soils, which are otherwise unproductive. This method offers a cleaner, more sustainable alternative to traditional nickel mining by reducing environmental damage and enabling phytoremediation to clean contaminated soils.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Can Waste From Nickel Production Create Better Concrete?</title><link>https://www.azobuild.com/news.aspx?newsID=23931</link><description>A new study shows that waste from nickel production can be repurposed to strengthen concrete, reduce emissions, and improve sustainable building practices. This innovation could reshape construction materials by turning nickel production scrap into valuable resources.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's top cable maker sees US copper tariff as opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Italy's Prysmian, the world's largest copper cable manufacturer, views the US's planned 50% copper tariff as a positive move that will strengthen the American supply chain. The company, which acquired Texas-based Encore Wire, expects costs to be passed on to customers and is in regular contact with the US administration regarding the implementation of the tariff.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Investors Amass Record Bull Bets on Aluminium Supply Shortage</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/fund-positioning-market-transformation-2025/</link><description>Record investment surges in aluminum reflect structural supply shortages amplified by US tariffs and EU sanctions on Russian aluminum. The US Midwest premium hit $1,938 per ton, 67% above the LME price, indicating tight supply and depleted inventories ahead of tariff hikes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,856.95 per tonne on November 7, 2025, supported by demand in electrification sectors and supply disruptions including a potline suspension at Iceland's Grundartangi smelter and Alcoa's shutdown of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia. China maintains a production cap of 45 million tons annually, limiting supply growth amid rising energy costs and regulatory risks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global bauxite upswing triggers exports, expansions and collaborations across the aluminium ecosystem</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/global-bauxite-upswing-triggers-new-expansions-and-collaborations-across-the-aluminium-ecosystem-heres-whats-unfolding-116130</link><description>The global increase in bauxite demand is driving new exports, expansions, and collaborations within the aluminum industry. This upswing is fostering advancements in aluminum casthouse technology and supporting sustainable growth across the aluminum ecosystem worldwide.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,029 CNY/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.33% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have declined 2.13%, and are down 6.22% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts suggest steel will trade at 3,039.40 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,904.76 in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 7-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 15,020 USD/ton on November 7, 2025, marking the lowest level since September and a 2.40% decline over the past month. The market is expected to trade at 14,887.32 USD/ton by the end of the quarter, with further declines projected over the next 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market Shows Recovery Signs Amid Policy Support &amp; Trade Tensions</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-market-shows-recovery-signs-amid-policy-support-trade-tensions</link><description>Nickel prices have moved into the upper half of the $15,000-$15,800 per ton range, suggesting a potential recovery as battery supply chains may be entering a restocking cycle. Policy support and trade tensions, including US tariffs on Chinese graphite and deals with Indonesia, are influencing the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Live Nickel Price</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/price/base-metals/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices are currently at 15,089.99 USD/ton, down slightly from the previous day. The market remains volatile, with prices fluctuating within a narrow range.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME Nickel Official Prices</title><link>https://www.lme.com/en/metals/non-ferrous/lme-nickel</link><description>The official LME nickel price for November 9, 2025, is 14,830.00 USD/ton (bid) and 14,840.00 USD/ton (offer), reflecting a continued downward trend in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel prices traded flat at 847 USD/T on November 7, 2025, but have risen 4.18% over the past month and 19.80% year-on-year. Forecasts suggest prices will reach 858.87 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 930.60 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals Report (11.09.2025): Financing Critical Minerals 2.0 Through Government Equity and Private Capital</title><link>https://investornews.com/critical-minerals-rare-earths/critical-minerals-report-11-09-2025-financing-critical-minerals-2-0-through-government-equity-and-private-capital/</link><description>Copper prices have reached a record $11,200 per tonne, reflecting tight supply conditions driven by demand from electric vehicles and power grids. The report highlights supply chain concerns, including Glencore's potential closure of its Horne copper smelter in Quebec, Canada's largest copper metal operation, due to environmental upgrade requirements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,856.95/t on November 7, up 0.45% from the previous day. The price has increased 3.55% over the past month and is up 8.63% year-on-year. Futures are expected to trade at $2,879.83/t by the end of the quarter.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Hits 627,000 mt on Nov 10, Up 5,000 mt WoW from Last Thu</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611375/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Hits-627000-mt-on-Nov-10-Up-5000-mt-WoW-from-Last-Thu</link><description>Domestic aluminum ingot social inventory in China reached 627,000 mt on November 10, up 5,000 mt week-on-week. LME aluminum is projected to trade between $2,830-$2,930/mt in the coming week.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever pioneer carbon-free aluminum manufacturing for consumer packaging</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-pioneer-carbon-free-aluminum-manufacturing-for-consumer-packaging/</link><description>Alcoa, in partnership with Ball Corporation and Unilever, announced the first use of ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology for consumer packaging, eliminating direct greenhouse gas emissions by producing oxygen instead of CO2. This initiative represents a significant step toward low-carbon aluminum products and highlights cross-sector collaboration ahead of COP30 climate discussions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Hits 627,000 mt on Nov 10, Up 5,000 mt WoW from Last Thu</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611375/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Hits-627000-mt-on-Nov-10-Up-5000-mt-WoW-from-Last-Thu</link><description>Social inventory of domestic aluminum ingots in China reached 627,000 metric tons as of November 10, 2025, increasing by 5,000 metric tons week-over-week. Market expectations for SHFE aluminum prices range between 21,300-21,900 yuan/mt, while LME aluminum is projected between $2,830-$2,930/mt next week.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Asian steel market seen under pressure in Q4 amid weak demand, trade barriers</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/asian-steel-market-seen-under-pressure-in-q4-amid-weak-demand-trade-barriers/</link><description>The Asian steel market is under pressure in Q4 2025 due to weak demand and rising trade barriers, according to a recent S&amp;P Global Commodity Insights report.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>WA to source green steel from local manufacturers for gov't projects</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/wa-to-source-green-steel-from-local-manufacturers-for-govt-projects/</link><description>The Western Australian Government has launched an initiative to use locally made green steel in major government projects, supporting job creation and local manufacturing. The program encourages the use of sustainable building materials and introduces a new procurement approach favoring local green steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Steel?</title><link>https://fremantleshippingnews.com.au/2025/11/10/green-steel/</link><description>Fortescue has initiated a green iron pilot project at Christmas Creek in the Pilbara, with first production scheduled for 2025. This marks a significant step in Australia's efforts to develop green steel production capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Participation in the Development of Critical Minerals and Rare Earths Feedstock Production Project in Australia</title><link>https://www.marubeni.com/en/news/2025/info/00037.html</link><description>Marubeni Corporation announced its participation in a critical minerals and rare earths feedstock production project in Australia, supporting the development of essential materials for advanced manufacturing, including steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>WA to source green steel from local manufacturers for gov't projects</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/wa-to-source-green-steel-from-local-manufacturers-for-govt-projects/</link><description>The Western Australian Government announced an initiative to prioritize locally made green steel for major government infrastructure projects, supporting the state's manufacturing sector and sustainability goals. The program includes a new procurement approach favoring green steel and aims to create jobs while advancing decarbonization in construction materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Consumer Confidence Falls to a Low Level, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611345/US-Consumer-Confidence-Falls-to-a-Low-Level-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper futures opened at $10,743.5/mt on Friday night, fluctuated during the session, and closed slightly higher at $10,695/mt with a 0.07% increase. The SHFE copper contract closed marginally lower at 85,920 yuan/mt. Vedanta Resources announced the establishment of CopperTech Metals Inc. in the US to meet copper resource security needs amid rising demand driven by data centers, power grids, and defense technology.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price holds loss as equity rout, strong dollar weigh on metals</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-holds-loss-as-equity-rout-strong-dollar-weigh-on-metals/</link><description>Copper prices traded near $10,650 per ton on the LME after a four-day losing streak, pressured by a stronger US dollar and global equity market declines. The recent rally cooled following a record high last month amid optimism over a US-China trade deal and supply disruptions. Chinese buyers were seen purchasing dips, and a key African port for copper trade reopened, easing supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium rises with copper as US govt shutdown nears end</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/node/778947</link><description>Copper prices rose alongside aluminium on November 10, boosted by improving risk appetite as the US government shutdown neared resolution. This positive market sentiment contributed to gains in base metals including copper.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise Amid Uncertainty Over U.S. Tariffs</title><link>https://www.gurufocus.com/news/3197726/copper-prices-rise-amid-uncertainty-over-us-tariffs</link><description>Copper prices have risen amid uncertainty over potential changes to U.S. tariffs, with indications from the U.S. President about reconsidering copper tariffs. This could tighten global copper supply outside the United States, influencing market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US Consumer Confidence Falls to a Low Level, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611345/US-Consumer-Confidence-Falls-to-a-Low-Level-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated and closed lower on Friday, ending at $10,695/mt with a 0.07% increase, while SHFE copper also saw a slight decline. Trading volumes and open interest remained robust, reflecting ongoing market activity. The meeting also noted Vedanta's spin-off of Konkola Copper Mines into US-based CopperTech Metals Inc.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Critical Minerals List: 2025 Strategic Addition</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/critical-minerals-strategic-value-copper-demand-2025/</link><description>The US officially added copper to its critical minerals list in November 2025, highlighting its strategic importance. The article discusses global copper production concentration, with Chile leading, and notes China's dominance in refining capacity, which creates supply chain vulnerabilities. Infrastructure and workforce limitations in the US are also highlighted.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Bullish Outlook: China's Industrial Resilience and Global Supply Constraints Drive Growth</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-bullish-outlook-china-industrial-resilience-global-supply-constraints-drive-growth-2511/</link><description>China's industrial output surged in Q3 2025, boosting copper demand, especially from high-tech manufacturing and NEV production. The article forecasts a 150,000 metric ton deficit in 2026 and a 40% rise in global demand by 2040, underscoring the need for supply-side solutions. Copper's role in decarbonization and digitalization is emphasized.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper and Potassic alteration above main Southern Porphyry Target at Llahuin</title><link>https://www.shmining.com.au/2025/11/copper-and-potassic-alteration-above-main-southern-porphyry-target-at-llahuin/</link><description>Exploration drilling at the Llahuin project has advanced to 1,198.9m downhole, with copper and potassic alteration identified above the main Southern Porphyry Target. The results indicate potential for further copper discoveries in the region.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>USGS officially adds copper, silver to critical minerals list</title><link>https://www.mining.com/us-officially-adds-copper-silver-to-critical-minerals-list/</link><description>The US Geological Survey has officially added copper and silver to the critical minerals list, emphasizing their importance to the US economy and national security. The update will inform policy decisions on trade, investment, and mine permitting, reflecting growing concerns over supply chain security.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Hits 4-Year Low as Gloom Offsets Potential Indonesia Cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell to their lowest level in four years, driven by a lackluster outlook from the Federal Reserve and concerns over a stronger US dollar. Despite Indonesia considering sharp mining quota cuts, the market remains oversupplied and sentiment is weak.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices were in the doldrums on ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103607793</link><description>Nickel prices remained weak on November 10, 2025, with little movement as market participants awaited further developments. The US dollar index continued to influence price trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Breakthrough Tech Yields 99% Pure Nickel, Cobalt</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/breakthrough-tech-yields-99-pure-nickel-cobalt-1566990/</link><description>A new electrochemical process has been developed to recover nickel and cobalt with over 97% nickel recovery and 99% purity from battery leachates. This technology minimizes chemical usage and enables sustainable recycling with high metal purity and recovery rates, potentially impacting nickel supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Reason for Today's Sharp Aluminum Price Hike (November 10, 2025)</title><link>https://vmrf.vn/en/the-reason-for-todays-sharp-aluminum-price-hike-november-10-2025-1784</link><description>Aluminum prices rose sharply by about 0.7-1.2% reaching $2,856-$2,860 per ton due to global alumina and bauxite supply shortages caused by disruptions in Guinea and Brazil. Production cuts in China and Australia, combined with increased demand from green industries and economic stimulus, are driving a global deficit and pushing prices higher.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Surge Amid U.S. Government Reopening Hopes</title><link>https://www.gurufocus.com/news/3198766/aluminum-prices-surge-amid-us-government-reopening-hopes</link><description>Aluminum prices on the London Metal Exchange surged 1.7% to $2,895 per ton driven by optimism over a potential U.S. government reopening. The market remains strong due to Chinese capacity curbs and resilient demand, with analysts predicting a market deficit of 1.8 million tons this year despite high producer margins potentially limiting further price rises.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rises on the outlook of reopening the US government</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/aluminum-rises-on-the-outlook-of-reopening-the-us-government-47712</link><description>Aluminum prices rose 1.7% to $2,895 per ton on the London Metal Exchange, supported by optimism about a U.S. government reopening. Production cuts in China and sustained global demand contribute to a supply deficit of around 1.8 million tons this year, though high producer margins may cap further price increases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Premium Reaches Record High in the US Due to Tariffs and Global Squeeze</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/11/10/aluminum-premium-reaches-record-high-in-the-us-due-to-tariffs-and-global-squeeze</link><description>Record-high aluminum premiums in the US are driven by steep import tariffs and a global supply shortage. The physical market is experiencing tight conditions, with limited supply and increased demand pushing premiums to unprecedented levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Premiums for Aluminum in U.S. Reach Record Highs</title><link>https://globalnews.ca/video/11519806/premiums-for-aluminum-in-u-s-reach-record-highs</link><description>US aluminum premiums have hit record highs due to import tariffs and a global supply squeeze. The situation is impacting the physical market, with producers and consumers facing increased costs and limited availability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Aluminium Expands Low-Carbon Portfolio with Launch of Restora Production at BALCO</title><link>https://thecsruniverse.com/articles/vedanta-aluminium-expands-low-carbon-portfolio-with-launch-of-restora-production-at-balco</link><description>Vedanta Aluminium has expanded its low-carbon product portfolio by launching Restora production at BALCO, reflecting ongoing efforts to enhance ecological restoration and community stewardship through sustainable aluminum manufacturing practices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Raw Steel Production Is Up 1.0 Percent - Week 46, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-10-percent-week-46-2025-1418884.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production rose 1.0% for the week ending November 8, 2025, reaching 1.758 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.7%. This marks a 9.1% increase compared to the same period last year, reflecting continued growth in the sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Holds November Pullback</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel/news/500255</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China fell to CNY 3,040 per tonne due to lower demand and increased trade protectionism. Exports from China dropped 12.5% year-on-year in October, and the construction PMI hit a record low, signaling ongoing sector contraction.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices in the Second Week of November 2025</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/37868/</link><description>Global steel markets showed mixed price movements in the second week of November 2025, with some products increasing and others declining. The report highlights regional differences in price trends and market sentiment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices Down As Ship Recycling Slows</title><link>https://www.marinelink.com/news/steel-prices-down-ship-recycling-slows-532241</link><description>Global steel prices are falling as ship recycling activity slows, particularly in South Asia. Prices in Pakistan and India have dropped below USD 400/LDT, with weak demand and limited supply contributing to the downturn.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AISI: Weekly raw steel production ticks up</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/10/aisi-weekly-raw-steel-production-ticks-up/</link><description>US mills produced an estimated 1,758,000 short tons of raw steel in the week ending November 8, 2025, up 1.0% from the previous week. The mill capability utilization rate was 76.7% last week, up from 76.0% the week prior and 9.1% higher than the same week a year earlier. Year-to-date production now stands at 77,228,000 short tons, 3.1% higher than the same period in 2024.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises as Risk Appetite Improves</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/500503</link><description>Copper futures climbed back above $5 per pound on Monday, reaching a one-week high as risk appetite strengthened amid optimism that the US government shutdown may soon end. The red metal also benefited from a weaker dollar and the Trump administration's addition of copper to its list of critical materials for the US economy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Surge Copper Highlights Strengthening Policy Environment for Critical Minerals Development in Canada</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/10/3184388/0/en/Surge-Copper-Highlights-Strengthening-Policy-Environment-for-Critical-Minerals-Development-in-Canada.html</link><description>Surge Copper welcomes measures in Budget 2025 that support critical minerals development in Canada, with the Berg Project positioned to benefit from infrastructure initiatives and federal-provincial support. The project features a large-scale copper and molybdenum resource with low-carbon, hydro-powered design aligned with national priorities for responsible resource development.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aqua Metals partners with Westwin to strengthen US nickel supply chain</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aqua-metals-partners-with-westwin-to-strengthen-us-nickel-supply-chain/</link><description>Aqua Metals signed a non-binding letter of intent with Westwin Elements to supply up to 1,000 metric tons of recycled nickel carbonate annually starting in 2027. This partnership aims to build one of the first fully domestic recycled nickel supply chains in the US, reducing reliance on imports and supporting clean energy systems. The deal is valued at around $12 million annually based on current nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aqua Metals and Westwin Elements Sign LOI for U.S.-Produced Nickel Carbonate Supply</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/10/3184463/36806/en/Aqua-Metals-and-Westwin-Elements-Sign-LOI-for-U-S-Produced-Nickel-Carbonate-Supply.html</link><description>Aqua Metals announced a non-binding Letter of Intent with Westwin Elements to supply up to 1,000 metric tons of recycled battery-grade nickel carbonate annually starting in 2027. The agreement follows successful qualification of Aqua Metals' nickel carbonate product and aims to establish one of the first domestic sources of nickel carbonate to support US industrial and battery manufacturing needs.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aqua Metals Westwin Partnership Creates US Nickel Supply</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/aqua-metals-westwin-nickel-supply-2025/</link><description>Aqua Metals and Westwin have partnered to create America's first integrated nickel battery recycling supply chain, aiming to produce 500 to 1,000 metric tons of recycled nickel carbonate annually by 2027. This closed-loop system converts battery waste into new battery production feedstock, enhancing US nickel supply security amid growing electric vehicle adoption and reducing dependence on foreign imports.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aqua Metals and Westwin Elements Sign LOI for U.S.-Produced Nickel Carbonate Supply</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/10/3184463/36806/en/Aqua-Metals-and-Westwin-Elements-Sign-LOI-for-U-S-Produced-Nickel-Carbonate-Supply.html</link><description>Aqua Metals and Westwin Elements have signed a letter of intent to create one of the first domestic sources of battery-grade nickel carbonate in the U.S., using advanced recycling technologies. The collaboration aims to strengthen the circular supply chain for critical minerals and reduce dependence on imports, supporting sustainable and secure domestic manufacturing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Recycling Technology Achieves 99% Purity of Nickel and Cobalt</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-recycling-technology-purity-nickel-cobalt.html</link><description>A research team affiliated with UNIST has developed a new recycling technology that recovers over 95% of nickel and cobalt from waste batteries, achieving up to 99% purity. This eco-friendly method could significantly reduce the environmental impact of battery production and support the circular economy.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>New Recycling Tech Recovers Nearly Pure Nickel and Cobalt from Old Batteries</title><link>https://interestingengineering.com/energy/recycling-nickel-cobalt-ev-batteries</link><description>Researchers have unveiled an innovative recycling technology that extracts 99% pure nickel and cobalt from spent electric vehicle batteries. The breakthrough could help meet the growing demand for sustainable battery materials and reduce reliance on virgin mining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>EU CBAM Adjustments Transform Aluminium Pricing Markets</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/eu-carbon-border-adjustment-aluminium-markets-2025/</link><description>The European Union's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM), effective January 1, 2026, will impose carbon-based pricing on aluminum imports, reshaping global aluminum trade by linking prices to environmental compliance. This new regulatory framework introduces certificate costs based on embedded carbon emissions, significantly impacting international aluminum market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Eases from 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/499462</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK fell to $2,850 per tonne from a three-year high amid soft manufacturing PMIs in the US and China, though supply concerns kept prices 12% higher year-to-date. China's annual aluminum output cap of 45 million tons is expected to be breached next year, and smelters face challenges expanding in Indonesia due to energy costs and regulations. Issues at key smelters, including Iceland's Grundartangi and Alcoa's Kwinana refinery, also pressured supply.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>EU CBAM Adjustments Transform Aluminium Pricing Markets</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/eu-carbon-border-adjustment-aluminium-markets-2025/</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) is reshaping global aluminum pricing, favoring regions with low-carbon production like Norway, Iceland, Canada, and Brazil. High-carbon producers in China, India, and Russia face increased costs and competitive disadvantages, prompting shifts in production and investment toward cleaner technologies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 11, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-11-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd shares rose 0.10% to ₹1,181.20 on November 11, 2025. The update reflects current market sentiment and minor gains in the company's stock price.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 1.0 percent - week 46, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-10-percent-week-46-2025-1418884.htm</link><description>According to the American Iron and Steel Institute (AISI), US domestic raw steel production for the week ending November 8, 2025, was 1.758 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.7%. Year-to-date adjusted production through November 8, 2025, was 77.228 million net tons at a capacity utilization rate of 77.0%, representing a 3.1% increase from the same period last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vale gearing up to meet Indian demand as China steel output stagnates</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/vale-gearing-up-to-meet-indian-demand-as-china-steel-output-stagnates-ceo-says-2025-11-11</link><description>Brazilian miner Vale is preparing to meet rising iron ore demand from India, which could double its steel production by the end of the decade. This shift reflects changing global steel dynamics as China's steel output stagnates.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>South Korea confronts global steel barriers as US, EU and Canada tighten rules</title><link>https://koreapro.org/2025/11/south-korea-confronts-global-steel-barriers-as-us-eu-and-canada-tighten-rules/</link><description>South Korea's trade ministry held a joint public-private meeting to assess the impact of global protectionist measures targeting steel, including US Section 232 tariffs and Tariff Rate Quota systems in the EU and Canada. The ministry announced a Steel Industry Advancement Plan that includes stronger domestic safeguards and financial support for affected producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Grasberg Accident Investigation Concludes, LME Copper Surged Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103613614/Grasberg-Accident-Investigation-Concludes-LME-Copper-Surged-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper settled at $10,874.5/mt, up 1.68%, after opening at $10,820/mt and reaching a high of $10,903/mt. Freeport Indonesia completed its investigation into the slurry leakage incident at Grasberg copper-gold mine, with the Big Gossan and Deep Mill Level Zone mines resuming operations at the end of October.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices drop on Fed policy uncertainty and Codelco supply</title><link>https://www.miningreporters.com/noticia/news/2025/11/copper-price-falls-fed-policy-codelco-supply</link><description>Copper prices extended losses on Tuesday, falling as much as 2.4% to around $10,855 per tonne on the LME, pressured by renewed uncertainty over US interest rates and easing supply concerns from Chilean miner Codelco. The US dollar reached its highest level since May, further weighing on metals that had surged in anticipation of a US-China trade truce.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper climbs on US shutdown deal, supply tightness</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3WN05Z:0-copper-climbs-on-us-shutdown-deal-supply-tightness/</link><description>Copper prices climbed on Tuesday as a potential resolution to the US federal government shutdown lifted market sentiment, with the three-month copper contract up 0.24% at $10,822 per ton. Fresh production data showing reduced output at Chile's Codelco reinforced expectations of tighter supply next year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>3 ASX copper shares soaring amid 28% surge in commodity price this year</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/11/11/3-asx-copper-shares-soaring-amid-28-surge-in-commodity-price-this-year/</link><description>ASX copper shares are benefiting from a 28% surge in the commodity price this year to US$5.08 per pound on Tuesday, driven by higher demand amid the global energy transition. Copper has been supported by its designation as a critical material for the US economy and national security, as well as a weaker US dollar.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>ARENA commits $25.3 million to continue SunDrive's copper solar cell breakthrough</title><link>https://arena.gov.au/news/arena-commits-25-3-million-to-continue-sundrives-copper-solar-cell-breakthrough/</link><description>Australia’s ARENA has committed $25.3 million to advance SunDrive’s copper metallisation technology for solar cells, aiming to provide a silver-free alternative amid rising silver prices. This investment supports scaling up production of copper-based solar technology, contributing to clean energy innovation.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Collapse Forces Market Repricing as Oversupply Weak Demand Challenge Producers</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-price-collapse-forces-market-repricing-as-oversupply-weak-demand-challenge-producers</link><description>The nickel market is undergoing severe structural adjustment with prices collapsing to around US$15,000 per tonne in mid-2025 due to oversupply and weak demand. Macroeconomic factors such as US dollar strength and tariffs on imports from major producers like Indonesia and Russia are adding complexity, driving supply chain realignment and creating distinct pricing mechanisms based on source jurisdiction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 11, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 119,400-123,200 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103614036/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 119,400 to 123,200 yuan per metric ton on November 11, with an average price of 121,300 yuan/mt, marking a slight increase of 100 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Sulphate Daily Review] November 11 Nickel Salt Prices Slightly Declined</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103614820/%5BSMM-Nickel-Sulphate-Daily-Review%5D-November-11-Nickel-Salt-Prices-Slightly-Declined</link><description>On November 11, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price was 28,285 yuan/mt, with a slight decline in the quotation range for battery-grade nickel sulphate.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price hikes slightly on Nov 11, remaining stable</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/NewsItem/130109</link><description>The international nickel price remained stable on November 11, with the three-month futures price on the London Metal Exchange (LME) slightly rising, reflecting a steady market condition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries targets US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-targets-us-1-billion-ebitda-by-2026</link><description>Australia-listed nickel miner and processor Nickel Industries Limited aims to achieve US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026, signaling strong growth ambitions amid current market conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries targets US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-targets-us-1-billion-ebitda-by-2026</link><description>Nickel Industries aims to achieve US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026, reflecting growth ambitions in the nickel sector. The company is expanding production capacity amid strong demand for nickel, particularly for battery and stainless steel applications.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S.A. Announces Share Buyback Reaching 5.01% of Voting Rights</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/story/news/29731024/tenaris-sa-announces-share-buyback-reaching-501-of-voting-rights</link><description>Tenaris announced that the company is expected to report earnings on November 11, 2025, before market open. This earnings report serves as a clear catalyst for traders and investors.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>