<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 05:15:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Extreme Steel Inc. Announces Strategic Recapitalization to Accelerate Growth and Expansion in Structural Steel Industry</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/11/19/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/extreme-steel-inc-announces-strategic-recapitalization-to-accelerate-growth-and-expansion-in-structural-steel-industry/2226747</link><description>Extreme Steel Inc. has announced a strategic recapitalization aimed at accelerating growth and expansion in the structural steel sector. The move is expected to enhance the company's production capabilities and market presence.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Mantel Develops New Take on Carbon Capture</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2025/mantel-develops-new-take-carbon-capture-1119</link><description>Mantel, founded by MIT alumni, has developed a carbon capture system that can be added to factories and power plants producing cement, steel, paper, and other materials, reducing carbon emissions by around 95 percent. The system captures CO2 and converts it into pure CO2 that can be transported or stored, while also generating steam as a useful revenue stream. Mantel is currently in conversations with close to 100 industrial partners worldwide, including steel plant owners.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Stainless Steel World Sustainability Day 2025</title><link>https://stainless-steel-world-event.com/sustainability-day/</link><description>The Stainless Steel World Sustainability Day 2025 brings together visionaries, engineers and decision-makers to address sustainability challenges in the stainless steel industry. The event focuses on decarbonizing production, developing low-impact alloys, and embracing circular design while navigating geopolitical strategies and global supply chain pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper extends loss as dollar strengthens</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-extends-loss-as-dollar-strengthens/</link><description>Copper prices extended losses as the strengthening U.S. dollar weighed on commodity markets. The decline reflects broader market pressures and investor sentiment tied to currency movements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper inches up as investors weigh US job data, Fed rate decision</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3WV035:0-copper-inches-up-as-investors-weigh-us-job-data-fed-rate-decision/</link><description>Copper prices edged higher after a three-day decline, as investors monitored delayed U.S. job data and awaited the Federal Reserve's rate decision. Market movements were cautious amid uncertainty about economic indicators and monetary policy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>During the day buyers' purchase willingness significantly increased, market transactions recovered and premiums rose [SMM Yangshan Spot Copper]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103628646/During-the-day-buyers-purchase-willingness-significantly-increased-market-transactions-recovered-and-premiums-rose-%5BSMM-Yangshan-Spot-Copper%5D</link><description>Buyer demand for copper increased during the day, leading to a recovery in market transactions and higher premiums. Warrant prices rose slightly, reflecting improved market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FireFly boosts Green Bay's resources</title><link>https://mining.com.au/firefly-boosts-green-bays-resources/</link><description>FireFly Metals has increased the resource estimate for its Green Bay Copper-Gold Project in Newfoundland, Canada, to 50.4 million tonnes at 2% for 1 million tonnes copper-equivalent. The project now features a high-grade core and remains open for further expansion, with underground drilling continuing into 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper inches up as investors weigh US job data, Fed rate decision</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3WV035:0-copper-inches-up-as-investors-weigh-us-job-data-fed-rate-decision/</link><description>Copper prices edged up as investors assessed US job data and the Federal Reserve's rate decision. Freeport expects its 2026 copper and gold output to be roughly in line with 2025 levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>After deadly accident, Freeport aims to restart Grasberg copper production by July 2025</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/after-deadly-accident-freeport-aims-to-restart-grasberg-copper-production-by-july-2025-11-19</link><description>Freeport-McMoRan plans to restore production at Indonesia's Grasberg copper and gold mine by July 2025 following a fatal incident. The restart will bring large-scale copper production back online.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Freeport Provides Update on Restart Plans for Grasberg Minerals District</title><link>https://investors.fcx.com/investors/news-releases/news-release-details/2025/Freeport-Provides-Update-on-Restart-Plans-for-Grasberg-Minerals-District/default.aspx</link><description>Freeport announced plans to restore large-scale production from PT Freeport Indonesia's Grasberg operations in Indonesia. The restart is expected to significantly increase copper output in the coming year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in November (Period I)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103862-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-november-period-i</link><description>The Indonesia Nickel Miners Association (APNI) announced the benchmark prices for nickel ore for the first half of November 2025, with the reference price set at $15,075.33/wmt, a 0.44% decrease from October. Prices for various nickel grades also saw slight declines compared to the previous period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 19, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 115,400-119,800 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103628480/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on November 19 was reported at 115,400-119,800 yuan/mt, averaging 117,600 yuan/mt, an increase of 650 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects a modest upward movement in the refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's 120M Ton Cut and Its Ripple on Carbon Markets</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/indonesian-government-reduces-national-nickel-mining-quotas-by-120-million-tons-impacting-global-supply/</link><description>Indonesia has reduced its national nickel mining quota by 120 million tons for 2025, cutting permitted production from 272 million tons in 2024 to 150 million tons. This reduction, aimed at preserving resources and promoting sustainable processing, is expected to tighten global nickel supply by about 35%, impacting global supply chains and nickel pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Supply-Demand Dynamics &amp; Price Outlook for Nickel Sulphate</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103624823/refined-nickel-producers-switching-to-nickel-sulphate-productionsupply-demand-dynamicsprice-outlook-for-nickel-sulphate/</link><description>Refined nickel producers are switching to nickel sulphate production amid shifting supply-demand dynamics. While nickel sulphate production is ramping up, overall downstream demand is not expected to grow significantly in November and December. Nickel salt prices are forecasted to face downward pressure due to easing supply and steady demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices reached $14,648.75 per tonne on November 19, 2025, showing a slight increase from the previous day but down 7.74% year-over-year. The market remains oversupplied due to expanded Indonesian production capacity despite recent quota cuts. Stockpiles at LME warehouses have increased, reflecting ongoing supply surplus amid mixed demand from stainless steel and electric vehicle sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>PE eyes BHP's Nickel West as China tightens rare earth grip</title><link>https://www.marketsgroup.org/news/pe-eyes-bhps-nickel-west-as-china-tightens-rare-earth-grip</link><description>Private equity firms are showing interest in BHP's Nickel West amid China's tightening control over rare earths and nickel supply chains. Nickel prices have halved over three years due to Indonesian low-cost production. Strategic moves by Japanese companies and investors aim to diversify nickel supply outside Chinese influence, with projects in Australia expected to produce competitive nickel volumes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia limits new nickel permits to add value to production</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/indonesia-limits-new-nickel-permits-to-add-value-to-production/</link><description>Indonesia has stopped approving new permits for nickel plants producing certain intermediate products without further processing plans, aiming to push the industry up the value chain. This policy is expected to reduce oversupply and encourage investment in downstream processing, potentially causing project delays or cancellations. The move aligns with Indonesia's 2020 ban on raw nickel ore exports to boost domestic processing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>$42M manufacturing facility keeps Coast Aluminum — and its workers</title><link>https://thebusinessjournal.com/42m-manufacturing-facility-keeps-coast-aluminum-and-its-workers-rooted-in-fresno/</link><description>Coast Aluminum, a Hayward-based aluminum supplier, is breaking ground on a $42 million, 163,000-square-foot manufacturing and distribution facility near Fresno Yosemite International Airport. The new facility, expected to open in 2026, represents a major expansion securing the company's future workforce and operational flexibility in the region.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Will Carbon-Free Aluminum Packaging Partnerships Shift Alcoa's Trajectory?</title><link>https://simplywall.st/stocks/us/materials/nyse-aa/alcoa/news/will-carbon-free-aluminum-packaging-partnerships-shift-alcoa/amp</link><description>Ball Corporation, Unilever, and Alcoa announced the first use of ELYSIS® carbon-free aluminum smelting technology in consumer packaging, featuring cans with 50% ELYSIS aluminum and 50% recycled content. This partnership exemplifies cross-industry efforts to accelerate low-carbon innovation and meets growing global demand for sustainable materials ahead of COP30.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Cochilco hikes 2025-2026 copper price forecasts to record highs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/cochilco-hikes-2025-2026-copper-price-forecasts-to-record-highs/</link><description>Chile's state copper commission Cochilco increased its copper price forecasts to record highs, projecting average prices of $4.45 per pound for 2025 and $4.55 per pound for 2026, up from the previous $4.30 forecast. The higher forecasts reflect weak production in Chile, including issues at major mines like Collahuasi and El Teniente, with supply expected to lag demand through at least 2030.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ashry Steel Seeks to Increase Exports and Strengthen the Presence of Egyptian Products in Global Markets</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/38228/</link><description>Ashry Steel announced plans to increase exports and enhance the global presence of Egyptian steel products. The company aims to capitalize on growing international demand and strengthen its market position through strategic initiatives.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Analysis: despite Chinese slowdown worries, copper and aluminum poised for further gains</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/analysis-despite-chinese-slowdown-worries-copper-and-aluminum-poised-for-further-gains/</link><description>Despite concerns about a slowdown in China, copper and aluminum markets are expected to continue gaining. The analysis suggests that base metals, including aluminum, are set to finish the year on a positive note, reflecting underlying demand and supply dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 20, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-20-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's stock surged by 0.25%, currently trading at ₹1,167.00 with a PE ratio of 46.7800, reflecting market movements in the Indian steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's rebar output down 2.0 percent in January-October 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/chinas-rebar-output-down-20-percent-in-january-october-2025-1420272.htm</link><description>China's rebar production totaled 158.01 million mt in January-October 2025, down 2.0 percent year-on-year. In October alone, rebar production fell 18.6 percent year-on-year to 14.34 million mt, while wire rod production increased 0.4 percent and welded pipe output rose 3.7 percent for the full period.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Ship scrap steel can help decarbonise European steelmaking: Report</title><link>https://shippingtelegraph.com/shipping-reports/ship-scrap-steel-can-help-decarbonise-european-steelmaking-report/</link><description>A new report highlights how recycled ship scrap steel can reduce CO₂ emissions by up to 80% compared to virgin materials in European steelmaking. EU/EFTA-owned ship demolitions are forecast to peak at approximately 12 Mt of scrap steel per year, potentially satisfying 10-15 Mt of the EU's annual scrap steel demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel consumption in the US: major upheavals</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/posts/steel-consumption-in-the-us-major-upheavals/</link><description>U.S. steel imports are projected to decline by approximately 12% annually by the end of 2025, with monthly imports unlikely to exceed 1.5 million tons. This represents a significant shift in American steel consumption patterns.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 20, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-20-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's stock surged 0.25% and is trading at ₹1,167.00 with a PE ratio of 46.78. The update provides current market performance data for the Indian steel producer.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper rebounds as stocks stabilise, amid supply worries</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-rebounds-as-stocks-stabilise-amid-supply-worries/</link><description>Copper prices rebounded as market stocks stabilized, with prices climbing 1.7% to $37,505. The rebound occurred amid ongoing concerns about copper supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rises on bullish Chile outlook as investors weigh Fed rate decision</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3WW03U:0-copper-rises-on-bullish-chile-outlook-as-investors-weigh-fed-rate-decision/</link><description>Copper prices rose following Cochilco's bullish outlook for Chilean copper production and the commission's record-high price forecasts of $4.45 for 2025 and $4.55 for 2026. Market movements were also influenced by investor considerations regarding Federal Reserve rate decisions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rises</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40393275</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.8 percent to USD 10,810 per metric ton in official open-outcry trading. The increase reflects broader market strength in copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chile's Cochilco hikes 2025 and 2026 copper price forecasts to record highs</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/chiles-cochilco-hikes-2025-and-2026-copper-price-forecasts-to-record-highs-2025-11-20</link><description>Chile's state copper commission, Cochilco, has raised its copper price forecasts for 2025 and 2026 to record highs. The agency expects Chilean copper production to grow by just 0.1% to 5.51 million metric tons in 2025, with a 2.5% increase projected for 2026, reaching 5.6 million metric tons.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US fund managers have established positions in Canadian copper ore companies while LME copper fluctuated and closed higher overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103629537/US-fund-managers-have-established-positions-in-Canadian-copper-ore-companies-while-LME-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-higher-overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>US fund managers have taken positions in Canadian copper ore companies amid fluctuating LME copper prices, which closed higher overnight. LME copper inventories rose, while SHFE warrant inventories declined, reflecting ongoing shifts in supply and demand dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell to their lowest since November 2020 amid a pessimistic Federal Reserve outlook that outweighed Indonesia's plans to sharply cut nickel mining quotas from 272 million tons to 150 million tons next year. The metal, crucial for EV batteries, has declined about 8% this year due to new supply waves and slowing EV sales, with prices dropping 1.8% to $15,235 a ton on the LME.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices edged higher on November 20</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103630924/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-higher-on-November-20-while-the-US-Fed-remained-deeply-divided-over-whether-to-cut-interest-rates-in-December</link><description>On November 20, refined nickel prices in China edged up by 600 yuan/mt to an average of 118,200 yuan/mt, reflecting a slight recovery amid mixed market signals including US Federal Reserve interest rate uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Smelter Restrictions Explained</title><link>https://chinaglobalsouth.com/2025/11/20/indonesia-nickel-smelter-restrictions-chinese-commentator/</link><description>Indonesia has introduced restrictions on new nickel-smelter investments to slow the rapid expansion of its nickel sector, which has caused oversupply and environmental concerns. However, analysts warn that without upstream mining permit limits and integrated policies, the impact may be limited, as many smelters are already operational or under construction, with China playing a central role in the sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Smelter Restrictions Explained</title><link>https://chinaglobalsouth.com/2025/11/20/indonesia-nickel-smelter-restrictions-chinese-commentator/</link><description>Indonesia has imposed restrictions on new nickel smelter investments to control its rapid nickel sector expansion, which has caused environmental and social strain. Although the freeze on new smelter licenses slows future growth, existing projects continue, and without upstream mining limits, the policy may have limited impact on reducing oversupply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>NexMetals Mining Eliminates Smelter Risk and Secures US$80M to Fast-Track Botswana Copper-Nickel Assets</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nexmetals-mining-eliminates-smelter-risk-and-secures-us-80m-to-fast-track-botswana-copper-nickel-assets</link><description>NexMetals Mining secured US$80 million in funding and eliminated a US$21 million debt, enabling it to fast-track copper-nickel assets in Botswana without the need for costly smelter infrastructure. The metallurgical breakthrough reduces capital costs and allows cobalt recovery, with exploration upside expected to expand resources significantly in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Creek Platinum Announces Closing of $1.5 Million Tranche of Private Placement</title><link>https://investingnews.com/nickel-creek-platinum-announces-closing-of-1-5-million-tranche-of-private-placement/</link><description>Nickel Creek Platinum closed a $1.5 million tranche of financing to support exploration at its Nickel Shäw Project, a large undeveloped nickel sulphide deposit in Canada. The funds will be used in 2026 to explore additional nickel and copper mineralization, with the project benefiting from excellent infrastructure and access to shipping ports.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Attends Benchmark Week 2025 Conference Highlighting Awaruite, a Naturally Magnetic Nickel-Cobalt Alloy as a Smelter-Free Source for North America’s Critical Minerals Supply</title><link>https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/first-atlantic-nickel-attends-benchmark-week-2025-conference-highlighting-awaruite-a-naturally-magnetic-nickel-cobalt-alloy-as-a-smelter-free-source-for-north-america-s-critical-minerals-supply-1035572779</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel presented its Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project at Benchmark Week 2025, promoting it as a secure, low-impact domestic source of nickel and cobalt. The project aims to provide a smelter-free solution to North America's critical minerals supply challenges.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Crawford Gets Federal Priority Status</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/federal-priority-critical-minerals-2025-development-canada/</link><description>Canada Nickel's Crawford project has received federal priority status for its revolutionary IPT Carbonation process, which transforms mining waste into permanent carbon storage and produces carbon-neutral critical minerals. This technology supports sustainable mining and meets growing demand for low-carbon supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Strengthen Indonesia's Global Nickel Leadership</title><link>https://vale.com/w/strengthen-indonesia-s-global-nickel-leadership-pt-vale-indonesia-and-huayou-commits-to-climate-aligned-technology-pathways-at-cop30</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia and Huayou are deploying advanced hydrometallurgical technologies, including waste heat recovery and CO2 solidification, to reduce emissions and carbon intensity in nickel production. Their efforts aim to deliver low-carbon nickel and support Indonesia's role in the global clean energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Breakthrough Strengthens North America</title><link>https://icttm.org/nickel-breakthrough-strengthens-north-america/</link><description>A recent nickel technology breakthrough is set to enhance North America's clean energy supply chain, supporting industries such as electric vehicles and batteries with more sustainable and efficient production methods.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Monster faces modest tariff impact from aluminum costs</title><link>https://www.supplychaindive.com/news/monster-faces-modest-tariff-impact-from-aluminum-costs/806002/</link><description>Monster Beverage expects a modest impact from tariffs in the current quarter and next year, primarily due to high duties on imported aluminum for cans. The Midwest premium for aluminum surged to a record high in November, driven by the 50% Section 232 import tariff imposed by the Trump administration. The company raised prices effective November 1, though the increases were focused on revenue growth rather than being directly tariff-related.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>A second fire breaks out at Ford's aluminum supplier Novelis</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/11/20/a-second-fire-breaks-out-at-ford-aluminum-supplier-novelis</link><description>A second fire broke out at Novelis' Oswego aluminum plant, which supplies Ford's F-150 truck range. Bank of America noted that aluminum prices are unlikely to return to current levels until early next decade, with forecasts expecting prices to trade between $2,900-3,400 from 2030-2035. The facility had been targeting December for production restart despite earlier disruptions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Third Fire Hits Ford's Key Aluminum Supplier, Threatening $2B Recovery</title><link>https://www.techbuzz.ai/articles/third-fire-hits-ford-s-key-aluminum-supplier-threatening-2b-recovery</link><description>A third fire in three months erupted at the Novelis aluminum plant in Oswego, NY, threatening to derail Ford's recovery from supply chain disruptions that have already cost the automaker $2 billion. The four-alarm blaze broke out Thursday morning at the facility that supplies critical aluminum sheets for Ford's F-150 trucks, including the all-electric Lightning. The fire forced a complete evacuation, with all workers safely evacuated and the fire brought under control.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum plant supplying Ford pickups erupts in fire again</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-plant-supplying-ford-pickups-erupts-in-fire-again/</link><description>Heavy black plumes of smoke were visible coming from the roof of the Novelis plant, with the fire originating from the plant's cold mill. Ford was working with Novelis to restart the plant as early as the following week, with CFO Sherry House telling investors that efforts to resume work were on track with expectations for restart around Thanksgiving or early December. Novelis declined to discuss whether the latest fire would affect its production restart plans.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Update and Market Outlook</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) Steel prices rose slightly to 856 USD/T on November 20, 2025, up 0.12% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices increased by 4.81%, and are up 22.60% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect HRC Steel to trade at 865.36 USD/T by the end of the quarter and forecast a rise to 938.96 USD/T within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Price gap between US HRC and imports narrows</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com</link><description>The price gap between US hot rolled coil steel and landed offshore products narrowed week over week. The market shows signs of an imminent demand spike in Q1, with steelmaking raw material prices stabilizing through November. Industry leaders express optimism about the current US steel market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Barry Zekelman says it's a 'fantastic' time for steel in the US</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/20/barry-zekelman-says-its-a-fantastic-time-for-steel-in-the-us/</link><description>Barry Zekelman expressed optimism about the US steel market, noting strong volumes and positive conditions driven by data center demand and infrastructure needs. He highlighted that hot rolled prices are on the upswing and emphasized the massive amount of steel being used in data center construction and related infrastructure. However, he acknowledged challenges in Canada's steel industry, which he described as being significantly impacted by China's global steel displacement.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Good news in Gary and Pittsburgh — but still America declines</title><link>https://baystatebanner.com/2025/11/20/good-news-in-gary-and-pittsburgh-but-still-america-declines/</link><description>The Gary Works steel mill, located thirty miles south of Chicago, is receiving a $14 billion modernization that will protect tens of thousands of jobs. This investment represents positive developments for major US steel production centers despite broader industry challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel sector needs more investment in R&amp;D, use of AI for overall growth</title><link>https://www.taxtmi.com/news?id=62262</link><description>A central government minister emphasized that India's steel sector requires increased investment in research and development and wider adoption of technologies such as artificial intelligence, machine learning, digitalization and modern mining methods to enhance competitiveness and operational efficiency. Speaking at a two-day policy retreat in Odisha, authorities highlighted steel's role as the backbone of national infrastructure and stressed collaboration between central public sector enterprises and private entities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Stavian Industrial Metal Unveils Green Strategy at VIMOX 2025 as Platinum Sponsor, Positioning Vietnam as Global Metals Hub</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/11/20/stavian-industrial-metal-unveils-green-strategy-at-vimox-2025-as-platinum-sponsor-positioning-vietnam-as-global-metals-hub/</link><description>Stavian Industrial Metal announced a comprehensive green strategy focused on sustainable metal production and trading partnerships. The company signed a binding agreement with India's ACME Group to distribute and off-take 800,000 tons per year of green hot briquetted iron (HBI) and direct reduced iron (DRI) for the Asian market for at least 10 years, aligning with Vietnam's Net Zero 2050 agenda.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper price falls on Fed uncertainty, Codelco supply relief</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-falls-on-fed-uncertainty-codelco-supply-relief/</link><description>Copper prices dropped as much as 2.4% due to uncertainty over US monetary policy and eased supply concerns following Codelco's announcement of increased output. The dollar strengthened, adding pressure on metals, while demand remains subdued despite earlier supply disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices rise after Nvidia's results, but the dollar is still strong</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/11/20/copper-prices-rise-after-nvidias-results-but-the-dollar-is-still-strong</link><description>Copper prices saw a modest rise after Nvidia's results, with LME copper trading around $10,738.50 per ton. Goldman Sachs raised its copper price forecast for December 2025 and remains bullish on copper through 2026-2027, citing demand growth and resource constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Dyno Nobel: setting a new standard for safer, smarter blasting</title><link>https://www.dynonobel.com/news-and-media/news/dyno-nobel-setting-a-new-standard-for-safer-smarter-blasting/</link><description>Dyno Nobel announced new precision blasting technology that enables mining companies to extract copper, iron ore, and gold more efficiently and sustainably. The company developed an electric MPU (Mobile Processing Unit) that can be fully charged in 45 minutes using renewable energy and significantly reduces explosive waste by delivering precise amounts for each blast hole.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Twin Metals seeking state mineral leases Boundary Waters?</title><link>http://www.timberjay.com/stories/twin-metals-seeking-state-mineral-leases-boundary-waters,23712</link><description>Franconia Minerals, a subsidiary of Twin Metals, is requesting new mineral leases from Minnesota to explore for copper-nickel near Birch Lake. The company proposes drilling up to 19 test holes centered around Bob Bay, with work to be completed by March 31, 2027 if approved.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Italy's Tenaris posts surprise 2% rise in sales on stable US, Canada drilling</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/italys-tenaris-posts-surprise-2-rise-in-sales-on-stable-us-canada-drilling-4317727</link><description>Italian steel pipe maker Tenaris reported a 2% increase in third-quarter net sales to $2.98 billion, driven by stable drilling activity in North America, offsetting weakness in other regions. Despite the sales rise, the company warned that margins would be affected by the full impact of tariff costs, with EU steel producers operating at reduced capacity due to rising imports and tariffs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking raw material prices stabilize through November</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/20/steelmaking-raw-material-prices-stable-to-higher-2/</link><description>Most steelmaking raw material prices remained stable or slightly changed in November, with iron ore and aluminum prices down 1%, coking coal up 3%, and aluminum Midwest premium up 9%. Prices are mixed compared to last year, with some materials more expensive than three months ago. Chinese iron ore fines held steady at around $104/dmt, while scrap prices were unchanged after declines in previous months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper futures reversed gains as China demand slumped</title><link>https://www.cmegroup.com/videos/2025/11/20/copper-futures-reversed-gains-as-china-demand-slumped-11-20-25.html</link><description>December copper futures showed significant volatility, reversing early gains due to a 22% drop in China's October copper imports and sluggishness in the property and power grid sectors. Despite Chile raising price forecasts for 2025 and 2026 citing supply disruptions, weak Chinese demand weighed on market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Plunge Sharply on November 21 as Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cut Weaken</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103633277</link><description>Nickel prices dropped sharply on November 21 due to weakening expectations for a US Fed interest rate cut, despite a surge in non-farm payrolls. The spot price for refined nickel averaged 116,700 yuan/mt, down 1,500 yuan/mt from the previous day. Macro pressures and high inventory are expected to keep prices under pressure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tartisan Nickel Launches 3,600m Drill Program at Kenbridge</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/TTSRF/tartisan-nickel-corp-engages-rodren-drilling-ltd-for-drill-program-nclylbqzyjeu.html</link><description>Tartisan Nickel Corp. has initiated a 3,600-meter diamond drilling program at its 100% owned Kenbridge Nickel-Copper-Cobalt Deposit. The program aims to convert inferred mineral resources into measured and indicated categories and support an updated Mineral Resource Estimate and a forthcoming Pre-Feasibility Study. Mobilization is scheduled for December 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Industry Mulls Unveiled CBAM Benchmarks, Default Values</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/aluminum-industry-mulls-unveiled-cbam-benchmarks-default-values/</link><description>Aluminum producers are reviewing the preliminary benchmarks and default values for the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM), which could impact trade and pricing in the sector. The industry is assessing how these new standards will affect competitiveness and compliance.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Falls on Nov 21</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103632229/SMM-Flash-News:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Falls-on-Nov-21</link><description>Social inventory of secondary aluminum ingots declined on November 21, according to SMM statistics. The market saw a slight recovery in aluminum prices, with ADC12 alloy prices stabilizing at 21,450 yuan/mt.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices fell to 4.92 USD/lb on November 21, 2025, down 0.63% from the previous day. The price has declined 0.79% over the past month but remains 20.73% higher than the same time last year. Market sentiment has been affected by uncertainty over Federal Reserve rate cuts, reducing expectations for a December cut.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper demand set to soar amid supply crunch</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/11/21/copper-demand-set-to-soar-amid-supply-crunch/</link><description>Copper demand is expected to surge due to global electrification, electric vehicles, renewables, and grid upgrades, while supply constraints persist across mining, refining, and smelting. Analysts warn that new supply additions and recycling will not be enough to close the widening supply-demand gap by 2035.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Widening Supply-Demand Gap to Drive Copper Prices to New Heights</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/commodity-news/petail-28158.html</link><description>Global copper mine output dropped 4.7% year-on-year in Q3 2025 due to disruptions in major producing regions, including Peru, DRC, and Indonesia. The supply-demand gap is projected to widen to 300,000 tons in 2026, supporting expectations for copper prices to reach new highs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price Update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103632922/</link><description>On November 21, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 114,400-119,000 yuan/mt, with an average price of 116,700 yuan/mt. This represents a decline of 1,500 yuan/mt from the previous trading session, marking nickel prices breaking below the 118,000–123,000 yuan/mt range that had persisted for nearly four months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alaska, Montana projects added to FAST-41</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/11/21/news/alaska-montana-projects-added-to-fast-41/9367.html</link><description>Alaska Energy Metals' Nickolai nickel project and US Critical Materials' Sheep Creek gallium-rare earths project have been added to the FAST-41 dashboard. This designation aims to expedite permitting for critical mineral projects.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alaska, Montana projects added to FAST-41</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/11/21/news/alaska-montana-projects-added-to-fast-41/9367.html</link><description>Alaska Energy Metals' Nickolai nickel project and US Critical Materials' Sheep Creek gallium-rare earths projects have been added to the FAST-41 dashboard. This represents progress in developing North American critical mineral infrastructure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Market Dominance: Supply Chain Control</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/indonesian-nickel-dominance-global-market-2025/</link><description>Indonesia's nickel market dominance is transforming global supply chains and driving innovation in battery technology, including accelerated research into nickel-free batteries, recycling technologies, and alternative chemistry scaling like LFP batteries. Supply chain concentration risk is spurring investment in alternative technologies and substitution materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Raises Annual Targets After Record Q3 Performance</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/prysmian-raises-annual-targets-after-record-q3-performance/</link><description>Prysmian has raised its full-year 2025 guidance following a record-breaking third quarter. The company’s strong financial performance reflects its leadership in the cable industry, including copper cables, and its strategic focus on innovation and growth in Italy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 4-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to $2,792.50 per ton on November 21, 2025, down 0.72% from the previous day, marking a 4-week low. Despite the recent decline, aluminum prices remain nearly 6% higher than a year ago, reflecting ongoing market volatility influenced by supply and demand factors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>GACC: China's alumina imports soar 216% MoM in October</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/list-all/latest-updates/aluminum/</link><description>China's alumina imports reached 189,326 tonnes in October 2025, marking the highest monthly volume this year and a 215.6% increase from September. This surge reflects strong demand in China's aluminum production sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AIP to sell or list French aluminum plant, union claims</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/11/21/aip-to-sell-or-list-french-aluminum-plant-union-claims</link><description>AIP is reportedly planning to sell or list its French aluminum plant as part of a strategy to increase aluminum recycling capacity to 15 million tonnes per year by 2027. This move is seen in the context of global competition, especially from China in secondary aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel fell to 3,057 CNY/T on November 21, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China fell slightly by 0.33% to 3,057 CNY per tonne on November 21, 2025. Despite a small monthly increase of 0.20%, steel prices remain about 7.53% lower than a year ago. The market shows some short-term fluctuations but overall remains below last year's levels.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Shagang holds list prices for steel longs for late-Nov sales</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5104914-shagang-holds-list-prices-for-steel-longs-for-late-nov-sales</link><description>Shagang Group, a leading Chinese steelmaker, decided to maintain its list prices for long steel products for sales in late November 2025. This move reflects a cautious approach amid current market conditions and price stability in the steel longs segment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Price on Trade: Changes to USMCA needed to support American steelmaking</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/21/price-on-trade-changes-to-usmca-needed-to-support-american-steelmaking/</link><description>Since Canada and Mexico were brought back under the Section 232 steel program in 2025, U.S. domestic raw steel production increased nearly one-to-one with the decrease in steel imports from these countries. From January to September 2025, U.S. production rose by approximately 1.4 million short tons while imports from Canada and Mexico decreased by about 1.5 million short tons, reflecting the impact of trade policy on domestic steelmaking.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Federal Steel Systems Reaffirms Commitment to Quality Standards and Transparent Building Delivery</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/pressadvantage-2025-11-22-federal-steel-systems-reaffirms-commitment-to-quality-standards-and-transparent-building-delivery</link><description>Federal Steel Systems reaffirmed its commitment to maintaining high-quality standards and transparency in building delivery. The company emphasized its dedication to customer satisfaction and adherence to industry best practices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper prices fall on firm dollar, as traders evaluate US employment data</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/11/21/copper-prices-fall-on-firm-dollar-as-traders-evaluate-us-employment-data</link><description>Copper prices declined on November 21, 2025, with the London Metal Exchange benchmark three-month price falling 0.62% to $10,671.5 per ton amid a strong US dollar and cautious investor sentiment ahead of the Federal Reserve's interest rate decision. China's weak demand further pressured prices, with Shanghai Futures Exchange copper contracts down 0.83%, marking a weekly decline of 1.43%. Traders are closely watching US employment data and Fed rate cut probabilities, which have increased to 70%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices fall on week-end dollar firm as traders evaluate US employment data</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/11/21/copper-prices-fall-on-weekend-dollar-firm-as-traders-evaluate-us-employment-data</link><description>Copper prices dropped 0.39% to $10,696.5 per ton on the London Metal Exchange, expected to close the week with a 1.41% loss. The strong US dollar and hawkish Fed officials weighed on commodity prices, making them costlier for investors using other currencies. Despite high prices this year, demand from China remains weak, contributing to the price decline. Other metals like lead, nickel, and tin also saw price drops.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Grasberg Mine Suspension Creates Major Copper Production Crisis</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/grasberg-underground-catastrophe-copper-supply-2025/</link><description>The Grasberg mine suspension following a tragic underground incident has caused a significant disruption in copper production. Freeport McMoRan's Q3 2025 copper output dropped 13.2% quarter-on-quarter, with a projected 35% decrease in 2025 production, reducing output by approximately 262,000 metric tons. This event impacts global copper supply amid rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CRML Secures One of the Largest Strategic Stockpiles of Ultra-High-Purity Copper Powder in a US$20M All-Share Acquisition</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/21/3192887/0/en/CRML-Secures-One-of-the-Largest-Strategic-Stockpiles-of-Ultra-High-Purity-Copper-Powder-in-a-US-20M-All-Share-Acquisition-Issued-at-a-40-Premium-to-Market.html</link><description>CRML has acquired one of the largest strategic stockpiles of ultra-high-purity copper powder through a US$20 million all-share acquisition, issued at a 40% premium to market. This move aims to strengthen supply chain security for critical copper materials in the US.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Amid Expectations of Copper Concentrate Shortages, How Are Smelters Adjusting Their Operating Strategies?</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103634470/amid-expectations-of-copper-concentrate-shortages-how-are-smelters-adjusting-their-operating-strategies</link><description>Copper concentrate shortages are expected to persist through 2025, with spot treatment charges remaining negative. Smelters are adjusting their operating strategies to cope with the tight supply, reflecting ongoing challenges in copper concentrate availability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP's Copper Boom: Sustainable Mining to Meet Soaring Global Demand</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/bhps-copper-boom-sustainable-mining-to-meet-soaring-global-demand/</link><description>BHP reported record copper production with a 28% increase since FY22, emphasizing copper's role in energy transition technologies and urban development. The company is advancing sustainable mining by reducing greenhouse gas emissions, electrifying operations, expanding renewable energy use, and minimizing methane emissions, aiming for net zero by 2050. BHP expects global copper demand to rise by about 70% by 2050.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Mining 2025: Innovative Sustainable Solutions</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-mining-2025-innovative-sustainable-solutions</link><description>This article explores innovations in copper mining that reduce water usage by up to 30% per ton of copper produced and integrate blockchain for traceability and transparency in the supply chain. It highlights environmental and social considerations and the use of satellite technology to improve resource management, aligning copper mining with climate action targets and sustainable development.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Energy Efficiency in Copper Processing Plants 2025 - Technology, Sustainability &amp; Innovation</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/energy-efficiency-in-copper-processing-plants-2025</link><description>Energy-efficient copper processing plants in 2025 are cutting emissions by up to 30% through automation, digitization, smelting improvements, thermal recovery, and renewable energy integration. These innovations reduce fossil fuel reliance, lower operational costs, and support renewable infrastructure, reinforcing the copper sector's commitment to a green circular economy. Blockchain-based traceability ensures supply chain authenticity and transparency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CRML Secures One of the Largest Strategic Stockpiles of Ultra-High-Purity Copper Powder in a US$20M All-Share Acquisition</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/21/3192887/0/en/CRML-Secures-One-of-the-Largest-Strategic-Stockpiles-of-Ultra-High-Purity-Copper-Powder-in-a-US-20M-All-Share-Acquisition-Issued-at-a-40-Premium-to-Market.html</link><description>CRML acquired a large strategic stockpile of ultra-high-purity copper powder, securing a G7/EU-origin, fully traceable resource to support Western industrial resilience. This acquisition enhances CRML's ability to support R&amp;D and production for advanced manufacturing and defense, central to innovation in these sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>UNCTAD urges smarter copper trade as bottlenecks threaten global transition</title><link>https://unctad.org/news/unctad-urges-smarter-copper-trade-bottlenecks-threaten-global-transition</link><description>UNCTAD warns that a looming copper shortfall could stall the global shift to clean energy and digital infrastructure. The organization calls for smarter copper trade policies to address supply bottlenecks critical for the energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's role in the energy transition grows as demand surges</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_us/insights/mining-metals/coppers-role-in-the-energy-transition-grows-as-demand-surges</link><description>With intensifying supply pressures, copper companies are increasing production while embracing sustainability and digital innovations. The article discusses copper's expanding role in the energy transition and the industry's efforts to meet rising demand responsibly.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel rose to 14,420.75 USD/T on November 21, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices rose slightly to 14,420.75 USD per metric ton on November 21, up 0.11% from the previous day. However, prices are down 4.75% over the past month and 9.05% compared to the same time last year, reflecting ongoing market weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Sumitomo Metal Mining's Q3 nickel production rises 3.31% Year-on-Year</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103772-flash-sumitomo-metal-minings-q3-nickel-production-rises-331-year-on-year</link><description>Sumitomo Metal Mining reported nickel production of 22,900 tonnes for Q3 2025, a 5.32% increase from the previous quarter and a 3.31% rise compared to the same period last year. Production included electrolytic nickel, nickel sulfate, and ferronickel, while nickel-cobalt sulfide production at the Nickel Asia Corporation project in the Philippines declined.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Implats Q3 2025 nickel production rises 15.35% Year-on-Year</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103774-flash-implats-q3-2025-nickel-production-rises-1535-year-on-year</link><description>South Africa's Implats reported nickel production of 4,531 tonnes in briquette form for Q3 2025, a 19.43% increase from the previous quarter and 15.35% higher than the same period last year. The nickel was produced as a by-product of platinum group metals refining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Antitrust opens an investigation against the main producers of copper cables in Italy, accused of fixing prices since 2005</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/tag/prysmian/</link><description>The Italian antitrust authority has launched an investigation into the main producers of copper cables in Italy, including Prysmian, for alleged price-fixing practices dating back to 2005. This probe targets the copper cable market in Italy, potentially impacting Prysmian's operations and market behavior.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Italy's Prysmian sees stronger U.S. pricing, margins after new copper tariff scheme</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3TS0GY:0-italy-s-prysmian-sees-stronger-u-s-pricing-margins-after-new-copper-tariff-scheme/</link><description>Prysmian Group expects improved pricing and margins in the U.S. market following the implementation of a new copper tariff scheme. The company projects full-year adjusted EBITDA between 2.3 and 2.375 billion euros, reflecting positive financial impacts from tariff adjustments on copper cables.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CoinCover Joins Digital Asset's Copper-based Disaster Recovery Setup at Canton Treasury</title><link>https://smbtech.au/news/coincover-joins-digital-assets-copper-based-disaster-recovery-setup-at-canton-treasury/</link><description>Digital Asset strengthened its treasury operations by integrating CoinCover into its Copper-based custody and disaster recovery setup. This move enhances security and operational resilience for digital asset management using Copper's technology platform.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices on Nov 22 climb to two-week high amid tightened supply</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/NewsItem/151442</link><description>Nickel futures at the London Metal Exchange surged by $256/ton to close at $15,970/ton on November 22, reaching a two-week high due to tightened supply conditions. The sharp increase reflects recent market volatility and supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Price Today</title><link>https://www.investing.com/commodities/nickel</link><description>The nickel price today is reported at 14,526.13 USD per metric ton. The market continues to show volatility, with prices fluctuating amid macroeconomic uncertainty and supply-demand dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 22 Nov 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/11/22/the-market-in-numbers-22-nov-2025/</link><description>Nickel prices declined by 2.59% on November 22, continuing a downward trend amid broader market pressures. The article highlights recent price movements and their implications for the metals sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (November 17, 2025 - November 21, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-november-17-2025-a-november-21-2025-on-the-ce7d5edfd189f422</link><description>Tenaris reported holding 37,359,848 ordinary shares in treasury, representing 3.49% of its total issued share capital as of November 21, 2025. The company remains a leading global supplier of steel tubes and related services for the energy industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>