<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 05:21:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Coppers Tightest Moment Yet: Record Prices Growing Deficits and a Rush to Secure Supply</title><link>https://www.streetwisereports.com/article/2025/12/19/coppers-tightest-moment-yet-record-prices-growing-deficits-and-a-rush-to-secure-supply.html</link><description>The copper market faces its tightest period with record prices and growing deficits, as mine supply is expected to be weakest in Q4 2025 and Q1 2026. This signals entry into a clear deficit phase amid supply challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 20.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides the latest updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures rebar contracts showing no change at 0.00 on December 19, 2025. The platform offers real-time prices, news, analyses, and comments on the iron and steel industry. It tracks key exchanges and indices for market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices surge on Dec 20 amid weaker dollar, increased ...</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/NewsItem/151985</link><description>LME nickel futures reportedly jumped US$243/ton to close at US$15,356/ton on Dec 20, with spot prices also rising—moves attributed to a softer dollar and stronger risk flows supporting short‑term price strength.[4]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining Announces Sale of the Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill to Talon Metals</title><link>https://lundinmining.com/news/lundin-mining-announces-sale-of-the-eagle-mine-and-123223/</link><description>Lundin Mining is selling the Eagle Mine, the only primary nickel mine operating in the US, and Humboldt Mill to Talon Metals, creating a pure-play American nickel-copper company. Eagle has produced over 194,000 tonnes of nickel and 185,000 tonnes of copper since operations began, generating US$3.2 billion in revenue. The transaction unlocks synergies for shared processing and supports regional growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium prices rally near USD 2960/t as markets tighten toward year-end</title><link>https://www.balajialuminium.com/aluminium-prices-rally-near-usd-2960-t-as-markets-tighten-toward-year-end-20-december-2025/</link><description>LME aluminium prices rose sharply to approximately USD 2,958.90 per tonne on December 19, 2025, up 1.47% from the prior session. Markets are tightening toward year-end, driving the rally in prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Stabilizes on Robust Demand</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/510576</link><description>Copper futures steadied near multi‑month highs as strong demand from China and the U.S. — driven by EVs, energy infrastructure and AI‑related investment — supported prices, while supply disruptions in Chile and Peru tightened market conditions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Nears Record High as Supply Tightness Back in Focus</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40398494/copper-nears-record-high-as-supply-tightness-back-in-focus</link><description>Copper prices approached record highs in 2025 as concerns over supply tightness returned to the forefront; the metal has gained sharply this year amid strong demand and constrained output, pushing market attention to production capacity and stock levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>B.C. Eyes Copper Smelter to Move Up Mining Value Chain</title><link>https://www.biv.com/news/resources-agriculture/bc-eyes-copper-smelter-to-move-up-mining-value-chain-11650876</link><description>British Columbia is evaluating development of a copper smelter to add value locally, increase domestic processing capacity and address supply‑chain and national security considerations, while weighing environmental and economic tradeoffs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali completes SMP acquisition</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-acciai-speciali-completes-smp-acquisition/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali, a subsidiary of Walsin Lihwa, has completed the acquisition of Sheffield-headquartered Special Melted Products (SMP), following necessary clearances and a €200 million capital increase by the company's shareholders to support the merger. The deal is presented as a strategic step to expand product mix and market presence in Europe, Asia and the US, alongside prior investments in the Aosta plant.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel price extends rebound after Indonesia signals mine output cut</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-extends-rebound-after-indonesia-signals-mine-output-cut/</link><description>Indonesia, the world's top nickel producer, has proposed cutting nickel ore production to 250 million tons in 2026, down from 379 million tons this year, in response to a significant slump in nickel prices. The metal rose 1.5% on Friday following this announcement, extending a rebound from an eight-month low. Nickel prices have declined roughly 50% over the past three years due to oversupply from Indonesia and China outpacing global demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>December 21st LME Closing: Metals Fluctuate, Copper Slightly Up</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/102541857</link><description>LME copper prices rose slightly as a weakening dollar after U.S. data supported the metal, producing modest intraday gains amid broader metal market fluctuations reported at the London Metal Exchange close.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and Market Analysis</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides comprehensive global iron and steel price tracking across major exchanges including Shanghai Futures, Turkey, China, Europe, and North America. The platform tracks rebar and billet prices with recent reports noting gradual declines in Turkey's long products market as of December 18, 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>CHAMPION IRON TO LAUNCH CASH TENDER OFFER TO ACQUIRE RANA GRUBER, RECEIVES FINANCIAL SUPPORT FROM LA CAISSE AND A TERM LOAN COMMITMENT FROM SCOTIABANK</title><link>https://newsroom.championiron.com/2025-12-21-CHAMPION-IRON-TO-LAUNCH-CASH-TENDER-OFFER-TO-ACQUIRE-RANA-GRUBER,-RECEIVES-FINANCIAL-SUPPORT-FROM-LA-CAISSE-AND-A-TERM-LOAN-COMMITMENT-FROM-SCOTIABANK</link><description>Champion Iron announced a cash tender offer to acquire Rana Gruber, a producer of high-grade iron ore concentrate (upgraded to 65% Fe) primarily for European steel production. The deal is expected to boost revenue, EBITDA, and cash flows accretively while maintaining financial leverage, supporting decarbonization in steel via quality resources. Rana Gruber produced 1,867 thousand metric tons of iron ore in the prior year at a cash cost of $565 per ton.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM Analysis: The Two-Month Low-Price War Concludes, Aluminum Rod Processing Fees Reach an Inflection Point</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103681877/smm-analysis-the-two-month-low-price-war-concludes-aluminum-rod-processing-fees-reach-an-inflection-point</link><description>Domestic aluminum rod inventories dropped to 4.37 days as of December 19, 2025, with the inventory ratio at 45.28%, signaling supply stabilization after a low-price period. Aluminum rod processing fees rebound as supply returns to safe levels, though aluminum wire and cable operating rates dipped to 62% amid weak year-end demand and holiday slowdowns in exports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Marimaca Copper: Low-Cost Path to Production in Chile</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/marimaca-copper-low-cost-path-to-production-in-chile</link><description>Profile of Marimaca Copper describing its advance toward production with a low-capital oxide project in Chile; the article places the project in context of high late-2025 copper prices and a tight supply outlook, noting expected construction and first-production timelines that could add capacity in the near term.[5]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global aluminum ingot prices tumble in Q2 2025 amid tariffs, oversupply and weak demand</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5096284-global-aluminum-ingot-prices-tumble-in-q2-2025-amid-tariffs-oversupply-and-weak-demand</link><description>The Asia-Pacific Aluminium Ingot Price Index fell 8.1% in Q2 2025 due to weak downstream demand and steady supply, with North America seeing an 18% drop from tariffs and oversupply. Recent regional price updates include Hangzhou, Nanchang, and Foshan on Dec 22. Looking ahead, LME aluminum prices are forecasted to rise 6.3% year-on-year to around USD 2,573 per tonne amid potential supply shortfalls and demand from EVs and infrastructure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Hot-Rolled Coil Prices Strengthen with Coke Price Reductions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103681619/</link><description>Hot-rolled coil prices strengthened this week with price reductions announced for wet-quenched coke (50 yuan/mt) and dry-quenched coke (55 yuan/mt), effective from December 22, 2025. The most-traded HRC contract gained 0.85% and settled at 3,305 yuan/mt.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Domestic Steel Industry Dynamics 2026 &amp; Falling LME ...</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zDozQJEMfDM</link><description>The stainless steel market bulletin discusses dynamics entering late December 2025, with nickel prices on the LME dropping to around $14,500 per ton, easing cost pressures temporarily. It highlights policy, supply-demand, and raw material impacts shaping trends into early 2026. The update covers industrial metal price adjustments amid cautious investor sentiment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>December 22, 2025，Liberty Steel has successfully restarted the blast furnace at its Whyalla steelworks</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103682391/</link><description>Liberty Steel successfully restarted its blast furnace at the Whyalla steelworks in Australia after a strategic three-week pause. This resumption supports ongoing steel production capacity at the facility. The update falls under ferrous metals news coverage.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Forecast for Next Week (22nd - 26th December 2025)</title><link>https://choiceindia.com/blog/copper-price-forecast-for-next-week</link><description>Copper prices rose 2.71% to $11,880 per metric ton amid expectations of U.S. interest rate cuts and 50% tariffs on refined copper causing arbitrage and shortages in Europe and Asia. A mudslide at Indonesia’s Grasberg mine is expected to limit 300,000-500,000 tons of supply until mid-2026. MCX Copper shows a bullish trend, with forecasts for a moderately bullish week ahead.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to 5.46 USD/Lbs on December 22, up 0.98% daily and 9.45% monthly, supported by strong demand from China and the US in sectors like electric vehicles, energy infrastructure, and AI investments. Futures held above $5.4 per pound near multi-month highs. Recent updates note rises on December 19 and earlier fluctuations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Surge Despite Economic Slowdown, Structural Factors Cited</title><link>https://www.chosun.com/english/market-money-en/2025/12/22/JT3YSIGCABHJHB4AOEHKGNHFRA/</link><description>LME copper prices rose to $11,886.23 per ton on December 19, up 37% year-over-year, driven by supply disruptions, low refining fees, and inventory distortions rather than manufacturing recovery. Experts highlight mine issues, tariffs, and limited new supply development. Citi forecasts $13,000-$15,000 per ton in early 2026 amid AI demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Bank of Japan raised interest rates by 25 basis points as expected and LME copper fluctuated and closed higher last Friday [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103681971/The-Bank-of-Japan-raised-interest-rates-by-25-basis-points-as-expected-and-LME-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-higher-last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper closed at $11,870.5/mt on Friday, up 1.22%, after fluctuating between $11,785.5 and $11,928/mt, while SHFE copper rose 0.91% to 93,560 yuan/mt. Bank of Japan rate hike and hawkish US Fed views tempered gains amid loose spot supply and cautious downstream demand. Prices face limited upside potential.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese copper smelter and Antofagasta agree to record low fees</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/my/node/786741</link><description>A Chinese smelter and Antofagasta agreed to record low processing fees for copper concentrate in 2026, signaling tight supply conditions. This deal underscores ongoing pressures in the copper market amid global trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper nears US$12,000 a tonne as base metals rally</title><link>https://www.klsescreener.com/v2/news/view/1640829/copper-nears-us-12-000-a-tonne-as-base-metals-rally</link><description>Copper prices rallied up to 1.3% to $11,928 a tonne, approaching an all-time high and nearing $12,000, as part of a broader base metals surge. This reflects strong market momentum in industrial metals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Surge Despite Economic Slowdown, Structural Factors Cited</title><link>https://www.chosun.com/english/market-money-en/2025/12/22/JT3YSIGCABHJHB4AOEHKGNHFRA/</link><description>International copper prices have hit record highs, rising to $11,886.23 per ton on December 19th, marking a 37% increase from the end of last year. The surge is driven by supply disruptions, AI infrastructure demand, and limited development of new mines, with Goldman Sachs and Citi maintaining bullish outlooks projecting prices between $13,000-$15,000 per ton in early 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Bank of Japan raised interest rates by 25 basis points as expected and LME copper fluctuated and closed higher last Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103681971/The-Bank-of-Japan-raised-interest-rates-by-25-basis-points-as-expected-and-LME-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-higher-last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper closed at $11,870.5/mt on Friday with a 1.22% increase, while Chinese copper smelters and Antofagasta finalized 2026 copper concentrate long-term contract benchmark TC at record low fees. Global refined copper inventories reached a 35-year low of 1,451 thousand tons as of November 30, with supply constraints becoming increasingly prominent.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nonferrous Metals Surge Over 75% Year-to-Date; U.S. Rate Cut</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28993.html</link><description>Copper production capacity has been constrained by output reductions at Indonesia's Grasberg mine and production disruptions at Chilean copper companies, contributing to historically low global refined copper inventories. New energy vehicles and AI computing infrastructure construction have emerged as major growth drivers, with copper demand from EVs and charging piles growing significantly in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Continue to Rebound</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Nickel</link><description>Nickel prices continued their rebound momentum, with LME select nickel 3-month contracts rising to $14,935/mt, up $35 from the previous session. The strong recovery began on Wednesday, with the most-traded SHFE nickel contract 2601 settling at 117,180 yuan/mt on December 19, gaining 1.27% week-over-week.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Rose to 14,916.25 USD/T</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel rose to $14,916.25 per ton on December 22, 2025, up 0.11% from the previous day. Over the past month, nickel prices have risen 1.26%, though the metal remains 2.93% lower than a year ago.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China's power reforms, global data centre buildout usher in battery boom</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/business/chinas-power-reforms-global-data-centre-buildout-usher-in-battery-boom/articleshow/126112234.cms</link><description>Article discussing how China's power sector reforms and the global expansion of data centers are driving significant growth in battery technology and production.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 2,942.95 USD/T on December 22, 2025, down 0.54% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 4.55%, and are up 15.86% compared to the same time last year. The price recently hit a 3-1/2-year high of 2,926.00 USD/T.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash firms at USD 2,898.5/t as forward prices quietly retreat</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-firms-at-usd-2-898-5-t-as-forward-prices-quietly-retreat-116679</link><description>LME aluminium cash prices edged higher on December 22, with the cash offer at USD 2,898.5 per tonne, up 0.09% from the previous day. The 3-month bid and offer declined slightly to USD 2,940-2,942 per tonne, down 0.1%. Forward contracts for December 26 also saw a minor reduction of 0.13%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminum price trend: Historical context, 2025 market dynamics &amp; 2026 price outlook</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5107828-lme-aluminum-price-trend-historical-context-2025-market-dynamics-and-2026-price-outlook</link><description>LME aluminium cash prices started 2025 at around USD 2,500 per tonne, reaching USD 2,685.50 later in the year. The article provides historical context, analyzes 2025 market dynamics, and offers a price outlook for 2026. It references daily price updates in Chinese markets on December 22.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell slightly to 2,942.95 USD/T on December 22, 2025, amid supply disruptions including South32's Mozal smelter in Mozambique entering care and maintenance by March 2026 due to power issues, tightening global supplies. Additional pressures from Iceland’s Grundartangi smelter suspension and declining Japanese inventories support prices, with China nearing its 45-million-ton output cap.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 0.04% Lower at $5.4375 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512225487/comex-copper-settles-004-lower-at-54375-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for December delivery declined 0.20 cent per pound to $5.4375, marking the largest one-day decline since December 16 and snapping a three-session winning streak. Year-to-date, copper is up 36.41% from its 2025 low, though it remains 6.17% below its 52-week high of $5.795 reached in July.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Hercules Metals Intersects 285 m of 0.47% Copper, Including 56 m of 0.89% Copper at the Leviathan Porphyry System and Discovers New Silver Zone in Southern Flats with 10.7 m of 420.5 g/t AgEq</title><link>https://investingnews.com/hercules-metals-intersects-285-m-of-0-47-copper-including-56-m-of-0-89-copper-at-the-leviathan-porphyry-system-and-discovers-new-silver-zone-in-southern-flats-with-10-7-m-of-420-5-g-t-ageq/</link><description>Hercules Metals Corp. reported results from its 2025 drilling campaign at the Leviathan porphyry copper discovery in Idaho, intersecting 285 m of 0.47% copper including 56 m of 0.89% copper in hole HER-25-12, extending the Footwall Zone 400 meters southwest. A new epithermal silver discovery was made in the Southern Flats zone with 10.7 m of 420.5 g/t AgEq. The company anticipates refined targeting from Phase II MT survey results.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME nickel on Dec 22 hits near 2-month high on Indonesia production cut, Fed expected rate drop</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-on-dec-22-hits-near-2-month-high-on-indonesia-production-cut-fed-expected-rate-drop/158448</link><description>The LME nickel futures price on December 22 rose by US$473/ton to US$15,276/ton. The spot price also increased significantly. This surge was driven by Indonesia's production cuts and expectations of a Federal Reserve rate drop.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: GEM's recycled nickel resources account for 20% of China's primary nickel mining output</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5107850-flash-gems-recycled-nickel-resources-account-for-20-of-chinas-primary-nickel-mining-output</link><description>GEM announced that its recycled nickel resources represent 20% of China's primary nickel mining output, as the company operates the world's largest recycling industrial base for key metals. In the first three quarters of 2025, GEM produced and recycled significant quantities of nickel-related materials while maintaining normal operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy's Antitrust Authority has initiated an investigation into major low-voltage copper cable manufacturers, including Prysmian Cavi e Sistemi Italia Srl, for alleged price-fixing since 2005. Inspections were conducted yesterday at company offices, distributors, and the Italian Association of Electrical Cable Industries. Prysmian shares dropped 1.26% following the news, though analysts view the impact as negligible given the small market share.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Closes in on $12,000-a-Ton Mark</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-heads-toward-12000-a-ton-as-banks-predict-further-gains/copper-closes-in-on-12000-a-ton-mark-prices-have-surged-by-more-than-a-third-on-trade-dislocations-and-mine-outages/</link><description>Coverage of the price surge toward $12,000/ton, emphasizing analyst warnings that structural deficits may begin in 2026 as demand from energy transition and technology accelerates while supply faces outages and trade disruptions.[6]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Inventory Update: Decrease in Ingots, Increase in Billets as of December 23</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103100302/Aluminum-Inventory-Update:-Decrease-in-Ingots-Increase-in-Billets-as-of-December-23</link><description>SMM reports aluminum inventory changes as of December 23, with decreases in ingots and increases in billets. Macro boosts failed to outweigh fundamental pressures, leading to expectations of slight price pullbacks from recent highs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is down 1.6 percent - week 52, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-down-16-percent-week-52-2025-1425864.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending December 20, 2025, was 1.725 million net tons at 76.3% capacity utilization, down 1.6% from the prior week. This represents a 3.6% increase from the same week in 2024. Year-to-date production through December 20 is up 3.4% at 87.606 million net tons.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is down 1.6 percent - week 52, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-down-16-percent-week-52-2025-1425864.htm</link><description>According to the American Iron and Steel Institute (AISI), US domestic raw steel production for the week ending December 20, 2025, was 1.725 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.3 percent. Production decreased 1.6 percent from the previous week but increased 3.6 percent compared to the same week in 2024. Year-to-date production through December 20, 2025, reached 87.606 million net tons, up 3.4 percent from the prior year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SDI predicts Q4 earnings greater than in 2024</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/sdi-steel-aluminum-production-recycling-profits-q4-2025-usa-mexico/</link><description>Steel Dynamics Inc. (SDI) reports that fourth quarter 2025 steel operations profitability is expected to be meaningfully lower than Q3 2025, impacted by planned maintenance outages that reduced flat-rolled steel production by 140,000-150,000 tons and a $70+ per ton decline in hot-rolled steel prices from July to October. However, the company notes recent improvements in flat-rolled steel prices due to declining import volumes and steady underlying demand, with order backlogs extending into Q2 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper scales new peak as zero-fee smelter processing highlights shortages</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/copper-scales-new-peak-as-zero-fee-smelter-processing-highlights-shortages/articleshow/126123369.cms</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.4% to $11,930 per metric ton in official trading, reaching a new peak supported by speculative buying and news of zero-fee smelter processing agreements that underscore global supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP eyes Canadian copper after Anglo bid</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/23/bhp-eyes-canadian-copper-after-anglo-bid/</link><description>BHP is redirecting focus to copper growth in Canada following the withdrawal of its bid for Anglo American. CEO Mike Henry highlighted copper exploration partnerships across Canada and plans for further investments in high-quality copper assets amid rising demand from electrification. BHP is already investing over $10 billion in its Jansen potash project in Saskatchewan.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Solis Minerals Strengthens Copper Path With Project Milestones</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/stocks/metal-and-mining/solis-minerals-strengthens-copper-path-with-project-milestones</link><description>Solis Minerals announced project milestones advancing its copper exploration efforts. The updates strengthen the company's position in copper development. Specific details on milestones were highlighted in the announcement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 23, SMM #1 refined nickel prices were 121,500-129,000 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103685427/</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices on December 23 ranged from 121,500-129,000 yuan/mt, with an average of 125,250 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 3,450 yuan/mt from the previous day. The price rise indicates a short-term bullish shift amid recent market volatility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] Indonesian High-Grade NPI Traded at 920 Yuan/Nickel Unit for Jan 2025 Delivery</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103685675/Indonesian-High-Grade-NPI-Traded-at-920-YuanNickel-Unit-for-Jan-2025-Delivery:-SMM</link><description>High inventory and market pessimism pushed nickel prices to new lows before a strong rebound started on Wednesday. Indonesian high-grade NPI traded at 920 yuan per nickel unit for January 2025 delivery. This reflects ongoing supply pressures balanced by recent recovery signals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel on Dec 22 hits near 2-month high on Indonesia production cut &amp; Fed expected rate drop</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-on-dec-22-hits-near-2-month-high-on-indonesia-production-cut-fed-expected-rate-drop/158448</link><description>LME nickel prices reached near 2-month highs on December 22, driven by Indonesia's announced production cuts and expectations of Federal Reserve rate drops. The price movement reflects market response to supply-side interventions aimed at supporting commodity prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer rises to $2,916/t as opening stocks hold steady at 519,600t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-rises-to-2-916-t-as-opening-stocks-hold-steady-at-519-600t-116693</link><description>LME aluminium cash and forward prices firmed on December 23, with the cash offer rising to USD 2,916/t while LME opening stocks remained unchanged at 519,600 tonnes; 3-month forward bids also increased modestly amid firming physical bids and steady warehouse inventories. The report notes parallel gains for near-dated contracts and provides regional reference prices and an assessment of alumina (Platts) as supportive context for near-term market strength.[2]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price falls to one-month low in wider commodity slump</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-falls-to-one-month-low-in-wider-commodity-slump/</link><description>Aluminum led base metals lower amid a broader commodity selloff, dropping as much as 1.6% to $2,526/t on the LME—the lowest since Nov. 14—as traders reacted to macro data and Fed-rate expectations; the piece highlights rising Chinese output and strong exports as contributors to near-term weakness while some banks remain bullish on longer-term price upside.[3]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Holds Near 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/512215</link><description>A Trading Economics news item notes aluminum futures in the UK near USD 2,950/t in December—close to the highest in over three years—driven by worries over low supply and China’s emphasis on preventing overcapacity, which is supporting prices and an 18% year-to-date gain.[4]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices remain elevated near three-year highs amid global supply tightness</title><link>https://ecopulse24.com/news/aluminum-prices-remain-elevated-near-three-year-highs-amid-global-supply-tightness</link><description>This article reports that aluminum prices are holding near three-year highs, attributing the strength to global supply tightness, tighter Chinese output controls, decreased exports, and broader production challenges that are limiting available metal and supporting prices.[7]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nucor Plate Group adds $40/ton to plate prices</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com</link><description>Nucor Plate Group has increased plate prices by $40/ton. This update appears amid latest news on steel market trends, including global steel production falling to a near two-year low in November and weekly raw steel mill output ticking lower.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China steel group urges domestic pricing in iron ore contracts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/china-steel-group-urges-domestic-pricing-in-iron-ore-contracts/</link><description>China's top steel industry group, the China Iron and Steel Association, urged the state-backed China Mineral Resources Group to use domestic price benchmarks in iron ore supply talks with major miners like BHP and Rio Tinto. A new port-side spot price index should serve as a core reference for long-term contracts to shift pricing power toward China. This reflects ongoing efforts to counter USD-dominated benchmarks amid negotiations for next year's supply deals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Clarification of holiday pricing schedule for Turkey flat steel, slab assessments</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/clarification-of-holiday-pricing-schedule-for-turkey-flat-steel-slab-assessments/</link><description>Fastmarkets clarified its holiday pricing calendar for Turkey flat steel and slab assessments, noting no publications on December 26 due to a UK public holiday, with updates resuming December 29. This affects prices like hot-rolled coil import CFR main port Turkey and related assessments. The updated calendar is available on their site.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits $12,000 a Ton. Time to Mine Freeport-McMoRan for More Profits</title><link>https://247wallst.com/investing/2025/12/23/copper-hits-12000-a-ton-time-to-mine-freeport-mcmoran-for-more-profits/</link><description>Copper prices hit an all-time high of around $12,000 per ton on the LME, fueled by Trump's tariff threats, supply constraints, and demand from EVs, renewables, and AI. Freeport-McMoRan, up 34% YTD, benefits from higher prices and strong operations at mines like Morenci and Cerro Verde. Analysts rate it a Buy with a $49.11 target.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits $12,000 a Ton. Time to Mine Freeport-McMoRan for More Profits</title><link>https://247wallst.com/investing/2025/12/23/copper-hits-12000-a-ton-time-to-mine-freeport-mcmoran-for-more-profits/</link><description>Investment-focused article highlights that copper's rally to $12,000/ton is boosting margins for major producers like Freeport-McMoRan, while noting production disruptions at Grasberg have constrained output; the piece discusses company-level production guidance and where earnings may benefit from higher prices.[4]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia may slash nickel output to steady prices</title><link>https://www.mining.com/indonesia-may-slash-nickel-output-to-steady-prices/</link><description>Indonesia, the world’s top nickel producer, is proposing a 34% reduction in nickel production to 250 million tonnes in 2026 from this year's roughly 379 million tonnes to curb oversupply and support prices. The plan, outlined in the government's 2026 Work Plan and Budget, aims to address a global surplus projected at 209 million tonnes in 2025, potentially widening to 261 million tonnes next year with Indonesia contributing 65%. Analysts note this could help nickel prices recover toward $18,000-$20,000 per tonne amid declining ore grades and imports.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>CVA and Cogne Acciai Speciali sign Energy Release contract; CVA to build four photovoltaic plants in Sicily</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>CVA Group and Cogne Acciai Speciali signed an Energy Release contract under which CVA will construct four photovoltaic plants in Sicily (total capacity &gt;20 MW) and advance electricity to CAS under Italy’s Energy Release scheme; the arrangement supports CAS’s decarbonisation and aligns with regional and EU energy goals.[1]</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Effective Tariff Rates and Revenues (Updated December 23, 2025)</title><link>https://budgetmodel.wharton.upenn.edu/issues/2025/12/23/effective-tariff-rates-and-revenues-updated-december-23-2025</link><description>Steel and aluminum products face the highest effective US tariff rates at 40%, due to Section 232 tariffs and recent increases. Average effective tariff rate rose to 10.65% in September 2025. China faces the highest partner tariffs at 37.1%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Company uses solar ovens for 100% recycled steel production</title><link>https://inspenet.com/en/noticias/100-recycled-steel-solar-oven-production/</link><description>PANATERE inaugurated two solar furnaces in La Chaux-de-Fonds, Switzerland, capable of melting 100% recycled steel using concentrated solar energy without fossil fuels. This innovation produces fully recycled stainless steel and copper with a near-zero carbon footprint, reducing emissions by a factor of 165 compared to conventional processes. The project promotes circular economy and industrial sovereignty, with potential for replication in other countries.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Dec. 24</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20251224/7655d55ac2ad4f4bbbe0ea44e8eaa12b/c.html</link><description>London Stock Exchange Group reports copper at 5.48 USD at 0200 GMT on December 24. Other metals include iron ore at 106.95 USD, palladium at 2,004.50 USD, and platinum at 2,359.20 USD. This update provides snapshot pricing for global commodities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On December 24, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103687575/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price reached 126,400–134,000 yuan/mt on December 24, with an average of 130,200 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 4,950 yuan/mt from the previous day. The rise reflects recent market momentum in nickel pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel hits near two-month high on supply Curbs, fed rate-cut hopes</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/lme-nickel-hits-near-two-month-high-on-supply-curbs-fed-rate-cut-hopes</link><description>LME nickel futures rose by US$473 per tonne to US$15,276 per tonne, while the spot price gained US$472 to US$15,087 per tonne. The rally, marking the fourth consecutive gain, is driven by supply curbs and hopes for Fed rate cuts. Prices jumped sharply on December 24.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel hits near two-month high on supply curbs, Fed rate-cut hopes</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/lme-nickel-hits-near-two-month-high-on-supply-curbs-fed-rate-cut-hopes</link><description>LME nickel futures rose sharply by US$473 per tonne to US$15,276 per tonne, with the spot price gaining US$472 to US$15,087 per tonne, marking a near two-month high. The rally is attributed to supply curbs and hopes for Fed rate cuts. Prices climbed on December 24 amid these factors influencing the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>This nickel stock leaves oversold area, reaches a new resistance</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/59860/this-nickel-stock-leaves-oversold-area-reaches-a-new-resistance</link><description>Analysts highlight positive sentiment for a nickel stock due to the Indonesian government's decision to cut the 2026 nickel production target to 250 million tonnes. The stock has exited an oversold area and is heading toward a new resistance level. This reflects market reactions to production restraint measures aimed at stabilizing prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>This nickel stock exits the oversold zone, heading toward a new resistance</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/videos/watch/2180/nickel-stock-exits-oversold-zone-heading-resistance</link><description>Ina Sekuritas analysts recommend a nickel mining and processing company, PT Merdeka Battery Materials Tbk (MBMA), following its exit from an oversold zone toward new resistance. The positive outlook stems from Indonesia's plan to reduce 2026 nickel production to 250 million tonnes. This move is expected to bolster market sentiment amid oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminium cash offer hits USD 2,932/t as LME momentum builds</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminium-cash-offer-hits-usd-2-932-t-as-lme-momentum-builds-116710</link><description>LME aluminium cash offers strengthened to USD 2,932 per tonne on December 24, up 0.54% from the prior session. The 3-month contract bid rose to USD 2,957 per tonne, with forward contracts also gaining. Alumina Platts prices edged down slightly to USD 310.22 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to 3½-Year Highs as Mozal Smelter to Be Placed Under Care and Maintenance</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Trading Economics reports aluminium futures climbed toward multi-year highs after South32 announced its Mozal smelter in Mozambique will be placed under care and maintenance by March 2026, tightening global primary aluminium supply; the report also cites a potline suspension at Iceland’s Grundartangi and falling Japanese port inventories as market-supportive. The item notes China is expected to approach its 45 million tonne annual output cap, contributing to supply concerns and higher prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 906 USD/T on December 24, 2025, down 0.22% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices rose 0.44% and are up 27.60% year-over-year. Recent news highlights HRC Steel hitting multi-week highs and lows earlier in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US steel tariffs cause scrap supply glut</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2769786-viewpoint-us-steel-tariffs-cause-scrap-supply-glut</link><description>US flat and long steel prices continued climbing in December amid tariffs causing a scrap supply glut, while Turkish rebar prices fell to $559/t ex-works. Production changes will take time, with China dampening global steel and scrap prices into 2026. US exporters may prefer domestic sales in Q1 due to price divergence.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper's Red Metal Revolution: Prices Target $12,000 Milestone Amid Supply Shocks and AI Demand</title><link>http://business.times-online.com/times-online/article/marketminute-2025-12-24-coppers-red-metal-revolution-prices-target-12000-milestone-amid-supply-shocks-and-ai-demand</link><description>Copper prices are surging toward $12,000 per metric ton due to supply shocks and surging demand from AI data centers, which require about 27 tons per megawatt. This rally is driven by the green transition and digital revolutions, with limited substitution options for high-performance uses. Mining firms are investing in recycling technologies, though secondary supply remains insufficient for projected demand growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Great Metal Super-Surge of 2025: Gold, Silver, and Copper Hit Historic Peaks as Economic Clouds Gather</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-12-24-the-great-metal-super-surge-of-2025-gold-silver-and-copper-hit-historic-peaks-as-economic-clouds-gather</link><description>Copper reached a historic $12,200 per metric ton in December 2025 amid supply disruptions at major mines and booming demand from AI data centers and grid upgrades. Mining giants like BHP and Rio Tinto are capitalizing with record production and strategic acquisitions to secure energy transition supply. The surge underscores copper's critical role in AI infrastructure and global electrification efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Xiarihamu Nickel-Cobalt Mine officially included in Provincial Green Mining List</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5108121-flash-xiarihamu-nickel-cobalt-mine-officially-included-in-provincial-green-mining-list</link><description>Qinghai Province added the Xiarihamu Nickel-Cobalt Mine to its 2025 Provincial Green Mining List, recognizing Qinghai Jinchuan Mining's efforts in ecological protection despite challenges like high altitude and arid conditions. The company has implemented vegetation restoration, windbreak measures, and technological innovations for efficient resource use and emission reductions. This supports both mining operations and environmental goals in the region.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Reach Record $12,000 a Metric Ton as Market Navigates Supply Constraints and Growing Demand Outlook</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-prices-reach-record-12-000-metric-ton-market-navigates-supply-constraints-growing-demand-outlook-2512/</link><description>Copper prices hit a record $12,000 per metric ton amid global supply tightness driven by U.S.-bound copper redirection, mine outages, and zero-fee smelter processing agreements that have forced some smelters to cut operations. Citigroup and Goldman Sachs project bullish copper markets for 2026, citing strong demand from energy transition and AI infrastructure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Structural Supercycle: Why $12,000 Is Just the Beginning</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-structural-supercycle-12-000-beginning-2512/</link><description>Opinion/analysis piece arguing geopolitical shocks, tariffs and accelerating demand tied to electrification and AI are creating a long-term 'supercycle' for copper, citing forecasts of a 2026 refined-copper deficit and multi-year price appreciation scenarios from major banks.[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Domestic and international liquidity easing supports aluminum prices hovering at highs [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103688975/Domestic-and-international-liquidity-easing-supports-aluminum-prices-hovering-at-highs-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME aluminum closed at $2,956.5/mt on December 24 after hitting a high of $2,969.5/mt, supported by liquidity easing. SHFE aluminum futures fell 0.83% to 22,145 yuan/mt, while spot A00 aluminum surged to 22,030 yuan/mt. Secondary aluminum prices like ADC12 rose, with import windows reopening due to stronger domestic prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 25.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel exchanges, including Shanghai Futures Rebar prices as of December 24, 2025. Various futures terms for rebar and other steel products show flat performance at 0.00 change. Coverage includes indices, prices, and news for major markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's 304 stainless steel export offers rise sharply on Tsingshan price hike</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5108057-indonesias-304-stainless-steel-export-offers-rise-sharply-on-tsingshan-price-hike</link><description>Indonesia's 304 stainless steel export prices rose sharply for the third week in December due to Tsingshan's price hike. Related updates include stainless HRC and round bar prices in China on December 25. Nickel and chrome ore markets also show activity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper hits record high as robust US GDP data boosts demand prospects</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-record-high-as-robust-us-gdp-data-boosts-demand-prospects/</link><description>Copper prices extended gains to hit all-time highs, supported by robust U.S. GDP data enhancing demand prospects. The rally reflects ongoing market strength amid broader commodity trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Weekly Market Recap (December 25) –Copper 2025</title><link>https://nai500.com/blog/2025/12/weekly-market-recap-december-25-copper-2025-shocks-mergers-and-megatrends/</link><description>Copper prices surged to unprecedented highs this week, concluding a year of supply shocks and trade realignments. The recap highlights key market shocks, mergers, and megatrends impacting copper in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690218/</link><description>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 123,400–131,400 yuan/mt, with an average price of 127,400 yuan/mt. This represents a decline of 2,800 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices experienced a significant correction on December 25...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690257/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-correction-on-December-25-while-the-central-bank-conducted-a-400-billion-yuan-MLF-operation</link><description>Nickel prices underwent a significant correction on December 25 amid a 400-billion-yuan MLF operation by the central bank. The SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 127,400 yuan/mt, down 2,800 yuan/mt from the prior session.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690218/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on December 25 averaged 127,400 yuan/mt, ranging from 123,400–131,400 yuan/mt, down 2,800 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects ongoing price pressures in the refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Why copper is set to play a big role in BHP's future</title><link>https://aheadoftheherd.com/why-copper-is-set-to-play-a-big-role-in-bhps-future/</link><description>BHP is positioning copper centrally in its strategy amid global critical minerals discussions, including meetings with US leadership on AI supply chains. The company's history of innovation supports its leadership in copper production for electrification and digital technologies. This focus highlights copper's growing importance in sustainable mining and technology advancements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel traded flat at 15,660 USD/T on December 25, 2025. Over the past month, nickel's price has risen 5.49%, and it is up 1.26% compared to the same time last year. This reflects trading on a contract for difference tracking the benchmark market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Talon buys nation's only nickel mine to create Midwest 'powerhouse'</title><link>https://www.eenews.net/articles/talon-buys-nations-only-nickel-mine-to-create-midwest-powerhouse/</link><description>Talon Metals announced the purchase of the Eagle nickel mine in Michigan's Upper Peninsula from Lundin Mining, along with a nearby mill, to expand production of nickel and copper for stainless steel and EV batteries. The deal positions Talon to develop a critical minerals hub in the Midwest amid rising demand. Lundin will hold nearly 20% stake in Talon as part of the agreement.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium opens the week with a fall of $13.5/t; December 26 bid price adds $5/t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-opens-the-week-with-a-fall-of-13-5-t-december-26-bid-price-adds-5-t-115507</link><description>LME aluminium cash bid and official settlement prices fell by USD 13-13.5 per tonne to around USD 2,693 per tonne. The December 26 bid and offer prices rose by USD 5 per tonne to USD 2,728-2,733 per tonne, while the 3-month Asian Reference Price increased by USD 11 to USD 2,700.5 per tonne. Alumina Platts price declined by USD 5.45 per tonne to USD 333.35 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SINBON Brings Enhanced EV Connection Solutions to Automotive World Tokyo 2026</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/26/sinbon-brings-enhanced-ev-connection-solutions-to-automotive-world-tokyo-2026/</link><description>SINBON Electronics is showcasing an expanded portfolio of EV connection technologies, including charging cables and inlets with aluminum busbars and rods, at Automotive World Tokyo 2026. The solutions support diverse standards and emphasize sustainable innovation in mobility. SINBON's commitment to ESG drives carbon management and green solutions across global manufacturing sites.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SINBON Brings Enhanced EV Connection Solutions to Automotive World Tokyo 2026</title><link>https://macaubusiness.com/sinbon-brings-enhanced-ev-connection-solutions-to-automotive-world-tokyo-2026/</link><description>SINBON Electronics announces its return to Automotive World Tokyo 2026 with enhanced EV connection solutions featuring aluminum designs for charging inlets and cables. The portfolio addresses regional standards and supports sustainable automotive advancements. The company focuses on full-process engineering and global support for cleaner mobility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3066 CNY/T on December 26, 2025, marking a 0.07% decline from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have dropped 0.87%, and are down 6.21% from the same period last year. On December 25, prices were at 3,084 CNY/T, down 0.03%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Surtaxes, Tariff Rate Quotas and Steel Derivatives – Is this for real??</title><link>https://sourcealliance.net/surtaxes-tariff-rate-quotas-and-steel-derivatives-is-this-for-real/</link><description>Effective December 26, 2025, Canada imposes 25% tariffs on steel derivative products from all countries. These measures target US, Chinese, and non-US imports containing Chinese steel or aluminum. This escalates protectionism in response to international trade tensions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China pledges to control steel output during 2026-2030 period</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/commodities-news/china-pledges-to-control-steel-output-during-20262030-period-4422922</link><description>China announced it will regulate crude steel output and prohibit illegal new capacity from 2026 to 2030 to address overcapacity and support supply-side reforms. In the first 11 months of 2025, crude steel output fell 4% year-on-year, on track to drop below 1 billion tons for the first time in six years amid a property downturn. The plan coincides with robust steel exports facing global protectionism, prompting a new export licensing system for 300 steel-related items.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel demand seen buoyed by autos, appliances in '26</title><link>https://www.chinadaily.com.cn/a/202512/26/WS694deb74a310d6866eb30963.html</link><description>China's steel consumption is projected at 808 million tons in 2025 and 800 million tons in 2026, with growth in automotive, shipbuilding, and appliance sectors despite overall decline. The report emphasizes steel enterprises advancing intelligent, green, and integrated development through industrial ecosystems. ESG ratings for 108 companies show improving disclosure and performance, calling for stronger industry-wide coordination.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Dec. 26</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20251226/14571663689a47869f9d42b3a7a3be3b/c.html</link><description>London Stock Exchange Group reported copper prices at 5.65 USD at 0200 GMT on December 26. This update provides the latest snapshot of global metals prices, including gold, iron ore, palladium, and platinum. The data reflects ongoing market movements in commodities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Oil Prices Dip, LME Copper Extends Record Rally, Gold Slightly Lower</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/m/page/commodity-news-detail/commodity-news-detail-29163.html</link><description>LME copper futures gained 0.9% to settle at $12,162.50 per tonne, extending its record rally. LME aluminum futures also rose 0.7% to $2,960.50 per tonne. The gains occur amid broader commodity market movements, with oil prices dipping and gold slightly lower.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>On December 26, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel was</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103692395/</link><description>On December 26, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel ranged from 125,700–133,700 yuan/mt, with an average of 129,700 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 2,300 yuan/mt from the previous day. The update highlights short-term price gains in the refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>