<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:16:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Germany's SPD Proposes Strategic Measures to Strengthen Europe's Steel Industry</title><link>https://millichronicle.com/2025/10/56782.html</link><description>Germany's Social Democrats (SPD) are advancing proposals to support sustainable growth and fair competition in Europe's steel sector. The plan includes a tariff-quota system to manage imports, promote a 'buy European' approach, and enhance oversight of steel imports to protect domestic production and jobs while fostering innovation in clean steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Trump Tariffs on China Cause Seismic Shift in Copper Markets</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/trump-tariffs-china-impact-copper-2025/</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange fell 4.9%, marking the largest single-day decline in five months, amid tariff threats against China. The market is already constrained by supply issues due to ESG barriers and major mine transitions, and new trade barriers risk disrupting the complex global copper supply chain, potentially delaying projects and causing inventory buildups.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices, Charts, Analysis &amp; Forecast</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper spot prices on major exchanges including SHFE, LME, and COMEX showed a price range around $10,700 per metric ton on October 10, 2025, with premiums and discounts fluctuating slightly. The market reflects ongoing adjustments amid supply constraints and tariff-related uncertainties.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price tumbles as Trump threatens massive new tariffs on China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-tumbles-as-trump-threatens-massive-new-tariffs-on-china/</link><description>Copper prices dropped significantly after President Donald Trump threatened to impose new tariffs on Chinese goods. This move reversed recent gains fueled by production setbacks at major copper mines. The tariffs could impact global copper demand and supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Gold Mine: 7 Innovations In Copper Mining 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-gold-mine-7-innovations-in-copper-mining-2025</link><description>This article explores how copper mining innovations in 2025 are driving sustainable infrastructure and green technologies. It highlights advanced ore beneficiation, AI-driven digital monitoring, and sustainability frameworks that are revolutionizing copper mining to support renewable energy systems, electric vehicles, and telecommunications.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Lithium &amp; Copper Mining Companies: 2025 Outlook</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/chinese-lithium-copper-mining-companies-2025-outlook</link><description>Chinese copper mining companies are leading in both production and technological innovation, with output expected to reach nearly 10 million metric tons in 2025. The sector focuses on resource efficiency, digital twin modeling, hydro-metallurgical extraction, and strict environmental mandates, while expanding overseas assets in Africa, South America, and Central Asia to secure supply and support sustainable mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Future of copper mining: global demand, strategic alliances</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/future-of-copper-mining-addressing-global-demand-with-strategic-alliances-and-sustainable-innovations-andrea-hotter/</link><description>The article discusses innovations in copper mining such as Anglo American's hydraulic dry stacking technology to address tailings capacity challenges, aiming for more sustainable production. It also covers ongoing environmental compliance efforts near the Chagres copper smelter and the potential for scaling new technologies industry-wide to meet global demand sustainably.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Resources at the Forefront of North America's Critical Minerals Security Push</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-10-teck-resources-at-the-forefront-of-north-americas-critical-minerals-security-push</link><description>Teck Resources, in a proposed merger with Anglo American, is central to North America's strategy to secure critical minerals like copper for clean energy and advanced technologies. The merger aims to create a resilient supply chain with sustainable mining practices, though challenges remain in investment, regulation, and workforce development to ensure long-term self-sufficiency and ESG compliance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices fluctuate amid inventory buildup and policy disruptions</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Nickel</link><description>Nickel prices showed significant volatility this week, initially rising due to disruptions in Indonesian mining policies but later pulling back. The SHFE nickel contract closed at 122,180 yuan/mt, up 0.49% from pre-National Day levels, while LME nickel prices fell to $15,320/mt, down 0.68% week-over-week. Domestic inventory also saw a substantial buildup during this period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to $15,215 USD/T on October 10, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped 1.74% from the previous day to $15,215 USD/T. Over the past month, prices remained nearly flat with a slight 0.03% decline and are down 14.99% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect nickel to trade around $15,184.79 USD/T by the end of the current quarter.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel 28 Confirms US$1.4M Cash Distribution from Ramu JV</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CONXF/nickel-28-announces-confirmation-of-cash-distribution-from-ramu-bnjb88y6mg2h.html</link><description>Nickel 28 Capital Corp. announced a cash distribution of approximately US$1.4 million from its Ramu joint venture for H1 2025, alongside a US$2.5 million partner debt repayment. The first half of 2025 was impacted by reduced production due to mechanical failures, but full production is expected in the second half, potentially improving future results.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel 28 Confirms US$1.4M Cash Distribution from Ramu JV</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CONXF/nickel-28-announces-confirmation-of-cash-distribution-from-ramu-bnjb88y6mg2h.html</link><description>Nickel 28 Capital Corp. announced a cash distribution of approximately US$1.4 million from its Ramu joint venture for the first half of 2025. The distribution was impacted by reduced production due to mechanical issues, but full production is expected in the second half of the year. Projects within Nickel 28's royalty portfolio are progressing positively.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia Targets 71,234 Tons of Nickel Production in 2025</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/vale-indonesia-inco-targets-71234-tons-of-nickel-production-in-2025</link><description>Vale Indonesia aims to produce 71,234 tons of nickel-in-matte in 2025, exceeding its 2024 target. This increase is part of the broader production trends in Indonesia.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : marks 25 years of seamless pipe production in Canada and commitment to its long-term industrial growth</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-marks-25-years-of-seamless-pipe-production-in-canada-and-commitment-to-its-long-term-i-ce7d5adbdb8ff725</link><description>Tenaris celebrated 25 years of seamless pipe production at its Canadian facility in Sault Ste. Marie, highlighting its role in supporting the domestic energy industry with high-quality steel pipes. The company also noted recent upgrades including electric resistance welded pipe manufacturing, reinforcing its unique capabilities in Canada.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel fell to 3,086 CNY/T on October 10, 2025, down 0.29% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices decreased slightly by 0.29% to 3,086 CNY/T on October 10, 2025. Despite a 2.12% rise over the past month, steel prices remain 8.70% lower than a year ago. Analysts expect steel to trade at 3,047.39 Yuan/MT by the end of this quarter and forecast a decline to 2,917.81 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel rose to 814 USD/T on October 10, 2025, up 0.12% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices increased by 0.12% to 814 USD/T on October 10, 2025. Over the past month, HRC steel prices rose 0.49% and are up 15.46% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts indicate prices may reach 822.71 USD/T by the end of this quarter and 883.35 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global steel forum sets 2026 framework deadline as US ups pressure on excess capacity</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/10/global-steel-forum-sets-2026-framework-deadline-as-us-ups-pressure-on-excess-capacity/</link><description>The global steel forum has set a deadline for a 2026 framework aimed at addressing excess steel production capacity worldwide. The US is increasing pressure on other countries to manage steel capacity to stabilize the market and reduce trade tensions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HVAC equipment shipments down through August amid China's booming steel exports</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/10/hvac-equipment-shipments-down-through-august/</link><description>Despite rising global protectionist measures, China's direct steel exports continue to grow strongly this year, impacting related markets such as HVAC equipment shipments, which have declined through August. The steel export boom is reshaping global steel trade flows and capacity utilization.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Falls to $15,215/T, Down 1.74% on the Day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped to $15,215 per tonne on October 10, 2025, marking a 1.74% decline from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have fallen 0.03%, and are down nearly 15% compared to the same period last year, reflecting ongoing market weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Fluctuate Significantly Amid Inventory Buildup</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103563065/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-fluctuated-significantly-this-week-while-domestic-inventory-saw-a-substantial-buildup</link><description>Nickel prices experienced notable volatility this week, initially rising due to Indonesian policy disruptions but then retreating as bullish sentiment faded. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 122,180 yuan/mt, up slightly from pre-holiday levels, while LME nickel was quoted at $15,320/mt, down 0.68% week-over-week.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium hits USD 2,799.5/t — steady gains or early signs of surge</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-hits-usd-2-799-5-t-steady-gains-or-early-signs-of-surge-115802</link><description>On October 10, the London Metal Exchange aluminum price rose to USD 2,799.5 per tonne, reflecting subtle market optimism amid shifting global conditions. The 3-month bid and offer prices also increased, while inventory levels showed slight changes. The alumina price remained steady at USD 323 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Asian Battery Metals advances high-grade copper-nickel discovery in Mongolia</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/10/asian-battery-metals-advances-high-grade-copper-nickel-discovery-in-mongolia/</link><description>Asian Battery Metals reported high-grade copper-nickel sulphide intercepts in Mongolia, with grades up to 6% copper and 3% nickel. The company is advancing exploration with promising metallurgy results and aims to establish a district-scale resource, positioning Mongolia as an emerging critical minerals hub near China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion in Italy focusing on the strategic role of nuclear energy in Europe's energy transition and Italy's boilermaking industry future. The event highlighted advances in nuclear technologies and Tenaris's recent accreditation to supply certified materials for nuclear facilities according to the ASME III standard, reflecting its commitment to quality and safety in the nuclear sector.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris in Italy achieves ASME certification for the supply of materials for the nuclear sector</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-in-italy-achieves-asme-certification-for-the-supply-of-materials-for-the-nuclear-sector</link><description>Tenaris's seamless steel pipe mill in Dalmine, Italy, obtained ASME III certification, qualifying it to supply certified materials for nuclear facilities. This accreditation supports Tenaris's participation in the low-carbon energy market by meeting stringent international standards essential for nuclear plant construction and maintenance.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest Tariff Developments</title><link>https://www.rvia.org/news-insights/latest-tariff-developments</link><description>Recent tariff updates include the imposition of Section 232 tariffs on various imports, with reciprocal tariffs on lauan plywood starting October 14, 2025. Additionally, new inclusion requests for steel and aluminum derivative products under Section 232 tariffs were published, with import taxes of 50% imposed on Brazil, affecting aluminum trade dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China Steel Prices Poised for Rebound in October</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/analysis/5100433-mysteel-china-steel-prices-poised-for-rebound-in-october</link><description>After declining over the past two months, Chinese steel prices are expected to rise in October due to improved market fundamentals. The article suggests that this rebound could stabilize the market, but details are available only with a subscription.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Eyeing China, EU unveils sweeping measures to shield struggling steel industry</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/aseanplus/aseanplus-news/2025/10/11/eyeing-china-eu-unveils-sweeping-measures-to-shield-struggling-steel-industry</link><description>The EU has introduced measures to protect its steel industry from global overcapacity, particularly focusing on steel of Chinese origin. Proposals include a 'melt and pour requirement' to prevent circumvention via other countries and ongoing investigations into China's trade practices. EU leaders emphasize the need for balanced trade and long-term solutions to overcapacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper fell to 4.80 USD/Lbs on October 10, 2025, down 6.16% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices dropped 6.16% to $4.80 per pound on October 10, 2025, despite a 4.07% rise over the past month and a 7.81% increase year-over-year. Analysts expect copper to trade at $5.18 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.66 in 12 months, reflecting ongoing market volatility and supply-demand dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Resources lowers copper production guidance for 2025</title><link>https://www.townandcountrytoday.com/national-business/teck-resources-lowers-copper-production-guidance-for-2025-11320351</link><description>Teck Resources has reduced its copper production forecast for 2025 due to operational challenges at key mining assets. The company now expects to produce between 415,000 and 465,000 tonnes of copper. Strong copper prices are partially offsetting the financial impact of reduced production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 10-week High at $15,551 USD/T</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/491774</link><description>Nickel prices increased to $15,551 USD/T, marking the highest level since July 2025. Over the past four weeks, nickel gained 2.42%, although it remains down 11.47% over the last 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Matte Production Down 0.05% MoM in Sep</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5100658-indonesia-nickel-matte-production-down-005-mom-in-sep</link><description>Indonesia's nickel matte production decreased by 0.05% month-over-month in September, totaling 28,800 tonnes in Ni content. This slight decrease reflects ongoing supply dynamics in the region.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Enters New Period in Steel Production with Green Hydrogen Facility</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/haber/cogne-located-in-aosta-has-entered-a-new-period-in-steel-production-with-a-green-hydrogen-facility/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is advancing sustainable steel production by integrating green hydrogen into its processes. The company aims to reduce carbon emissions by using green hydrogen, produced from renewable sources, in its industrial heat treatment processes. This innovation also positions Cogne as a material partner in the hydrogen value chain.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian was awarded the tender by Terna and STEG for the submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia under the Elmed Project. The contract could reach a value of around €460 million and involves laying cables at depths up to 800 meters, enhancing energy security between Europe and Africa.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy awards Prysmian $539mn contract for Tunisia-Europe power cable</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/italy-awards-prysmian-539mn-contract-for-tunisia-europe-power-cable/</link><description>Prysmian Group won a contract worth up to €460 million ($539 million) to build a submarine power cable linking Italy to Tunisia. This project is part of efforts to enhance power interconnections between Europe and Africa, supporting energy transition goals.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Al Arabia Co. for Aluminum targets over 10,000 tonnes in annual exports</title><link>https://www.dailynewsegypt.com/2025/10/11/al-arabia-co-for-aluminum-targets-over-10000-tonnes-in-annual-exports/</link><description>Al Arabia Co. for Aluminum aims to exceed 10,000 tonnes in annual aluminum exports, having recently increased exports by 75% in the last quarter to markets including Morocco, Tunisia, Libya, Lebanon, and Canada. The company is also enhancing operational efficiency through a new aluminum recycling plant and relocation of administrative offices, supporting Egypt's industrial and export development goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weekend Drive: Aluminum plant fire exposes supply chain fragility</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6BFLeLGpBAQ</link><description>A recent aluminum plant fire has caused significant disruptions for automakers like Ford, highlighting the fragility and interdependency of supply chains in the automotive industry. The discussion emphasizes how such incidents can lead to production slowdowns and layoffs, underscoring the critical role of domestic aluminum producers amid ongoing steel and aluminum tariffs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weak steel market threatens Chinese met coke prices in October</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/analysis/5100496-monthly-weak-steel-market-threatens-chinese-met-coke-prices-in-october</link><description>After a brief recovery early in October, Chinese metallurgical coke prices are expected to weaken in the second half of the month due to a weak steel market. Daily reports indicate cautious sentiment and stable prices during the holiday period, with some northern Chinese mills accepting price hikes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper falls on profit-taking</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40386931</link><description>Copper prices declined as investors booked profits following a rally that pushed prices to a 16-month high in the previous session. This profit-taking reflects short-term market corrections after recent strong price performance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Resources Lowers Copper Production Guidance for 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/teck-resources-copper-production-challenges-2025-2/</link><description>Teck Resources has revised its copper production guidance downward for 2025 by 55,000-60,000 metric tons due to operational challenges at the Quebrada Blanca and Highland Valley Copper mines. Despite these setbacks, the company expects to overcome geological issues by early 2026 and benefits from strong copper market prices averaging $4.44/lb in Q3 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Lowers Copper Production Forecast Amid Mine Challenges</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/teck-resources-copper-production-2025-challenges/</link><description>Teck Resources lowered its copper production guidance for 2025 due to operational difficulties at key mines, including unplanned maintenance and geological constraints. However, strong copper prices and tight global supply-demand dynamics are partially offsetting the financial impact of reduced output, with market fundamentals remaining favorable.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Italian steel factory invests USD 14 mln in training center in Romania</title><link>https://www.romania-insider.com/italian-steel-factory-invests-usd-14-mln-in-training-center-in-romania</link><description>Italian steel manufacturer Tenaris invested USD 14 million in a training center for its 1,700 employees in Zalau, Romania. This investment aims to enhance workforce skills and support the company's operations in the region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>North American Green Aluminium Summit 2025</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/events/north-american-green-aluminium-summit-2025/</link><description>The North American Green Aluminium Summit 2025 will explore aluminium's role in carbon reduction and discuss pathways to decarbonization, recycling technologies, and strategies for achieving net-zero emissions in the industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum's Sustainability Blueprint</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/century-aluminums-sustainability-blueprint-for-a-carbon-free-tomorrow-115782</link><description>Century Aluminium is advancing sustainability through low-carbon aluminium production, ASI certifications, carbon capture, and waste management. The company aims to improve efficiency and unlock a more sustainable future for the industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Shortens Mining Production Quotas to Annual Review</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/indonesia-mining-quota-reform-impact-production-prices-2025/</link><description>Indonesia has implemented an annual review system for mining production quotas to better control output and stabilize commodity prices. This change allows the government to adjust production levels annually based on market conditions and environmental considerations. Companies must now demonstrate environmental compliance to secure quotas.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>UN Calls for Transition Metals Mining Finance Reform</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/news/un-calls-for-transition-metals-mining-finance-reform-to-protect-environment-and-human-rights/</link><description>The United Nations has called for reform in financing the extraction of critical minerals like nickel to ensure sustainable development and respect for human rights and the environment. This comes as demand for clean energy technologies surges. The reform aims to make responsible mining practices the norm.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali signs Memorandum of Understanding with CVA for photovoltaic plants in Sicily</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will benefit from enhanced energy performance and reduced environmental impact through the construction of four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily with a total capacity of over 20 MW. This agreement with CVA supports the company's decarbonisation goals and economic competitiveness as part of its 2026–2029 Strategic Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://www.pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems for district heating and anti-corrosion coatings in Europe. The acquired business unit has been rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy, enhancing Tenaris's offshore market offerings and enabling anti-corrosion coating application at its facilities in Italy and other countries.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>The Cost Side Suppressed the Upward Space of Aluminum Prices, and Aluminum Prices May Stabilize First and Then Strengthen in October</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-27054.html</link><description>Aluminum prices initially strengthened and then weakened in September, with the average price of aluminum ingots in East China rising slightly. Prices fell primarily due to weakening costs but are expected to stabilize and then strengthen in October as destocking accelerates and costs rise.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium hits USD 2,799.5/t — steady gains or early signs of surge?</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-hits-usd-2-799-5-t-steady-gains-or-early-signs-of-surge-115802</link><description>LME aluminium cash offer climbed to USD 2,799.5 per tonne with 3-month prices firming, reflecting subtle market optimism amid shifting global conditions. The steady gains indicate positive sentiment in the aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel prices fall slightly but expected to rise by year-end</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,086 CNY/T on October 10, 2025, down 0.29% from the previous day. Despite this short-term dip, steel prices have risen 2.12% over the past month but remain 8.70% lower than a year ago. Analysts expect steel to trade at 3,047.39 Yuan/MT by the end of this quarter and forecast a price of 2,917.81 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel prices show modest gains with positive outlook</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) Steel prices rose to 814 USD/T on October 10, 2025, up 0.12% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices increased by 0.49% and are up 15.46% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts predict HRC Steel to reach 831.44 USD/T by the end of this quarter and 894.34 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel delivers solid returns amid steady market conditions</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/stock-liveblog/jsw-steel-share-price-live-13-oct-2025/liveblog/124515822.cms</link><description>JSW Steel has delivered a 12.59% return over the last three months, reflecting strong quarterly performance and positive investor sentiment despite recent market fluctuations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel shows solid 3-month returns in a stable market</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/stock-liveblog/tata-steel-stock-price-live-updates-13-oct-2025/liveblog/124515756.cms</link><description>Tata Steel has achieved an 8.77% return over the last three months, indicating steady performance in the steel sector amid current market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU Announces Higher Tariffs on Steel Imports, Raising Concerns for Scunthorpe and Humber Region Industries</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/eu-announces-higher-tariffs-steel-imports-raising-concerns-scunthorpe-humber-region-industries-2510/</link><description>The European Union has announced increased import tariffs on steel products to protect domestic producers, impacting UK industries in the Scunthorpe and Humber region. The tariffs target flat and long steel, raising costs for British Steel and risking job losses in key manufacturing hubs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Stegra in new financing round</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/stegra-in-new-financing-round-302581648.html</link><description>Stegra is in a new financing round to fund the construction of the world's first large-scale green-steel plant in Boden, Sweden. The funding will cover additional infrastructure scope, higher project costs, and provide a financial buffer, supporting Stegra's competitive position in the green steel market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World Steel Association August 2025 Production Report</title><link>https://worldsteel.org</link><description>World crude steel production for 70 countries was 145.3 million tonnes in August 2025, a 0.3% increase compared to August 2024. The steel industry continues to focus on sustainability, environmental performance, and supporting the Paris Agreement goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hanwha Ocean, POSCO develop special steel for next-gen naval vessels</title><link>https://cyprusshippingnews.com/2025/10/13/hanwha-ocean-posco-develop-special-steel-for-next-gen-naval-vessels-2/</link><description>Hanwha Ocean and POSCO have developed a special steel designed for next-generation naval vessels, highlighting advancements in steel technology for defense applications.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ACME Group to invest Rs 5,000-cr in green DRI facility for low-carbon steel production</title><link>https://www.projectstoday.com/News/ACME-Group-to-invest-Rs-5000-cr-in-green-DRI-facility-for-low-carbon-steel-production</link><description>ACME Group plans to invest Rs 5,000 crore in a greenfield direct reduced iron (DRI) facility aimed at producing low-carbon steel products, supporting sustainable steel production initiatives.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Accelerating Innovation Through Collaboration: Sustainable Future For Australia's Resources Sector</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/accelerating-innovation-through-collaboration-1549882/</link><description>The article highlights how collaboration between research, government, and industry in Australia is accelerating the development of green steel technologies. The initiative focuses on de-risking new technologies, promoting faster adoption of green processing, and building a skilled workforce to support a sustainable, competitive green metals sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Carbon Neutral Vision 2050 | Environmental activities - Nippon Steel</title><link>https://www.nipponsteel.com/en/csr/env/warming/zerocarbon.html</link><description>Nippon Steel aims to reduce CO2 emissions by 30% by 2030 and achieve carbon neutrality by 2050 through breakthrough technologies such as blast furnace hydrogen reduction and hydrogen-based reduced iron production. The company plans significant R&amp;D and capital investment to realize carbon-neutral steelmaking processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>I-Pulse Welcomes Codelco as Strategic Investor</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251012216264/en/I-Pulse-Welcomes-Codelco-as-Strategic-Investor</link><description>Codelco joined I-Pulse as a strategic investor to support innovative mining technology that can reduce energy consumption in copper extraction by up to 80%. This partnership aims to improve copper production efficiency and meet growing demand driven by energy transition and technology infrastructure needs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices fell sharply on October 13 as Trump claimed to impose a 100% tariff on all Chinese goods</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103565190/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fell-sharply-on-October-13-as-Trump-claimed-to-impose-a-100-tariff-on-all-Chinese-goods</link><description>On October 13, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel dropped by 1,400 yuan/mt to an average of 122,450 yuan/mt amid geopolitical tensions triggered by tariff announcements. This sharp decline reflects market sensitivity to trade policy developments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On October 13, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 121,000–123,900 yuan/mt, with an average price of 122,450 yuan/mt, down 1,400 yuan/mt from the previous day</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103565195/</link><description>The refined nickel price on October 13 averaged 122,450 yuan/mt, marking a decrease of 1,400 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. This price movement aligns with broader market reactions to trade and economic factors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Fire at Indonesia Nickel Hub Raises Safety Concerns</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/indonesia-nickel-hub-fire-2025-safety-concerns/</link><description>A fire occurred at Indonesia's largest nickel processing facility, the Morowali Industrial Park, causing minor injuries and affecting a scrubber tower under construction. While the incident had minimal immediate impact on production, it raises concerns about safety and potential regulatory impacts on Indonesia's nickel supply chain, which could influence global nickel markets.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Persistent Supply Disruptions Sustain Upward Pressure on LME Nickel Prices</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-27046.html</link><description>Ongoing supply disruptions in the nickel market continue to exert upward pressure on London Metal Exchange (LME) nickel prices. These disruptions contribute to market volatility and reflect tight supply conditions in the global nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia emerging as strategic hub in critical minerals supply chain</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/icc-indonesia-emerging-as-strategic-hub-in-critical-minerals-supply-chain</link><description>Indonesia is increasingly recognized as a strategic hub in the global critical minerals supply chain, particularly for nickel. The country's role is expanding due to its large reserves and government policies supporting the sector, which impacts global nickel production capacity and supply security.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises Toward 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,769.80 per tonne on October 13, 2025, up 0.74% from the previous day, marking a 2.44% increase over the past month and a 6.61% rise year-on-year. The price increase is driven by expectations of lower supply, with Chinese authorities cutting their annual output growth targets for base metals, tightening the market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Soars to 52-Week High Amidst Robust Market and Strategic Expansion</title><link>http://business.times-online.com/times-online/article/marketminute-2025-10-13-century-aluminum-soars-to-52-week-high-amidst-robust-market-and-strategic-expansion</link><description>Century Aluminum's stock hit a 52-week high driven by rising aluminum prices and constrained global supply. The company’s strategic expansion and focus on sustainability, including renewable energy use, have bolstered investor confidence amid tight global aluminum markets and ongoing trade policy challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alumobility to Present Lightweighting Study at EuroCarBody 2025</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/alumobility-to-present-lightweighting-study-at-eurocarbody-2025-302581652.html</link><description>Alumobility will present a study at the EuroCarBody 2025 conference showing that converting key vehicle systems from steel to aluminum can reduce the weight of a crossover BEV by 20% without increasing cost or manufacturing complexity. The study highlights aluminum's role in sustainable automotive design and lightweighting, supporting more efficient and cost-effective vehicle architectures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Green Steel Markets Near EU Emissions Policies Emerge</title><link>https://bioengineer.org/green-steel-markets-near-eu-emissions-policies-emerge/</link><description>Emerging green steel markets are being shaped by EU emissions policies, including the Emissions Trading System and Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism. Increased consumer and corporate demand for low-carbon steel is driving supply chain changes, with sustainability becoming a key competitive factor in the industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU seeks US trade concessions by doubling steel tariffs</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/eu-seeks-us-trade-concessions-by-doubling-steel-tariffs/</link><description>The EU Commission announced it will double tariffs on steel imports above a tariff-free quota to 50%, aiming to secure trade concessions from the US. This move reflects ongoing trade tensions and could impact global steel trade flows.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Daily Social Inventory of Secondary Aluminum Ingots Drops by 31 mt on Oct 14</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103566577/SMM-Flash-News:-Daily-Social-Inventory-of-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingots-Drops-by-31-mt-on-Oct-14</link><description>Secondary aluminum markets mostly lowered prices by 100 yuan/mt on October 14, 2025, although some enterprises remain optimistic about future price trends. This indicates a short-term price adjustment in the secondary aluminum ingot market amid ongoing market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Ripple Effects of Steel and Aluminum Tariffs on HVAC</title><link>https://www.achrnews.com/articles/164158-the-ripple-effects-of-steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-on-hvac</link><description>The article discusses the economic impact of re-imposing 25% tariffs on steel and aluminum imports, highlighting concerns from the Coalition of American Metal Manufacturers and Users (CAMMU) about harm to U.S. manufacturers. It includes insights from Stan Kolbe of the Sheet Metal and Air Conditioning Contractors' National Association on how tariffs affect the HVAC industry and broader economic challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>National Security Investigation: Section 232 Opportunities for U.S. Factories</title><link>https://www.bipc.com/national-security-investigation-section-232-opportunities-for-u.s.-factories</link><description>The U.S. Department of Commerce’s Bureau of Industry and Security has opened inclusion windows for Section 232 tariffs affecting steel and aluminum products. This process offers U.S. factories opportunities to request product inclusions to benefit from tariffs designed to protect domestic manufacturers, particularly in the automotive sector, with specific guidance on tariff stacking.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Latest Tariff Developments - RVIA</title><link>https://www.rvia.org/news-insights/latest-tariff-developments</link><description>The article provides updates on ongoing tariff developments, including the continuation of Section 232 tariffs on steel and aluminum products. It notes recent inclusion requests for additional steel and aluminum derivative products to be subject to these tariffs, with rates set at 50% on the metal portion, reflecting ongoing trade policy enforcement.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>【SMM Flash News】According to SMM statistics, on October 14 ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103566577/SMM-Flash-News:-Daily-Social-Inventory-of-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingots-Drops-by-31-mt-on-Oct-14</link><description>SMM reports a daily social inventory drop of secondary aluminum ingots by 31 metric tons on October 14, 2025. The news also highlights challenges faced by Indonesia in its strategic shift from bauxite exporter to integrated aluminum producer amid significant headwinds this year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weekly Recap: Aluminium's low-carbon revolution in action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminium industry is undergoing a transformation towards sustainability, focusing on low-carbon production and innovative recycling technologies. Companies like RUSAL are developing technologies to turn off-grade aluminium scrap into high-purity metal. Taural India is also implementing sustainable practices to reduce emissions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US government launches new aluminum recycling technology</title><link>https://www.rinnovabili.net/draft/aluminum-recycling-technology-us/</link><description>The Pacific Northwest National Laboratory has developed the Shear Assisted Processing and Extrusion Process (ShAPE), which transforms 100% of aluminum scrap into construction-ready extrusions. This technology reduces energy consumption and eliminates impurities, making it more efficient than traditional methods.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>How green aluminium is transforming the metal industry</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/how-green-aluminium-is-transforming-the-metal-industry/</link><description>Green aluminium production involves low-carbon smelting and recycling, significantly reducing the carbon footprint of aluminium production. The industry is shifting towards maximizing recycled content, which requires only 5% of the energy needed for new aluminium production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Update: Chinese Steel Falls Further, Down 11% Year-on-Year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China dropped to 3,041 CNY/T on October 14, 2025, down 0.59% from the previous day and 11.08% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect prices to remain under pressure, with forecasts suggesting a further decline to 2,917.81 CNY/T over the next 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Prices Decline, But Remain Up Year-on-Year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel prices fell to 803.07 USD/T on October 13, 2025, down 1.34% from the previous day, but still 15.05% higher than a year ago. Forecasts indicate a potential rebound, with prices expected to reach 831.44 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 894.34 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Steel Demand Forecasted to Remain Flat in 2025</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/14/global-steel-demand-forecasted-to-remain-flat/</link><description>Worldsteel projects global steel demand will remain flat in 2025 at about 1,750 million tonnes, mirroring 2024 levels, with a modest rebound of 1.3% expected in 2026. China’s steel demand is forecast to decline by 2% in 2025, driven by a weak housing market, with risks weighted to the downside due to trade tensions and financial pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU Seeks US Trade Concessions by Doubling Steel Tariffs</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/eu-seeks-us-trade-concessions-by-doubling-steel-tariffs/</link><description>The EU Commission announced it will double duties to 50% for steel imports above a tariff-free quota, a move aimed at securing trade concessions from the US. This policy shift reflects ongoing trade tensions and could impact global steel trade flows.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iran's steel export increases 26% in H1</title><link>https://www.tehrantimes.com/news/519083/Iran-s-steel-export-increases-26-in-H1</link><description>Iran's steel exports rose by 26% in the first half of 2025, according to the Iranian Steel Producers Association. Despite a 5.3% year-on-year drop in production from January to May, output in May alone increased by 4.5%, and Iran now ranks ninth globally in steel production, just behind Germany.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Steel Demand Forecasted to Remain Flat</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/14/global-steel-demand-forecasted-to-remain-flat/</link><description>Worldsteel forecasts global steel demand will remain flat in 2025 at about 1,750 million tonnes, with a modest rebound of 1.3% expected in 2026. China's steel demand is projected to decline by 2% in 2025, mainly due to a downturn in the housing market, while global manufacturing faces elevated costs and trade tensions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>VinFast and the Quiet Power of Integration: Building a Greener Future from the Ground Up</title><link>https://themalaysianreserve.com/2025/10/14/vinfast-and-the-quiet-power-of-integration-building-a-greener-future-from-the-ground-up/</link><description>VinFast has announced VinMetal, a new high-tech steel manufacturer, as part of its broader strategy to build a sustainable, integrated ecosystem for greener manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed interest rate cuts heat up, LME copper surges overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103566505/Expectations-for-US-Fed-interest-rate-cuts-heat-up-LME-copper-surges-overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper futures surged overnight amid expectations of U.S. Fed interest rate cuts. The price movement reflects ongoing supply disruptions and market dynamics. Spot prices in Shanghai and Guangdong showed mixed trends, with some premiums increasing while others decreased.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Accelerates Copper Production to Meet Global Demand</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/rio-tinto-copper-production-expansion-2025-market-impact/</link><description>Rio Tinto has reported a significant increase in copper production, reaching 204,000 tonnes in Q3 2025, a 10% rise from the previous year. This growth is part of the company's strategic expansion to capitalize on rising global demand for copper. The strong performance reflects Rio Tinto's commitment to its copper business segment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed interest rate cuts heat up, LME copper surges overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103566505/Expectations-for-US-Fed-interest-rate-cuts-heat-up-LME-copper-surges-overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices surged overnight amid expectations of US Fed interest rate cuts. The futures opened at $10,648.5/mt, reflecting ongoing market volatility. Copper prices remain high despite slight pullbacks in some regions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Sharp divide between copper bulls and bears at industry gathering</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/lmeweek-sharp-divide-between-copper-bulls-and-bears-at-industry-gathering/</link><description>The copper market is experiencing a sharp divide between bullish and bearish outlooks. Bulls predict price increases due to mine disruptions, while bears argue the market is oversupplied. The LME three-month copper price has gained significantly this year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Bulls vs Bears: The Sharp Divide in Copper Industry</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-market-divide-bulls-bears-industry-2025/</link><description>The copper market is divided between those expecting price increases due to supply disruptions and those seeing a surplus. The LME three-month copper contract has risen significantly year-to-date. Industry experts are debating whether this trend is sustainable.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Supply Shocks Set the Stage For Shortages</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-bulls-lme-week-party-clouded-by-trumps-china-threats/copper-supply-shocks-set-the-stage-for-shortages-morgan-stanley-expects-the-biggest-deficit-in-22-years-next-year/</link><description>Morgan Stanley expects a significant copper deficit next year, driven by supply shocks. Mine disruptions have already impacted global supply, leading to price increases. Analysts predict further shortages in the coming years.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco joins mining giants backing Friedland's I-Pulse's technology</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/codelco-joins-mining-giants-backing-friedlands-i-pulses-technology-2025-10-14</link><description>Codelco and other mining giants are supporting Friedland's I-Pulse technology, which aims to reduce energy consumption in drilling, rock crushing, and underground mining. This innovation is expected to contribute significantly to sustainability by lowering the environmental footprint of mining operations.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Approach 120,000 Yuan Again Amid Ongoing US-China Trade Tensions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103567756/</link><description>Nickel prices have been fluctuating, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranging from 120,700 to 123,500 yuan/mt on October 14. This reflects ongoing market dynamics influenced by trade tensions and other global factors. The average price was 122,100 yuan/mt, down 350 yuan/mt from previous levels.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Extend Gains as Weaker Dollar &amp; Fed Rate Cut Expectations Boost Market</title><link>https://yieh.com/es/News/nickel-prices-extend-gains-as-weaker-dollar-fed-rate-cut-expectations-boost-market/157126</link><description>Nickel prices have increased due to a weaker U.S. dollar and expectations of a Fed rate cut. The spot price rose by $120.5/ton to reach $15,257/ton. These factors have contributed to a boost in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Fathom Nickel's three-year journey to full project ownership</title><link>https://mining.com.au/fathom-nickels-three-year-journey-to-full-project-ownership/</link><description>Fathom Nickel has completed a 100% earn-in at the Gochager Lake Nickel Project in Saskatchewan, expanding the project area significantly. Recent wildfires revealed new outcrops and high-priority drill targets, supporting the development of a high-grade nickel camp in Canada.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Legacy Minerals Strengthens Nickel-Cobalt Ambitions with Strategic MoU</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/stocks/metal-and-mining/legacy-minerals-strengthens-nickel-cobalt-ambitions-with-strategic-mou</link><description>Legacy Minerals announced a strategic Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) to strengthen its nickel-cobalt ambitions, signaling increased focus on expanding its footprint in these critical minerals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Approach 120,000 Yuan Again on October 14 Amid Ongoing US-China Trade Tensions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103567756/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Approach-120000-Yuan-Again-on-October-14-Amid-Ongoing-US-China-Trade-Tensions</link><description>Nickel prices on October 14 hovered between 120,700 and 123,500 yuan per metric ton, with an average price of 122,100 yuan/mt, slightly down by 350 yuan/mt. The market remains influenced by ongoing US-China trade tensions impacting supply and demand dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy's Antitrust Authority has opened an investigation into major low voltage copper cable manufacturers, including Prysmian, over alleged price-fixing and anti-competitive practices since 2005. The probe was triggered by a clemency request from one company, leading to inspections at several firms and industry associations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>