<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nickel futures fall to over 1-month low as oversupply persists</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures dropped to their lowest level in over a month, pressured by persistent oversupply from Indonesia, where production capacity has surged since the 2020 ore export ban. LME nickel stockpiles have risen sharply this year, reflecting weak demand from stainless steel manufacturers despite growing nickel use in electric vehicles.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hunting e-waste: India pushes for recycling of critical minerals</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/hunting-e-waste-india-pushes-for-recycling-of-critical-minerals-dismantlers-crushers-and-shredders-to-join-chain/articleshow/124821185.cms</link><description>India is expanding its electronic waste recycling capacity to recover critical minerals including nickel, lithium, and cobalt. The government launched a Rs 1,500 crore Incentive Scheme for Critical Mineral Recycling to reduce import dependence and promote sustainable recovery from e-waste and spent lithium-ion batteries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cash Aluminium Climbs to USD 2852.5/t on LME</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/cash-aluminium-climbs-to-usd-2-845-t-on-lme-inventories-shed-nearly-4-600t-115956</link><description>The cash price of aluminum on the London Metal Exchange (LME) rose to USD 2852.5/t, with a 0.33% increase. This rise is accompanied by a decrease in warehouse stocks by 4550 tonnes. The reduction in inventory levels supports the upward trend in aluminum prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel rose to 3,054 CNY/T on October 24, 2025, up 0.46% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices increased slightly to 3,054 CNY per tonne on October 24, 2025, marking a 0.46% rise from the previous day. However, over the past month, steel prices have fallen by 0.75% and are down 5.83% compared to the same time last year. Steel is expected to trade at 3,022.85 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,890.00 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hovers Near $11000 as Market Tightness Intensifies</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/supply-disruptions-copper-market-2025/</link><description>Copper futures reached $10,962.50 per metric ton in recent London trading, marking a 25% gain year-to-date amid supply-demand imbalances rather than speculative trading. Strong Chinese manufacturing and renewable energy investments underpin sustained copper demand, while geopolitical trade policies continue to influence market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[Copper Inventory] On October 25th, LME copper inventory decreased by 1,550 tonnes to 276,775 tonnes</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103008947/LME-Metal-Inventories-Update-on-October-25th</link><description>The London Metal Exchange reported a decrease in copper inventory by 1,550 tonnes on October 25, 2025, lowering total stocks to 276,775 tonnes, indicating tightening supply conditions in the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hovers Near $11000 as Market Tightness Intensifies</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/supply-disruptions-copper-market-2025/</link><description>Copper futures are trading near $10,962.50 per ton, up about 25% year-to-date, as supply-demand imbalances drive prices toward record levels. Strong Chinese industrial demand, especially in renewable energy and electric vehicles, continues to support the market amid global supply disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Reverses Biden Copper Smelter Rules in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/trump-copper-smelter-policy-reversal-2025/</link><description>President Trump has reversed Biden-era emission standards for copper smelters, granting a two-year exemption to the two remaining U.S. facilities. The move aims to bolster domestic mineral security by reducing regulatory burdens on the already limited U.S. copper smelting industry.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME nickel prices rise on Oct 25 due to bullish news</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-prices-rise-on-oct-25-due-to-bullish-news/144361</link><description>LME nickel futures increased by US$43 on October 25, closing at US$18,317 per ton, while the spot price also rose by US$43 to US$18,085 per ton, reflecting bullish market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell slightly to 15,325 USD/T on October 24, down 0.07% from the previous day. Despite a 0.56% rise over the past month, prices remain 5.07% lower than a year ago, with forecasts suggesting a decline to around 14,206 USD/MT in the next 12 months due to oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>PP Presisi secures Rp150 billion contract for Antam nickel project</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/pp-presisi-secures-rp150-billion-contract-for-antam-nickel-project</link><description>PT PP Presisi Tbk has secured a contract worth Rp150 billion for an Antam nickel project, strengthening its presence in Indonesia's mining sector. The deal highlights the ongoing development of nickel projects in the region. Further details about the project's scope and timeline are not provided.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Axpo Italia to supply green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill</title><link>https://yieh.com/ru/NewsItem/150822</link><description>Axpo Italia has signed a Power Purchase Agreement (PPA) to supply 15 GWh of green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill in Italy. This agreement supports Tenaris's efforts to reduce its carbon footprint.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Alcoa invests $60M in US aluminium smelter &amp; signs 10-year energy pact at the same time</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/alcoa-invests-60m-in-us-aluminium-smelter-signs-10-year-energy-pact-at-the-same-time-115933</link><description>Alcoa Corporation announced a $60 million investment in its Massena, New York smelter and a new 10-year renewable energy agreement with the New York Power Authority, effective April 2026. The deal secures nearly 240 megawatts of renewable energy and supports sustainable aluminum production in the U.S., with potential for extension.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weekly Recap: Aluminium's low-carbon revolution in action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminium industry is undergoing a transformation focused on sustainability, innovation, and circular practices. Key developments include Taural India's adoption of Vedanta Aluminium's low-carbon Restora and green sand-casting techniques, reducing casting emissions by up to 80%, and Egypt's 'Dandara' Solar Energy project aiming to cut Egypt Aluminium's greenhouse gas emissions by 30% using renewable energy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>UAE Delivers First Batch of Low-Carbon Aluminium Powered by Nuclear Energy from Barakah</title><link>https://gccbusinesswatch.com/news/uae-delivers-first-batch-of-low-carbon-aluminium-powered-by-nuclear-energy-from-barakah/</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Emirates Nuclear Energy Company have produced the UAE's first low-carbon aluminium using clean electricity from the Barakah Nuclear Energy Plant. This product, branded MinimAL, demonstrates nuclear energy's role in decarbonising heavy industries by providing constant, carbon-free power, and has been supplied to Egypt's CANEX Aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>BMW Group joins Aluminium Stewardship Initiative</title><link>https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/usa/article/detail/T0135476EN_US/bmw-group-joins-aluminium-stewardship-initiative?language=en_US</link><description>BMW Group has joined the Aluminium Stewardship Initiative to support the development of stringent sustainability standards across the aluminium value chain. The company emphasizes aluminium's role in lightweight construction and its use of recycled or renewable electricity-produced aluminium to reduce CO2 emissions, reinforcing BMW's leadership in sustainable mobility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market at Inflection Point as Indonesia Signals Q1 2026 Tightness</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-market-at-inflection-point-as-indonesia-signals-q1-2026-tightness</link><description>Nickel prices are testing the upper end of their 3-4 month range with potential upward movement expected as Chinese markets return from holiday. Indonesian supply management plans and government interventions in critical minerals are creating a structural shift, signaling tightness in Q1 2026 and significant revaluations in nickel-related stocks.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>CMOC Group's Strategic Expansion in Congo and Its Implications for Energy Transition Metals</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/cmoc-group-strategic-expansion-congo-implications-energy-transition-metals-2510/</link><description>CMOC Group is investing $1.08 billion in the Democratic Republic of Congo to boost copper output by 100,000 tons annually, supporting the global energy transition. The project balances growth with sustainability, aiming to meet rising copper demand amid geopolitical and ESG risks, reflecting the metal's critical role in green economy supply chains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US Raw Steel Production Sees Slight Increase</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-02-percent-week-44-2025-1416835.htm</link><description>US raw steel production increased by 0.2% for the week ending October 25, 2025, reaching 1.747 million net tons. This represents a 9.9% increase from the same period last year. The capacity utilization rate was 76.3%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Future Minerals Forum 2025: Transforming Global Mining Partnerships</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/global-minerals-summit-2025-strategic-importance/</link><description>The forum highlights the critical role of nickel and other minerals in the energy transition and addresses supply chain vulnerabilities such as geographic concentration and processing capacity limitations. It emphasizes the need for innovation and sustainability initiatives to meet projected demand and secure supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Governor Hochul Announces New Alcoa Power Contract Supporting 500 Jobs &amp; Long-Term Investment in the North Country</title><link>https://www.wnylabortoday.com/news/2025/10/26/new-york-state-labor-news/governor-hochul-announces-new-alcoa-power-contract-supporting-500-jobs-long-term-investment-in-the-north-country-the-usw-praises-all-involved-for-maintaining-good-union-jobs-that-serve-as-the-bedrock-of-our-communities/</link><description>New York Governor Kathy Hochul announced a new power supply contract between NYPA and Alcoa, supporting 500 jobs and a $60 million plant modernization through 2028. The agreement, bolstered by state grants and tax credits, ensures Alcoa's continued presence in Massena and regional economic stability.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>[SMM Analysis] Nickel prices pulled back this week due to fundamental pressure and inventory levels increased further</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575414/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-pulled-back-this-week-due-to-fundamental-pressure-and-inventory-levels-increased-further</link><description>Nickel prices declined under fundamental pressure with SHFE nickel futures closing down 1.89% week-on-week and LME nickel prices down 0.53%. The market is characterized by cost support at the bottom and inventory pressure at the top, with improved trading sentiment despite the price pullback.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion on the future of the Italian boilermaking industry focused on nuclear energy, held at Fondazione Dalmine in Italy. The event gathered industry and institutional experts to discuss nuclear energy's strategic role in Europe's energy transition and Italy's manufacturing potential. Tenaris's Italian mill recently obtained accreditation to supply certified materials for nuclear facilities, aligning with the highest technical and quality standards.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Axpo Italia to supply green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill in Italy</title><link>https://yieh.com/ru/NewsItem/150822</link><description>Under a Power Purchase Agreement, Axpo Italia will provide 15 GWh of green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill in Italy, supporting the mill's sustainability and energy efficiency goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Tenaris to invest US$200 million in Colombian mill</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-tenaris-to-invest-us200-million-in-colombian-mill/56956</link><description>Tenaris plans to invest US$200 million to build a new heat treatment mill and install advanced technology for ultrasound inspection and finishing. This investment aims to enhance production capabilities and product sophistication, although it concerns a Colombian facility rather than Italy directly.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>INALUM Signs Key Agreements at Osaka Expo 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103587659/INALUM-Signs-Key-Agreements-at-Osaka-Expo-2025-to-Globalize-Downstream-Aluminum-Strategy-and-Boost-Green-Economy</link><description>INALUM has signed significant agreements at the World Expo 2025 in Osaka to globalize its downstream aluminum strategy and boost the green economy. These agreements aim to enhance aluminum production and distribution capabilities.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Found Energy begins real-world test of zero-carbon reactor</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminium-as-fuel-found-energy-begins-real-world-test-of-zero-carbon-reactor-115952</link><description>Found Energy, a Boston-based startup, is conducting the largest aluminium–water reactor test to convert scrap aluminium into zero-carbon industrial fuel. The 100-kilowatt reactor will be installed at a US tool manufacturing plant to produce heat and hydrogen, aiming to reduce industrial emissions through a circular waste-to-fuel model.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Driving Innovation for a Sustainable Future</title><link>https://www.aluminium-exhibition.com/germany/en-gb/blog/pressemitteilungen/alude2026-showpreparations.html</link><description>ALUMINIUM 2026 trade fair in Düsseldorf will emphasize sustainability with a focus on secondary aluminium for decarbonisation. The event will cover metal processing, recycling, automation, and cross-sector applications, featuring an expanded Sustainability &amp; Recycling Conference to share expert knowledge and best practices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Italian steel factory invests USD 14 mln in training center in Romania</title><link>https://www.romania-insider.com/italian-steel-factory-invests-usd-14-mln-in-training-center-in-romania</link><description>Italian steel company Tenaris invested USD 14 million in a training center for its 1,700 employees in Zalau, Romania. The investment aims to strengthen medium and long-term operations despite global challenges, with support from Romanian government officials and Tenaris leadership.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian has been awarded a tender by Terna S.p.A. and STEG for the construction of a submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia as part of the Elmed Project. The contract could reach a value of around €460 million and involves laying a power cable between Sicily and the Tunisian Cap Bon peninsula at depths up to 800 meters. This project aims to enhance energy security between Europe and Africa and supports the transition to cleaner energy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Will Prysmian's Shift to Recycled Copper Amid Tariffs Impact Its Business?</title><link>https://simplywall.st/stocks/it/capital-goods/bit-pry/prysmian-shares/news/will-prysmians-bitpry-shift-to-recycled-copper-amid-tariffs/</link><description>Prysmian has increased its use of recycled copper in the U.S. due to ongoing trade tensions and tariffs affecting the copper supply chain. This strategic shift aims to mitigate input cost volatility and maintain operational resilience. The move is part of Prysmian's broader efforts to adapt to global copper market disruptions while supporting its competitive position in cable production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian (BIT:PRY): Examining Valuation as Recycled Copper Strategy Advances</title><link>https://simplywall.st/stocks/it/capital-goods/bit-pry/prysmian-shares/news/prysmian-bitpry-examining-valuation-as-recycled-copper-strat</link><description>Prysmian is increasing its use of recycled copper in the U.S. amid trade tensions and tariffs, which complicate copper supply chains. This strategy supports Prysmian's growth in electrification and grid modernization, particularly in the U.S. market where tariffs provide a competitive advantage. However, potential rollback of tariffs could impact profitability and growth assumptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>NioCorp and IBC Advanced Alloys Successfully Cast Aluminum-Scandium Alloy</title><link>https://www.redchip.com/news/8293747800041119/niocorp-and-ibc-advanced-alloys-successfully-cast-aluminum-scandium-alloy-for-potential-expansion-into-al-sc-alloy-parts</link><description>NioCorp and IBC Advanced Alloys have successfully cast a 0.2% Aluminum-Scandium alloy, marking a potential expansion into Al-Sc alloy parts. This development is part of NioCorp's broader efforts to enhance domestic critical mineral production. NioCorp is hosting an investor webcast to discuss recent milestones and future plans.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>NioCorp to Conduct Live Investor Webcast</title><link>https://www.niocorp.com/niocorp-to-conduct-live-investor-webcast-on-monday-october-27-2025/</link><description>NioCorp is conducting a live investor webcast to update on its Elk Creek Critical Minerals Project and recent corporate milestones. The company has raised significant funding and is working to secure additional financing for project development. The webcast will include a Q&amp;A session with management.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory Rises</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103587839/Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Rises-to-102000-mt-on-Oct-27-2025:-SMM</link><description>According to SMM statistics, domestic aluminum billet inventory in two regions has increased to 102,000 mt. This update reflects recent trends in aluminum stock levels and market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Ministry to hold talks with industry stakeholders on import issues on October 27</title><link>https://manufacturing.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/industry/steel-ministry-to-hold-talks-with-industry-stakeholders-on-import-issues-on-october-27/124737300</link><description>The Ministry of Steel in India will conduct an Open House meeting on October 27, 2025, to discuss import-related issues with industry stakeholders. The meeting aims to address concerns and formulate strategies to stabilize the domestic steel market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel imports fall 29% in H1, but sector still records net forex outflow</title><link>https://indiaseatradenews.com/steel-imports-fall-29-in-h1-but-sector-still-records-net-forex-outflow/</link><description>India's steel imports have decreased by 29% in the first half of the year, yet the sector still experiences a net foreign exchange outflow. This indicates ongoing challenges in the domestic steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China proposes more stringent steel capacity swap plan to curb overcapacity</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/china-proposes-more-stringent-steel-capacity-swap-plan-to-curb-overcapacity/</link><description>China has proposed a more stringent steel capacity swap plan to address overcapacity issues in the industry. This plan follows the pause of a previous program that failed to achieve its goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hebei Songting Steel to Start Blast Furnace Shutdown on Oct 27</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103588781/Hebei-Songting-Steel-to-Start-Blast-Furnace-Shutdown-on-Oct-27</link><description>Hebei Songting Steel is set to begin a blast furnace shutdown for maintenance starting October 27. This shutdown is part of routine maintenance to ensure operational efficiency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Experts urge factories to produce 100% refined steel to cut carbon emissions</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/economy/industry/experts-urge-factories-produce-100-refined-steel-cut-carbon-emissions-1270086</link><description>Industry experts are calling for factories to adopt 100% refined steel production as a key measure to reduce carbon emissions. This push aligns with broader efforts to decarbonize the steel sector and promote sustainability in manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Greece's New Copper-Gold Mine Nears Completion, LME Copper Rose Sharply on Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103587605/Greeces-New-Copper-Gold-Mine-Nears-Completion-LME-Copper-Rose-Sharply-on-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices rose 1.2% to close at $10,947/mt on Friday, with trading volume and open interest increasing. Canadian company Eldorado Gold announced its Skouries copper-gold project in Greece is about 70% complete, with first production expected in early 2026 and commercial production by mid-2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Remain Near Record Highs</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/27/copper-prices-remain-near-record-highs/</link><description>Copper prices are holding near record highs just below $11,000 a tonne, driven by concerns over supply disruptions such as the suspension of Freeport-McMoRan’s Grasberg mine in Indonesia after a fatal mudslide. The metal has rallied about 25% this year, reflecting strong demand and supply-side challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Metals on fire: What's driving the unstoppable rally in copper, aluminium and zinc</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/metals-on-fire-whats-driving-the-unstoppable-rally-in-copper-aluminium-and-zinc/articleshow/124824209.cms</link><description>Copper prices have surged past $10,000 on the LME and are near record highs on India's MCX platform, driven by supply disruptions at major mines, strong demand from infrastructure and green energy sectors, and geopolitical tensions. The rally is supported by factors including accidents at Chile's El Teniente mine, protests in Peru, and a mudslide at Indonesia's Grasberg mine.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper jumps to 16-month high on trade deal optimism</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/metals-copper-jumps-to-16-month-high-on-trade-deal-optimism-158328/</link><description>Copper prices climbed to a 16-month high driven by optimism over a potential U.S.-China trade agreement, reflecting positive market sentiment on easing trade tensions between the two largest economies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to $5.16 USD/Lbs on October 27, 2025, up 1.42% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices increased to $5.16 per pound, up 1.42% from the previous day, with a 6.23% rise over the past month and an 18.92% increase year-over-year. Analysts expect copper to trade at $5.20 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.74 in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Remain Near Record Highs</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/27/copper-prices-remain-near-record-highs/</link><description>Copper prices are holding near record highs, just below $11,000 per tonne, driven by concerns over supply disruptions. A key factor is the suspension of operations at Freeport-McMoRan’s Grasberg mine in Indonesia after a fatal mudslide, impacting the world's second-largest copper mine. The metal's strong rally this year reflects rising global demand and supply-side challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Diablo Resources (ASX:DBO) Confirms Copper Mineralisation Open in All Directions at Phoenix Project</title><link>https://www.marketopen.com.au/diablo-resources-asxdbo-confirms-copper-mineralisation-open-in-all-directions-at-phoenix-project/</link><description>Diablo Resources reported early drilling success at its Phoenix Copper Project in Utah, USA, with significant copper mineralisation confirmed open in all directions and at depth. Maiden drilling returned 10.5 metres at 1.02% copper, including a high-grade interval of 1.5 metres at 3.99% copper. Follow-up drilling is planned for mid-November, targeting further exploration in this recognized copper district.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Copper Smelter Emissions Rule Reversal Explained</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/biden-copper-rule-air-quality-standards-2025/</link><description>The Trump administration reversed Biden-era copper smelter emissions rules, granting a two-year exemption to protect domestic processing. The US processes less than 5% of global copper despite significant mining, relying heavily on foreign smelters, especially in China, which controls about 50% of global copper smelting capacity. This reversal highlights strategic concerns about supply chain security amid rising copper demand driven by clean energy and electric vehicle growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FireFly Announces Major High-Grade Copper and Gold Exploration Breakthrough at Green Bay</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/26/3174278/0/en/FireFly-announces-major-high-grade-copper-and-gold-exploration-breakthrough-at-Green-Bay.html</link><description>FireFly Metals reported exceptional drilling results at its Green Bay Copper-Gold Project in Canada, revealing a high-grade mineralised core over at least 800 meters strike length. Recent assays include 43 meters at 7.6% copper equivalent and 15 meters at 16% copper equivalent, indicating significant potential to expand the mineral resource. Ongoing drilling aims to define the full extent of this core for upcoming resource updates.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Miner Sandfire Tracks Ahead of Plan in Strong First Quarter</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/copper-miner-sandfire-tracks-ahead-of-plan-in-strong-first-quarter-2025-10-27</link><description>Sandfire Resources produced 21,800 tonnes of copper-equivalent in the first quarter, representing 23% of its 2026 financial year guidance. This performance reflects planned mining activities and positions the company well for the remainder of the year. The strong start indicates robust operational execution in copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Corruption Probe Underway at Rio Tinto's Mongolian Copper Mine</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2025102752/corruption-probe-underway-at-rio-tintos-mongolian-copper-mine-update</link><description>An internal investigation into allegations of corruption and unethical conduct is underway at Rio Tinto's Oyu Tolgoi copper mine in Mongolia. The probe involves procurement-related activities and has sought law enforcement cooperation. Oyu Tolgoi is a major copper and gold deposit expected to become the world's fourth-largest copper mine by 2030, critical to Rio Tinto's strategic shift toward copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Reverses Biden-Era Rules on Copper Smelters</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/trump-reverses-biden-era-rules-on-copper-smelters-2025-10-27</link><description>US President Donald Trump reversed a Biden-era air pollution rule that imposed stricter emissions limits on copper smelters. This regulatory change aims to ease restrictions on domestic copper processing, addressing concerns about supply chain resilience and domestic capacity limitations. The move reflects ongoing tensions between environmental regulations and industrial policy in the copper sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Hellenic Copper Mines Ltd: 2026 Outlook For Large Copper Mines</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/hellenic-copper-mines-ltd-2026-outlook-for-large-copper-mines</link><description>Hellenic Copper Mines Ltd is advancing innovation and sustainability in copper mining through automation, AI-powered resource management, advanced recycling, and digital traceability. The company focuses on energy-efficient operations, enhanced waste management, and compliance with stringent EU environmental standards to boost productivity and minimize environmental impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, Silver &amp; Copper: tech and sustainability trends</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_ca/insights/mining-metals/gold-silver-and-copper-tech-and-sustainability-trends</link><description>Copper companies are addressing supply challenges by adopting digital innovations, AI, satellite technology, and advanced mineral processing to optimize recovery and productivity. Recycling plays a key role, with recycled copper accounting for 32% of global supply in 2023, and companies increasingly collaborating with cleantech firms to enhance sustainable copper supplies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Rise Slightly on October 27 as China-US Economic and Trade Consultations Make Positive Progress</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103588834/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Rise-Slightly-on-October-27-as-China-US-Economic-and-Trade-Consultations-Make-Positive-Progress</link><description>On October 27, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,900 yuan/mt, up 750 yuan/mt from the previous day. Positive progress in China-US economic and trade talks and lower-than-expected US CPI data boosted market sentiment, supporting a slightly higher nickel price with expected sideways movement in the near term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel price rose slightly to $15,334.13 per ton on October 27, 2025, up 0.06% from the previous day. Despite a modest monthly increase, prices remain about 4-5% lower than a year ago. Forecasts suggest nickel may trade around $15,152 by the end of the quarter but could decline to about $14,420 in 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>METALS-Copper jumps to 16-month high on trade deal optimism; nickel rose 0.25%</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/gold-silver-prices-extend-fall-yellow-metal-below-rs-1-23-lakh-what-should-investors-do/articleshow/124839539.cms</link><description>On October 27, nickel prices rose by 0.25% amid broader positive market sentiment driven by optimism over trade deals. This modest increase aligns with gains in other base metals like copper and tin.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SPC's polymetallic Muskox treads the path of giants</title><link>https://mining.com.au/spcs-polymetallic-muskox-treads-the-path-of-giants/</link><description>SPC Nickel has completed a comprehensive field program at the Muskox Project in Nunavut, Canada, including the most thorough modern geophysical survey ever flown over the intrusion. The project shows promising high-grade silver and significant nickel-copper resources, with a 1km trend of high conductivity EM targets identified for potential drilling.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China, ASEAN to upgrade free trade, bring more certainties to world</title><link>https://english.www.gov.cn/news/202510/27/content_WS68fec32dc6d00ca5f9a070ee.html</link><description>A new project covering the full supply chain from nickel mining and processing to battery materials production, manufacturing, and recycling is underway, aiming to strengthen trade and industrial cooperation between China and ASEAN countries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Trump Strikes Strategic Critical Minerals Trade Deals in Southeast Asia</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-2025-strategic-partnerships-southeast-asia/</link><description>Former President Trump secured critical minerals trade deals in Southeast Asia, focusing on strategic partnerships that include nickel among other critical minerals, to support supply chains for commercial and defense industries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,876.15 per tonne on October 27, 2025, marking a 0.57% daily increase and a 7.35% gain over the past month. The surge is attributed to tightening supply, especially due to China's aluminum output cap, with prices reaching their highest level in three years.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash price rises to $2,878.5/t on October 27 as stocks dip to 469,275t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-price-rises-to-2-878-5-t-on-october-27-as-stocks-dip-to-469-275t-115973</link><description>LME aluminum prices climbed to $2,878.5 per tonne on October 27, driven by firm demand and a 3,850-tonne drop in exchange stocks to 469,275 tonnes. The price increase reflects ongoing tightness in the physical aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Key takeaways from AICE 2025 SMM (14th) aluminium industry annual conference</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/key-takeaways-from-aice-2025-smm-14th-aluminium-industry-annual-conference-115965</link><description>The conference discussed China's 'dual carbon' goals impacting the aluminum industry with stricter energy and emission limits. Innovations like anode surface coating technology reduce carbon electrode consumption and emissions, while new roasting technologies for red mud were analyzed for energy efficiency and environmental impact.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum-air long-duration generation technology selected by Net Zero Innovation Hub for Data Centers</title><link>https://www.netzerodatacenters.com/aluminum-air-long-duration-generation-technology-selected-by-net-zero-innovation-hub-for-data-centers-for-groundbreaking-clean-backup-energy-initiative-in-data-centers</link><description>Phinergy's aluminum-air backup energy solution was selected by the Net Zero Innovation Hub from over 70 proposals to scale to megawatt levels for data centers. This technology aims to replace diesel backup generators, supporting the transition to net-zero operations in digital infrastructure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcast Company Advances the Future of Precision Aluminum Casting</title><link>https://www.digitaljournal.com/pr/news/prodigy-press-wire/alcast-company-advances-future-precision-153390634.html</link><description>Alcast Company integrates environmentally conscious practices in precision aluminum casting to minimize waste and maximize material efficiency. The company offers comprehensive services including machining and finishing, supporting sustainable production aligned with modern standards.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper price nears record on trade deal boost, supply woes</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-nears-record-on-trade-deal-boost-supply-woes/</link><description>Copper prices surged toward a record as optimism grows over an imminent US-China trade deal, boosting demand outlook amid supply disruptions at major mines in Congo, Chile, and Indonesia. The International Copper Study Group cut its 2025 mine supply forecast due to these disruptions, while demand is expected to rise significantly by 2050 driven by energy transition needs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises as Risk Appetite Improves</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/494267</link><description>Copper futures climbed above $5 per pound, reaching the highest level since July 2025, supported by easing US-China trade tensions and expectations of US Federal Reserve rate cuts. Supply disruptions at major mines and increased Chinese smelter shipments also influenced the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price nears record on trade deal boost, supply woes</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-nears-record-on-trade-deal-boost-supply-woes/</link><description>Copper prices surged toward a record as optimism over a potential US-China trade deal and ongoing supply disruptions at major mines drove the rally. The International Copper Study Group has cut its 2025 mine supply growth forecast to 1.4% due to recent incidents at key mines in Congo, Chile, and Indonesia, raising concerns about meeting future demand amid the global energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper to hold gains in 2026 as mine disruptions fuel deficit</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/metals-base-poll-two/</link><description>Analysts have raised their 2026 copper price forecasts due to ongoing mine disruptions, with the LME cash copper contract expected to average $10,500 per metric ton. Recent incidents, including the suspension of operations at Indonesia's Grasberg mine, have shifted market expectations from a surplus to a deficit in 2025, though new mine ramps could eventually ease supply pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper to hold gains in 2026 as mine disruptions fuel deficit</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/metals-base-poll-two/</link><description>Analysts raised copper price forecasts for 2026 due to mine disruptions in Indonesia, Congo, and Chile causing supply concerns and market deficits. The article notes copper's price gains in 2025 and anticipates a tightening refined copper market, while also discussing new mine developments that may moderate prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The world's first electric car without metals or minerals is launched</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/10/27/the-worlds-first-electric-car-without-metals-or-minerals-is-launched-and-it-doesnt-work/</link><description>This article presents eNimon, the first electric car made without metals or minerals, highlighting the critical role of sustainable mining in meeting the material demands of green technologies. It underscores the challenges of mineral shortages for climate goals and features Sandvik's efforts to innovate sustainable mining practices.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Nornickel, Russia’s largest nickel producer, has maintained its 2025 nickel production forecast at 196,000–204,000 metric tons despite a 4% year-to-date decline. The company reported an 18% quarterly increase in nickel output to 54,000 metric tons in Q3, attributed to higher processing of raw materials accumulated during Q2, but cited ongoing challenges from equipment replacement and seasonal disruptions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Dips on Oct 28</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103590099/SMM-Flash:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-on-Oct-28</link><description>Secondary aluminum alloy ingot inventories have declined, with prices expected to remain firm in the short term due to strong cost support and a tight supply-demand balance. The market outlook suggests continued price resilience for ADC12 aluminum alloy ingots.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Australia's largest aluminum smelter could close, says Rio Tinto</title><link>https://english.news.cn/asiapacific/20251028/8bce499c1acf41f3ab35ec946d82483d/c.html</link><description>Rio Tinto announced that Australia's largest aluminum smelter, Tomago, may shut down in 2028 due to rising electricity costs, with power making up over 40% of operating expenses. The company has begun consultations with employees, as both coal and renewable energy options are expected to become unaffordable after the current power contract expires.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto flags uncertain future at Australia’s largest aluminum smelter</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/rio-tinto-contemplates-ceasing-tomago-aluminum-operations/</link><description>Rio Tinto warned that the Tomago smelter, Australia's largest, faces closure after 2028 as it struggles to secure commercially viable power contracts. The smelter, a major power user in New South Wales, is emblematic of challenges facing energy-intensive industries amid Australia's transition to renewables.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tomago Aluminium Faces Closure Due to Rising Energy Costs</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/tomago-aluminium-closure-energy-2025-opportunities/</link><description>Tomago Aluminium in Australia is facing potential closure from rising energy costs. The article details technological innovations such as prebaked anode technology, advanced process controls, and inert anode research that could reduce energy consumption by up to 20%, though significant investment is required to implement these solutions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Extends Gains on Proposal to Constrain China's Steel Supply</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/iron-ore-extends-gains-on-new-proposal-aiming-to-constrain-chinas-steel-supply-158471/</link><description>Iron ore prices have increased due to a new proposal aimed at limiting China's steel supply. This development could impact global steel production and prices. The proposal's effects on the steel market are being closely monitored.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nigeria's Steel Development Transformation</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/nigeria-steel-development-transformation-2025/</link><description>Nigeria aims to transform its steel sector with ambitious production targets, including achieving 10 million tonnes of annual liquid steel production by 2030. This involves significant investment in infrastructure and utilizing local iron ore reserves to reduce import dependency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metso to Supply Advanced Iron Ore Sintering Plant to India</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/iron-ore-sintering-technology-2025-steel-production/</link><description>Metso is delivering an advanced iron ore sintering plant to India, integrating emission-optimized sintering technology to enhance sustainability and production efficiency. This technology reduces CO2 emissions by over 54,000 tonnes annually and optimizes fuel consumption. The plant will contribute to regional economic growth and diversification.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Omani Green Iron to Revive British Steel Industry</title><link>https://omanet.om/en/news/economy/omani-green-iron-revives-british-steel/</link><description>Meranti Green Steel plans to produce low-carbon Hot Briquetted Iron (HBI) in Oman using green hydrogen and natural gas. This will help the UK transition away from outdated blast furnaces and secure a reliable supply chain for clean iron, aligning with global trends towards low-carbon steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Utility and Seongnam City Sign H2Gen Hydrogen Demonstration and Certification Project</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/10/28/utility-and-seongnam-city-sign-h2gen-hydrogen-demonstration-and-certification-project/</link><description>Utility and Seongnam City have partnered on a hydrogen demonstration project using H2Gen technology, which produces low-carbon hydrogen from industrial off-gases. This project aims to decarbonize industrial sectors in Korea, starting with heavy mobility.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Argentina's Mining Sector Receives US Investment, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103590021/Argentinas-Mining-Sector-Receives-US-Investment-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, closing slightly higher at $11,000.5/mt amid trading volume of 25,000 lots. Argentina received about $20 billion in US support to promote mining projects including copper, aiming to boost foreign investment and infrastructure, though political and economic stability remain critical for sustained recovery.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Nears Record High on Trade Deal Hopes</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/28/copper-nears-record-high-on-trade-deal-hopes/</link><description>Copper prices surged close to record highs driven by optimism over a US-China trade agreement and supply disruptions at major mines worldwide. The metal has gained 25% this year, recovering from previous trade tension impacts, with demand expected to rise sharply due to electrification and energy transition needs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Oil Prices Stabilize, Copper Prices Rise, Gold Falls Below $4,000</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/63879177/commodities-overview-oil-prices-stabilize-copper-prices-rise-gold-falls</link><description>LME copper futures rose 0.61% to settle at $11,029 per ton, nearing historical highs due to ongoing supply disruptions at major mines. The rally is supported by supply constraints and strong demand outlook amid global energy transition efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper hits 17-month peak on US-China trade deal optimism</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-17-month-peak-on-us-china-trade-deal-optimism/</link><description>Copper prices reached a 17-month peak driven by optimism about a US-China trade deal, reflecting improved market sentiment and supply concerns. The metal's price strength is linked to expectations of increased demand and constrained supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices edge higher as US-China trade optimism lingers</title><link>https://www.klsescreener.com/v2/news/view/1610571/copper-prices-edge-higher-as-us-china-trade-optimism-lingers</link><description>Copper prices on the Shanghai Futures Exchange rose slightly by 0.18% to 88,100 yuan per metric ton, supported by ongoing optimism about a US-China trade agreement and supply disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Reach 16-Month High: Effects of the Trade Agreement</title><link>https://www.yatirimmasasi.com/en/haberler/bakir-fiyatlari-16-ayin-zirvesine-ulasti-ticaret-anlasmasinin-etkileri</link><description>Copper prices hit a 16-month high fueled by optimism surrounding the US-China trade agreement, which also positively impacted other metals. The trade deal outlook is a key driver behind the recent price surge.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Argentina's Mining Sector Receives US Investment, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103590021/Argentinas-Mining-Sector-Receives-US-Investment-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Argentina received about $20 billion in US support to promote mining projects in lithium, copper, and energy, aiming to boost foreign exchange reserves and attract more investment. Meanwhile, LME copper prices opened higher, fluctuated, and closed up 0.49%, reflecting ongoing market volatility and investor interest in copper amid global supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Nears Record High on Trade Deal Hopes</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/28/copper-nears-record-high-on-trade-deal-hopes/</link><description>Copper prices are approaching record highs, buoyed by optimism over a potential US-China trade deal and persistent supply disruptions at major mines in Chile, Congo, and Indonesia. The metal has gained 25% this year, with investors focused on the delicate balance between rising demand for electrification and constrained production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Harmony Gold Acquires MAC Copper for $1.01 Billion Deal</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/gold-miners-pivot-copper-2025/</link><description>Harmony Gold has acquired MAC Copper for $1.01 billion, reflecting a strategic shift by gold miners to expand into copper production amid surging demand for electrification metals. The move highlights the industry's response to projections that copper demand will rise 70% by 2040, driven by renewable energy and electric vehicle adoption.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>A Copper Mine In The Desert Could Recast Pakistan's Future – OpEd</title><link>https://www.eurasiareview.com/28102025-a-copper-mine-in-the-desert-could-recast-pakistans-future-oped/</link><description>The Reko Diq copper and gold project in Pakistan, one of the world's largest untapped mineral deposits, is moving forward again this month. The development could significantly impact Pakistan's economy and global copper supply, though the article focuses more on geopolitical and economic implications than current production or capacity details.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices experienced a significant decline on October 28 while nickel inventory reached a new record high</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103591204/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-decline-on-October-28-while-nickel-inventory-reached-a-new-record-high</link><description>Spot nickel prices in China fell sharply on October 28, with SMM #1 refined nickel trading at 120,700–123,600 yuan/mt, down 900 yuan/mt from the previous day, as inventories hit a record high, signaling continued weak demand and ample supply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Antam 9-month profit surges 197% on strong gold and nickel sales</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/antam-9-month-profit-surges-197-on-strong-gold-and-nickel-sales</link><description>Indonesian miner Antam reported a 197% jump in net profit for the first nine months of 2025, driven by robust sales of gold, nickel, and bauxite, alongside cost management and downstreaming efforts, despite broader nickel market weakness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Reports Strong September Quarter with Increased EBITDA</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/28/nickel-industries-reports-strong-september-quarter-with-increased-ebitda/</link><description>Nickel Industries announced a strong September quarter, with adjusted EBITDA up significantly due to lower cash costs and higher sales, though mine sales were impacted by quota delays; the company also highlighted progress on new projects and ESG achievements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Reports Strong September Quarter with Increased EBITDA</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/28/nickel-industries-reports-strong-september-quarter-with-increased-ebitda/</link><description>Nickel Industries announced robust Q3 2025 results, with adjusted EBITDA rising to US$87 million, driven by strong performance in both RKEF and HPAL operations. The company highlighted cost reductions, increased sales, and progress on new projects, though mine sales were impacted by quota delays. Nickel Industries also emphasized its safety record and recent debt refinancing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Q3 EBITDA rises on strong RKEF, HPAL performance</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-q3-ebitda-rises-on-strong-rkef-hpal-performance</link><description>Australia-listed Nickel Industries Ltd reported another solid quarterly performance, with EBITDA growth supported by strong RKEF and HPAL operations. Details are behind a paywall, but the headline confirms continued operational strength in Indonesian nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne, located in Aosta, has entered a new period in steel production with a green hydrogen facility</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/haber/cogne-located-in-aosta-has-entered-a-new-period-in-steel-production-with-a-green-hydrogen-facility/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started using green hydrogen produced via electrolysis to replace fossil natural gas in its heat treatment processes, marking a significant step toward climate-neutral steel production. The company also supplies high-performance stainless steels for hydrogen infrastructure, supporting the broader energy transition.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris signs agreement with Axpo for green energy supply to Dalmine plant</title><link>https://news.mesteel.com/tenaris-signs-agreement-with-axpo-for-green-energy-supply-to-dalmine-plant/</link><description>Tenaris signed a Power Purchase Agreement with Axpo Italia to supply green energy to its Dalmine seamless steel tube factory. This agreement supports Tenaris's commitment to renewable energy sources.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World's top cable maker sees US copper tariff as opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Prysmian, the world's largest cable maker, views the proposed US copper tariff as an opportunity. The company believes it can benefit from the tariff due to its vertically integrated copper operation in the U.S. This includes sourcing raw copper from a mine in Arizona and operating a copper rod mill in Texas.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>