<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 05:16:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SMM #1 refined nickel price down on November 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103623958/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price was reported at 116,500-120,900 yuan/mt on November 17, averaging 118,700 yuan/mt, a decrease of 900 yuan/mt from the previous day, reflecting continued downward pressure in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>TECH Project high-grade nickel is primed to fuel the global green transition</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/tech-project-high-grade-nickel-is-primed-to-fuel-the-global-green-transition/32893/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals' TECH Project aims to become a leading source of high-grade, ethically derived nickel for lithium-ion batteries, supporting the global green transition. The project uses the environmentally friendly DNi Process, which recycles over 98% of nitric acid, requires no tailings dam, and produces minimal waste, targeting carbon-negative and sustainable nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,846 USD/T on November 17, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices declined 0.49% to $2,846 per tonne on November 17, 2025, though prices remain up 2.60% over the past month and 8.96% compared to the same time last year. The commodity has historically reached an all-time high of $4,103 in March 2022, with current prices tracking near three-year highs amid ongoing supply concerns.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Russia's Aluminium Giant Rusal Shuts Key Plant as China's Low-Cost Silicon Crushes Industry</title><link>https://united24media.com/latest-news/chinas-cheap-silicon-crushes-russias-industry-rusal-forced-to-close-flagship-factory-13516</link><description>Russia's largest silicon producer, the Kremniy factory owned by Rusal, will halt operations on January 1, 2026, due to collapsing demand for Russian silicon as cheaper Chinese imports flood the market. The shutdown is part of a broader wave of production cuts across Russian heavy industry, with at least ten major companies implementing reduced schedules or closures due to weak domestic demand and falling exports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Fed's Hawkish Remarks Drive Stainless Steel Below Recent Lows</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Finished-Steel</link><description>Stainless steel futures broke below nearly five-year lows to reach 12,310 yuan/mt during Friday's night session, affected by weakened expectations for US Federal Reserve interest rate cuts. Stainless steel mills have lowered prices and are actively shipping goods to boost sales amid the market downturn.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Manufacturing in New York state jumps in November</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/17/manufacturing-in-new-york-state-jumps-in-november/</link><description>Manufacturing activity in New York state increased slightly from November 3-10, with firms forecasting improved business conditions despite a dip in optimism. Steel production dipped last week but remained above the year-to-date weekly average. Employment and hours worked rose modestly, while supply availability worsened slightly and input price increases slowed.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto's Green Steelmaking Pivot from BioIron to Zesty Technology</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/rio-tinto-green-steelmaking-challenge-2025/</link><description>Rio Tinto is shifting its green steelmaking focus from BioIron to hydrogen-based Zesty technology, investing $35 million to advance sustainable steel production. The company aims for a 95% reduction in carbon emissions compared to traditional blast furnaces, leveraging renewable agricultural waste and zero reliance on metallurgical coal. This pragmatic approach balances near-term commercial deployment with long-term innovation, positioning Rio Tinto as a leader in green steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BASF and ExxonMobil Join Forces to Advance Low-Emission Hydrogen Through Methane Pyrolysis Technology</title><link>https://www.basf.com/basf/www/global/en/media/news-releases/2025/11/p-25-233</link><description>BASF and ExxonMobil are collaborating to develop methane pyrolysis technology that produces low-emission hydrogen and solid carbon, which can be used in steel manufacturing among other industries. A demonstration plant in Texas will validate the technology at scale, aiming to reduce the carbon footprint of hydrogen production and support green transformations in chemical and steel sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SSAB Teams Up With EAB for Green Steel</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>SSAB and EAB have partnered to supply fossil-free steel, including SSAB Zero™, for use in warehouse fittings, doors, and steel buildings. This collaboration supports the green steel transition by promoting the use of sustainable steel products in construction and infrastructure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 0.98% Lower at $5.0000 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511176772/comex-copper-settles-098-lower-at-50000-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for November delivery lost 4.95 cents per pound, or 0.98%, settling at $5.0000. This marked the largest one-day dollar and percentage decline recently, reflecting market reactions to economic data and uncertainty.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Policy change in Argentina may boost Copper mining</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2755103-policy-change-in-argentina-may-boost-copper-mining</link><description>Argentina's President Javier Milei is considering policy changes that could enhance copper mining activities in the country. The article also mentions Rio Tinto's ongoing low-emission iron projects and production updates from other miners, highlighting a significant production decrease due to a plant shutdown in October.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lara Exploration Announces Filing of the Preliminary Economic Assessment for its Planalto Copper-Gold Project in Brazil</title><link>https://laraexploration.com/news/2025/lara-exploration-announces-filing-of-the-preliminary-economic-assessment-for-its-planalto-copper-gold-project-in-brazil/</link><description>Lara Exploration filed a Preliminary Economic Assessment for its Planalto copper-gold project in Brazil, estimating production of 560 kt of copper and 111 koz of gold over an 18-year mine life. The project aims to produce a clean chalcopyrite concentrate with potential for metallurgical improvements and power cost reductions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>One and One Green Technologies INC Reports Strong First Half 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/17/3189572/0/en/One-and-One-Green-Technologies-INC-Reports-Strong-First-Half-2025-Results.html</link><description>One and One Green Technologies reported a 51% revenue increase and 60% net income growth in the first half of 2025, driven by expansion in green technology solutions including sustainable copper processing. The company's strong performance highlights the growing market for environmentally friendly copper technology innovations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto to Cut Yarwun Alumina Output to Buy Time on Waste Plans</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511179281/rio-tinto-to-cut-yarwun-alumina-output-to-buy-time-on-waste-plans</link><description>Rio Tinto is reducing production at its Yarwun alumina refinery in Australia by 40% to allow more time to develop new waste management solutions. The move reflects ongoing environmental and operational challenges in the sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>World's top aluminium producer adds markups as Trump tariffs drive consumer costs</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/worlds-top-aluminium-producer-adds-markups-trump-tariffs-drive-consumer-costs</link><description>Rio Tinto Group is imposing surcharges on aluminium shipments to the US, ranging from one to three cents above the Midwest premium, translating to an extra $2,006 per tonne on top of the raw metal price. The price for aluminium delivered to the US reached a record high last week as stockpiles shrink, with the surcharge reflecting how deeply Trump's 50% import duty has disrupted the market structure. US warehouses used by the London Metal Exchange have no aluminium inventory remaining after the last 125 tonnes were withdrawn in October.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Dips by 71 mt on Nov 18</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103625109/SMM-Flash-News:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-by-71-mt-on-Nov-18</link><description>Secondary aluminum ingot social inventory decreased by 71 metric tons on November 18, 2025, reflecting current market dynamics in aluminum supply and inventory levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 18, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-18-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd stock price decreased by 0.28%, with the current market value at ₹1,166.00 per share as investors assess the stock's performance.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chinese steel production remains weak despite rising iron ore imports</title><link>https://cyprusshippingnews.com/2025/11/18/bimco-shipping-number-of-the-week-91/</link><description>Chinese steel production fell 3% year-on-year during Q3 2025 and may have remained weak entering Q4, despite a 7% increase in iron ore imports leading to record-high portside inventories. The property sector crisis continues to suppress domestic steel demand, and the World Steel Association forecasts a 1% decrease in Chinese steel demand for 2026. Rising trade barriers are expected to slow export growth.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>New EU tariffs on steel and Chinese export controls on rare earths</title><link>https://www.wr.no/en/news/new-eu-tariffs-on-steel-and-chinese-export-controls-on-rare-earths</link><description>The EU Commission announced proposed measures to reduce tariff-free steel imports by 47% and increase out-of-quota duties to 50%, alongside enhanced traceability requirements to prevent circumvention. A final decision on ferroalloy restrictions, critical for steel production, is expected on November 18, 2025, reflecting ongoing trade tensions impacting steel capacity and supply chains.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper slips as macro concerns, firmer dollar weigh</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-slips-as-macro-concerns-firmer-dollar-weigh/</link><description>Copper prices fell on Monday, weighed down by a slightly firmer dollar and broader macroeconomic concerns. Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange dropped 0.5% to $10,802.50 per metric ton amid cautious market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper slips as macro concerns, firmer dollar weigh - Markets</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40392923</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange was down 0.5 percent at $10,802.50 per metric ton in official open outcry trading. The decline was attributed to a firmer dollar and ongoing macroeconomic worries affecting demand outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Narrative Around Copper Has Not Changed</title><link>https://www.admis.com/the-narrative-around-copper-has-not-changed/</link><description>Copper prices fell as a slightly firmer dollar and broader macro concerns weighed on prices, with LME copper down 0.5% at $10,802. Markets remain focused on upcoming US economic data for clues on Federal Reserve policy and economic activity. Chinese industrial data has been disappointing, though infrastructure and green energy investments support long-term demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Ore Bridge Accident in DRC Kills 49, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103625020/Copper-Ore-Bridge-Accident-in-DRC-Kills-49-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>A tragic copper ore bridge accident in the Democratic Republic of Congo resulted in 49 deaths. Meanwhile, LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, opening at $10,796/mt and closing lower at $10,766.5/mt, with limited supply arrivals and weak downstream demand impacting the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Shooting for Canada's next discovery: Star Copper</title><link>https://mining.com.au/shooting-for-canadas-next-discovery-star-copper/</link><description>Star Copper is advancing its copper-gold porphyry discovery in British Columbia, Canada, with recent drilling extending mineralization north and west of the Star Main target. The company plans a 2026 program focusing on step-outs and deeper testing to define the project's larger scale potential.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Extends Birthday Wishes to President of South Africa Ahead of the Formal Opening of the Platreef Mine</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/274788/Ivanhoe-Mines-Extends-Birthday-Wishes-to-President-of-South-Africa-Cyril-Ramaphosa-Ahead-of-the-Formal-Opening-of-the-Platreef-Mine-on-November-18-2025</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced the formal opening of the Platreef mine, a multi-metal project including copper, in South Africa. The company is also exploring for copper in several regions including the Western Forelands and other international locations, highlighting its growth ambitions in copper exploration.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Buenaventura to Host Investor Day on November 18, 2025 in New York</title><link>https://investingnews.com/buenaventura-to-host-investor-day-on-november-18-2025-in-new-york/</link><description>Compañía de Minas Buenaventura, Peru's largest publicly traded precious and base metals company, announced its upcoming Investor Day event. The company operates several mines in Peru and holds a significant stake in Sociedad Minera Cerro Verde, a major Peruvian copper producer.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Economic Impact Study (2025 11 18 Gunnison Cu Corp Red Cloud)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/gunnison-copper-corporate-presentationgunnison-project-ni-43-101-technical-reportjohnson-camp-mine-ce7d5edadf8bf623</link><description>Gunnison Copper Corp. released information related to its economic impact study and corporate presentation, focusing on its copper projects. The company is listed on the TSX and is advancing its copper exploration and development activities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices plummeted on November 18 breaking through multiple key support levels</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103626220/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-plummeted-on-November-18-breaking-through-multiple-key-support-levels</link><description>On November 18, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 116,950 yuan/mt, down 1,750 yuan/mt from the previous day. The SHFE nickel contract fell 1.66%, breaking the 116,000 yuan/mt support level amid hawkish US Fed signals and high market inventory, suggesting short-term weakness in nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Collapse Forces Market Repricing as Oversupply &amp; Weak Demand Challenge Producers</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-price-collapse-forces-market-repricing-as-oversupply-weak-demand-challenge-producers</link><description>Nickel prices have fallen to around US$15,000/t in mid-2025, down 10% year-over-year, with 32% of production offline due to margin stress. Oversupply persists with a forecasted 198,000t surplus in 2025 and record inventories, driven by Indonesian output despite quotas. Trade tariffs and policy shifts are causing supply chain realignment, creating pricing bifurcation and long-term market restructuring.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel futures at LME rebound on Nov 18</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/nickel-futures-at-lme-rebound-on-nov-18/151328</link><description>On November 18, nickel spot price at the London Metal Exchange rose by US$194/ton to US$15,486/ton. Meanwhile, LME nickel inventory increased by 4,722 tons to 159,146 tons, indicating a rebound in nickel futures prices despite high stock levels.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel pivot sparks legal debate in mining sector</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/11/18/nickel-pivot-sparks-legal-debate-in-mining-sector</link><description>Indonesia's government faces legal debate over new nickel mining policies aimed at addressing global nickel surplus and curbing new market entrants. The policy shift focuses on downstream production of higher-value nickel products, raising investment thresholds and impacting existing license holders. Indonesia and China contribute 75% of global supply, with Indonesia seen as a key factor in declining global nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Nickel Industries Q3 2025 nickel production up 2.38% Quarter-on-Quarter</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5104342-flash-nickel-industries-q3-2025-nickel-production-up-238-quarter-on-quarter</link><description>Nickel Industries Limited reported a 2.38% increase in nickel production for Q3 2025, reaching 31,148 tonnes. The company's RKEF projects saw a 1.29% rise in nickel pig iron output, while the HPAL projects also contributed to growth despite ongoing maintenance at one facility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Nornickel reported an 18% increase in nickel production for Q3 2025, reaching 54,000 metric tons, and maintained its annual forecast at 196,000–204,000 metric tons. The rise was attributed to higher volumes of processed raw materials after seasonal disruptions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal, Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://www.pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, rebranding it as Tenaris Coating Italy. This acquisition enhances Tenaris's capabilities in anti-corrosion coatings for pipelines, aiming to reduce delivery times, maintain quality, and lower environmental impact with coating operations in Italy and other countries.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,794 USD/T on November 18, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices declined 0.77% to 2,794 USD/T on November 18, 2025, though the commodity has risen 0.73% over the past month and 5.55% compared to the same time last year. The price represents the lowest level since October 2025, with aluminum futures in the UK having recently approached a three-year high of $2,915 on November 3rd.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Rebounds to Highest in November</title><link>https://m.fastbull.com/news-detail/steel-rebounds-to-highest-in-november-news_8500_0_2025_4_5081_3</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China rose to CNY 3,050 per tonne, the highest since early November, driven by Beijing's anti-involution policy reducing supply. Crude steel output in China fell 12% year-on-year in October, marking the lowest output since 2021, while steel exports declined 12.5% due to protectionist policies in Southeast Asia and Latin America.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices in November 2025: Market Dynamics, Price Drivers, and Industry Outlook</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LoPbqr68qII</link><description>US steel prices have surged in November 2025, with hot rolled coil (HRC) prices reaching $910 per ton. Industry insiders attribute this rally to consecutive mill price hikes and extended lead times amid a manufacturing slowdown.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China reached 3,090 CNY per tonne on November 18, 2025, a slight increase of 0.16% from the previous day and the highest since early November. Despite a 2.05% rise over the past month, prices remain 7.46% lower than a year ago, reflecting ongoing supply constraints and demand fluctuations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices rose slightly to 856 USD per ton on November 18, 2025, marking a 5.42% increase over the past month and a 24.78% rise compared to the previous year. However, prices recently hit a 31-week low earlier in November, indicating volatility in the market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest Update in the SMM Finished Steel Market</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Finished-Steel</link><description>Steel mills have lowered listed prices, leading to weak stainless steel spot prices and bottoming-out patterns in stainless steel futures. The US Fed's hawkish remarks have pressured prices further, with mills lowering prices to boost sales amid cautious procurement by traders.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>MIT researchers use CT scans to unravel mysteries of early metal production</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2025/mit-researchers-use-ct-scans-unravel-mysteries-early-metal-production-1118</link><description>MIT researchers have adapted medical X-ray CT scanning technology to study ancient copper smelting slag, providing new insights into early metal production processes. This innovative application of imaging technology advances understanding of historical copper metallurgy and its development.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME Nickel Official Prices</title><link>https://www.lme.com/en/metals/non-ferrous/lme-nickel</link><description>The LME nickel official cash price on November 18, 2025, was $14,575–$14,580 per metric ton. The market remains stable, reflecting ongoing trends of oversupply and moderate demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Attends Benchmark Week 2025 Conference, Highlighting Awaruite – A Naturally Magnetic Nickel-Cobalt Alloy as a Smelter-Free Source For North America's Critical Mi</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/18/3189863/0/en/First-Atlantic-Nickel-Attends-Benchmark-Week-2025-Conference-Highlighting-Awaruite-A-Naturally-Magnetic-Nickel-Cobalt-Alloy-as-a-Smelter-Free-Source-For-North-America-s-Critical-Mi.html</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel presented at Benchmark Week 2025 Conference, showcasing Awaruite, a naturally magnetic nickel-cobalt alloy that offers a smelter-free alternative for North America's critical mineral supply chain. This innovation represents a sustainable approach to nickel extraction and processing without traditional smelting infrastructure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of its green hydrogen production project at its plant in Aosta, Italy. The project uses a 1.008 MW Anion Exchange Membrane electrolyzer to produce 165 tons of green hydrogen annually, aiming to reduce carbon emissions by powering one of its 70 furnaces entirely. This initiative is supported by €7.9 million funding from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai approves EUR 45 million capital increase for global expansion</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/cogne-acciai-approves-eur-45-million-capital-increase-for-global-expansion/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali approved a €45 million capital increase to support its acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Pipes and to strengthen its global expansion. The investment will enhance competitiveness in aerospace, nuclear, medical, and energy sectors and includes modernization of its Aosta production facility. The company is also expanding its market presence in Europe, Asia, and the US.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali SpA Announces Its Commitment to Sustainability with ResponsibleSteel™ Certification</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-25</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has embarked on the ResponsibleSteel™ certification process to formalize its commitment to sustainability, environmental protection, and social responsibility. The company aims to lead the steel industry transformation by integrating sustainable practices into its production processes at the Aosta site.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S.A. Reports Shareholder Update on Ownership Stake and Planned Share Sales</title><link>https://www.quiverquant.com/news/Tenaris+S.A.+Reports+Shareholder+Update+on+Ownership+Stake+and+Planned+Share+Sales</link><description>Tenaris's controlling shareholders plan to sell shares while maintaining at least a 67% ownership stake, reflecting confidence in the company's stock. The board authorized share sales depending on market conditions but intends to keep a significant long-term investment. This update follows the company's ongoing share repurchase program.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>China's alumina production with 8% growth rate races ahead of primary aluminum, signalling surplus pressure</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5104514-chinas-alumina-production-with-8-growth-rate-races-ahead-of-primary-aluminum-signalling-surplus-pressure</link><description>China's metallurgical-grade alumina capacity reached about 110.32 million tonnes by September 2025, with operating capacity near 80.23%. Aluminum production capacity rose to around 45.84 million tonnes, supported by new pots and technology upgrades. Despite sluggish construction demand, strong transport sector consumption, especially from new energy vehicles, keeps smelters busy. China plans to manage alumina surplus through policy limits, market adjustments, and operational fine-tuning.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Falls to 7-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/502702</link><description>Nickel futures in the UK dropped to $14,550 per tonne in November 2025, the lowest in seven months, driven by oversupply from Indonesia's expanded nickel sector. Despite Indonesia reducing mining quotas by 120 million tons this year, global supply remains high, with stockpiles rising and muted stainless steel demand offset by increased nickel use in electric vehicles.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Attends Benchmark Week 2025</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/18/3189863/0/en/First-Atlantic-Nickel-Attends-Benchmark-Week-2025-Conference-Highlighting-Awaruite-A-Naturally-Magnetic-Nickel-Cobalt-Alloy-as-a-Smelter-Free-Source-For-North-America-s-Critical-Mi.html</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel showcased Awaruite, a naturally magnetic nickel-cobalt alloy, as a smelter-free source for North America's critical minerals. This innovation offers a sustainable alternative for battery and clean energy applications.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Dips on Nov 19</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103627317/SMM:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-on-Nov-19</link><description>Secondary aluminum ingot social inventory has declined, with prices expected to drop back slightly before fluctuating at elevated levels. The report indicates ongoing market volatility in aluminum trading.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Russia's Aluminium Giant Rusal Shuts Key Plant as China's Low-Cost Silicon Undercuts Industry</title><link>https://united24media.com/latest-news/chinas-cheap-silicon-crushes-russias-industry-rusal-forced-to-close-flagship-factory-13516</link><description>Rusal is shutting down its Kremniy silicon factory in Russia due to collapsing demand and competition from cheaper Chinese imports. The closure is part of a broader trend of production cuts across Russian heavy industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rusal Ethiopia Aluminium Smelter: $1B African Project</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/rusal-ethiopia-aluminium-smelter-project-2025/</link><description>The Rusal Ethiopia aluminum smelter project is set to reshape African manufacturing, adding 500,000 tons of annual capacity and leveraging hydropower for sustainable production. The project could make Ethiopia the continent’s largest aluminum producer if other facilities face closures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>$42M Manufacturing Facility Keeps Coast Aluminum — and Its Workers Rooted in Fresno</title><link>https://thebusinessjournal.com/42m-manufacturing-facility-keeps-coast-aluminum-and-its-workers-rooted-in-fresno/</link><description>Coast Aluminum is breaking ground on a $42 million manufacturing and distribution facility in Fresno, California, securing its workforce and future growth in the region. The new facility will open in 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Dips on Nov 19</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103627317/SMM:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-on-Nov-19</link><description>Social inventory of secondary aluminum ingots declined on November 19, 2025, as aluminum foil production is expected to pull back due to high end-use inventory. The trend reflects ongoing market adjustments in aluminum supply and demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Across the Aluminum Value Chain: How Collaboration Drives Decarbonization</title><link>https://www.alcoa.com/global/en/stories/releases?id=2025%2F11%2Facross-the-aluminum-value-chain-how-collaboration-drives-decarbonization</link><description>ELYSIS, a joint venture between Alcoa and Rio Tinto, has successfully started up its 450 kiloampere inert anode cell at Rio Tinto's smelter in Alma, Quebec, marking the first commercial-size implementation of this technology. The metal produced has approximately 40% lower carbon footprint than conventional low-carbon primary aluminum, and when combined with 50% post-consumer recycled content, creates a significantly lower-carbon packaging solution.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ball, Unilever show green aluminium can work</title><link>https://minesandmoney.com/news/industry/ball-unilever-show-green-aluminium-can-work</link><description>Ball and Unilever are using aluminum produced with Alcoa's ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology in aerosol cans, combining higher recycled content with low-carbon primary aluminum. The ELYSIS process eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions from smelting by using inert anode technology that produces oxygen instead of CO2, with industrial-scale deployment underway in Quebec, Canada.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Investing In Innovation: GBCCA Showcases New Technology To Close the Recycling Loop for Aluminium Cans</title><link>https://international-aluminium.org/investing-in-innovation-gbcca-showcases-new-technology-to-close-the-recycling-loop-for-aluminium-cans/</link><description>The Global Beverage Can Circularity Alliance (GBCCA) is showcasing breakthrough innovations including robotics, AI, and next-generation home recycling systems to achieve 100% recycling of aluminium beverage cans by 2050, with an interim goal of 80% by 2030. Advanced technologies are designed to autonomously sort and recover aluminium cans from municipal waste, unlocking immense volumes of valuable material that would otherwise be lost.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Extreme Steel Inc. Announces Strategic Recapitalization to Accelerate Growth and Expansion in Structural Steel Industry</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/11/19/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/extreme-steel-inc-announces-strategic-recapitalization-to-accelerate-growth-and-expansion-in-structural-steel-industry/2226747</link><description>Extreme Steel Inc. has announced a strategic recapitalization aimed at accelerating growth and expansion in the structural steel sector. The move is expected to enhance the company's production capabilities and market presence.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Mantel Develops New Take on Carbon Capture</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2025/mantel-develops-new-take-carbon-capture-1119</link><description>Mantel, founded by MIT alumni, has developed a carbon capture system that can be added to factories and power plants producing cement, steel, paper, and other materials, reducing carbon emissions by around 95 percent. The system captures CO2 and converts it into pure CO2 that can be transported or stored, while also generating steam as a useful revenue stream. Mantel is currently in conversations with close to 100 industrial partners worldwide, including steel plant owners.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Stainless Steel World Sustainability Day 2025</title><link>https://stainless-steel-world-event.com/sustainability-day/</link><description>The Stainless Steel World Sustainability Day 2025 brings together visionaries, engineers and decision-makers to address sustainability challenges in the stainless steel industry. The event focuses on decarbonizing production, developing low-impact alloys, and embracing circular design while navigating geopolitical strategies and global supply chain pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper extends loss as dollar strengthens</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-extends-loss-as-dollar-strengthens/</link><description>Copper prices extended losses as the strengthening U.S. dollar weighed on commodity markets. The decline reflects broader market pressures and investor sentiment tied to currency movements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper inches up as investors weigh US job data, Fed rate decision</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3WV035:0-copper-inches-up-as-investors-weigh-us-job-data-fed-rate-decision/</link><description>Copper prices edged higher after a three-day decline, as investors monitored delayed U.S. job data and awaited the Federal Reserve's rate decision. Market movements were cautious amid uncertainty about economic indicators and monetary policy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>During the day buyers' purchase willingness significantly increased, market transactions recovered and premiums rose [SMM Yangshan Spot Copper]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103628646/During-the-day-buyers-purchase-willingness-significantly-increased-market-transactions-recovered-and-premiums-rose-%5BSMM-Yangshan-Spot-Copper%5D</link><description>Buyer demand for copper increased during the day, leading to a recovery in market transactions and higher premiums. Warrant prices rose slightly, reflecting improved market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FireFly boosts Green Bay's resources</title><link>https://mining.com.au/firefly-boosts-green-bays-resources/</link><description>FireFly Metals has increased the resource estimate for its Green Bay Copper-Gold Project in Newfoundland, Canada, to 50.4 million tonnes at 2% for 1 million tonnes copper-equivalent. The project now features a high-grade core and remains open for further expansion, with underground drilling continuing into 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper inches up as investors weigh US job data, Fed rate decision</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3WV035:0-copper-inches-up-as-investors-weigh-us-job-data-fed-rate-decision/</link><description>Copper prices edged up as investors assessed US job data and the Federal Reserve's rate decision. Freeport expects its 2026 copper and gold output to be roughly in line with 2025 levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>After deadly accident, Freeport aims to restart Grasberg copper production by July 2025</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/after-deadly-accident-freeport-aims-to-restart-grasberg-copper-production-by-july-2025-11-19</link><description>Freeport-McMoRan plans to restore production at Indonesia's Grasberg copper and gold mine by July 2025 following a fatal incident. The restart will bring large-scale copper production back online.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Freeport Provides Update on Restart Plans for Grasberg Minerals District</title><link>https://investors.fcx.com/investors/news-releases/news-release-details/2025/Freeport-Provides-Update-on-Restart-Plans-for-Grasberg-Minerals-District/default.aspx</link><description>Freeport announced plans to restore large-scale production from PT Freeport Indonesia's Grasberg operations in Indonesia. The restart is expected to significantly increase copper output in the coming year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in November (Period I)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103862-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-november-period-i</link><description>The Indonesia Nickel Miners Association (APNI) announced the benchmark prices for nickel ore for the first half of November 2025, with the reference price set at $15,075.33/wmt, a 0.44% decrease from October. Prices for various nickel grades also saw slight declines compared to the previous period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 19, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 115,400-119,800 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103628480/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on November 19 was reported at 115,400-119,800 yuan/mt, averaging 117,600 yuan/mt, an increase of 650 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects a modest upward movement in the refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's 120M Ton Cut and Its Ripple on Carbon Markets</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/indonesian-government-reduces-national-nickel-mining-quotas-by-120-million-tons-impacting-global-supply/</link><description>Indonesia has reduced its national nickel mining quota by 120 million tons for 2025, cutting permitted production from 272 million tons in 2024 to 150 million tons. This reduction, aimed at preserving resources and promoting sustainable processing, is expected to tighten global nickel supply by about 35%, impacting global supply chains and nickel pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Supply-Demand Dynamics &amp; Price Outlook for Nickel Sulphate</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103624823/refined-nickel-producers-switching-to-nickel-sulphate-productionsupply-demand-dynamicsprice-outlook-for-nickel-sulphate/</link><description>Refined nickel producers are switching to nickel sulphate production amid shifting supply-demand dynamics. While nickel sulphate production is ramping up, overall downstream demand is not expected to grow significantly in November and December. Nickel salt prices are forecasted to face downward pressure due to easing supply and steady demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices reached $14,648.75 per tonne on November 19, 2025, showing a slight increase from the previous day but down 7.74% year-over-year. The market remains oversupplied due to expanded Indonesian production capacity despite recent quota cuts. Stockpiles at LME warehouses have increased, reflecting ongoing supply surplus amid mixed demand from stainless steel and electric vehicle sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>PE eyes BHP's Nickel West as China tightens rare earth grip</title><link>https://www.marketsgroup.org/news/pe-eyes-bhps-nickel-west-as-china-tightens-rare-earth-grip</link><description>Private equity firms are showing interest in BHP's Nickel West amid China's tightening control over rare earths and nickel supply chains. Nickel prices have halved over three years due to Indonesian low-cost production. Strategic moves by Japanese companies and investors aim to diversify nickel supply outside Chinese influence, with projects in Australia expected to produce competitive nickel volumes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia limits new nickel permits to add value to production</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/indonesia-limits-new-nickel-permits-to-add-value-to-production/</link><description>Indonesia has stopped approving new permits for nickel plants producing certain intermediate products without further processing plans, aiming to push the industry up the value chain. This policy is expected to reduce oversupply and encourage investment in downstream processing, potentially causing project delays or cancellations. The move aligns with Indonesia's 2020 ban on raw nickel ore exports to boost domestic processing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>$42M manufacturing facility keeps Coast Aluminum — and its workers</title><link>https://thebusinessjournal.com/42m-manufacturing-facility-keeps-coast-aluminum-and-its-workers-rooted-in-fresno/</link><description>Coast Aluminum, a Hayward-based aluminum supplier, is breaking ground on a $42 million, 163,000-square-foot manufacturing and distribution facility near Fresno Yosemite International Airport. The new facility, expected to open in 2026, represents a major expansion securing the company's future workforce and operational flexibility in the region.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Will Carbon-Free Aluminum Packaging Partnerships Shift Alcoa's Trajectory?</title><link>https://simplywall.st/stocks/us/materials/nyse-aa/alcoa/news/will-carbon-free-aluminum-packaging-partnerships-shift-alcoa/amp</link><description>Ball Corporation, Unilever, and Alcoa announced the first use of ELYSIS® carbon-free aluminum smelting technology in consumer packaging, featuring cans with 50% ELYSIS aluminum and 50% recycled content. This partnership exemplifies cross-industry efforts to accelerate low-carbon innovation and meets growing global demand for sustainable materials ahead of COP30.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Cochilco hikes 2025-2026 copper price forecasts to record highs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/cochilco-hikes-2025-2026-copper-price-forecasts-to-record-highs/</link><description>Chile's state copper commission Cochilco increased its copper price forecasts to record highs, projecting average prices of $4.45 per pound for 2025 and $4.55 per pound for 2026, up from the previous $4.30 forecast. The higher forecasts reflect weak production in Chile, including issues at major mines like Collahuasi and El Teniente, with supply expected to lag demand through at least 2030.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Analysis: despite Chinese slowdown worries, copper and aluminum poised for further gains</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/analysis-despite-chinese-slowdown-worries-copper-and-aluminum-poised-for-further-gains/</link><description>Despite concerns about a slowdown in China, copper and aluminum markets are expected to continue gaining. The analysis suggests that base metals, including aluminum, are set to finish the year on a positive note, reflecting underlying demand and supply dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 20, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-20-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's stock surged by 0.25%, currently trading at ₹1,167.00 with a PE ratio of 46.7800, reflecting market movements in the Indian steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's rebar output down 2.0 percent in January-October 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/chinas-rebar-output-down-20-percent-in-january-october-2025-1420272.htm</link><description>China's rebar production totaled 158.01 million mt in January-October 2025, down 2.0 percent year-on-year. In October alone, rebar production fell 18.6 percent year-on-year to 14.34 million mt, while wire rod production increased 0.4 percent and welded pipe output rose 3.7 percent for the full period.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Ship scrap steel can help decarbonise European steelmaking: Report</title><link>https://shippingtelegraph.com/shipping-reports/ship-scrap-steel-can-help-decarbonise-european-steelmaking-report/</link><description>A new report highlights how recycled ship scrap steel can reduce CO₂ emissions by up to 80% compared to virgin materials in European steelmaking. EU/EFTA-owned ship demolitions are forecast to peak at approximately 12 Mt of scrap steel per year, potentially satisfying 10-15 Mt of the EU's annual scrap steel demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel consumption in the US: major upheavals</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/posts/steel-consumption-in-the-us-major-upheavals/</link><description>U.S. steel imports are projected to decline by approximately 12% annually by the end of 2025, with monthly imports unlikely to exceed 1.5 million tons. This represents a significant shift in American steel consumption patterns.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 20, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-20-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's stock surged 0.25% and is trading at ₹1,167.00 with a PE ratio of 46.78. The update provides current market performance data for the Indian steel producer.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper rebounds as stocks stabilise, amid supply worries</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-rebounds-as-stocks-stabilise-amid-supply-worries/</link><description>Copper prices rebounded as market stocks stabilized, with prices climbing 1.7% to $37,505. The rebound occurred amid ongoing concerns about copper supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rises on bullish Chile outlook as investors weigh Fed rate decision</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3WW03U:0-copper-rises-on-bullish-chile-outlook-as-investors-weigh-fed-rate-decision/</link><description>Copper prices rose following Cochilco's bullish outlook for Chilean copper production and the commission's record-high price forecasts of $4.45 for 2025 and $4.55 for 2026. Market movements were also influenced by investor considerations regarding Federal Reserve rate decisions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rises</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40393275</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.8 percent to USD 10,810 per metric ton in official open-outcry trading. The increase reflects broader market strength in copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chile's Cochilco hikes 2025 and 2026 copper price forecasts to record highs</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/chiles-cochilco-hikes-2025-and-2026-copper-price-forecasts-to-record-highs-2025-11-20</link><description>Chile's state copper commission, Cochilco, has raised its copper price forecasts for 2025 and 2026 to record highs. The agency expects Chilean copper production to grow by just 0.1% to 5.51 million metric tons in 2025, with a 2.5% increase projected for 2026, reaching 5.6 million metric tons.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US fund managers have established positions in Canadian copper ore companies while LME copper fluctuated and closed higher overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103629537/US-fund-managers-have-established-positions-in-Canadian-copper-ore-companies-while-LME-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-higher-overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>US fund managers have taken positions in Canadian copper ore companies amid fluctuating LME copper prices, which closed higher overnight. LME copper inventories rose, while SHFE warrant inventories declined, reflecting ongoing shifts in supply and demand dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell to their lowest since November 2020 amid a pessimistic Federal Reserve outlook that outweighed Indonesia's plans to sharply cut nickel mining quotas from 272 million tons to 150 million tons next year. The metal, crucial for EV batteries, has declined about 8% this year due to new supply waves and slowing EV sales, with prices dropping 1.8% to $15,235 a ton on the LME.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices edged higher on November 20</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103630924/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-higher-on-November-20-while-the-US-Fed-remained-deeply-divided-over-whether-to-cut-interest-rates-in-December</link><description>On November 20, refined nickel prices in China edged up by 600 yuan/mt to an average of 118,200 yuan/mt, reflecting a slight recovery amid mixed market signals including US Federal Reserve interest rate uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Smelter Restrictions Explained</title><link>https://chinaglobalsouth.com/2025/11/20/indonesia-nickel-smelter-restrictions-chinese-commentator/</link><description>Indonesia has introduced restrictions on new nickel-smelter investments to slow the rapid expansion of its nickel sector, which has caused oversupply and environmental concerns. However, analysts warn that without upstream mining permit limits and integrated policies, the impact may be limited, as many smelters are already operational or under construction, with China playing a central role in the sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Smelter Restrictions Explained</title><link>https://chinaglobalsouth.com/2025/11/20/indonesia-nickel-smelter-restrictions-chinese-commentator/</link><description>Indonesia has imposed restrictions on new nickel smelter investments to control its rapid nickel sector expansion, which has caused environmental and social strain. Although the freeze on new smelter licenses slows future growth, existing projects continue, and without upstream mining limits, the policy may have limited impact on reducing oversupply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>NexMetals Mining Eliminates Smelter Risk and Secures US$80M to Fast-Track Botswana Copper-Nickel Assets</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nexmetals-mining-eliminates-smelter-risk-and-secures-us-80m-to-fast-track-botswana-copper-nickel-assets</link><description>NexMetals Mining secured US$80 million in funding and eliminated a US$21 million debt, enabling it to fast-track copper-nickel assets in Botswana without the need for costly smelter infrastructure. The metallurgical breakthrough reduces capital costs and allows cobalt recovery, with exploration upside expected to expand resources significantly in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Creek Platinum Announces Closing of $1.5 Million Tranche of Private Placement</title><link>https://investingnews.com/nickel-creek-platinum-announces-closing-of-1-5-million-tranche-of-private-placement/</link><description>Nickel Creek Platinum closed a $1.5 million tranche of financing to support exploration at its Nickel Shäw Project, a large undeveloped nickel sulphide deposit in Canada. The funds will be used in 2026 to explore additional nickel and copper mineralization, with the project benefiting from excellent infrastructure and access to shipping ports.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Attends Benchmark Week 2025 Conference Highlighting Awaruite, a Naturally Magnetic Nickel-Cobalt Alloy as a Smelter-Free Source for North America’s Critical Minerals Supply</title><link>https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/first-atlantic-nickel-attends-benchmark-week-2025-conference-highlighting-awaruite-a-naturally-magnetic-nickel-cobalt-alloy-as-a-smelter-free-source-for-north-america-s-critical-minerals-supply-1035572779</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel presented its Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project at Benchmark Week 2025, promoting it as a secure, low-impact domestic source of nickel and cobalt. The project aims to provide a smelter-free solution to North America's critical minerals supply challenges.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Crawford Gets Federal Priority Status</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/federal-priority-critical-minerals-2025-development-canada/</link><description>Canada Nickel's Crawford project has received federal priority status for its revolutionary IPT Carbonation process, which transforms mining waste into permanent carbon storage and produces carbon-neutral critical minerals. This technology supports sustainable mining and meets growing demand for low-carbon supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Strengthen Indonesia's Global Nickel Leadership</title><link>https://vale.com/w/strengthen-indonesia-s-global-nickel-leadership-pt-vale-indonesia-and-huayou-commits-to-climate-aligned-technology-pathways-at-cop30</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia and Huayou are deploying advanced hydrometallurgical technologies, including waste heat recovery and CO2 solidification, to reduce emissions and carbon intensity in nickel production. Their efforts aim to deliver low-carbon nickel and support Indonesia's role in the global clean energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Breakthrough Strengthens North America</title><link>https://icttm.org/nickel-breakthrough-strengthens-north-america/</link><description>A recent nickel technology breakthrough is set to enhance North America's clean energy supply chain, supporting industries such as electric vehicles and batteries with more sustainable and efficient production methods.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>