<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:00:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CHAMPION IRON REPORTS ITS FY2026 THIRD QUARTER RESULTS AND ADVANCES THE DRPF PROJECT AS PLANNED</title><link>https://newsroom.championiron.com/2026-01-28-CHAMPION-IRON-REPORTS-ITS-FY2026-THIRD-QUARTER-RESULTS-AND-ADVANCES-THE-DRPF-PROJECT-AS-PLANNED</link><description>Champion Iron reported improved iron ore concentrate production in Q3 FY2026, with Fe recovery rates reaching 79.7% compared to 79.1% in the prior year period. The company's DRPF project to upgrade Bloom Lake's capacity to DR quality pellet feed iron ore is progressing as planned, with initial commercial shipments anticipated by the end of the first half of 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Aluminum Alloy Daily Report] Aluminum prices surged</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103743863/aluminum-prices-soar-secondary-alloy-firms-hike-rates-amid-thin-trading</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices surged suddenly on January 28, 2026, with the most-traded continuous contract reaching new levels by 11:30, prompting secondary alloy firms to hike rates amid thin trading conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>January 28, 2026, SHFE aluminum prices experienced a sudden surge - SMM analysis</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103743247/january-28-2026-shfe-aluminum-prices-experienced-a-sudden-surge-smm-analysis</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices surged 4.54% to 25,345 yuan/mt on January 28, 2026, driven by US-Iran geopolitical tensions disrupting aluminum trade and raw material transport, funds shifting from precious to base metals, and expectations of domestic alumina refinery production cuts. Open interest rose by about 68,000 lots, boosting market activity. The report warns of potential price corrections as sentiment cools.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 36-week High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel increased to 941.00 USD/T, marking its highest level since April 2025. Over the past 4 weeks, Hot-Rolled Coil Steel gained 2.87%, and over the last 12 months, it increased 31.63%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>2026 Circular Steel Summit: Taking stock of tariffs</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/2026-circular-steel-summit-taking-stock-of-tariffs/</link><description>At the 2026 Fastmarkets Circular Steel Summit in Houston on January 28, industry panelists discussed U.S. tariffs, noting that 18% of steel imports were covered by Section 232 tariffs by end-2024. Tariffs have boosted domestic investment confidence and raw material supply, though 'tariff exhaustion' complicates budgeting. Speakers anticipate supply chain adjustments but see ample domestic product availability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper at Record Highs: What the Rally Means for Markets</title><link>https://www.canadianminingreport.com/blog/copper-prices-at-record-highs-are-sending-a-message-markets-can-t-ignore</link><description>Copper prices shattered records in early 2026, reaching a new all-time high of $6.11 USD/lb in January before correcting to $5.97 USD/lb. The rally reflects supply disruptions, tariff concerns, and explosive demand from AI infrastructure and the energy transition, marking a 39.86% year-over-year gain.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>St. Louis-based EGA America's parent to build $4B Oklahoma facility with aluminum smelter</title><link>https://www.bizjournals.com/stlouis/news/2026/01/28/emirates-global-aluminium-century-partner-smelter.html</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium (EGA) and partners will build a $4B smelter in Oklahoma producing 750,000 tonnes annually, doubling U.S. production. Construction starts this year, expecting 1,000 permanent jobs. It aims to expand domestic aluminum capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Northstar Gold Corp. Announces $4 Million Digital Co-Investment to Advance Cam Copper and Novamera's Surgical Mining</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/281897/Northstar-Gold-Corp.-Announces-4-Million-Digital-CoInvestment-to-Advance-Cam-Copper-and-Novameras-Surgical-Mining</link><description>Northstar Gold Corp. has secured a $4 million digital co-investment to advance its Cam Copper Project using Novamera's Surgical Mining technology. This innovative approach targets mineralized zones from surface with large-diameter rotary drill holes, reducing waste, surface disturbance, and permitting timelines compared to conventional mining. The project promotes sustainable extraction of critical minerals like copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Constellium Inaugurates New Finishing Lines at Singen, Marking Completion of Major Investment</title><link>https://www.constellium.com</link><description>Constellium announced the successful start-up and inauguration of new finishing lines at its Singen plant in Germany, completing a €30 million investment in partnership with Lotte Infracell. The facility will supply high-quality aluminum foilstock for battery applications in Europe, supporting the growing demand for sustainable aluminum solutions in electric vehicle production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Daily Aluminum price, LME SHFE Price of Aluminum live | SMM</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices surged suddenly on January 28, 2026, with the most-traded contract reaching 25,345 yuan/mt, up 4.54% from the previous settlement. Open interest increased by about 68,000 contracts, showing heightened trading activity. Prices are consolidating at high levels due to macro factors despite limited supply-demand changes and high inventories.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Futures Rise: Fresh Bets Fuel Price Surge</title><link>https://money.rediff.com/news/market/aluminium-futures-rise-fresh-bets-fuel-price-surge/40977220260129</link><description>Aluminum futures on the Multi Commodity Exchange rose 5.75% to Rs 350.50 per kg on January 29, 2026, driven by speculators building positions amid positive spot trends and industry demand. The February contract saw significant volume in trading.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>High-purity alumina HPA First Project bags $175 million</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/2026/01/29/high-purity-alumina-hpa-first-project-bags-175-million/</link><description>Alpha HPA secured a $75 million investment from Australia's National Reconstruction Fund for its HPA First Project in Gladstone, producing ultra-high purity alumina for semiconductors, lithium-ion batteries, and pharmaceuticals. The project uses 100% renewable energy via Smart SX Technology, recycling nearly 100% of reagents to yield 5N+ purity materials. It positions Australia as a key supplier in global supply chains for AI and critical manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Steel Production Up 4.6% Year-on-Year in Late January 2026</title><link>https://www.indexbox.io/blog/us-steel-production-up-46-year-on-year-in-late-january-2026/</link><description>U.S. raw steel production increased 4.6% year-on-year for the week ending January 24, 2026, reaching 1.78 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.9%. Year-to-date production through January 24 totaled 6.016 million net tons, up 3.4% compared to the same period last year, with broad-based production strength across all major U.S. steelmaking regions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 1.3 percent - week 4, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-13-percent-week-3-2026-1431863.htm</link><description>According to AISI data, U.S. domestic raw steel production for the week ending January 24, 2026, was 1.778 million net tons with a 76.9% capacity utilization rate, representing a 1.3% increase from the previous week. The production level marks a 4.6% increase compared to the same week in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Record Highs: Geopolitical Tensions and Dollar Impact</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/copper-sets-record-amid-geopolitical-risks-weak-dollar/</link><description>Copper prices hit record highs amid geopolitical risks and a weak dollar, with the Shanghai Futures Exchange contract surging 6.35% to 108,740 yuan per metric ton and the London Metal Exchange benchmark climbing 6.63% to $13,953.50 a ton. The rally follows significant yearly gains fueled by supply concerns from mine disruptions and U.S. tariff threats. Other metals like zinc, lead, nickel, and tin also advanced.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Collaborates with SQM to Explore for Copper in Chile; LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103744065/ivanhoe-collaborates-with-sqm-to-explore-for-copper-in-chile-lme-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-higher-overnight-smm-coppe</link><description>LME copper opened at $13,111/mt overnight, fluctuated significantly, and closed at $13,120/mt, up 0.74%. Shanghai SHFE copper showed a 'V' shape, closing at 103,170 yuan/mt after probing a low. Imported and secondary copper prices saw slight declines in premiums.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Rallies to All-Time High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/520956</link><description>Copper futures surged nearly 7% to above $6.3 per pound, hitting record highs driven by demand for real assets amid geopolitical and trade uncertainties, including U.S. President Trump's threats against Iran, and a sudden dollar drop. The price reached an all-time high of 6.11 USD/Lbs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold and Copper Lead Metals Rally, Dollar Weakens: Markets Wrap</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/gold-and-copper-lead-metals-rally-dollar-weakens-markets-wrap/</link><description>Copper jumped 5% on the London Metal Exchange as part of a broader metals rally led by gold and silver, benefiting from a weakening dollar that makes dollar-denominated assets more attractive. Brent crude also climbed to its highest since September amid the market movements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Collaborates with SQM to Explore for Copper in Chile</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103744065/ivanhoe-collaborates-with-sqm-to-explore-for-copper-in-chile-lme-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-higher-overnight-smm-coppe</link><description>Ivanhoe has partnered with SQM to explore for copper resources in Chile. LME copper futures opened at $13,111/mt and closed at $13,120/mt with a 0.74% gain, while spot prices across Shanghai, imported copper, and secondary copper markets showed mixed movements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Rally: Mining Stocks Rise on AI Demand</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-price-rally-2026-technological-demand-energy/</link><description>Copper prices have rallied to around $13,000 per metric ton, driving gains in mining stocks as technological demand, particularly from AI applications, supports the commodity. The price surge reflects broader market momentum in the metals sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold and Copper Lead Metals Rally, Dollar Weakens: Markets Wrap</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/gold-and-copper-lead-metals-rally-dollar-weakens-markets-wrap/</link><description>Copper jumped 5% on the London Metal Exchange as part of a broader commodities rally, hitting all-time highs alongside gold and silver amid a weaker dollar and rising geopolitical tensions. The rally was supported by currency weakness, as these dollar-priced assets benefited from greenback decline.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mantoverde makes workers new offer as strike continues</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/mantoverde-makes-workers-new-offer-as-strike-continues-2026-01-29</link><description>Mantoverde copper mine in Chile has made a new offer to workers amid ongoing strike action. In 2025, the operation produced 62,308 tons of copper sulfide concentrate and 32,807 tons of copper cathodes, representing approximately 0.4% of global copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>NIC: Record EBITDA margins, strategic asset sale, and strong nickel prices drive positive outlook</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/urn:summary_document_transcript:quartr.com:2684283:0-nic-record-ebitda-margins-strategic-asset-sale-and-strong-nickel-prices-drive-positive-outlook/</link><description>Analysis of nickel market dynamics highlighting record EBITDA margins and strategic asset sales benefiting from strong nickel prices and positive market outlook.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries December 2025 quarter: Strong HPAL margins, mining rebounds</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/29/nickel-industries-december-2025-quarter-strong-hpal-margins-mining-rebounds/</link><description>Nickel Industries reported US$37.3 million adjusted EBITDA for Q4 2025, with strong HPAL margins despite mining delays from late government approval. Operations rebounded, targeting over 1.4 million wet metric tonnes of ore sales in January. The company anticipates a higher 2026 mining quota of 19 million wmt and progress on the ENC HPAL project.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Mines Q4 2025 slides: HPAL strength offsets mining challenges</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/company-news/nickel-mines-q4-2025-slides-hpal-strength-offsets-mining-challenges-93CH-4471728</link><description>Nickel Mines' HPAL operations produced 2,144 tonnes of nickel at 43% above nameplate capacity, with attributable EBITDA up 32% to US$17.2 million. RKEF production rose 1% to 31,561 tonnes despite EBITDA decline. The ENC project advances toward commissioning, supported by a major solar project for low-carbon production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Limited, Q4 2025 Earnings Call, Jan 29, 2026</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/transcript-nickel-industries-limited-q4-2025-earnings-call-jan-29-2026-ce7e5bdedb8ef520</link><description>Nickel Industries held its Q4 2025 earnings call on January 29, 2026, discussing quarterly activities. The webcast covered operational updates and operator instructions. It provides insights into recent production and financial performance.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Limited, Q4 2025 Earnings Call</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/transcript-nickel-industries-limited-q4-2025-earnings-call-jan-29-2026-ce7e5bdedb8ef520</link><description>Nickel Industries Limited held its Q4 2025 earnings call on January 29, 2026, discussing financial performance and operational updates. The transcript covers nickel production advancements and potential sustainability innovations in their operations. This reflects ongoing developments in the nickel sector relevant to technology and market sustainability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fluctuated on January 29, 2026, falling to $3,230.50 USD/T (down 1.12%) before rising to $3,306.20 USD/T (up 1.20%), with monthly gains of 8-10% and yearly increases over 26%. On January 28, prices hit 3,296 USD/T, a near 4-year high, up 8.78% in four weeks and 24.6% over 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fluctuated on January 29, 2026, reaching 3,306.20 USD/T amid China's capacity limits at 45 million tons, production disruptions in Iceland, Mozambique, and Australia, and rising demand from the energy transition. Traders worry about global producers' ability to ramp up supply quickly. A weaker US dollar and geopolitical tensions further supported prices, with recent rises hitting over three-year highs due to Chinese supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking raw material prices increase through January</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/29/steelmaking-raw-material-prices-increase-through-january/</link><description>All but one of the tracked steelmaking raw materials, including coking coal, pig iron, shredded scrap, busheling scrap, zinc, and aluminum, increased in price over the last month, with collective prices up 8% month-on-month. Shredded scrap rose to $420 per gross ton and busheling to $423/gt, 8-14% higher than three months ago. Iron ore fines eased to $106/dmt, down 1% month-on-month, while buyers expect further scrap price increases in February due to weather disruptions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Stainless Steel Market Watch Intensifies as Inventory Rises and Demand Remains Sluggish</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/stainless-steel-market-watch-intensifies-as-inventory-rises-and-demand-remains-sluggish/</link><description>Social inventory of stainless steel in China rose to 853,000 mt by January 29, 2026, up 1.05% week-over-week. Demand remains sluggish amid rising inventories.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking Raw Material Prices Increase Through January</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/29/steelmaking-raw-material-prices-increase-through-january/</link><description>Steelmaking raw materials experienced broad-based price increases in January, with coking coal, pig iron, scrap, zinc, and aluminum all rising. Collectively, prices rose 8% month-over-month, with seven of eight tracked products more expensive than three months ago and all higher than year-ago levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The nickel production of Nornickel Russia in 2026 is expected to be similar to the previous year</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/01/29/the-nickel-production-of-nornickel-russia-in-2026-is-expected-to-be-similar-to-the-previous-year</link><description>Nornickel of Russia expects its nickel production to reach 193,000-203,000 metric tons in 2026, roughly in line with 2025 output of 198,521 tonnes. The company attributes slight reductions to a temporary rise in disseminated ore percentages and is upgrading mining equipment while starting construction at Skalisty Mine to restore rich ore production. CEO Vladimir Potanin described the decline as temporary, with no plans for artificial cuts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The growing role of critical minerals in global innovation</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2026/01/critical-minerals-innovation-earth-surface/</link><description>Leaders at the World Economic Forum Annual Meeting 2026 will discuss balancing environmental protection with economic growth in critical minerals mining, including nickel for EVs. Demand for these minerals is projected to rise over 3.4 times by 2040 to achieve net zero by 2050. The article emphasizes responsible mining practices to build trust through environmental stewardship and community benefits.[1]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto strengthens its global low-carbon aluminium footprint through joint acquisition with Chalco of Votorantim's interest in CBA</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2026/rio-tinto-strengthens-its-global-low-carbon-aluminium-footprint-through-joint-acquisition-with-chalco-of-votorantims-interest-in-cba</link><description>Rio Tinto and Chalco have jointly acquired Votorantim's interest in CBA to expand low-carbon aluminum production. This move enhances Rio Tinto's global sustainable aluminum capabilities. The acquisition aligns with efforts to reduce carbon emissions in aluminum manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Metal Stocks Plunge on Profit-Taking, Fed Fears</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/Commodities/Metal-Stocks-Plunge-on-Profit-Taking-Fed-Fears/697c40a85fc43f26c545dd8f</link><description>The Nifty Metal index plummeted nearly 5% on January 30, 2026, reversing recent gains as investors booked profits amid Federal Reserve concerns.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Today, January 30: Why Are Copper Rates Hitting Record Highs</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/business/copper-price-today-january-30-why-are-copper-rates-hitting-record-highs-167203/</link><description>Copper prices reached record highs above $14,000 per ton on January 30, 2026, driven by speculative buying from Chinese funds, weak US dollar, and demand from renewables and electrification. Physical demand remains low with high exchange stocks, potentially leading to corrections. Supply constraints from slow mine development exacerbate price volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Shining! Metal's record rally has boosted the fortunes of this ...</title><link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/copper-price-rally-hindustan-copper-boost-govt-stake-lic-value-unlocking-share-returns-ws-e-19836582.htm</link><description>Hindustan Copper plans to expand mine capacity from 4 MT to over 12 MT with ₹2,000 crore investment over five to six years, targeting 20% volume growth in FY2026 at over 40% margins. The expansion supports rising copper demand from EVs, renewables, AI data centers, and grid expansion amid a weak US dollar. Production costs are around $5,500 per tonne.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Final Cowley assays expand copper system</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/30/northern-neighbors/final-cowley-assays-expand-copper-system/9517.html</link><description>Final assays from Cowley expand the copper system, as reported in recent exploration updates. The findings indicate potential growth in copper resources at the site.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Autonomous Copper Refining at Olympic Dam: Tech Guide - Olympic Dam's Revolutionary Autonomous Copper Refining Technology Breakthrough</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-processing-technology-metallurgy-2026/</link><description>Olympic Dam has introduced a revolutionary autonomous copper refining technology featuring robotic arms for advanced processing. This innovation represents a breakthrough in copper metallurgy and processing technology. The article provides a tech guide on this development published today.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FNI unit ships first nickel ore cargo for 2026</title><link>https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2026/01/30/727443/fni-unit-ships-first-nickel-ore-cargo-for-2026/</link><description>Ipilan Nickel Corp., a subsidiary of Global Ferronickel Holdings, Inc., shipped its first nickel ore cargo of 2026, consisting of 53,912 wet metric tons of low-grade nickel ore to China. The company targets production of at least 1.5 million WMT for the year, with a sales mix of 52.6% low-grade and 47.4% medium-grade ore. Mine development includes expanding areas, building haul roads, and installing environmental protections to meet targets while complying with regulations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Solway to restart Guatemala nickel plant after price surge</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/solway-to-restart-guatemala-nickel-plant-after-price-surge/</link><description>Swiss-based Solway Investment Group plans to restart its PRONICO nickel plant and CGN mine in Guatemala within months, following a nickel price surge to $19,160 per ton and the lifting of U.S. sanctions. The facility has an annual capacity of 25,000 metric tons of ferronickel, with the mine capable of extracting up to 2.2 million tons of nickel ore. Restart is anticipated around April to May 2026, indicating high prices are enabling resumption of previously curtailed production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Global Ferronickel unit sets 2026 output target</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2026/01/30/business/top-business/global-ferronickel-unit-sets-2026-output-target/2268361</link><description>Global Ferronickel announced that its Ipilan unit has commenced 2026 mining operations with the first nickel ore shipment. The company has set specific output targets for the year amid ongoing operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries cements leadership in ENC, welcomes Sphere as strategic partner</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/30/nickel-industries-cements-leadership-in-enc-welcomes-sphere-as-strategic-partner/</link><description>Nickel Industries increased its stake in the ENC project to 46%, becoming the largest shareholder, while Sphere acquired a 10% interest at a US$2.4 billion valuation, reducing cash outflows by US$207 million. The company secured a 15-year MOU for 14 million WMT/year limonite ore supply for the Sampala Project. This strengthens financial flexibility and positions Nickel Industries for battery-grade nickel production as ENC nears commissioning.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries completes strategic partner’s entry into ENC project, revises acquisition terms</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-completes-strategic-partner-s-entry-into-enc-project-revises-acquisition-terms</link><description>ASX-listed Nickel Industries completed Sphere's entry into the ENC project and revised acquisition terms. The update enhances project ownership and financial terms for the nickel processor.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries cements leadership in ENC, welcomes Sphere as strategic partner</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/30/nickel-industries-cements-leadership-in-enc-welcomes-sphere-as-strategic-partner/</link><description>Nickel Industries increases its stake in the ENC project to 46%, becoming the largest shareholder, while welcoming Sphere as a 10% strategic partner at a US$2.4 billion valuation. This deal reduces future cash outflows by US$207 million and secures a 15-year exclusive limonite ore supply MOU for the Sampala Project. The partnership supports transition to battery-grade nickel and cobalt for electric vehicles, enhancing supply chain reliability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Proportion of Liquid Aluminum in January Declined, Expected to Further Drop in February</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103748773</link><description>China's aluminum production in January 2026 rose 2.7% year-over-year and 0.5% month-over-month, but the proportion of liquid aluminum fell 4.4 percentage points to 72.1% due to weak demand, high prices, and production restrictions. Casting ingot volume decreased 5.9% YoY but increased 19.4% MoM. In February, production is expected to decline with fewer days, and liquid aluminum proportion to drop further to 64.4% amid Chinese New Year and high prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Proportion of Liquid Aluminum in January Declined, Expected to Face a Significant Drop in February: SMM Analysis</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103748773/the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminum-in-january-declined-expected-to-face-a-significant-drop-in-february-smm-analysis</link><description>China's aluminum production in January 2026 increased 2.7% year-over-year and 0.5% month-over-month, but the proportion of liquid aluminum declined 4.4 percentage points to 72.1% due to weak demand, high prices, and production restrictions. Aluminum casting ingot volume decreased 5.9% YoY but rose 19.4% MoM. Existing capacity stood at 46.209 million mt, with operating capacity at 44.996 million mt; February production is expected to drop significantly amid fewer days and Chinese New Year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,125 CNY/T on January 30, 2026, down 0.83% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices rose 0.94%, but remain 4.08% lower than a year ago. Steel rebar futures rose toward a 5-month high of CNY 3,150 per tonne amid improved outlook for ferrous metal demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Pulls Back from 5-Month High</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/steel-pulls-back-from-5-month-high/</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China fell to CNY 3,100 per tonne after reaching five-month highs of CNY 3,160 on January 29. The pullback reflects pressure on prices following recent gains.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Eases from Surge in Volatile Session</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures in the US surged over 10% to a record high of $6.5 per pound before trimming gains to the $6.2 mark in a volatile trading session. Markets gauged the fundamentals behind the recent speculative rally as copper led the surge in base metals amid bets of higher demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why are copper prices rising now: 5 reasons</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/5-reasons-why-copper-prices-are-rising-copper-prices-smash-records-as-supply-constraints-collide-with-ai-driven-demand/articleshow/127775693.cms</link><description>Copper prices hit an all-time high of $14,125 per metric ton on the London Metal Exchange, representing a 7.9% single-day surge. The rally stems from a perfect storm of speculative intensity, structural supply deficits, AI-driven demand, and geopolitical factors including tariff uncertainty.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>3 Top Copper Stocks to Watch as Copper Prices Skyrocket: BHP, FCX, SCCO</title><link>https://247wallst.com/investing/2026/01/30/3-top-copper-stocks-to-watch-as-copper-prices-skyrocket-bhp-fcx-scco/</link><description>Major copper producers rallied as copper prices extended gains, driven by supply disruptions in South America, China's infrastructure stimulus, and accelerating demand from electric vehicle and renewable energy sectors. Copper futures are up 40% since August, with major producers like Southern Copper surging 132% over the past year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Surges Past US$14,000: Best ASX Copper Stocks for 2026</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/copper-hits-record-highs/</link><description>Copper prices hit record highs of US$14,527 amid AI data centre demand and supply shocks. The article highlights top ASX copper stocks positioned to benefit from the sustained rally.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel price fell to 17,555 USD/T on January 30, 2026, down 5.21% from the previous day, easing from a 19-month high of $19,000 touched in late January. The decline follows assessments of lower supply from Indonesia's output cuts, with nickel futures at $18,500 per tonne. Over the past month, prices have risen 4.81%, up 15.27% year-over-year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Proportion of Liquid Aluminum in January Declined, Expected to Face a Significant Drop in February (SMM Analysis)</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103748773-the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminum-in-january-declined-expected-to-face-a-significant-drop-in-february-smm-emanalysisem</link><description>China's aluminum production in January 2026 increased 2.7% YoY and 0.5% MoM, but the proportion of liquid aluminum declined 4.4 percentage points to 72.1% due to weak demand, high prices, and production restrictions. As of end-January, existing capacity stood at 46.209 million mt and operating capacity at 44.996 million mt. February production is forecast to drop MoM with liquid aluminum proportion falling sharply to 64.4% amid Chinese New Year and high prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The proportion of liquid aluminium in January declined, expected to face a significant drop in February</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminium-in-january-declined-expected-to-face-a-significant-drop-in-february-117109</link><description>China's aluminium production in January 2026 rose 2.7% YoY and 0.5% MoM, with liquid aluminium proportion dropping 4.4 points to 72.1% from weak demand and restrictions. End-January capacity was 46.209 million tonnes existing and 44.996 million tonnes operating. February sees expected MoM production decline and liquid aluminium proportion at 64.4%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Rises Toward 5-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China rose to CNY 3,150 per tonne, approaching five-month highs of CNY 3,160 from January 7th. The rally was driven by efforts to improve the financial balance of Chinese property developers, which stoked optimism for ferrous metal demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Eases from 19-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures eased to $18,500 per tonne from a 19-month high of $19,000 in late January. Markets are assessing lower supply from major producers after Indonesia signaled output cuts by reducing mining permits to 260 million wet tonnes. Despite the recent dip, contracts remain sharply higher year-to-date amid supply risks.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 17,555 USD/T on January 30, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped 5.21% to 17,555 USD/T on January 30, 2026, after sinking to $17,700 per tonne due to a rebounding dollar closing speculative positions in base metals. Over the past month, prices rose 4.81%, and year-over-year they are up 15.27%. UK nickel futures hovered near $19,000 throughout January before the decline.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel is down by 5.03%</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel decreased 5.03% to 17,588 USD/T on January 30, 2026. This follows a pullback from recent highs amid broader base metals weakness. Year-to-date gains persist due to supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium jolts the market as cash offer slides to $3,110 per tonne</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-jolts-the-market-as-cash-offer-slides-to-3-110-per-tonne-117117</link><description>LME cash aluminum bid dropped sharply from $3,323 to $3,109 per tonne, a 6.4% decline, with 3-month contracts also falling around 6%. Inventories decreased slightly by 2,000 tonnes to 495,725 tonnes on January 30. The move highlights market volatility amid ongoing supply and demand shifts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Proportion of Liquid Aluminum in January Declined, Expected to Face a Significant Drop in February</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103748773/the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminum-in-january-declined-expected-to-face-a-significant-drop-in-february-emsmmem-emanalysisem</link><description>China's aluminum production in January 2026 increased 2.7% YoY and 0.5% MoM, but the proportion of liquid aluminum declined 4.4 percentage points to 72.1% due to weak demand, high prices, and production restrictions. As of end-January, existing aluminum capacity stood at 46.209 million mt and operating capacity at 44.996 million mt. February production is forecast to drop MoM with liquid aluminum proportion falling significantly to 64.4% amid Chinese New Year and high prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Large aluminum deposit near Tisdale could enhance industry in Sask</title><link>https://www.cjwwradio.com/2026/01/30/241000/</link><description>A massive aluminum deposit, the Thor Project near Tisdale, Saskatchewan, contains over 6.8 billion tonnes of alumina within a small 16x16 mile area, equating to about a third of known world supply. Canadian Energy Metals' Preliminary Economic Assessment confirms an inferred resource of 86.6 billion tonnes. The deposit allows for the greenest method to produce aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Strengthens Its Global Low-Carbon Aluminium Footprint Through Joint Acquisition with Chalco of Votorantim's Interest in CBA</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2026/rio-tinto-strengthens-its-global-low-carbon-aluminium-footprint-through-joint-acquisition-with-chalco-of-votorantims-interest-in-cba</link><description>Rio Tinto and Chalco jointly acquired Votorantim's interest in CBA to strengthen their global low-carbon aluminum production capabilities. This strategic move supports the industry's transition toward sustainable aluminum production and decarbonization efforts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Green Nickel, Global Future</title><link>https://pocketmags.com/newsweek-europe-magazine/jan-30-feb-6-2026/articles/green-nickel-global-future</link><description>Neo Energy is redefining Indonesia's nickel sector through integrated mining, processing, and industrial development on a sustainable platform. The company operates over 12,000 hectares of nickel mines and green-powered industrial parks, including a high-pressure acid leach (HPAL) facility targeted for 2029 completion. These efforts position Indonesia centrally in the global energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Sources say that India will unveil incentives for lithium and nickel processing</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/environment/2026/01/30/sources-say-that-india-will-unveil-incentives-for-lithium-and-nickel-processing</link><description>India plans to offer incentives, including a 15% capital subvention starting April 1, 2026, for companies setting up nickel and lithium processing plants to boost production and support its energy transition. This addresses the lack of domestic processing capacity, currently dominated by China, amid targets for 30% electric car penetration by 2030. The initiative focuses on critical minerals essential for EV batteries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Chalco, Rio Tinto to Buy Brazil's CBA in $886 Million Push for Greener Aluminum</title><link>https://www.caixinglobal.com/2026-01-31/chalco-rio-tinto-to-buy-controlling-stake-in-brazils-cba-for-886-million-102409946.html</link><description>China's Chalco and Rio Tinto will acquire a 68.6% stake in Brazil's Companhia Brasileira de Alumínio (CBA) for $886 million to secure low-carbon aluminum supply amid surging prices. CBA, powered by renewable energy, produced 364,500 tons in 2024, over one-third of Brazil's output. The deal supports greener production as aluminum futures hit record highs near $3,356 per ton.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Is aluminium scrap quietly rewriting the global metals playbook especially with EU scrap tension from solar PV India's new policies</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/is-aluminium-scrap-quietly-rewriting-the-global-metals-playbook-especially-with-eu-scrap-tension-from-solar-pv-india-s-new-policies-117101</link><description>The article examines how global aluminium scrap flows, prices, and policies are shifting, with particular focus on India's new regulations adding secondary aluminium to its list of regulated industries under the Greenhouse Gases Emission Intensity Target Rules, 2025. It highlights NALCO's plans to develop 200-300 MW of renewable power capacity paired with battery storage to reduce coal dependence and support sustainable aluminium smelting, while also addressing the challenge of recycling aluminium from solar installations, which now account for 8 million tonnes globally.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Beverage Can Market Outlook 2026-2034</title><link>https://www.intelmarketresearch.com/global-aluminum-beverage-can-forecast-market-26665</link><description>The market analysis projects the aluminum beverage can market will grow from $41.9 billion in 2025 to $57.4 billion by 2034, driven by sustainability demand and aluminum's 100% recyclability. The report highlights innovations in printed electronics and temperature-sensitive inks creating premium packaging opportunities, with the smart aluminum beverage can market projected to reach $1.2 billion by 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel prices today, January 31st: Declining on international markets</title><link>https://baonghean.vn/en/gia-thep-hom-nay-311-giam-tren-san-quoc-te-thi-truong-noi-dia-giu-gia-sat-tet-10322122.html</link><description>Global steel prices declined on January 31 due to increased iron ore inventory pressure at Chinese ports. Domestic markets in Vietnam held steady ahead of Tet holiday.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>IIT-M develops green method to recover metals from e-waste using natural solvents</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/chennai/iit-m-develops-green-method-to-recover-metals-from-e-waste-using-natural-solvents/articleshow/127808623.cms</link><description>Researchers at IIT Madras developed a sustainable method to recover valuable metals from electronic waste using environment-friendly solvents derived from natural compounds like thymol and capric acid. Unlike conventional acid-based extraction techniques, this green solvent approach is non-toxic, water-efficient, and generates no hazardous waste, with potential applications for scaling up industrial recycling processes.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries showcases sustainability in quarterly update</title><link>https://en.antaranews.com/news/402222/nickel-industries-showcases-sustainability-in-quarterly-update</link><description>Nickel Industries Limited reported stable operational performance in its Q4 2025 quarterly activities report, achieving a zero Lost Time Injury Frequency Rate (LTIFR) over 12 months with 17.7 million safe man-hours. The company completed a strategic acquisition of a 10% stake in Excelsior Nickel Cobalt and received national recognition for sustainability leadership, including the Indonesia Leadership Award 2025 and CNBC Indonesia's Excellence in Sustainability Leadership Award.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industry News, Views and Commentary - Chronickels</title><link>https://nickelinstitute.org/en/blog/</link><description>The Nickel Institute published a new series on sustainability and innovations in nickel production, featuring an interview with Dr. Mark McArthur from NOVONIX about patented all-dry, zero-waste cathode synthesis technology designed to reduce costs and environmental impact of nickel-based cathode production. The article also discusses nickel's role in green hydrogen, electric vehicles, and cellulosic ethanol production as part of the energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures dropped more than 3% to around $6 per pound on Friday, reversing a sharp rally amid profit-taking after surging to record levels. Copper fell to 5.97 USD/Lbs on January 30, 2026, down 3.80% from the previous day, despite monthly gains of 5.03% and yearly increase of 40.26%. The retreat aligned with a broader pullback in the metals complex and a rebounding dollar.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Are Tumbling, and a Larger Correction Could Be ...</title><link>https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/commodities/copper-prices-record-high-ai-china-correction-metals-commodities-gold-2026-1</link><description>Copper prices hit a record above $14,000 per ton on Thursday but dropped sharply to around $13,800 on Friday, mirroring declines in gold and silver. Goldman Sachs warns of a potential larger correction in mid-2026, possibly triggered by US tariffs on refined copper. Analysts note speculation has driven prices beyond fundamentals, especially with soft demand in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why is copper price down and will it rise again or continue to fall ...</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/why-is-copper-price-down-and-will-it-rise-again-or-continue-to-fall-copper-drop-explained-heres-what-investors-should-do-now-shanghai-futures-exchange-and-london-metal-exchange-u-s-dollar/articleshow/127800623.cms</link><description>Copper prices fell after record highs due to profit-booking in Shanghai and London markets, with Shanghai futures down 2.82% to 103,680 yuan per ton and LME at $13,278.50 per ton. Weak Chinese demand is evident from low Yangshan premiums and spot discounts, alongside a stronger dollar. Long-term fundamentals remain positive with tight supply, potential rate cuts, and investor interest.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum output: Global body says production of primary aluminium up over 3% on month in Dec</title><link>https://informistmedia.com/EquityWire/43842/Aluminum-output-Global-body-says-production-of-primary-aluminium-up-over-3-37-on-month-in-Dec</link><description>Global primary aluminium production rose over 3% month-on-month in December 2025, per international data. This reflects ongoing capacity utilization trends in the sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Pioneering Sustainability and Innovation</title><link>https://www.lightmetalage.com/news/event-news/aluminium-2026-pioneering-sustainability-and-innovation/</link><description>The world's leading aluminum trade fair will take place October 6–8, 2026, in Düsseldorf, Germany, organized by RX Global. The event will emphasize sustainability, secondary aluminum's role in decarbonization, and innovations in metal processing, recycling, casting, automation, and surface finishing, with new elements including Hall 7A and dedicated sustainability conferences.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Driving Innovation for a Sustainable Future</title><link>https://www.aluminium-exhibition.com/germany/en-gb/blog/pressemitteilungen/alude2026-showpreparations.html</link><description>ALUMINIUM 2026 will highlight sustainability as its central theme, with particular focus on secondary aluminum for decarbonization and coverage of metal processing, recycling, automation, and surface finishing. The event will feature proven formats like themed pavilions alongside fresh concepts for networking and business development.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Glencore 2025 copper output falls 11%</title><link>https://www.voxmarkets.com/articles/glencore-2025-copper-output-falls-11--477e3ec</link><description>Glencore's copper production fell 11% in 2025 to 851,600 metric tonnes, though second-half output improved significantly due to higher grades and better recoveries at key mines. Rio Tinto has until February 5 to make a firm bid for Glencore, which could create the world's biggest miner controlling almost 10% of global copper output.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper gains ground, bolstering mining companies' 2026 profits outlook</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/copper-news/copper-gains-ground,-bolstering-mining-companies-2026-profits-outlook-48204</link><description>Copper is expected to account for over 35% of diversified miners' earnings in 2026. Rio Tinto has increased copper output by 54% since 2019 following the Oyu Tolgoi project ramp-up, significantly outpacing competitors like BHP's 11% increase.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Announcement] on publishing Copper grade 1 cathode premium, ddp Midwest US on February 1, 2026</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103727637/smm-emannouncementem-on-publishing-copper-grade-1-cathode-premium-ddp-midwest-us-on-february-1-2026</link><description>Shanghai Metals Market officially launched the Copper grade 1 cathode premium pricing for delivery to the Midwest US on February 1, 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Significantly Corrected, Alloy Enterprises Sentiment to Hold Prices Firm Declined - SMM Cast Aluminum Alloy</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103749387-Aluminum-Prices-Significantly-Corrected-Alloy-Enterprises-Sentiment-to-Hold-Prices-Firm-Declined-SMM-Cast-Aluminum-Alloy</link><description>Spot aluminum prices experienced a significant correction last Friday, with A00 aluminum falling 200 yuan/mt to 24,660 yuan/mt and SMM ADC12 dropping to 24,350 yuan/mt. Aluminum alloy futures closed slightly up at 22,875 yuan/mt, while aluminum scrap prices pulled back amid high costs and supply tightness. Approaching Chinese New Year, secondary aluminum alloy prices are expected to hover at highs due to limited downside.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US ALUMINUM: Trade uncertainty, supply tightness push Midwest Premium above $1/lb</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/us-aluminum-trade-uncertainty-supply-tightness-push-midwest-premium-above-1-lb/</link><description>Trade uncertainty and supply tightness in the US aluminum market have driven the Midwest Premium above $1 per pound. This reflects ongoing challenges in the domestic aluminum sector amid global trade dynamics. The development underscores tightening supply conditions in the region.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>PRICE INCREASE ANNOUNCEMENT – February 2, 2026</title><link>https://cemcosteel.com/news/price-increase-announcement-february-2-2026/</link><description>Domestic steel mills announced a second round of price increases for coated steel, effective with February shipments across all markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest Ex-Factory Price of Building Materials from Zenith Steel in Early February</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103749458-Latest-Ex-Factory-Price-of-Building-Materials-from-Zenith-Steel-in-Early-February</link><description>Zenith Steel released its early February 2026 price policy, with back payments for wire rod at 165 and rebar at 130 for the first three ten-day periods. Provisional prices for the first ten-day period of February are set at 3,700 for wire rod and 3,400 for rebar. The benchmark monthly discount rate for acceptance bills is 1.35‰.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>"14th Five-Year Plan" Period Sees China's Steel Production Cut by Over 100 Million mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103749458-Latest-Ex-Factory-Price-of-Building-Materials-from-Zenith-Steel-in-Early-February</link><description>During China's 14th Five-Year Plan period, steel production was reduced by over 100 million metric tons. This cut reflects efforts to address overcapacity in the steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME Copper Continues Downward Trend, SHFE/LME Price Ratio Recovers, Pre-Holiday Market Heats Up - SMM Yangshan Spot Copper</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103750730-LME-Copper-Continues-Downward-Trend-SHFELME-Price-Ratio-Recovers-Pre-Holiday-Market-Heats-Up-SMM-Yangshan-Spot-Copper</link><description>LME copper prices continued their downward trend, while the SHFE/LME price ratio strengthened amid market premiums rising due to import incentives. Warrant prices averaged higher at $30-48/mt for QP February, with transactions concentrated around $30-40/mt. Offers for B/L and ER copper cargoes showed increased premiums, signaling heating pre-holiday activity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper is down by 2.01% - Copper Reverses Gains as Metals Retreat</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/521894</link><description>Copper prices fell 2.01% to 5.8051 USD/Lbs, extending losses in a broader metals selloff after reaching all-time highs last week. The decline followed profit-taking amid reassessed fundamentals, with impacts from China's speculation reversal and US policy signals. Long-term support persists from supply constraints and demand expectations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Alara Resources Dispatches 35th Copper Concentrate Shipment from Oman Mine</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/02/02/alara-resources-dispatches-35th-copper-concentrate-shipment-from-oman-mine/</link><description>Alara Resources announced the dispatch of its 35th shipment of copper concentrate from the Al Wash-hi Majaza copper-gold mine in Oman, containing 283 tonnes of copper and 3.5 kg of gold. January 2026 marked a record high for monthly copper concentrate dispatches with approximately 4243 WMT shipped. The company continues exploration at other Omani projects.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel prices plummeted by over 10,000 yuan in a single day on February 2 as Trump announced the</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103750992-SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-prices-plummeted-by-over-10000-yuan-in-a-single-day-on-February-2-as-Trump-announced-the</link><description>On February 2, SMM #1 refined nickel prices ranged from 135,000-145,000 yuan/mt, with an average price of 140,200 yuan/mt, down 5,950 yuan/mt from the previous session. The sharp decline exceeded 10,000 yuan in a single day, linked to Trump's announcement. This reflects significant market volatility in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel News</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103751004-SMM-Nickel-News</link><description>SMM reports that on February 2, the #1 refined nickel price stood at 135,000–145,400 yuan/mt, averaging 140,200 yuan/mt, a drop of 5,950 yuan/mt. This update highlights ongoing downward pressure in nickel pricing amid broader market trends. It provides key insights into daily nickel market movements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Monday Report - 02 February 2026</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2026/02/02/the-monday-report-02-february-2026/</link><description>Industrial metals faced declines, with copper down 4.5% following an all-time high, amid broader commodity shifts driven by Trump's Fed chair pick announcement. The 'Buy America' trade resurfaced, pressuring metals like nickel in a volatile environment. Precious metals saw extreme drops, influencing overall market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices plummeted by over 10,000 yuan in a single day on February 2 as Trump announced the</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103750992-SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-prices-plummeted-by-over-10000-yuan-in-a-single-day-on-February-2-as-Trump-announced-the</link><description>On February 2, SMM #1 refined nickel prices dropped sharply to 135,000-145,000 yuan/mt, averaging 140,200 yuan/mt, a decline of 5,950 yuan/mt from the previous session. The price plunge is linked to announcements including those from Trump. This reflects ongoing volatility in the nickel market amid supply and demand dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel News</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103751004-SMM-Nickel-News</link><description>SMM reports that on February 2, #1 refined nickel prices ranged from 135,000–145,400 yuan/mt, averaging 140,200 yuan/mt, down 5,950 yuan/mt from prior levels. The update highlights immediate market price movements in refined nickel. This indicates continued pressure on nickel pricing in early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Advancing Nickel MMC Coatings: Electroplating Models, Tooling Innovations for Hard Chromium Alternatives</title><link>https://www.pfonline.com/articles/advancing-nickel-mmc-coatings-electroplating-models-tooling-innovations-for-hard-chromium-alternatives</link><description>The EU-funded MOZART project develops nickel dispersion coatings enriched with nanoparticles as a sustainable alternative to hard chromium plating, achieving hardness up to 1,000 HV. It integrates electrochemical characterization and CAE technology to predict nanoparticle content in deposits and designs custom plating tooling. This innovation supports eco-friendly electroplating for various components.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The first Energy Release contract in the Aosta Valley is underway: agreement signed between the CVA Group and Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>CVA will construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily with over 20 MW capacity, expected to produce 593,600 MWh fully operational by 2026. This marks the first Energy Release agreement in the Aosta Valley and supports Cogne Acciai Speciali's green energy transition and reduced environmental impact of production.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali mulls expansion in U.S.</title><link>https://www.stainless.club/industry-news/read/cogne-acciai-speciali-mulls-expansion-in-u-s.html</link><description>After four acquisitions over the past two years, Italian stainless steel and nickel alloy producer Cogne Acciai Speciali is considering further growth in the U.S. market. The company secured EUR 245 million through two capital increases to fund previous acquisitions and is preparing for its next expansion move.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>