<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:25:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 906 USD/T on December 24, 2025, down 0.22% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices rose 0.44% and are up 27.60% year-over-year. Recent news highlights HRC Steel hitting multi-week highs and lows earlier in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US steel tariffs cause scrap supply glut</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2769786-viewpoint-us-steel-tariffs-cause-scrap-supply-glut</link><description>US flat and long steel prices continued climbing in December amid tariffs causing a scrap supply glut, while Turkish rebar prices fell to $559/t ex-works. Production changes will take time, with China dampening global steel and scrap prices into 2026. US exporters may prefer domestic sales in Q1 due to price divergence.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper's Red Metal Revolution: Prices Target $12,000 Milestone Amid Supply Shocks and AI Demand</title><link>http://business.times-online.com/times-online/article/marketminute-2025-12-24-coppers-red-metal-revolution-prices-target-12000-milestone-amid-supply-shocks-and-ai-demand</link><description>Copper prices are surging toward $12,000 per metric ton due to supply shocks and surging demand from AI data centers, which require about 27 tons per megawatt. This rally is driven by the green transition and digital revolutions, with limited substitution options for high-performance uses. Mining firms are investing in recycling technologies, though secondary supply remains insufficient for projected demand growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Great Metal Super-Surge of 2025: Gold, Silver, and Copper Hit Historic Peaks as Economic Clouds Gather</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-12-24-the-great-metal-super-surge-of-2025-gold-silver-and-copper-hit-historic-peaks-as-economic-clouds-gather</link><description>Copper reached a historic $12,200 per metric ton in December 2025 amid supply disruptions at major mines and booming demand from AI data centers and grid upgrades. Mining giants like BHP and Rio Tinto are capitalizing with record production and strategic acquisitions to secure energy transition supply. The surge underscores copper's critical role in AI infrastructure and global electrification efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Xiarihamu Nickel-Cobalt Mine officially included in Provincial Green Mining List</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5108121-flash-xiarihamu-nickel-cobalt-mine-officially-included-in-provincial-green-mining-list</link><description>Qinghai Province added the Xiarihamu Nickel-Cobalt Mine to its 2025 Provincial Green Mining List, recognizing Qinghai Jinchuan Mining's efforts in ecological protection despite challenges like high altitude and arid conditions. The company has implemented vegetation restoration, windbreak measures, and technological innovations for efficient resource use and emission reductions. This supports both mining operations and environmental goals in the region.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China launches first million-tonne near-zero-carbon steel line</title><link>https://news.cgtn.com/news/2025-12-24/China-launches-first-million-tonne-near-zero-carbon-steel-line-1JmEgY4p1WU/p.html</link><description>China has completed its first million-tonne near-zero-carbon steel production line in Zhanjiang City, Guangdong Province, using a hydrogen-based metallurgical electric smelting process that replaces traditional coke with hydrogen. This technology reduces carbon emissions by 50 to 80 percent compared to conventional methods and can cut over 3.14 million tonnes of emissions annually. The project marks a major breakthrough in the steel industry's green transformation during the 14th Five-Year Plan period.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Reach Record $12,000 a Metric Ton as Market Navigates Supply Constraints and Growing Demand Outlook</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-prices-reach-record-12-000-metric-ton-market-navigates-supply-constraints-growing-demand-outlook-2512/</link><description>Copper prices hit a record $12,000 per metric ton amid global supply tightness driven by U.S.-bound copper redirection, mine outages, and zero-fee smelter processing agreements that have forced some smelters to cut operations. Citigroup and Goldman Sachs project bullish copper markets for 2026, citing strong demand from energy transition and AI infrastructure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Structural Supercycle: Why $12,000 Is Just the Beginning</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-structural-supercycle-12-000-beginning-2512/</link><description>Opinion/analysis piece arguing geopolitical shocks, tariffs and accelerating demand tied to electrification and AI are creating a long-term 'supercycle' for copper, citing forecasts of a 2026 refined-copper deficit and multi-year price appreciation scenarios from major banks.[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Domestic and international liquidity easing supports aluminum prices hovering at highs [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103688975/Domestic-and-international-liquidity-easing-supports-aluminum-prices-hovering-at-highs-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME aluminum closed at $2,956.5/mt on December 24 after hitting a high of $2,969.5/mt, supported by liquidity easing. SHFE aluminum futures fell 0.83% to 22,145 yuan/mt, while spot A00 aluminum surged to 22,030 yuan/mt. Secondary aluminum prices like ADC12 rose, with import windows reopening due to stronger domestic prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 25.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel exchanges, including Shanghai Futures Rebar prices as of December 24, 2025. Various futures terms for rebar and other steel products show flat performance at 0.00 change. Coverage includes indices, prices, and news for major markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's 304 stainless steel export offers rise sharply on Tsingshan price hike</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5108057-indonesias-304-stainless-steel-export-offers-rise-sharply-on-tsingshan-price-hike</link><description>Indonesia's 304 stainless steel export prices rose sharply for the third week in December due to Tsingshan's price hike. Related updates include stainless HRC and round bar prices in China on December 25. Nickel and chrome ore markets also show activity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper hits record high as robust US GDP data boosts demand prospects</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-record-high-as-robust-us-gdp-data-boosts-demand-prospects/</link><description>Copper prices extended gains to hit all-time highs, supported by robust U.S. GDP data enhancing demand prospects. The rally reflects ongoing market strength amid broader commodity trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Weekly Market Recap (December 25) –Copper 2025</title><link>https://nai500.com/blog/2025/12/weekly-market-recap-december-25-copper-2025-shocks-mergers-and-megatrends/</link><description>Copper prices surged to unprecedented highs this week, concluding a year of supply shocks and trade realignments. The recap highlights key market shocks, mergers, and megatrends impacting copper in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690218/</link><description>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 123,400–131,400 yuan/mt, with an average price of 127,400 yuan/mt. This represents a decline of 2,800 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices experienced a significant correction on December 25...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690257/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-correction-on-December-25-while-the-central-bank-conducted-a-400-billion-yuan-MLF-operation</link><description>Nickel prices underwent a significant correction on December 25 amid a 400-billion-yuan MLF operation by the central bank. The SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 127,400 yuan/mt, down 2,800 yuan/mt from the prior session.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690218/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on December 25 averaged 127,400 yuan/mt, ranging from 123,400–131,400 yuan/mt, down 2,800 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects ongoing price pressures in the refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Why copper is set to play a big role in BHP's future</title><link>https://aheadoftheherd.com/why-copper-is-set-to-play-a-big-role-in-bhps-future/</link><description>BHP is positioning copper centrally in its strategy amid global critical minerals discussions, including meetings with US leadership on AI supply chains. The company's history of innovation supports its leadership in copper production for electrification and digital technologies. This focus highlights copper's growing importance in sustainable mining and technology advancements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel traded flat at 15,660 USD/T on December 25, 2025. Over the past month, nickel's price has risen 5.49%, and it is up 1.26% compared to the same time last year. This reflects trading on a contract for difference tracking the benchmark market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Talon buys nation's only nickel mine to create Midwest 'powerhouse'</title><link>https://www.eenews.net/articles/talon-buys-nations-only-nickel-mine-to-create-midwest-powerhouse/</link><description>Talon Metals announced the purchase of the Eagle nickel mine in Michigan's Upper Peninsula from Lundin Mining, along with a nearby mill, to expand production of nickel and copper for stainless steel and EV batteries. The deal positions Talon to develop a critical minerals hub in the Midwest amid rising demand. Lundin will hold nearly 20% stake in Talon as part of the agreement.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper's Record-Breaking Rally: A Strategic Buy Opportunity Amid Tariffs, Supply Constraints, and the Energy Transition</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-record-breaking-rally-strategic-buy-opportunity-tariffs-supply-constraints-energy-transition-2512/</link><description>Copper prices reached an all-time high of $11,700 per metric ton in December 2025, fueled by supply shocks from mine outages, tariff uncertainties, and surging demand from the energy transition. Mine disruptions at key sites like Grasberg and Quebrada Blanca have created a 330kmt deficit projected for 2026. J.P. Morgan forecasts prices peaking at $12,500/mt in Q2 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium opens the week with a fall of $13.5/t; December 26 bid price adds $5/t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-opens-the-week-with-a-fall-of-13-5-t-december-26-bid-price-adds-5-t-115507</link><description>LME aluminium cash bid and official settlement prices fell by USD 13-13.5 per tonne to around USD 2,693 per tonne. The December 26 bid and offer prices rose by USD 5 per tonne to USD 2,728-2,733 per tonne, while the 3-month Asian Reference Price increased by USD 11 to USD 2,700.5 per tonne. Alumina Platts price declined by USD 5.45 per tonne to USD 333.35 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SINBON Brings Enhanced EV Connection Solutions to Automotive World Tokyo 2026</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/26/sinbon-brings-enhanced-ev-connection-solutions-to-automotive-world-tokyo-2026/</link><description>SINBON Electronics is showcasing an expanded portfolio of EV connection technologies, including charging cables and inlets with aluminum busbars and rods, at Automotive World Tokyo 2026. The solutions support diverse standards and emphasize sustainable innovation in mobility. SINBON's commitment to ESG drives carbon management and green solutions across global manufacturing sites.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SINBON Brings Enhanced EV Connection Solutions to Automotive World Tokyo 2026</title><link>https://macaubusiness.com/sinbon-brings-enhanced-ev-connection-solutions-to-automotive-world-tokyo-2026/</link><description>SINBON Electronics announces its return to Automotive World Tokyo 2026 with enhanced EV connection solutions featuring aluminum designs for charging inlets and cables. The portfolio addresses regional standards and supports sustainable automotive advancements. The company focuses on full-process engineering and global support for cleaner mobility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3066 CNY/T on December 26, 2025, marking a 0.07% decline from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have dropped 0.87%, and are down 6.21% from the same period last year. On December 25, prices were at 3,084 CNY/T, down 0.03%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Surtaxes, Tariff Rate Quotas and Steel Derivatives – Is this for real??</title><link>https://sourcealliance.net/surtaxes-tariff-rate-quotas-and-steel-derivatives-is-this-for-real/</link><description>Effective December 26, 2025, Canada imposes 25% tariffs on steel derivative products from all countries. These measures target US, Chinese, and non-US imports containing Chinese steel or aluminum. This escalates protectionism in response to international trade tensions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China pledges to control steel output during 2026-2030 period</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/commodities-news/china-pledges-to-control-steel-output-during-20262030-period-4422922</link><description>China announced it will regulate crude steel output and prohibit illegal new capacity from 2026 to 2030 to address overcapacity and support supply-side reforms. In the first 11 months of 2025, crude steel output fell 4% year-on-year, on track to drop below 1 billion tons for the first time in six years amid a property downturn. The plan coincides with robust steel exports facing global protectionism, prompting a new export licensing system for 300 steel-related items.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel demand seen buoyed by autos, appliances in '26</title><link>https://www.chinadaily.com.cn/a/202512/26/WS694deb74a310d6866eb30963.html</link><description>China's steel consumption is projected at 808 million tons in 2025 and 800 million tons in 2026, with growth in automotive, shipbuilding, and appliance sectors despite overall decline. The report emphasizes steel enterprises advancing intelligent, green, and integrated development through industrial ecosystems. ESG ratings for 108 companies show improving disclosure and performance, calling for stronger industry-wide coordination.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Dec. 26</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20251226/14571663689a47869f9d42b3a7a3be3b/c.html</link><description>London Stock Exchange Group reported copper prices at 5.65 USD at 0200 GMT on December 26. This update provides the latest snapshot of global metals prices, including gold, iron ore, palladium, and platinum. The data reflects ongoing market movements in commodities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Oil Prices Dip, LME Copper Extends Record Rally, Gold Slightly Lower</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/m/page/commodity-news-detail/commodity-news-detail-29163.html</link><description>LME copper futures gained 0.9% to settle at $12,162.50 per tonne, extending its record rally. LME aluminum futures also rose 0.7% to $2,960.50 per tonne. The gains occur amid broader commodity market movements, with oil prices dipping and gold slightly lower.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>On December 26, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel was</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103692395/</link><description>On December 26, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel ranged from 125,700–133,700 yuan/mt, with an average of 129,700 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 2,300 yuan/mt from the previous day. The update highlights short-term price gains in the refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Environmental protection-driven production restrictions intensified, coupled with high aluminum prices suppressing demand, the operating rate of downstream aluminum processors weakened to 60.8% - SMM Aluminum Processing Weekly Survey</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103693363/environmental-protection-driven-production-restrictions-intensified-coupled-with-high-aluminum-prices-suppressing-demand-the-operating-rate-of-downstream-aluminum-processors-weakened-to-608-smm-aluminum-processing-weekly-survey</link><description>The weekly operating rate of domestic aluminum downstream processing enterprises fell to 60.8% as of December 26, 2025, down 0.6 percentage points week-over-week. High aluminum prices suppressed demand, leading to cautious buying, while intensified environmental production restrictions in central China constrained operations. Export orders faced pressure from holiday slowdowns, with weak year-end stockpiling expected to persist.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Environmental protection-driven production restrictions intensified, coupled with high aluminum prices suppressing demand; the operating rate of downstream aluminum processors weakened to 60.8% - SMM Aluminum Processing Weekly Survey</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103693363/environmental-protection-driven-production-restrictions-intensified-coupled-with-high-aluminum-prices-suppressing-demand-the-operating-rate-of-downstream-aluminum-processors-weakened-to-608-smm-aluminum-processing-weekly-survey</link><description>The weekly operating rate of leading domestic aluminum downstream processing enterprises fell 0.6 percentage points week-over-week to 60.8% due to weak orders, environmental protection controls, and high aluminum prices. Environmental protection-driven production restrictions escalated in central China, with a red alert for air pollution in Gongyi lasting until December 28, constraining production and transportation. Downstream sectors like aluminum alloy, wire, cable, and foil face ongoing pressure from slow orders and delayed stockpiling, with operating rates expected to remain weak.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China to rein in copper, alumina capacity expansion under next five-year plan</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2025-12-26/china-rein-copper-alumina-capacity-expansion-under-next-five-year-plan</link><description>China will tighten oversight of new copper and alumina projects from 2026 to 2030 to curb irrational investment and overcapacity, as it is the world’s largest producer of both. From January to November 2025, China produced 13.3 million metric tons of refined copper (up 9.8% year-over-year) and 84.7 million tons of alumina, both on track for records. This policy aims to address risks of unchecked expansion amid rising output.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Russia expects 5pc drop steel output 2025</title><link>https://www.nation.com.pk/26-Dec-2025/russia-expects-5pc-drop-steel-output-2025</link><description>Russia anticipates a 5 percent decline in steel output for 2025, reaching 67 million tonnes. This forecast comes from First Deputy Prime Minister Denis Manturov amid ongoing industry challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Beijing tightens reins on copper and alumina projects to stop disorderly expansion</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/beijing-tightens-reins-on-copper-and-alumina-projects-to-stop-disorderly-expansion-116733</link><description>China's National Development and Reform Commission is tightening controls on new copper and alumina projects to prevent irrational investment and disorderly expansion from 2026 to 2030. From January to November 2025, China produced 13.3 million tonnes of refined copper, up 9.8% year-over-year, on track for a record. The policy emphasizes regional differences, mergers among large firms, and continued overseas mining investments.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China to rein in copper, alumina capacity expansion under next five-year plan</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2025-12-26/china-rein-copper-alumina-capacity-expansion-under-next-five-year-plan</link><description>China's NDRC announced tighter oversight on copper and alumina projects to curb overcapacity, requiring feasibility studies aligned with national policy. China produced 13.3 million metric tons of refined copper from January to November 2025, up 9.8%, with plans for 2 million tons of smelting capacity already suspended. The measures support industry consolidation and overseas investments amid strong production and rising prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Hindustan Copper Surges as Global Copper Prices Hit 16-Year High</title><link>https://news.legalparivar.com/hindustan-copper-surges-as-global-copper-prices-hit-16-year-high/</link><description>Hindustan Copper's stock surged as global copper prices reached a 16-year high, reflecting strong market momentum. The price rally underscores tightening supply conditions in copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Daily Nickel price, LME SHFE Price of Nickel live</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Nickel</link><description>SMM reports #1 Jinchuan Nickel at 16,790.92 USD/mt on Dec 26, with high-grade NPI averaging 904 yuan/mtu, up 5 yuan MoM, showing bottom support and short-term upside potential. Various nickel premiums and prices listed, including import nickel at 15,946.96 USD/mt. Includes review of nickel ore for 2025 and outlook for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Environmental protection-driven production restrictions intensified, coupled with high aluminum prices suppressing demand, the operating rate of downstream aluminum processors weakened to 60.8% [SMM Aluminum Processing Weekly Survey]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103693363/Environmental-protection-driven-production-restrictions-intensified-coupled-with-high-aluminum-prices-suppressing-demand-the-operating-rate-of-downstream-aluminum-processors-weakened-to-608-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Processing-Weekly-Survey%5D</link><description>The weekly operating rate of leading domestic aluminum downstream processing enterprises fell 0.6 percentage points week-on-week to 60.8% due to weak orders, environmental protection controls, and high aluminum prices. Environmental restrictions escalated in central China, with a red alert for air pollution in Gongyi lasting until December 28, constraining production and transportation. Looking ahead, ongoing restrictions and weak year-end stockpiling are expected to keep operating rates under pressure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Environmental protection-driven production restrictions intensified, coupled with high aluminium prices suppressing demand, the operating rate of downstream aluminium processors weakened</title><link>http://www.alcircle.com/press-release/environmental-protection-driven-production-restrictions-intensified-coupled-with-high-aluminium-prices-suppressing-demand-the-operating-rate-of-downst-116731</link><description>The weekly operating rate of leading domestic aluminium downstream processing enterprises fell 0.6 percentage points week-on-week to 60.8%. This decline is attributed to intensified environmental protection-driven production restrictions and high aluminium prices suppressing demand. The report highlights challenges in the aluminium processing sector amid off-season dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Five-Month Peak</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures climbed to $5.7 per pound, a five-month high, driven by global energy transition demand and supply constraints. The metal has gained 42% annually in New York. Prices partially pared gains but remain supported by robust fundamentals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Holds Near 5-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures hovered around $5.7 per pound near a five-month high, bolstered by tight supply and strong US economic growth. The US economy expanded at its fastest pace in two years in Q3, aiding prices. Robust industrial activity continues to underpin the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price 26 dec 2025</title><link>https://www.mining.com/new-york-copper-price-surges-again-shanghai-sets-record/copper-price-26-dec-2025/</link><description>Copper prices surpassed $12,000 per tonne for the first time on record, propelled by mine disruptions and tariff concerns despite weak Chinese demand. Shanghai copper also set a record. The rally reflects persistent supply tightness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>New IIT (ISM) Dhanbad Centre to Drive Critical Minerals Innovation for Clean-Tech</title><link>https://solarquarter.com/2025/12/26/new-iit-ism-dhanbad-centre-to-drive-critical-minerals-innovation-for-clean-tech/</link><description>IIT (ISM) Dhanbad launched a Critical Minerals Centre under India's National Critical Mineral Mission to boost innovation in minerals like nickel for clean energy technologies. The centre focuses on applied research and industry collaboration to secure supply chains for EVs, renewables, and battery storage. This addresses India's growing demand and reduces import dependence amid global competition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper surges to record near $13,000 in London after a 7% jump</title><link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/commodities/copper-surges-to-record-near-13000-in-london-after-a-7-jump-19805731.htm</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange surged nearly 7% to an all-time high near $13,000 per tonne after reopening following a two-day hiatus. The metal hit as high as $12,960 per tonne, driven by expectations of massive flows to the US leaving global shortages. Aluminium and zinc also rose by 0.6% and 0.9% respectively.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Five-Month Peak; Prices Rise on Tight Supply and Strong Demand</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures hit five-month highs (around $5.7 per pound) as tight supply, robust US economic activity and structural demand from EVs, renewables and AI infrastructure underpinned prices; the page also reports recent national production figures for Chile and Peru. The report highlights inventory pressures and continued price appreciation through late December.[4]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 27.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures rebar contracts showing no change on December 26, 2025. Coverage includes indices, news, and analyses for various markets like Turkey, China, Europe, and North America. Users can track commodities via watch lists for the latest price changes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Beyond Gold: Copper's Explosive Rise as AI and EVs Fuel Demand!</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/commodities/Beyond-Gold-Coppers-Explosive-Rise-as-AI-and-EVs-Fuel-Demand/694f469c4342f77179d8a3fe</link><description>Copper prices have surged 36% due to demand from AI data centers, electric vehicles, and supply disruptions, with analysts bullish citing Chinese buying and recommending mining stocks like Freeport McMoRan. Industrial metals rally reflects technology and energy transition trends. Uranium and cobalt also saw significant gains amid broader market strength.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits $12K: Supply Crisis Drives Historic Rally</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-historic-rally-2025-supply-demand-tech-geopolitics/</link><description>Copper prices have exceeded $12,000 per tonne amid a supply crisis sparking a historic market rally. The surge is driven by ongoing supply-demand imbalances in production and capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel fell 1.8% to $15,235 a ton on the LME amid stronger dollar and higher financing costs from fewer expected Fed rate cuts in 2025. Indonesia considers deep cuts to nickel mining quotas to boost slumping prices, offsetting market gloom. Prices are down 8% year-to-date due to new Indonesian supply and slowing EV sales.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Talon Metals to Acquire Lundin Mining's Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill Operations, Creating a Multi-Asset U.S. Nickel-Copper Company</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=6944a95118e86fe8dc044412</link><description>Talon Metals is acquiring the cash-flow-positive Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill from Lundin Mining to form a unified US nickel-copper platform with exploration and expansion opportunities. The move advances priorities like extending Eagle's mine life, exploring in Michigan and Minnesota, and permitting the Tamarack Nickel-Copper Project. It addresses US dependence on foreign critical minerals for defense and energy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CISA mills' daily crude steel output down 1.3% in mid-December, stocks up</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cisa-mills-daily-crude-steel-output-down-13-in-mid-december-stocks-up-1426220.htm</link><description>The China Iron and Steel Association reported average daily crude steel output of large and medium Chinese steel enterprises fell to 1.845 million tonnes during December 11–20, down 1.3% from early December, while finished steel inventories rose to 16.01 million tonnes as of December 20. The story also notes recent week-by-week movements in US raw steel production and broader inventory trends for Chinese mills.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China pledges to control steel output during 2026–2030 period</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/china-pledges-to-control-steel-output-during-2026-2030-period/</link><description>China said it will continue to regulate crude steel output and prohibit the addition of illegal new capacity from 2026–2030 as part of supply-side reforms and carbon-emission controls, noting crude steel output fell about 4% in the first 11 months of 2025 versus a year earlier. The announcement also referenced a planned export licensing system for roughly 300 steel-related items starting in 2026.[2]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China pledges to control steel output during 2026–2030 period</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40399452/china-pledges-to-control-steel-output-during-2026-2030-period</link><description>A re-reporting of the Chinese state planner's pledge to regulate crude steel output through 2026–2030, noting the 4% drop in crude steel production in the first 11 months of 2025 and the planned licensing system for steel-related exports; the piece summarizes official comments on supply-side reform and overcapacity.[6]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper hits all-time high today: Will Trump's tariffs and mine disruptions keep prices soaring despite slowing China demand?</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/copper-hits-all-time-high-today-will-trumps-tariffs-and-mine-disruptions-keep-prices-soaring-despite-slowing-china-demand/articleshow/126144292.cms</link><description>Copper prices hit a record high above $12,000 per ton, driven by Trump tariff concerns and mine disruptions. The rally persists even amid weaker demand from China. Supply constraints are expected to maintain upward pressure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nornickel believes 2026 will bring dividends, CEO says</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-believes-2026-will-bring-dividends-ceo-says/</link><description>Nornickel’s CEO Vladimir Potanin stated that the company expects positive cash flow in 2026, enabling resumption of dividend payments after skipping them in 2022-2024. The world’s largest nickel producer faces challenges from Western sanctions but is redirecting sales to Asia. Potanin anticipates dividends, though smaller than before, amid improving financial conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is down 1.7 percent - week 53, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-down-17-percent-week-53-2025-1426913.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending December 27, 2025, was 1.695 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 74.0%, down 1.7% from the previous week. Year-to-date production through December 27, 2025, reached 89.301 million net tons at 76.7% capacity utilization, representing a 3.4% increase compared to the same period in 2024.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Why Metal Prices Keep Climbing</title><link>https://www.businesstoday.com.my/2025/12/28/why-metal-prices-keep-climbing/</link><description>Precious and industrial metals, including aluminum, are surging to record highs as 2025 ends, driven by economic and geopolitical uncertainty. The article highlights ongoing climbs in metal prices amid broader market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel industry urges FBR to seek advance tax guarantees on duty-free Chinese imports via Sost</title><link>https://profit.pakistantoday.com.pk/2025/12/29/steel-industry-urges-fbr-to-seek-advance-tax-guarantees-on-duty-free-chinese-imports-via-sost/</link><description>Pakistan's steel producers have urged the Federal Board of Revenue to require advance tax guarantees from importers of duty-free Chinese steel products via the Sost Dry Port to prevent diversion to taxable areas. The industry highlights Pakistan's surplus steel production capacity and opposes tax exemptions on finished steel goods. They suggest limiting exemptions to raw materials or scrap to protect local production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Business sentiment for January pessimistic over slump in construction, steel sectors: Poll</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-12-29/business/economy/Business-sentiment-for-January-pessimistic-over-slump-in-construction-steel-sectors-Poll/2488134</link><description>South Korea's business sentiment index for January signals pessimism, particularly in the steel and construction sectors, with the steel sector reading at 85.2 below the 100 benchmark. The Federation of Korean Industries attributes the slump to weak performance dragging down related industries like metal processing. Experts call for government support in restructuring steel and reducing financial burdens on raw materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices, Charts, Analysis &amp; Forecast | SMM Metals Market</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper prices have surged strongly since mid-September 2025, repeatedly hitting record highs, with SHFE.CU2602 at CNY/mt 101,380. High-grade copper traded around USD 12,316.7 per mt as of Dec 26. Rising prices are driving up motor costs and supply chain pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices hit record as investors bet on tighter times coming ...</title><link>https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/biz/archives/2025/12/29/2003849659</link><description>Copper prices hit records in Shanghai and rallied in New York, with Shanghai futures nearing 100,000 yuan per tonne and Comex up 5.6% to $5.8075 a pound. Investors anticipate tighter global supplies next year amid a weaker US dollar and energy transition demand. The rally caps a 42% yearly gain for copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices hit record as investors bet on tighter times coming</title><link>https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/biz/archives/2025/12/29/2003849659</link><description>Shanghai and New York copper prices surged to record or near-record levels as investors priced in tighter global supplies next year, aided by a weaker US dollar and large annual gains; the piece links price strength to trade dislocations and the energy transition boosting long-term demand. The article reports SHFE copper trading near 100,000 yuan/tonne and Comex copper reaching intraday highs above $5.80/lb.[5]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Can the sizzling rally in ASX 200 copper stocks boost BHP shares in 2026?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/12/29/can-the-sizzling-rally-in-asx-200-copper-stocks-boost-bhp-shares-in-2026/</link><description>The article examines how the rally in copper is benefiting ASX-listed miners and notes BHP's record FY25 copper production of 2,017 kt, driven by stronger performances across operated assets and projects that could deliver ~2 Mtpa of attributable copper production during the 2030s. It contextualizes producer-level capacity increases amid the broader market rally.[7]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 29, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103694778/</link><description>Shanghai Metals Market reported the SMM #1 refined nickel price range and an average price for December 29, 2025, showing an intraday rise (average price 131,700 yuan/mt, up 2,000 yuan/mt from the prior period), reflecting local refined-nickel market moves amid supply tightness in Indonesia and year-end dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Flash — December 29: Indonesia’s ore market remains tight as 2025 closes</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103694014</link><description>A rapid market note summarised December 29 developments, stating Indonesia's nickel ore market remains structurally tight and describing downward price pressure from weak demand in some segments while noting policy and supply shifts that could alter near-term balances.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 2,951.15 USD/T on December 29, 2025, down 0.20% from the previous day, though up 2.03% over the past month and 15.69% year-over-year. UK aluminum futures stood at $2,950 per tonne, near a three-year high, amid concerns of low supply. China emphasized preventing overcapacity to address deflationary pressures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Spot Demand Temporarily Shrinks, Aluminum Prices Under Pressure in the Short-Term [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103696290/Spot-Demand-Temporarily-Shrinks-Aluminum-Prices-Under-Pressure-in-the-Short-Term-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME aluminum closed at $2,950.5/mt, down 0.20%, slightly below key moving averages indicating short-term balance. SHFE aluminum closed at 22,320 yuan/mt, down 0.95%, consolidating around moving averages with a suggested trading range of 22,200-22,650. Spot demand has shrunk temporarily, with cost support and supply tightening providing a price floor amid slowing demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[SMM Aluminum Alloy Morning Briefing] Cast Aluminum Alloy 2603 Contract Drops, ADC12 Prices to Stay High Short-term</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103696292/Cast-Aluminum-Alloy-2603-Contract-Drops-ADC12-Prices-to-Stay-High-Short-term</link><description>Overnight, the most-traded cast aluminum alloy 2603 contract dropped, while ADC12 prices are expected to remain high in the short term. Aluminum prices are anticipated to fluctuate within a range with clear upside resistance. This reflects ongoing market dynamics in non-ferrous base metals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Oregon Steel Mills ups plate prices by $40/ton</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/12/29/oregon-steel-mills-ups-plate-prices-by-40-ton/</link><description>Oregon Steel Mills announced a price increase of at least $40 per short ton for steel plate, effective immediately for all new orders. The hike applies to carbon, HSLA, hot-rolled coil, normalized, and quenched and tempered products. This follows similar increases by Nucor and SSAB Americas last week.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Surge in 2025 Amid Renewable Energy Transition</title><link>https://www.binance.com/en/square/post/12-29-2025-copper-prices-surge-in-2025-amid-renewable-energy-transition-34359202839153</link><description>Copper prices have risen over 30% in 2025, reaching a historic high of over $12,000 per ton in December, the largest annual increase since 2009. Analysts expect continued demand from renewable energy, electrification, and AI data centers to sustain high prices into 2026. Regional supply tensions are evident with record-high Comex inventories in the U.S. and low LME stocks in Europe.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Are Having a Banner Year — Commodities Roundup</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512292788/copper-prices-are-having-a-banner-year-commodities-roundup</link><description>LME three-month copper futures rose 1.8% to $12,379.50 per metric ton, advancing nearly 2% early Monday toward another record high. The surge is attributed to supply disruptions at major mines, looming U.S. tariffs prompting increased shipments, interest-rate cuts, and long-term demand from electrification and AI infrastructure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Delayed publication of Turkey flat steel prices: pricing notice</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/delayed-publication-of-turkey-flat-steel-prices-pricing-notice/</link><description>Publication of Fastmarkets' Turkey flat steel prices for December 29, 2025, was delayed due to a reporter error and updated the following day. Affected prices include HRC import CFR Turkey, CRC import, HRC export FOB, domestic exw prices for HRC, CRC, HDG, PPGI, and slab import CFR Turkey. Contact details provided for feedback or data submission.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>COMMODITIES 2026: Mexican aluminum prices poised to rise after atypical year, sources say</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/commodities-2026-mexican-aluminum-prices-poised-to-rise-after-atypical-year-sources-say/</link><description>The aluminum industry in Mexico is expected to experience price increases in 2026 following an atypical year in the commodity market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>India: Coated flat steel prices rise w-o-w but demand yet to recover</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5108571-india-coated-flat-steel-prices-rise-w-o-w-but-demand-yet-to-recover</link><description>Coated flat steel prices in India rose week-on-week due to surges in HRC and coking coal prices. Buyers are procuring material to avoid higher prices in January 2026. However, demand has yet to recover fully.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Thyssenkrupp to reduce steel production, cut or outsource 11,000 jobs</title><link>https://economictimes.com/us/business/thyssenkrupp-to-reduce-steel-production-cut-or-outsource-11000-jobs/articleshow/125697230.cms</link><description>German steelmaker Thyssenkrupp plans to cut or outsource about 11,000 jobs while reducing its steel production capacity. This move addresses pressures in the sector amid declining output and market challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper spikes to record near $13000 before paring gains</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-spikes-to-record-near-13000-before-paring-gains/</link><description>Copper prices spiked to a record near $13,000 per tonne before paring gains, reflecting ongoing volatility in the market. The move aligns with recent surges on the London Metal Exchange amid supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper racks up longest rally since 2017 with bulls at the helm</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/my/node/787555</link><description>Copper is headed for the longest winning run since 2017 in a December rally. The surge is powered by the prospect of more stress in the supply chain. This reflects ongoing supply concerns driving prices higher.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper: Bulls Eye Retest of July High as Key Support Holds</title><link>https://www.investing.com/analysis/copper-bulls-eye-retest-of-july-high-as-key-support-holds-200672412</link><description>Copper futures remain in bullish momentum despite testing lows, supported by supply disruptions and looming U.S. tariffs on refined metal imports. Prices held above key support at $5.474 and are eyeing a retest of July highs around $5.964. Analysts note potential for profit-taking but sustained bullish sentiments amid trade uncertainties.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper analyst speculates about a bubble</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/copper-demand-ai-data-centers-usa-pricing-gdp-share/</link><description>U.S. Comex copper prices hit a record $5.80 per pound in July 2025 but stood at $5.44 on Dec. 26, driven by potential 50% tariffs and demand from AI data centers. Analyst John E. Gross cautions about possible over-enthusiasm akin to the dot-com era, with narrowing premiums suggesting arbitrage opportunities. Some predict new highs in 2026 amid ongoing supply tightness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Surged Sharply to Break Through 130000 yuan/mt on December 30 as the Customs Tariff Commission of the State Council Released the 2026 Tariff Adjustment Plan</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103697607/</link><description>Nickel prices surged sharply on December 30, with SMM #1 refined nickel trading at 128,400-136,700 yuan/mt, averaging 132,550 yuan/mt. The price increase was driven by the Customs Tariff Commission of the State Council releasing the 2026 tariff adjustment plan.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On December 30, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 128,400–136,700 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103697555/</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices on December 30 ranged from 128,400–136,700 yuan/mt with an average price of 132,550 yuan/mt, up 850 yuan/mt from the previous trading session.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>From Glencore trader to Indonesia's nickel king</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/30/from-glencore-trader-to-indonesias-nickel-king</link><description>A former Glencore trader has become the dominant figure in Indonesia's nickel ore trade, handling about a third of the market amid the country's 70% global production share. His stakes span vast mining concessions critical for batteries and EVs. This occurs as Indonesia transitions to influencing nickel prices deliberately.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>ZincFive Raises $30 Million in Oversubscribed Series F Financing</title><link>https://zincfive.com/news/zincfive-raises-30-million-in-oversubscribed-series-f-financing/</link><description>ZincFive secured $30 million in Series F funding to scale production of its patented nickel-zinc battery technology for AI data centers. The company launched its BC 2 AI cabinet, engineered for dynamic AI workloads with zero thermal-runaway risk and 96% recyclability, strengthening its position as a key enabler of sustainable, AI-ready infrastructure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>From Glencore trader to Indonesia's nickel king</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/30/from-glencore-trader-to-indonesias-nickel-king</link><description>Indonesia controls nearly 70% of global nickel production through technological innovations that transformed low-grade deposits into battery-grade nickel. Key developments include a 2014 ore export ban that shifted the country toward processing and manufacturing, and the adoption of high-pressure acid leaching (HPAL) technology that enabled cost-effective battery-grade nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>US tariff policy affects Japanese steel industry – JISF</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>US tariff policy is impacting the Japanese steel industry, as reported by JISF on December 30, 2025. Other recent notes include 8% growth in Indian steel demand for FY2025/26. The site aggregates steel market news on prices and trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Kutcho Copper Announces Closing of Flow-Through Financing</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/279231/Kutcho-Copper-Announces-Closing-of-FlowThrough-Financing</link><description>Kutcho Copper Corp closed a flow-through financing to fund exploration on its Kutcho copper-zinc property in British Columbia. The proceeds will qualify as Canadian exploration expenses to be incurred by December 31, 2026. This supports the company's development plans for the project amid risks in mineral exploration and mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Soar to Phase Highs on Dec 30, 2025 Driven by Fund Flows and Supply Disruptions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103698385/Nickel-Prices-Soar-to-Phase-Highs-on-Dec-30-2025-Driven-by-Fund-Flows-and-Supply-Disruptions</link><description>Nickel prices surged significantly on December 30, 2025, with the LME nickel three-month contract reaching $16,700/mt. The single-day increase exceeded 5%, hitting new phase highs driven by fund flows and supply disruptions. This momentum approached previous peaks amid non-ferrous metal market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>New aluminium projects in Indonesia ramp up, boosting daily average aluminium production outside China</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/new-aluminium-projects-in-indonesia-ramp-up-boosting-daily-average-aluminium-production-outside-china-116757</link><description>Overseas aluminium production increased 2.2% year-over-year in December 2025, with cumulative 2025 production up 2.8% YoY. New Indonesian aluminium projects in ramp-up stage diluted overall operating rates to 87.7%, while energy challenges threaten smelters in Australia (Tomago) and Mozambique (Mozal), with Mozal scheduled for maintenance shutdown around March 15, 2026 due to power supply disagreements.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>New Aluminum Projects in Indonesia Ramp Up, Boosting Daily Average Aluminum Production Outside China</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103699828/New-Aluminum-Projects-in-Indonesia-Ramp-Up-Boosting-Daily-Average-Aluminum-Production-Outside-China</link><description>Overseas aluminum production in December 2025 rose 2.2% year-over-year with an average monthly operating rate of 87.7%, primarily impacted by new Indonesian projects still in commissioning phase. Energy supply agreements remain critical concerns for major smelters, with Tomago securing long-term energy arrangements and Mozal facing shutdown due to power supply negotiations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel stocks up 2nd straight day, rally up to 5%; SAIL, JSL hit 52-wk highs</title><link>https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/steel-stocks-up-2nd-straight-day-rally-up-to-5-sail-jsl-hit-52-wk-highs-125123100167_1.html</link><description>Share prices of steel companies rallied up to 5% for the second straight day amid government notification of anti-dumping and safeguard duties on flat steel imports for three years. Leading Indian steelmakers hiked domestic HRC and CRC prices by ₹750/tonne on December 30, 2025, to ~₹49,800/ton and ~₹56,400/ton respectively, with further hikes planned for early January 2026. Prices reflect higher raw material costs, moderate inventories, and recovering demand despite prior corrections from May 2025 highs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 31.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides daily updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar terms unchanged on December 30, 2025, and various 1- and 2-month futures for Turkey, China, Europe, and North America as of December 29, 2025. The platform covers indices, prices, and news for rebar, scrap, and iron/steel markets. No specific price changes noted in the latest snapshot.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper drifts higher, but holds below record with investors wary</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-drifts-higher-but-holds-below-record-with-investors-wary/</link><description>Copper prices rose on Tuesday but remained well below recent record highs as investors stayed cautious. The drift higher reflects ongoing market trends amid supply concerns and demand pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Alara Resources Dispatches 32nd Copper Concentrate Shipment</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/31/alara-resources-dispatches-32nd-copper-concentrate-shipment/</link><description>Alara Resources announced the dispatch of its 32nd shipment of copper concentrate from the Al Wash-hi – Majaza copper-gold mine in Oman on December 30, 2025. The shipment totaled 1378.6 WMT of copper concentrate containing approximately 252.6 MT of copper and 5.3 kg of gold. The mine, operated by Alara’s joint venture Al Hadeetha Resources LLC, has maintained consistent production levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 31, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103699678/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price reached 132,700-142,400 yuan/mt on December 31, with an average of 137,550 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 5,000 yuan/mt from the previous day. The price surge reflects ongoing market volatility in nickel trading.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel hits nine-month high</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/31/nickel-hits-nine-month-high</link><description>Nickel prices hit a nine-month high after Indonesia announced plans to cut supply in 2026 to balance demand and boost prices. The country, producing nearly 70% of global nickel for stainless steel and EV batteries, will tighten mining quotas. Despite a weaker year due to battery demand disappointment, Indonesian output remains central to 2026 price outlook.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Surge Reaches Nine-Month High Following Indonesian Cuts</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/nickel-price-surge-2025-policy-intervention/</link><description>Nickel prices surged to a nine-month high following signals of supply cuts from Indonesia. The move aims to address oversupply and support market prices amid global demand trends. This development highlights Indonesia's influence on nickel market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices jump to multi-month high on Indonesia supply cut signals</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-prices-jump-to-multi-month-high-on-indonesia-supply-cut-signals</link><description>Nickel prices on the LME surged to a multi-month high on Tuesday after Indonesia signaled supply cuts. The announcement triggered sharp gains amid ongoing supply concerns. Prices reflect expectations of tighter quotas to stabilize the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits Nine-month High as Indonesia Plans to Cut Output</title><link>https://klse.i3investor.com/web/blog/detail/ceomorningbrief/2025-12-31-story-h500614173-Nickel_Hits_Nine_month_High_as_Indonesia_Plans_to_Cut_Output</link><description>Nickel prices hit a nine-month high following Indonesia's announcement to cut supply and boost prices. As the top producer, Indonesia's output reduction plans are driving the market surge.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Hits Nine-Month High on Indonesia Cuts</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/nickel-price-surge-2025-policy-intervention/</link><description>Nickel prices surged to a nine-month high following Indonesia's planned output cuts. The policy intervention by the top producer is fueling the price rally.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>