<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:17:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Europe heavy steel plate prices buoyed by CBAM cost pressures</title><link>https://eurometal.net/europe-heavy-steel-plate-prices-buoyed-by-cbam-cost-pressures-strong-slab-offers-lack-of-imports/</link><description>Domestic heavy steel plate prices in Europe remained strong in the week ending November 6, supported by the EU's impending Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) cost pressures. The market is also influenced by strong slab offers and a lack of imports, which are sustaining price levels.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Europe heavy steel plate prices buoyed by CBAM cost pressures and strong slab offers</title><link>https://eurometal.net/europe-heavy-steel-plate-prices-buoyed-by-cbam-cost-pressures-strong-slab-offers-lack-of-imports/</link><description>Domestic heavy steel plate prices in Europe remained strong due to the EU's upcoming Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) and limited imports. Cost pressures and robust slab offers have supported price levels in the European steel plate market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Resources Launches CopperTech Metals to Bolster U.S. Copper Security and Advance Technology and Infrastructure Transformation</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/business-wire/20251106537189/vedanta-resources-launches-coppertech-metals-to-bolster-us-copper-security-and-advance-technology-and-infrastructure-transformation</link><description>Vedanta Resources launched CopperTech Metals, a U.S.-domiciled company focused on expanding copper production from the Konkola Copper Mines in Zambia. The company plans to increase production from 140,000 tonnes in FY26 to 300,000 tonnes by 2031, with ambitions to reach 500,000 tonnes annually, leveraging advanced mining and AI-driven technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CopperTech Metals Launch: High-Grade Mining Investment</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/coppertech-metals-launch-2025-strategic-vision/</link><description>CopperTech Metals launched with a focus on high-grade copper mining assets in Zambia, boasting ore grades of 2.9–3.3% copper, significantly above global averages. The company emphasizes integrated operations and advanced technology to maximize efficiency and profitability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Dixie Gold Inc. Readies for a Tightening Copper Environment with the Soo East Copper Project</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/273408/Dixie-Gold-Inc.-Readies-for-a-Tightening-Copper-Environment-with-the-Soo-East-Copper-Project-Divests-Interest-in-Preston-JV</link><description>Dixie Gold Inc. has acquired the Soo East Copper Project in Ontario, comprising 137 mining claims over approximately 3,013 hectares. This acquisition follows recent high-grade copper discoveries nearby and positions the company to capitalize on tightening copper supply conditions. The project aims to leverage exploration advances to meet growing copper demand sustainably.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SKF presents a novel bearing steel designed to enable the next generation of aeroengine technology</title><link>https://www.skf.com/group/news-and-events/news/2025/2025-Nov-06-skf-presents-a-novel-bearing-steel-designed-to-enable-the-next-generation-of-aeroengine-technology</link><description>SKF introduced a novel bearing steel that supports faster development cycles and aligns with industry sustainability goals. This innovation is designed to enhance aeroengine technology while contributing to sustainability in steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel to Attend North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference 2025, Highlighting Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project’s Smelter-Free Processing and Chromium Byproduct Potential</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/06/3182419/0/en/First-Atlantic-Nickel-to-Attend-North-American-Stainless-Special-Alloys-Conference-2025-Highlighting-Pipestone-XL-Nickel-Alloy-Project-s-Smelter-Free-Processing-and-Chromium-Byprod.html</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel is showcasing its Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project at the 2025 North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference, emphasizing its smelter-free, low-impact processing. Metallurgical tests confirm high-grade nickel concentrates (1.30–1.47% nickel) with significant chromium content, achievable through magnetic separation and flotation, reducing mass by ~90% and energy use. The project leverages large awaruite grain sizes for efficient recovery and uses established North American mineral processing technologies.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel Announces Consolidated Production Results for 9M 2025</title><link>https://nornickel.com/news-and-media/press-releases-and-news/nornickel-announces-consolidated-production-results-for-9m-2025/</link><description>Nornickel has released its consolidated production results for the first nine months of 2025, highlighting increased ore volumes due to the gradual adoption of new mining equipment at its Polar Division. The update provides insights into the company’s operational performance and capacity adjustments, though specific nickel production figures are not detailed in the summary.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>West High Yield’s Barry Baim on Securing the Mining Permit for Record Ridge Magnesium Nickel Silica Iron</title><link>https://investornews.com/critical-minerals-rare-earths/west-high-yields-barry-baim-on-securing-the-mining-permit-for-record-ridge-magnesium-nickel-silica-iron/</link><description>West High Yield has secured a mining permit for its Record Ridge project in British Columbia, which contains nickel alongside magnesium, silica, and iron. The project emphasizes a simple, low-environmental-impact extraction process (drill, blast, crush, and ship), with ore delivery expected to begin mid-2026. The company highlights its partnership with the Osoyoos Indian Band and the project’s proximity to existing infrastructure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever Pioneer Carbon-Free Aluminum in Packaging</title><link>https://marketchameleon.com/articles/b/2025/11/6/alcoa-ball-unilever-elysis-carbon-free-aluminum-packaging</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever have launched the world's first consumer personal and home care packaging using ELYSIS carbon-free aluminum. The ELYSIS technology eliminates greenhouse gas emissions from aluminum smelting by using inert anode technology, producing oxygen instead of CO2. This marks a significant step toward decarbonizing the aluminum industry and meeting global sustainability goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball, Unilever unveil ELYSIS zero-carbon smelted aerosol</title><link>https://www.packaging-gateway.com/news/alcoa-ball-unilever-unveil-elysis/</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever have introduced a new aluminum smelting technology that replaces traditional carbon anodes with inert materials, eliminating direct greenhouse gas emissions. The first industrial-scale deployment of ELYSIS technology is underway, supporting decarbonization across the aluminum value chain. The announcement coincides with COP30 and highlights industry collaboration for sustainable packaging.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever make announcement ahead of COP30</title><link>https://metalpackager.com/2025/11/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-make-announcement-ahead-of-cop30/</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever have announced the first use of ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology in consumer personal and home care packaging. The new aerosol can uses 50% ELYSIS primary aluminum and 50% post-consumer recycled content, representing one of the lowest-carbon packaging solutions available. This initiative demonstrates cross-value chain collaboration for decarbonization.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Italy's Tenaris posts 2% rise in quarterly net sales</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/italy-s-tenaris-posts-2-rise-in-quarterly-net-sales-ce7d5dd2de8cf321</link><description>Italian steel pipe maker Tenaris reported a 2% increase in net sales for the third quarter of 2025, driven by higher sales volumes. The company primarily produces steel pipes for the oil and gas industry, with sales distributed globally including 9.6% in Europe.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Surging: Bull Run Amid Supply Crunches</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2024/11/27/aluminum-prices-to-surge/</link><description>Global aluminum prices have surged to a five-month high, reaching around $2,710 a tonne on November 7, 2025, driven by economic growth, supply concerns, and the impact of China's production caps. Supply constraints are exacerbated by halted bauxite exports from Guinea and reduced output from Australia and Jamaica, causing inventories to drop to their lowest since 2015.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CBA CEO signals Brazilian aluminum export shift</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/cba-ceo-signals-brazilian-aluminium-export-shift/</link><description>Brazilian aluminum producer CBA is shifting its product mix toward ingots to meet demand and redirecting volumes from U.S. to European customers amid tariff-driven market changes. Despite increased competition and tariffs, CBA maintains a competitive advantage with low-carbon products and strong client relationships, while U.S. Midwest aluminum premiums hit historic highs due to inventory depletion.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Price Difference Between Steel Coil and Steel Screw Contracts</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103028892</link><description>On November 7, the price gap between the main contract for steel coil and steel screw was 154 yuan/ton, down 10 yuan/ton from the previous day. This reflects ongoing volatility and narrowing margins in the Chinese steel futures market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Steel Glut Threatens Japan Trading Houses in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/china-steel-export-surge-2025-market-disruption/</link><description>China's record steel exports in 2025, exceeding 100 million tons annually, are causing market disruption and financial pressure on Japan's major trading houses. The oversupply is driven by weak domestic demand and unchanged production capacity, leading to aggressive export strategies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metallus Announces Third-Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/metallus-announces-third-quarter-2025-results-302607495.html</link><description>Metallus reports Q3 2025 results and provides an outlook for Q4, noting lower expected shipments and adjusted EBITDA due to seasonality and supply chain issues. The company anticipates a slight increase in base prices for bar and tube products, with extended lead times into early 2026.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>150 Small Steel Mills in India Halt Production Due to Low Prices</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/150-small-steel-mills-in-india-have-suspended-operations-due-to-low-steel-prices/</link><description>Approximately 150 small steel mills in India have suspended operations because of excessively low steel prices, highlighting the financial strain on smaller producers amid challenging market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 07, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-07-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's share price rose by 0.15% to ₹1,155.70, reflecting positive market sentiment despite broader industry challenges. The update provides real-time insight into investor confidence in one of India's largest steel producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Trump expands critical minerals list to copper, met coal, uranium</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-11-07/national/politics/Trump-expands-critical-minerals-list-to-copper-met-coal-uranium/2438979</link><description>The Trump administration added 10 minerals, including metallurgical coal used for steel production, to the U.S. critical minerals list to boost domestic mining and reduce reliance on imports from China. This expansion supports federal investments and incentives to secure materials vital for defense, manufacturing, and clean energy, aiming to strengthen U.S. supply chains against global disruptions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metallus Announces Third-Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/metallus-announces-third-quarter-2025-results-302607495.html</link><description>Metallus reported its Q3 2025 financial results and highlighted a new long-term supply agreement for vacuum arc remelt (VAR) steel, securing a stable, high-quality steel source to support growth in aerospace and defense markets. The company is targeting $250 million in annual aerospace and defense sales by mid-2026 and continues labor negotiations with the United Steelworkers union.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A billion lessons for green iron in Australia</title><link>https://ieefa.org/articles/billion-lessons-green-iron-australia</link><description>Australia is investing $1 billion in developing a green iron industry, aiming to learn from the experiences of Europe and the US in transitioning to sustainable steel production. The initiative reflects growing global interest in decarbonizing steel manufacturing to meet environmental goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Composite Metal Foam Could Lead to Safer Hazmat Transportation</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-composite-metal-foam-safer-hazmat.html</link><description>A new study reveals that composite metal foam (CMF) can withstand extreme forces, making it a promising material for safer transportation of hazardous materials. This innovation could significantly improve safety standards in the steel and transportation sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Trump expands critical minerals list to copper, met coal, uranium</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-11-07/national/politics/Trump-expands-critical-minerals-list-to-copper-met-coal-uranium/2438979</link><description>The U.S. administration expanded its critical minerals list to include copper, metallurgical coal, and uranium, emphasizing copper's importance for electric vehicles, power grids, and data centers. This move aims to boost domestic mining, reduce reliance on imports from China, and guide federal investments and incentives to secure supply chains for defense and clean energy technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/nickel-price-update-q3-2025-review</link><description>Nickel prices were volatile in the first half of 2025 but stabilized in Q3 amid ongoing oversupply concerns driven mainly by rapid production growth in Indonesia. Despite rising demand, the market remains structurally oversupplied, with LME nickel stockpiles increasing significantly through the third quarter. The end of the US EV tax credit on September 30 may also impact future nickel demand in the electric vehicle sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Falling Stainless Prices Drag Suppliers</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2024/11/07/steel-nickel-prices-drag-suppliers/</link><description>Chinese primary nickel prices fell 7.06% to $15,940 per metric ton, while Indian prices dropped 8.54%, reflecting a bearish trend in nickel following a decline in stainless steel prices. The stainless steel market remains weak due to contraction in the U.S. manufacturing sector, with major producers reporting year-over-year sales declines, further pressuring nickel demand and prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/492981</link><description>Nickel futures dropped below $15,100 per tonne, the lowest level in over a month, due to continued oversupply from Indonesia. Indonesian production has flooded global supply chains, pushing LME inventories to a record high of 308,000 tons. In response, Indonesia has tightened production quotas and mining permit regulations to stabilize prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Stellantis terminates Alliance Nickel offtake deal</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/stellantis-terminates-alliance-nickel-offtake-deal-2025-11-07</link><description>Stellantis has ended its nickel offtake agreement with Alliance due to falling nickel prices and tighter financing conditions, which have delayed project progress. The termination reflects the challenging market environment for nickel amid price declines and financial constraints.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel to Attend North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference 2025</title><link>https://investingnews.com/first-atlantic-nickel-to-attend-north-american-stainless-special-alloys-conference-2025-highlighting-pipestone-xl-nickel-alloy-project-s-smelter-free-processing-and-chromium-byproduct-potential-for-no/</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel announced its participation in the North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference, highlighting its Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project. The project features a unique nickel-iron-cobalt alloy mineral, awaruite, which allows for smelter-free processing and supports a resilient domestic supply chain amid ongoing nickel market volatility and oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alliance Nickel's Offtake Agreement with Stellantis to be Renegotiated</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/07/alliance-nickels-offtake-agreement-with-stellantis-to-be-renegotiated/</link><description>Alliance Nickel announced that Stellantis has provided notice of termination for their binding offtake agreement effective December 3, 2025, due to missed contractual milestones amid challenging nickel market conditions. Stellantis remains interested in renegotiating terms aligned with the revised project timeline and market environment. Alliance Nickel is also exploring strategic alternatives including a potential SPAC transaction for a Nasdaq listing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia tightens nickel smelter licensing, limits new projects</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-tightens-nickel-smelter-licensing-limits-new-projects</link><description>The Indonesian government has officially restricted new investment permits for nickel smelters by tightening licensing requirements. This policy aims to push the nickel industry towards higher value-added processing and control the rapid expansion of smelting capacity. The move is expected to impact new projects and investment decisions in Indonesia's nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to Over 3-Year High Amid Tight Supply and China's Production Cap</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK rose to $2,915 per tonne, the highest in over three years, driven by tight supply and China's commitment to preventing overcapacity with an annual output cap of 45 million tons. Prices rose 0.45% to $2,856.95 USD/T on November 7, 2025, with forecasts expecting prices to reach $2,918.78 USD/T by the end of the quarter and $3,053.09 in 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US aluminum scrap trade faces 2025 shake-up amid tariffs and global demand</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5101605-us-aluminum-scrap-trade-faces-2025-shake-up-amid-tariffs-and-global-demand</link><description>The US aluminum scrap trade experienced significant changes in early 2025 due to new import tariffs and shifting global demand. Imports of aluminum scrap rose 31% in the first half of 2025 compared to the previous year, despite a 25% import tariff implemented in March. This tariff led recyclers to increasingly rely on domestic scrap recovery rather than foreign imports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Pioneering Sustainable Practices Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever Lead with Carbon-Free Smelting Technology</title><link>https://csimarket.com/news/pioneering-sustainable-practices-alcoa-ball-and-unilever-lead-with-carbon-free-smelting-technology2025-11-07140104</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever are leading the way in sustainable aluminum technology by deploying ELYSIS carbon-free smelting for consumer packaging. This initiative demonstrates how material innovation and industry collaboration can drive tangible sustainability benefits and reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel prices fall slightly amid ongoing market adjustments</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,034 CNY/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.16% from the previous day. Over the past month, steel prices have declined by 1.97% and are down 6.07% compared to the same time last year. The price is expected to trade at 3,039.40 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,904.76 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel prices show modest decline but remain up year-on-year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel traded flat at 847 USD/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.35% from the previous day. Despite the slight daily drop, prices have risen 3.82% over the past month and are up 19.39% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect HRC Steel to reach 864.45 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 934.57 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Klöckner sharpens US focus as Americas segment delivers strong Q3</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/07/klockner-sharpens-us-focus-as-americas-segment-delivers-strong-q3/</link><description>Klöckner Metals Americas reported robust earnings in Q3 2025 despite softer steel prices, with shipments up 2.8% year-on-year. The company is selling eight US distribution sites to focus more on higher-value-added metal processing, aiming to reduce exposure to volatile commodity markets and increase service center business to 87% of sales.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel posts strong Q3 as Nippon centers it in global growth strategy</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/07/u-s-steel-posts-strong-q3-as-nippon-centers-it-in-global-growth-strategy/</link><description>U.S. Steel reported a 15% increase in net sales to $4.43 billion in Q3 2025, driven by strong performance in its Mini Mill and Tubular segments. Despite higher costs and weaker European demand reducing net income by 16% year over year to $100 million, the Mini Mill segment saw an 86% sales increase and improved margins due to higher prices and contributions from Big River Steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron ore logs weekly loss on soft steel demand, production cuts in China</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/iron-ore-logs-weekly-loss-on-soft-steel-demand-production-cuts-in-china/</link><description>Blast furnace production cuts in North China, a major steelmaking region, have led to a decline in steel output, contributing to a weekly loss in iron ore prices. The reduced steel demand and production adjustments reflect ongoing challenges in the Chinese steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China will promote value-added steel production</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/china-will-promote-value-added-steel-production/</link><description>China's annual steel production is expected to fall below 1 billion tons for the first time in six years by the end of 2025, driven by declining demand. The country plans to focus on promoting value-added steel production to adapt to changing market conditions and improve product quality.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>USWC's Rare November Bulk Scrap Cargo Sale to Turkey</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/scrap-metal-trade-anomaly-2025-rare-cargo-turkey/</link><description>The U.S. West Coast (USWC) sold a rare bulk scrap cargo to Turkey amid disruptions in Asian scrap markets, creating a unique arbitrage opportunity. Turkey remains a major scrap importer with strong demand for premium scrap grades, benefiting from geographic advantages and electric arc furnace technology adoption.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Falls on Fed Policy, Codelco Supply</title><link>https://www.miningreporters.com/noticia/news/2025/11/copper-price-falls-fed-policy-codelco-supply</link><description>Copper extended losses as renewed uncertainty over US interest rates and positive production signals from Chile's Codelco eased supply fears, with LME three-month copper around $10,855/tonne and COMEX near $5.013/lb. The US dollar's strength and mixed signals from Fed officials further pressured prices, though copper remains up over 20% in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Set for Weekly Drop</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/500126</link><description>Copper futures steadied around $4.95/lb but were set for a weekly loss amid a global risk-off mood, weak Chinese trade data, and speculation about Beijing curbing copper refining overcapacity. Concerns over AI valuations and a prolonged US government shutdown added to the cautious market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 15020 USD/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.23% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices decreased to 15,020 USD per tonne on November 7, 2025, marking a 0.23% drop from the previous day. Over the past month, nickel prices fell by 2.40%, and are down 8.01% compared to the same time last year, reflecting ongoing oversupply concerns and muted momentum in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The world nickel market in 2025 – a growing surplus in an uncertain global landscape</title><link>https://stainless-steel-world.net/the-world-nickel-market-in-2025-a-growing-surplus-in-an-uncertain-global-landscape/</link><description>Global primary nickel production is projected to grow by 5.9% in 2025, contributing to a growing surplus amid record-high EV sales and rising stainless steel production. LME and SHFE nickel inventories have been rising steadily, surpassing 230,000 tonnes in early 2025, reflecting ongoing oversupply despite geopolitical uncertainties.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Woes: Innovations Steering a Sustainable EV Future</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-supply-woes-innovations-steering-a-sustainable-ev-future-aemc/</link><description>This article discusses the critical role of nickel in battery technology for electric vehicles (EVs) and highlights innovations such as low-nickel or nickel-free battery chemistries, advanced battery recycling, and smaller battery sizes to ensure sustainability. It also emphasizes financial incentives and policies like the U.S. Inflation Reduction Act and the EU’s Battery Fund to boost domestic battery production and mining capacities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Greening nickel extraction requires institutional and financial support</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-01811-8</link><description>The article highlights the environmental challenges of nickel mining, particularly the greenhouse gas emissions from clearing carbon-rich forests. It stresses the need for institutional and financial backing to scale up low-carbon nickel extraction technologies to reduce the industry's carbon footprint.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,856.95 per tonne on November 7, 2025, marking a 0.45% daily increase and an 8.63% rise year-over-year. Prices are expected to reach $2,918.78 by the end of the quarter and $3,053.09 in 12 months, driven by tight supply and China's output caps.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever launch first consumer packaging using carbon-free ELYSIS aluminum</title><link>https://esgpost.com/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-launch-first-consumer-packaging-using-carbon-free-elysis-aluminum/</link><description>Alcoa Corporation, Ball Corporation, and Unilever PLC announced the first commercial use of ELYSIS® carbon-free smelting technology in consumer packaging. This innovation eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions from aluminum smelting by generating oxygen instead of CO2, producing aerosol cans with 50% ELYSIS primary aluminum and 50% recycled content, representing one of the lowest-carbon packaging solutions available.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Pioneering Sustainable Practices: Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever Lead with Carbon-Free Smelting Technology</title><link>https://csimarket.com/news/pioneering-sustainable-practices-alcoa-ball-and-unilever-lead-with-carbon-free-smelting-technology2025-11-07140104</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever are leading sustainable aluminum production by adopting ELYSIS technology that eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions during smelting. This breakthrough aligns with global decarbonization goals and demonstrates how cross-sector collaboration can scale low-carbon innovations in industrial supply chains.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Billions at stake: Chancellor Merz backs European patriotism for steel</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/business/2025/11/07/billions-at-stake-chancellor-merz-backs-european-patriotism-for-steel</link><description>German steel production faces challenges due to Chinese subsidies and US tariffs, with EU steel output declining and major producers like Thyssenkrupp cutting jobs. The EU is proposing stricter trade measures, including tighter import quotas and higher tariffs, to protect its steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper prices soars due to mine closures!</title><link>https://www.xtb.com/int/market-analysis/news-and-research/copper-prices-soars-due-to-mine-closures</link><description>Copper prices surged to their highest levels since May last year following a serious accident at the Grasberg Block Cave mine in Indonesia and mine closures in Peru. These supply disruptions, combined with rising demand from the energy transition, have increased market uncertainty and pushed prices closer to record highs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Electrification Fuels Unprecedented Demand and Market Volatility</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-11-7-coppers-green-revolution-electrification-fuels-unprecedented-demand-and-market-volatility</link><description>Copper demand is surging due to the global energy transition, driven by electric vehicles, renewable energy infrastructure, and grid modernization. Technological advances like AI, data centers, and 5G networks further increase copper consumption, with emerging markets such as India becoming significant demand drivers alongside China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer eases to $2,841/t as opening stock edges up to 549,225t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-eases-to-2-841-t-as-opening-stock-edges-up-to-549-225t-116132</link><description>LME aluminium prices declined slightly on November 7, with the cash bid slipping to $2,840/t and the cash offer easing to $2,841/t. Stocks showed a marginal increase, with opening stock rising to 549,225 tonnes and live warrants up 0.51%. The 3-month Asian Reference Price was $2,848/t.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Stainless Steel Daily Review: Stainless Steel Market Faces Year-End Off-Season, Low Spot Prices Fail to Boost Demand</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Finished-Steel</link><description>Stainless steel futures and spot prices remain weak due to the year-end off-season and tepid demand, despite active discounting by mills. Social inventory increased slightly, and major steel mills lowered list prices, keeping the market sluggish.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vedanta spins off Konkola Copper Mines into US-domiciled CopperTech Metals Inc.</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2025/11/07/vedanta-spins-off-konkola-copper-mines-into-us-domiciled-coppertech-metals-inc/</link><description>Vedanta Resources has spun off Konkola Copper Mines into a US-based company, CopperTech Metals Inc., to meet US copper resource security needs. CopperTech plans to invest an additional $1.5 billion on top of Vedanta's existing $3 billion investment in the Konkola mine.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] On November 7, nickel prices moved ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103609730</link><description>Nickel prices declined after a higher opening on November 7, 2025, as the US dollar index continued to fall. The market showed signs of weakness despite some early gains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Russia’s Nornickel, one of the largest nickel producers globally, maintained its 2025 nickel production outlook at 196,000-204,000 metric tons. Nickel production rose 18% to 54,000 metric tons in Q3 2025, attributed to higher volumes of processed raw materials, despite earlier shipment cuts due to seasonal flooding.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Green steel revolution: navigating a new frontier in 2025</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/green-steel-revolution-navigating-a-new-frontier-in-2025/</link><description>Sweden is set to produce the world's first zero-carbon emission steel in 2025, marking a historic milestone for the industry. The shift to green steel, driven by hydrogen-based direct reduction iron and scrap-based electric arc furnace technologies, will reshape pricing, markets, and supply chains, though challenges remain around energy costs and infrastructure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Coarse Particle Flotation: Mining Recovery Revolution</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/coarse-particle-flotation-technology-2025-benefits/</link><description>Coarse particle flotation (CPF) technology is transforming mineral processing by enabling efficient recovery of valuable minerals from larger particles, improving sustainability and operational efficiency in mining. The technology reduces energy and water use, minimizes tailings, and is gaining rapid adoption across major mining operations.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Strengthens as Trade Tensions Ease</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-strengthens-as-trade-tensions-ease/</link><description>Copper prices rose on Friday, supported by signs of easing trade tensions between major economies, providing some relief after recent declines driven by Fed uncertainty and supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Maxus Mining Announces Closing of Flow Through Private Placement</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/6239431</link><description>Maxus Mining closed a flow-through private placement, supporting exploration at its Penny Copper Project in British Columbia. The project has returned high copper values in grab samples, indicating potential for future copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM News Flash: High-Nickel Pig Iron Prices Decline on November 8</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103030296/SMM-News-Flash:-High-Nickel-Pig-Iron-Prices-Decline-on-November-8</link><description>SMM reported that the price range for 8-12% high-nickel pig iron (ex-factory price) declined to 1005~1025 yuan/nickel on November 8, 2025. The drop reflects ongoing market pressures and subdued demand in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Q3 2025 slides: Sequential growth amid missed expectations</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/company-news/century-aluminum-q3-2025-slides-sequential-growth-amid-missed-expectations-93CH-4340937</link><description>Century Aluminum reported sequential progress in Q3 2025 despite missing expectations. The company is advancing a new smelter project expected to take 4-6 years and create over 6,500 jobs, which will help address the U.S. aluminum deficit. For 2025, Century projects total aluminum shipments of 660,000 tonnes and anticipates improved EBITDA in Q4.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Record Bull Bets Signal a New Era for Industrial Metals</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-11-8-aluminums-unprecedented-ascent-record-bull-bets-signal-a-new-era-for-industrial-metals</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged past $2,900 per metric ton, driven by a forecasted supply shortfall growing from 8,000 tons in 2025 to 365,000 tons in 2026. Primary producers like Alcoa stand to benefit from higher margins and potential capacity expansions, while downstream industries face cost pressures and supply challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Environmental Engineering Researchers are Using Plants to Extract Nickel for Sustainable Mining</title><link>https://www.stevens.edu/news/environmental-engineering-plants-nickel-mining</link><description>Researchers at Stevens are developing phytomining technology that uses hyperaccumulator plants to extract nickel from ultramafic mine tailings and serpentine barren soils, which are otherwise unproductive. This method offers a cleaner, more sustainable alternative to traditional nickel mining by reducing environmental damage and enabling phytoremediation to clean contaminated soils.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Can Waste From Nickel Production Create Better Concrete?</title><link>https://www.azobuild.com/news.aspx?newsID=23931</link><description>A new study shows that waste from nickel production can be repurposed to strengthen concrete, reduce emissions, and improve sustainable building practices. This innovation could reshape construction materials by turning nickel production scrap into valuable resources.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's top cable maker sees US copper tariff as opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Italy's Prysmian, the world's largest copper cable manufacturer, views the US's planned 50% copper tariff as a positive move that will strengthen the American supply chain. The company, which acquired Texas-based Encore Wire, expects costs to be passed on to customers and is in regular contact with the US administration regarding the implementation of the tariff.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Investors Amass Record Bull Bets on Aluminium Supply Shortage</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/fund-positioning-market-transformation-2025/</link><description>Record investment surges in aluminum reflect structural supply shortages amplified by US tariffs and EU sanctions on Russian aluminum. The US Midwest premium hit $1,938 per ton, 67% above the LME price, indicating tight supply and depleted inventories ahead of tariff hikes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,856.95 per tonne on November 7, 2025, supported by demand in electrification sectors and supply disruptions including a potline suspension at Iceland's Grundartangi smelter and Alcoa's shutdown of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia. China maintains a production cap of 45 million tons annually, limiting supply growth amid rising energy costs and regulatory risks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global bauxite upswing triggers exports, expansions and collaborations across the aluminium ecosystem</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/global-bauxite-upswing-triggers-new-expansions-and-collaborations-across-the-aluminium-ecosystem-heres-whats-unfolding-116130</link><description>The global increase in bauxite demand is driving new exports, expansions, and collaborations within the aluminum industry. This upswing is fostering advancements in aluminum casthouse technology and supporting sustainable growth across the aluminum ecosystem worldwide.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,029 CNY/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.33% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have declined 2.13%, and are down 6.22% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts suggest steel will trade at 3,039.40 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,904.76 in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 7-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 15,020 USD/ton on November 7, 2025, marking the lowest level since September and a 2.40% decline over the past month. The market is expected to trade at 14,887.32 USD/ton by the end of the quarter, with further declines projected over the next 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market Shows Recovery Signs Amid Policy Support &amp; Trade Tensions</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-market-shows-recovery-signs-amid-policy-support-trade-tensions</link><description>Nickel prices have moved into the upper half of the $15,000-$15,800 per ton range, suggesting a potential recovery as battery supply chains may be entering a restocking cycle. Policy support and trade tensions, including US tariffs on Chinese graphite and deals with Indonesia, are influencing the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Live Nickel Price</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/price/base-metals/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices are currently at 15,089.99 USD/ton, down slightly from the previous day. The market remains volatile, with prices fluctuating within a narrow range.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME Nickel Official Prices</title><link>https://www.lme.com/en/metals/non-ferrous/lme-nickel</link><description>The official LME nickel price for November 9, 2025, is 14,830.00 USD/ton (bid) and 14,840.00 USD/ton (offer), reflecting a continued downward trend in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel prices traded flat at 847 USD/T on November 7, 2025, but have risen 4.18% over the past month and 19.80% year-on-year. Forecasts suggest prices will reach 858.87 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 930.60 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,856.95/t on November 7, up 0.45% from the previous day. The price has increased 3.55% over the past month and is up 8.63% year-on-year. Futures are expected to trade at $2,879.83/t by the end of the quarter.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Hits 627,000 mt on Nov 10, Up 5,000 mt WoW from Last Thu</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611375/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Hits-627000-mt-on-Nov-10-Up-5000-mt-WoW-from-Last-Thu</link><description>Domestic aluminum ingot social inventory in China reached 627,000 mt on November 10, up 5,000 mt week-on-week. LME aluminum is projected to trade between $2,830-$2,930/mt in the coming week.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever pioneer carbon-free aluminum manufacturing for consumer packaging</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-pioneer-carbon-free-aluminum-manufacturing-for-consumer-packaging/</link><description>Alcoa, in partnership with Ball Corporation and Unilever, announced the first use of ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology for consumer packaging, eliminating direct greenhouse gas emissions by producing oxygen instead of CO2. This initiative represents a significant step toward low-carbon aluminum products and highlights cross-sector collaboration ahead of COP30 climate discussions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Hits 627,000 mt on Nov 10, Up 5,000 mt WoW from Last Thu</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611375/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Hits-627000-mt-on-Nov-10-Up-5000-mt-WoW-from-Last-Thu</link><description>Social inventory of domestic aluminum ingots in China reached 627,000 metric tons as of November 10, 2025, increasing by 5,000 metric tons week-over-week. Market expectations for SHFE aluminum prices range between 21,300-21,900 yuan/mt, while LME aluminum is projected between $2,830-$2,930/mt next week.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Asian steel market seen under pressure in Q4 amid weak demand, trade barriers</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/asian-steel-market-seen-under-pressure-in-q4-amid-weak-demand-trade-barriers/</link><description>The Asian steel market is under pressure in Q4 2025 due to weak demand and rising trade barriers, according to a recent S&amp;P Global Commodity Insights report.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>WA to source green steel from local manufacturers for gov't projects</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/wa-to-source-green-steel-from-local-manufacturers-for-govt-projects/</link><description>The Western Australian Government has launched an initiative to use locally made green steel in major government projects, supporting job creation and local manufacturing. The program encourages the use of sustainable building materials and introduces a new procurement approach favoring local green steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Steel?</title><link>https://fremantleshippingnews.com.au/2025/11/10/green-steel/</link><description>Fortescue has initiated a green iron pilot project at Christmas Creek in the Pilbara, with first production scheduled for 2025. This marks a significant step in Australia's efforts to develop green steel production capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Participation in the Development of Critical Minerals and Rare Earths Feedstock Production Project in Australia</title><link>https://www.marubeni.com/en/news/2025/info/00037.html</link><description>Marubeni Corporation announced its participation in a critical minerals and rare earths feedstock production project in Australia, supporting the development of essential materials for advanced manufacturing, including steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>WA to source green steel from local manufacturers for gov't projects</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/wa-to-source-green-steel-from-local-manufacturers-for-govt-projects/</link><description>The Western Australian Government announced an initiative to prioritize locally made green steel for major government infrastructure projects, supporting the state's manufacturing sector and sustainability goals. The program includes a new procurement approach favoring green steel and aims to create jobs while advancing decarbonization in construction materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Consumer Confidence Falls to a Low Level, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611345/US-Consumer-Confidence-Falls-to-a-Low-Level-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper futures opened at $10,743.5/mt on Friday night, fluctuated during the session, and closed slightly higher at $10,695/mt with a 0.07% increase. The SHFE copper contract closed marginally lower at 85,920 yuan/mt. Vedanta Resources announced the establishment of CopperTech Metals Inc. in the US to meet copper resource security needs amid rising demand driven by data centers, power grids, and defense technology.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price holds loss as equity rout, strong dollar weigh on metals</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-holds-loss-as-equity-rout-strong-dollar-weigh-on-metals/</link><description>Copper prices traded near $10,650 per ton on the LME after a four-day losing streak, pressured by a stronger US dollar and global equity market declines. The recent rally cooled following a record high last month amid optimism over a US-China trade deal and supply disruptions. Chinese buyers were seen purchasing dips, and a key African port for copper trade reopened, easing supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium rises with copper as US govt shutdown nears end</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/node/778947</link><description>Copper prices rose alongside aluminium on November 10, boosted by improving risk appetite as the US government shutdown neared resolution. This positive market sentiment contributed to gains in base metals including copper.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise Amid Uncertainty Over U.S. Tariffs</title><link>https://www.gurufocus.com/news/3197726/copper-prices-rise-amid-uncertainty-over-us-tariffs</link><description>Copper prices have risen amid uncertainty over potential changes to U.S. tariffs, with indications from the U.S. President about reconsidering copper tariffs. This could tighten global copper supply outside the United States, influencing market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US Consumer Confidence Falls to a Low Level, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611345/US-Consumer-Confidence-Falls-to-a-Low-Level-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated and closed lower on Friday, ending at $10,695/mt with a 0.07% increase, while SHFE copper also saw a slight decline. Trading volumes and open interest remained robust, reflecting ongoing market activity. The meeting also noted Vedanta's spin-off of Konkola Copper Mines into US-based CopperTech Metals Inc.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Critical Minerals List: 2025 Strategic Addition</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/critical-minerals-strategic-value-copper-demand-2025/</link><description>The US officially added copper to its critical minerals list in November 2025, highlighting its strategic importance. The article discusses global copper production concentration, with Chile leading, and notes China's dominance in refining capacity, which creates supply chain vulnerabilities. Infrastructure and workforce limitations in the US are also highlighted.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Bullish Outlook: China's Industrial Resilience and Global Supply Constraints Drive Growth</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-bullish-outlook-china-industrial-resilience-global-supply-constraints-drive-growth-2511/</link><description>China's industrial output surged in Q3 2025, boosting copper demand, especially from high-tech manufacturing and NEV production. The article forecasts a 150,000 metric ton deficit in 2026 and a 40% rise in global demand by 2040, underscoring the need for supply-side solutions. Copper's role in decarbonization and digitalization is emphasized.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper and Potassic alteration above main Southern Porphyry Target at Llahuin</title><link>https://www.shmining.com.au/2025/11/copper-and-potassic-alteration-above-main-southern-porphyry-target-at-llahuin/</link><description>Exploration drilling at the Llahuin project has advanced to 1,198.9m downhole, with copper and potassic alteration identified above the main Southern Porphyry Target. The results indicate potential for further copper discoveries in the region.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>USGS officially adds copper, silver to critical minerals list</title><link>https://www.mining.com/us-officially-adds-copper-silver-to-critical-minerals-list/</link><description>The US Geological Survey has officially added copper and silver to the critical minerals list, emphasizing their importance to the US economy and national security. The update will inform policy decisions on trade, investment, and mine permitting, reflecting growing concerns over supply chain security.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Hits 4-Year Low as Gloom Offsets Potential Indonesia Cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell to their lowest level in four years, driven by a lackluster outlook from the Federal Reserve and concerns over a stronger US dollar. Despite Indonesia considering sharp mining quota cuts, the market remains oversupplied and sentiment is weak.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices were in the doldrums on ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103607793</link><description>Nickel prices remained weak on November 10, 2025, with little movement as market participants awaited further developments. The US dollar index continued to influence price trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Breakthrough Tech Yields 99% Pure Nickel, Cobalt</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/breakthrough-tech-yields-99-pure-nickel-cobalt-1566990/</link><description>A new electrochemical process has been developed to recover nickel and cobalt with over 97% nickel recovery and 99% purity from battery leachates. This technology minimizes chemical usage and enables sustainable recycling with high metal purity and recovery rates, potentially impacting nickel supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>