<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 05:17:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>European Green Steel Summit 2025: shaping the future of the steel industry</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/european-green-steel-summit-2025-shaping-the-future-of-the-steel-industry/</link><description>The European Green Steel Summit 2025 will address carbon emission reduction, green steel production, and innovative technologies, focusing on sustainable advancements in the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper fell to 4.87 USD/Lbs on October 10, 2025, down 4.80% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices dropped to 4.87 USD per pound on October 10, 2025, marking a 4.80% decline from the previous day. Despite this recent fall, copper prices have risen 5.58% over the past month and are up 9.37% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect copper to trade at 5.18 USD/Lb by the end of the current quarter and 5.66 USD/Lb in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 4.14% Lower at $4.8485 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510105682/comex-copper-ends-the-week-414-lower-at-48485-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for October delivery lost 20.95 cents per pound, or 4.14%, closing at $4.8485 this week. This represents the largest one-week net and percentage decline since early August 2025, snapping a two-week winning streak. The price is down 16.33% from its 52-week high of $5.795 hit in July 2025 but remains up 8.92% from 52 weeks ago.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Goldman Sachs expects copper price to remain in $10,000-$11,000 range in 2026/2027</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/metals-research-goldman-sachs-zero</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts copper prices to stay within the $10,000 to $11,000 per metric ton range during 2026 and 2027 due to an expected market surplus. This outlook reflects anticipated supply and demand dynamics influencing the copper market in the medium term.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold Higher Following a Historic Week</title><link>https://www.admis.com/gold-higher-following-a-historic-week/</link><description>The International Copper Study Group (ICSG) forecasts a surplus of approximately 178,000 tons in the global refined copper market for 2025, down from an earlier forecast of 289,000 tons. Refined copper production is expected to rise by 3.4% in 2025 but slow to 0.9% growth in 2026. Copper usage is predicted to increase by about 3% in 2025 and 2.1% in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Eroding trust in US dollar behind gold, silver and copper price rally, says TD Securities</title><link>https://www.mining.com/eroding-trust-in-us-dollar-behind-gold-silver-and-copper-price-rally-says-td-securities/</link><description>Copper prices are surging as investors lose faith in the US dollar, driving a rush into hard assets. This trend is attributed to a breakdown in confidence in the dollar as a reliable store of value. Copper surged toward $11,000 a tonne amidst this market shift.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anglo American moving forward with SandLix™ heap leach innovation</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2025/10/10/anglo-american-moving-forward-with-sandlix-heap-leach-innovation/</link><description>Anglo American is advancing the SandLix™ heap leaching process, which can reduce the cut-off grade for copper extraction by up to 20%, improving resource efficiency and sustainability. This innovative technology aims to optimize copper recovery while minimizing environmental impact in mining operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Falls to 15,168 USD/T, Down 2.05% from Previous Day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped to 15,168 USD per ton on October 10, 2025, marking a 2.05% decline from the previous day. Over the past month, nickel has fallen 0.34%, and is down 15.25% compared to a year ago.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 4-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/492274</link><description>Nickel decreased to 15,151.00 USD per ton, the lowest level since September 2025. Over the past four weeks, nickel lost 0.43%, and it has declined 15.33% in the last 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price Update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103561993/</link><description>On October 10, the SMM #1 refined nickel price in China was 122,400–125,300 yuan per metric ton, with an average price of 123,850 yuan/mt, up 250 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>NexMetals Announces Continuance into British Columbia</title><link>https://nexmetalsmining.com/investors/news-releases/nexmetals-announces-continuance-into-british-colum-11528/</link><description>NexMetals Mining Corp., a company focused on copper, nickel, and cobalt resource redevelopment in Botswana, announced its legal continuance from Ontario to British Columbia. The move includes updated corporate articles under the British Columbia Business Corporations Act but retains its stock symbols and CUSIP/ISIN numbers. The company emphasizes its experienced team and commitment to governance in advancing its nickel-related mining projects.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Exane BNP favors Vallourec over Tenaris</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L5N3VR0CX:0-exane-bnp-favors-vallourec-over-tenaris/</link><description>Exane BNP Paribas downgraded its rating on Tenaris to 'neutral' from 'outperform' due to a challenging outlook for oil country tubular goods makers amid weaker prices and tariff uncertainties. The brokerage prefers Vallourec over Tenaris, citing Vallourec's better market positioning and revenue exposure in less risky regions.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S.A. Reports Shareholder Update on Ownership Stake and Planned Share Sales</title><link>https://www.quiverquant.com/news/Tenaris+S.A.+Reports+Shareholder+Update+on+Ownership+Stake+and+Planned+Share+Sales</link><description>Tenaris's controlling shareholders plan to sell some shares while maintaining at least 67% ownership, responding to the company's share repurchase program. The shareholders have no current plans to reduce their stake below 67%, indicating confidence in Tenaris's governance and stock value.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Daily Aluminum price, LME Comex Shfe Price of Aluminum live</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>SMM reports current aluminum prices with the SMM A00 Aluminum Ingot priced between $2,595.78 and $2,600.73 per metric ton. Premiums for aluminum in various regions remain stable, with Yangshan Aluminum Premium at $90 per metric ton. Expectations for US Fed interest rate cuts are influencing market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel and aluminum tariffs drive up costs for everyday fasteners</title><link>https://www.scrippsnews.com/life/money/steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-drive-up-costs-for-everyday-fasteners</link><description>Tariffs on steel and aluminum are significantly increasing costs for fasteners like screws and bolts, impacting construction and consumer goods. These tariffs have led to price hikes of 30-50% for some items, affecting both distributors and consumers. The broader economic impact includes delayed projects and higher consumer prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Falls to 811.06 USD/T, Down 0.48% from Previous Day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel prices dropped to 811.06 USD per tonne on October 10, 2025, marking a 0.48% decrease from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have seen a modest 0.13% increase, but remain near their lowest levels since February 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>MMI Daily Iron Ore Index Report October 10 2025</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/mmi-daily-iron-ore-index-report-october-10-2025/</link><description>The most-traded iron ore contract (I2601) closed at 795, up 1.02% from the previous day, as traders adjusted positions in line with market conditions. The report highlights ongoing activity among steel mills and traders in response to current market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Delayed Publication of Flat Steel Reduced Carbon Emissions Inferred Price</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/delayed-publication-of-flat-steel-reduced-carbon-emissions-inferred-price/</link><description>Fastmarkets announced a delay in the publication of its flat steel reduced carbon emissions price assessment for China, now scheduled for October 17. The previous assessment ranged from 3,360 to 3,870 yuan per tonne.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>STEEL TECH - International Seminar '25</title><link>https://tenova.com/newsroom/upcoming-events/steel-tech-international-seminar-25</link><description>The STEEL TECH International Seminar 2025 in Kolkata, India, focuses on integrating AI and advanced technologies to enhance efficiency and sustainability in steel production. Praveen Chaturvedi from Tenova Technologies presented a paper on 'Intelligent EAF,' an expert technology aimed at maximizing furnace process efficiency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BIR warns that a proposed regulation could lay groundwork for trade limitations on ferrous scrap</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/bir-warns-that-proposed-regulation-could-lay-groudwork-for-trade-limitations-on-ferrous-scrap/</link><description>The Bureau of International Recycling (BIR) highlights concerns over a new EU regulation aimed at protecting the steel industry from global overcapacity. The regulation could impact investments in green steel projects, threatening the EU's decarbonization goals and risking job losses in the steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>MSCI Announces Annual Safety Innovation and Culture Improvement Award Winners</title><link>https://www.msci.org/msci-announces-annual-safety-innovation-and-culture-improvement-award-winners-4/</link><description>MSCI honored Metallus, Steel Services, Inc., and Worthington Steel with its annual Safety Innovation and Culture Improvement awards, recognizing advancements in safety practices within the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Near 10-Week High on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/492245</link><description>Copper futures slipped below $5.1 per pound amid profit-taking but stayed near ten-week highs due to supply disruptions in Chile and Indonesia. Chile's state miner Codelco reported its lowest monthly output in over two decades following a fatal accident that halted operations. Indonesia's Grasberg mine also faces limited output after a recent fatal accident, with full capacity not expected until early 2027.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>After a rally to $11,000/t, copper prices fall on the back of profit-taking</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/10/10/after-a-rally-to-11000t-copper-prices-fall-on-the-back-of-profittaking</link><description>Copper prices fell on October 10, 2025, as investors took profits following a rally to a 16-month high of $11,000 per tonne the previous session. The decline reflects typical market corrections after sharp price increases.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Near 10-Week High on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/491990</link><description>Copper futures remain near ten-week highs despite a slight slip due to profit-taking, driven by ongoing mine disruptions in Chile and Indonesia that are tightening global supply. Chile's state miner Codelco reported its lowest monthly output in over 20 years for August, and Indonesia’s Grasberg mine is operating below capacity after a fatal accident. Additionally, Canada's Teck Resources lowered its annual production outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>TNR Gold NSR Royalty Update – Los Azules Feasibility Study Confirms Economically Robust Copper Project With Leading ESG Performance</title><link>https://tnrgoldcorp.com/2025-news/tnr-gold-nsr-royalty-update-los-azules-feasibility-study-confirms-economically-robust-copper-project-with-leading-esg-performance/</link><description>The Los Azules copper project in Argentina is confirmed as a long-life, low-cost producer with strong economic returns and sustainability credentials. The project advances toward construction readiness with a design that reduces environmental footprint and aligns with the global energy transition toward a low-carbon future.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price on October 10</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103561993/</link><description>On October 10, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 122,400 and 125,300 yuan per metric ton, with an average price of 123,850 yuan/mt, which is an increase of 250 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Update: High-Grade NPI Prices Under Pressure with Limited Downside</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103562889/SMM-Update:-High-Grade-NPI-Prices-Under-Pressure-with-Limited-Downside</link><description>Nickel prices have fluctuated significantly, with domestic inventory seeing a substantial buildup. The market dynamics are influenced by supply and demand factors, impacting high-grade nickel pig iron (NPI) prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Constructs Photovoltaic Plants</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is involved in a project to construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily, enhancing its energy performance and reducing environmental impact. This aligns with its partnership with CVA to support regional decarbonization targets. The project contributes to the competitiveness of the local steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Launches Green Hydrogen Pilot Plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has launched a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, Italy. This initiative is part of the company's efforts to innovate and reduce its environmental impact.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Completes $85 Million Exhaust System Upgrade</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-completes-85-million-exhaust-system-upgrade-to-boost-sustainability</link><description>Tenaris has completed an $85 million exhaust system upgrade at its steel mill in Koppel, Pennsylvania. The new system aims to improve air quality by more effectively collecting and separating dust and particulates. This investment is part of a broader $140 million upgrade since 2020.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Celebrates 25 Years of Seamless Pipe Production in Canada</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-marks-25-years-of-seamless-pipe-production-in-canada-and-commitment-to-its-long-term-i-ce7d5adbdb8ff725</link><description>Tenaris marked 25 years of seamless pipe production in Canada, highlighting its role in supporting the energy industry. The company has expanded its capabilities with both seamless and electric resistance welded (ERW) pipe manufacturing. This milestone underscores Tenaris's commitment to industrial growth.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Exane BNP Favors Vallourec Over Tenaris</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L5N3VR0CX:0-exane-bnp-favors-vallourec-over-tenaris/</link><description>Exane BNP Paribas prefers Vallourec over Tenaris due to a weaker price environment for oil country tubular goods (OCTG). It downgraded Tenaris's rating to 'neutral' while maintaining 'outperform' for Vallourec. The decision reflects Vallourec's diversified market exposure.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Shareholder Update on Ownership Stake and Planned Share Sales</title><link>https://www.quiverquant.com/news/Tenaris+S.A.+Reports+Shareholder+Update+on+Ownership+Stake+and+Planned+Share+Sales</link><description>Tenaris's controlling shareholders plan to sell shares while maintaining at least a 67% ownership stake. This decision is in response to Tenaris's ongoing share repurchase program. The move aims to stabilize long-term investment in the company.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Week | October 10</title><link>https://www.aluminum.org/news/aluminum-week-october-10</link><description>The U.S. Aluminum Industry Sector Snapshot report released during Aluminum Week highlights positive environmental impact trends, showcasing the industry's progress in sustainability and innovation. The event provides access to technical articles, standards, and data to support sustainable aluminum solutions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Korea to unveil policy plan for EU steel tariffs in October</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-10-10/business/industry/Korea-to-unveil-policy-plan-for-EU-steel-tariffs-in-October/2417248</link><description>The Korean government plans to release a comprehensive policy package by late October to address the European Union's tightened steel tariffs. The strategy includes enhanced incentives, strengthened antidumping measures, support for hydrogen-based steelmaking, and efforts to leverage the Korea-EU FTA to protect domestic producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany's SPD Proposes Strategic Measures to Strengthen Europe's Steel Industry</title><link>https://millichronicle.com/2025/10/56782.html</link><description>Germany's Social Democrats (SPD) are advancing proposals to support sustainable growth and fair competition in Europe's steel sector. The plan includes a tariff-quota system to manage imports, promote a 'buy European' approach, and enhance oversight of steel imports to protect domestic production and jobs while fostering innovation in clean steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Trump Tariffs on China Cause Seismic Shift in Copper Markets</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/trump-tariffs-china-impact-copper-2025/</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange fell 4.9%, marking the largest single-day decline in five months, amid tariff threats against China. The market is already constrained by supply issues due to ESG barriers and major mine transitions, and new trade barriers risk disrupting the complex global copper supply chain, potentially delaying projects and causing inventory buildups.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices, Charts, Analysis &amp; Forecast</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper spot prices on major exchanges including SHFE, LME, and COMEX showed a price range around $10,700 per metric ton on October 10, 2025, with premiums and discounts fluctuating slightly. The market reflects ongoing adjustments amid supply constraints and tariff-related uncertainties.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price tumbles as Trump threatens massive new tariffs on China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-tumbles-as-trump-threatens-massive-new-tariffs-on-china/</link><description>Copper prices dropped significantly after President Donald Trump threatened to impose new tariffs on Chinese goods. This move reversed recent gains fueled by production setbacks at major copper mines. The tariffs could impact global copper demand and supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Gold Mine: 7 Innovations In Copper Mining 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-gold-mine-7-innovations-in-copper-mining-2025</link><description>This article explores how copper mining innovations in 2025 are driving sustainable infrastructure and green technologies. It highlights advanced ore beneficiation, AI-driven digital monitoring, and sustainability frameworks that are revolutionizing copper mining to support renewable energy systems, electric vehicles, and telecommunications.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Lithium &amp; Copper Mining Companies: 2025 Outlook</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/chinese-lithium-copper-mining-companies-2025-outlook</link><description>Chinese copper mining companies are leading in both production and technological innovation, with output expected to reach nearly 10 million metric tons in 2025. The sector focuses on resource efficiency, digital twin modeling, hydro-metallurgical extraction, and strict environmental mandates, while expanding overseas assets in Africa, South America, and Central Asia to secure supply and support sustainable mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Future of copper mining: global demand, strategic alliances</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/future-of-copper-mining-addressing-global-demand-with-strategic-alliances-and-sustainable-innovations-andrea-hotter/</link><description>The article discusses innovations in copper mining such as Anglo American's hydraulic dry stacking technology to address tailings capacity challenges, aiming for more sustainable production. It also covers ongoing environmental compliance efforts near the Chagres copper smelter and the potential for scaling new technologies industry-wide to meet global demand sustainably.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Resources at the Forefront of North America's Critical Minerals Security Push</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-10-teck-resources-at-the-forefront-of-north-americas-critical-minerals-security-push</link><description>Teck Resources, in a proposed merger with Anglo American, is central to North America's strategy to secure critical minerals like copper for clean energy and advanced technologies. The merger aims to create a resilient supply chain with sustainable mining practices, though challenges remain in investment, regulation, and workforce development to ensure long-term self-sufficiency and ESG compliance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices fluctuate amid inventory buildup and policy disruptions</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Nickel</link><description>Nickel prices showed significant volatility this week, initially rising due to disruptions in Indonesian mining policies but later pulling back. The SHFE nickel contract closed at 122,180 yuan/mt, up 0.49% from pre-National Day levels, while LME nickel prices fell to $15,320/mt, down 0.68% week-over-week. Domestic inventory also saw a substantial buildup during this period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to $15,215 USD/T on October 10, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped 1.74% from the previous day to $15,215 USD/T. Over the past month, prices remained nearly flat with a slight 0.03% decline and are down 14.99% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect nickel to trade around $15,184.79 USD/T by the end of the current quarter.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel 28 Confirms US$1.4M Cash Distribution from Ramu JV</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CONXF/nickel-28-announces-confirmation-of-cash-distribution-from-ramu-bnjb88y6mg2h.html</link><description>Nickel 28 Capital Corp. announced a cash distribution of approximately US$1.4 million from its Ramu joint venture for H1 2025, alongside a US$2.5 million partner debt repayment. The first half of 2025 was impacted by reduced production due to mechanical failures, but full production is expected in the second half, potentially improving future results.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel 28 Confirms US$1.4M Cash Distribution from Ramu JV</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CONXF/nickel-28-announces-confirmation-of-cash-distribution-from-ramu-bnjb88y6mg2h.html</link><description>Nickel 28 Capital Corp. announced a cash distribution of approximately US$1.4 million from its Ramu joint venture for the first half of 2025. The distribution was impacted by reduced production due to mechanical issues, but full production is expected in the second half of the year. Projects within Nickel 28's royalty portfolio are progressing positively.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia Targets 71,234 Tons of Nickel Production in 2025</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/vale-indonesia-inco-targets-71234-tons-of-nickel-production-in-2025</link><description>Vale Indonesia aims to produce 71,234 tons of nickel-in-matte in 2025, exceeding its 2024 target. This increase is part of the broader production trends in Indonesia.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : marks 25 years of seamless pipe production in Canada and commitment to its long-term industrial growth</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-marks-25-years-of-seamless-pipe-production-in-canada-and-commitment-to-its-long-term-i-ce7d5adbdb8ff725</link><description>Tenaris celebrated 25 years of seamless pipe production at its Canadian facility in Sault Ste. Marie, highlighting its role in supporting the domestic energy industry with high-quality steel pipes. The company also noted recent upgrades including electric resistance welded pipe manufacturing, reinforcing its unique capabilities in Canada.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel fell to 3,086 CNY/T on October 10, 2025, down 0.29% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices decreased slightly by 0.29% to 3,086 CNY/T on October 10, 2025. Despite a 2.12% rise over the past month, steel prices remain 8.70% lower than a year ago. Analysts expect steel to trade at 3,047.39 Yuan/MT by the end of this quarter and forecast a decline to 2,917.81 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel rose to 814 USD/T on October 10, 2025, up 0.12% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices increased by 0.12% to 814 USD/T on October 10, 2025. Over the past month, HRC steel prices rose 0.49% and are up 15.46% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts indicate prices may reach 822.71 USD/T by the end of this quarter and 883.35 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global steel forum sets 2026 framework deadline as US ups pressure on excess capacity</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/10/global-steel-forum-sets-2026-framework-deadline-as-us-ups-pressure-on-excess-capacity/</link><description>The global steel forum has set a deadline for a 2026 framework aimed at addressing excess steel production capacity worldwide. The US is increasing pressure on other countries to manage steel capacity to stabilize the market and reduce trade tensions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HVAC equipment shipments down through August amid China's booming steel exports</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/10/hvac-equipment-shipments-down-through-august/</link><description>Despite rising global protectionist measures, China's direct steel exports continue to grow strongly this year, impacting related markets such as HVAC equipment shipments, which have declined through August. The steel export boom is reshaping global steel trade flows and capacity utilization.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Falls to $15,215/T, Down 1.74% on the Day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped to $15,215 per tonne on October 10, 2025, marking a 1.74% decline from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have fallen 0.03%, and are down nearly 15% compared to the same period last year, reflecting ongoing market weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Fluctuate Significantly Amid Inventory Buildup</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103563065/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-fluctuated-significantly-this-week-while-domestic-inventory-saw-a-substantial-buildup</link><description>Nickel prices experienced notable volatility this week, initially rising due to Indonesian policy disruptions but then retreating as bullish sentiment faded. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 122,180 yuan/mt, up slightly from pre-holiday levels, while LME nickel was quoted at $15,320/mt, down 0.68% week-over-week.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium hits USD 2,799.5/t — steady gains or early signs of surge</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-hits-usd-2-799-5-t-steady-gains-or-early-signs-of-surge-115802</link><description>On October 10, the London Metal Exchange aluminum price rose to USD 2,799.5 per tonne, reflecting subtle market optimism amid shifting global conditions. The 3-month bid and offer prices also increased, while inventory levels showed slight changes. The alumina price remained steady at USD 323 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Asian Battery Metals advances high-grade copper-nickel discovery in Mongolia</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/10/asian-battery-metals-advances-high-grade-copper-nickel-discovery-in-mongolia/</link><description>Asian Battery Metals reported high-grade copper-nickel sulphide intercepts in Mongolia, with grades up to 6% copper and 3% nickel. The company is advancing exploration with promising metallurgy results and aims to establish a district-scale resource, positioning Mongolia as an emerging critical minerals hub near China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion in Italy focusing on the strategic role of nuclear energy in Europe's energy transition and Italy's boilermaking industry future. The event highlighted advances in nuclear technologies and Tenaris's recent accreditation to supply certified materials for nuclear facilities according to the ASME III standard, reflecting its commitment to quality and safety in the nuclear sector.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris in Italy achieves ASME certification for the supply of materials for the nuclear sector</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-in-italy-achieves-asme-certification-for-the-supply-of-materials-for-the-nuclear-sector</link><description>Tenaris's seamless steel pipe mill in Dalmine, Italy, obtained ASME III certification, qualifying it to supply certified materials for nuclear facilities. This accreditation supports Tenaris's participation in the low-carbon energy market by meeting stringent international standards essential for nuclear plant construction and maintenance.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Steel Prices Poised for Rebound in October</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/analysis/5100433-mysteel-china-steel-prices-poised-for-rebound-in-october</link><description>After declining over the past two months, Chinese steel prices are expected to rise in October due to improved market fundamentals. The article suggests that this rebound could stabilize the market, but details are available only with a subscription.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Eyeing China, EU unveils sweeping measures to shield struggling steel industry</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/aseanplus/aseanplus-news/2025/10/11/eyeing-china-eu-unveils-sweeping-measures-to-shield-struggling-steel-industry</link><description>The EU has introduced measures to protect its steel industry from global overcapacity, particularly focusing on steel of Chinese origin. Proposals include a 'melt and pour requirement' to prevent circumvention via other countries and ongoing investigations into China's trade practices. EU leaders emphasize the need for balanced trade and long-term solutions to overcapacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper fell to 4.80 USD/Lbs on October 10, 2025, down 6.16% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices dropped 6.16% to $4.80 per pound on October 10, 2025, despite a 4.07% rise over the past month and a 7.81% increase year-over-year. Analysts expect copper to trade at $5.18 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.66 in 12 months, reflecting ongoing market volatility and supply-demand dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Resources lowers copper production guidance for 2025</title><link>https://www.townandcountrytoday.com/national-business/teck-resources-lowers-copper-production-guidance-for-2025-11320351</link><description>Teck Resources has reduced its copper production forecast for 2025 due to operational challenges at key mining assets. The company now expects to produce between 415,000 and 465,000 tonnes of copper. Strong copper prices are partially offsetting the financial impact of reduced production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 10-week High at $15,551 USD/T</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/491774</link><description>Nickel prices increased to $15,551 USD/T, marking the highest level since July 2025. Over the past four weeks, nickel gained 2.42%, although it remains down 11.47% over the last 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Matte Production Down 0.05% MoM in Sep</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5100658-indonesia-nickel-matte-production-down-005-mom-in-sep</link><description>Indonesia's nickel matte production decreased by 0.05% month-over-month in September, totaling 28,800 tonnes in Ni content. This slight decrease reflects ongoing supply dynamics in the region.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Enters New Period in Steel Production with Green Hydrogen Facility</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/haber/cogne-located-in-aosta-has-entered-a-new-period-in-steel-production-with-a-green-hydrogen-facility/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is advancing sustainable steel production by integrating green hydrogen into its processes. The company aims to reduce carbon emissions by using green hydrogen, produced from renewable sources, in its industrial heat treatment processes. This innovation also positions Cogne as a material partner in the hydrogen value chain.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian was awarded the tender by Terna and STEG for the submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia under the Elmed Project. The contract could reach a value of around €460 million and involves laying cables at depths up to 800 meters, enhancing energy security between Europe and Africa.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy awards Prysmian $539mn contract for Tunisia-Europe power cable</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/italy-awards-prysmian-539mn-contract-for-tunisia-europe-power-cable/</link><description>Prysmian Group won a contract worth up to €460 million ($539 million) to build a submarine power cable linking Italy to Tunisia. This project is part of efforts to enhance power interconnections between Europe and Africa, supporting energy transition goals.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Al Arabia Co. for Aluminum targets over 10,000 tonnes in annual exports</title><link>https://www.dailynewsegypt.com/2025/10/11/al-arabia-co-for-aluminum-targets-over-10000-tonnes-in-annual-exports/</link><description>Al Arabia Co. for Aluminum aims to exceed 10,000 tonnes in annual aluminum exports, having recently increased exports by 75% in the last quarter to markets including Morocco, Tunisia, Libya, Lebanon, and Canada. The company is also enhancing operational efficiency through a new aluminum recycling plant and relocation of administrative offices, supporting Egypt's industrial and export development goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weekend Drive: Aluminum plant fire exposes supply chain fragility</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6BFLeLGpBAQ</link><description>A recent aluminum plant fire has caused significant disruptions for automakers like Ford, highlighting the fragility and interdependency of supply chains in the automotive industry. The discussion emphasizes how such incidents can lead to production slowdowns and layoffs, underscoring the critical role of domestic aluminum producers amid ongoing steel and aluminum tariffs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weak steel market threatens Chinese met coke prices in October</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/analysis/5100496-monthly-weak-steel-market-threatens-chinese-met-coke-prices-in-october</link><description>After a brief recovery early in October, Chinese metallurgical coke prices are expected to weaken in the second half of the month due to a weak steel market. Daily reports indicate cautious sentiment and stable prices during the holiday period, with some northern Chinese mills accepting price hikes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper falls on profit-taking</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40386931</link><description>Copper prices declined as investors booked profits following a rally that pushed prices to a 16-month high in the previous session. This profit-taking reflects short-term market corrections after recent strong price performance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Resources Lowers Copper Production Guidance for 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/teck-resources-copper-production-challenges-2025-2/</link><description>Teck Resources has revised its copper production guidance downward for 2025 by 55,000-60,000 metric tons due to operational challenges at the Quebrada Blanca and Highland Valley Copper mines. Despite these setbacks, the company expects to overcome geological issues by early 2026 and benefits from strong copper market prices averaging $4.44/lb in Q3 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Lowers Copper Production Forecast Amid Mine Challenges</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/teck-resources-copper-production-2025-challenges/</link><description>Teck Resources lowered its copper production guidance for 2025 due to operational difficulties at key mines, including unplanned maintenance and geological constraints. However, strong copper prices and tight global supply-demand dynamics are partially offsetting the financial impact of reduced output, with market fundamentals remaining favorable.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Italian steel factory invests USD 14 mln in training center in Romania</title><link>https://www.romania-insider.com/italian-steel-factory-invests-usd-14-mln-in-training-center-in-romania</link><description>Italian steel manufacturer Tenaris invested USD 14 million in a training center for its 1,700 employees in Zalau, Romania. This investment aims to enhance workforce skills and support the company's operations in the region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>North American Green Aluminium Summit 2025</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/events/north-american-green-aluminium-summit-2025/</link><description>The North American Green Aluminium Summit 2025 will explore aluminium's role in carbon reduction and discuss pathways to decarbonization, recycling technologies, and strategies for achieving net-zero emissions in the industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum's Sustainability Blueprint</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/century-aluminums-sustainability-blueprint-for-a-carbon-free-tomorrow-115782</link><description>Century Aluminium is advancing sustainability through low-carbon aluminium production, ASI certifications, carbon capture, and waste management. The company aims to improve efficiency and unlock a more sustainable future for the industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Shortens Mining Production Quotas to Annual Review</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/indonesia-mining-quota-reform-impact-production-prices-2025/</link><description>Indonesia has implemented an annual review system for mining production quotas to better control output and stabilize commodity prices. This change allows the government to adjust production levels annually based on market conditions and environmental considerations. Companies must now demonstrate environmental compliance to secure quotas.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>UN Calls for Transition Metals Mining Finance Reform</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/news/un-calls-for-transition-metals-mining-finance-reform-to-protect-environment-and-human-rights/</link><description>The United Nations has called for reform in financing the extraction of critical minerals like nickel to ensure sustainable development and respect for human rights and the environment. This comes as demand for clean energy technologies surges. The reform aims to make responsible mining practices the norm.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali signs Memorandum of Understanding with CVA for photovoltaic plants in Sicily</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will benefit from enhanced energy performance and reduced environmental impact through the construction of four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily with a total capacity of over 20 MW. This agreement with CVA supports the company's decarbonisation goals and economic competitiveness as part of its 2026–2029 Strategic Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://www.pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems for district heating and anti-corrosion coatings in Europe. The acquired business unit has been rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy, enhancing Tenaris's offshore market offerings and enabling anti-corrosion coating application at its facilities in Italy and other countries.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>The Cost Side Suppressed the Upward Space of Aluminum Prices, and Aluminum Prices May Stabilize First and Then Strengthen in October</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-27054.html</link><description>Aluminum prices initially strengthened and then weakened in September, with the average price of aluminum ingots in East China rising slightly. Prices fell primarily due to weakening costs but are expected to stabilize and then strengthen in October as destocking accelerates and costs rise.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium hits USD 2,799.5/t — steady gains or early signs of surge?</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-hits-usd-2-799-5-t-steady-gains-or-early-signs-of-surge-115802</link><description>LME aluminium cash offer climbed to USD 2,799.5 per tonne with 3-month prices firming, reflecting subtle market optimism amid shifting global conditions. The steady gains indicate positive sentiment in the aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel prices fall slightly but expected to rise by year-end</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,086 CNY/T on October 10, 2025, down 0.29% from the previous day. Despite this short-term dip, steel prices have risen 2.12% over the past month but remain 8.70% lower than a year ago. Analysts expect steel to trade at 3,047.39 Yuan/MT by the end of this quarter and forecast a price of 2,917.81 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel prices show modest gains with positive outlook</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) Steel prices rose to 814 USD/T on October 10, 2025, up 0.12% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices increased by 0.49% and are up 15.46% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts predict HRC Steel to reach 831.44 USD/T by the end of this quarter and 894.34 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel delivers solid returns amid steady market conditions</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/stock-liveblog/jsw-steel-share-price-live-13-oct-2025/liveblog/124515822.cms</link><description>JSW Steel has delivered a 12.59% return over the last three months, reflecting strong quarterly performance and positive investor sentiment despite recent market fluctuations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel shows solid 3-month returns in a stable market</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/stock-liveblog/tata-steel-stock-price-live-updates-13-oct-2025/liveblog/124515756.cms</link><description>Tata Steel has achieved an 8.77% return over the last three months, indicating steady performance in the steel sector amid current market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU Announces Higher Tariffs on Steel Imports, Raising Concerns for Scunthorpe and Humber Region Industries</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/eu-announces-higher-tariffs-steel-imports-raising-concerns-scunthorpe-humber-region-industries-2510/</link><description>The European Union has announced increased import tariffs on steel products to protect domestic producers, impacting UK industries in the Scunthorpe and Humber region. The tariffs target flat and long steel, raising costs for British Steel and risking job losses in key manufacturing hubs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Stegra in new financing round</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/stegra-in-new-financing-round-302581648.html</link><description>Stegra is in a new financing round to fund the construction of the world's first large-scale green-steel plant in Boden, Sweden. The funding will cover additional infrastructure scope, higher project costs, and provide a financial buffer, supporting Stegra's competitive position in the green steel market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World Steel Association August 2025 Production Report</title><link>https://worldsteel.org</link><description>World crude steel production for 70 countries was 145.3 million tonnes in August 2025, a 0.3% increase compared to August 2024. The steel industry continues to focus on sustainability, environmental performance, and supporting the Paris Agreement goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hanwha Ocean, POSCO develop special steel for next-gen naval vessels</title><link>https://cyprusshippingnews.com/2025/10/13/hanwha-ocean-posco-develop-special-steel-for-next-gen-naval-vessels-2/</link><description>Hanwha Ocean and POSCO have developed a special steel designed for next-generation naval vessels, highlighting advancements in steel technology for defense applications.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ACME Group to invest Rs 5,000-cr in green DRI facility for low-carbon steel production</title><link>https://www.projectstoday.com/News/ACME-Group-to-invest-Rs-5000-cr-in-green-DRI-facility-for-low-carbon-steel-production</link><description>ACME Group plans to invest Rs 5,000 crore in a greenfield direct reduced iron (DRI) facility aimed at producing low-carbon steel products, supporting sustainable steel production initiatives.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Accelerating Innovation Through Collaboration: Sustainable Future For Australia's Resources Sector</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/accelerating-innovation-through-collaboration-1549882/</link><description>The article highlights how collaboration between research, government, and industry in Australia is accelerating the development of green steel technologies. The initiative focuses on de-risking new technologies, promoting faster adoption of green processing, and building a skilled workforce to support a sustainable, competitive green metals sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Carbon Neutral Vision 2050 | Environmental activities - Nippon Steel</title><link>https://www.nipponsteel.com/en/csr/env/warming/zerocarbon.html</link><description>Nippon Steel aims to reduce CO2 emissions by 30% by 2030 and achieve carbon neutrality by 2050 through breakthrough technologies such as blast furnace hydrogen reduction and hydrogen-based reduced iron production. The company plans significant R&amp;D and capital investment to realize carbon-neutral steelmaking processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>I-Pulse Welcomes Codelco as Strategic Investor</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251012216264/en/I-Pulse-Welcomes-Codelco-as-Strategic-Investor</link><description>Codelco joined I-Pulse as a strategic investor to support innovative mining technology that can reduce energy consumption in copper extraction by up to 80%. This partnership aims to improve copper production efficiency and meet growing demand driven by energy transition and technology infrastructure needs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices fell sharply on October 13 as Trump claimed to impose a 100% tariff on all Chinese goods</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103565190/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fell-sharply-on-October-13-as-Trump-claimed-to-impose-a-100-tariff-on-all-Chinese-goods</link><description>On October 13, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel dropped by 1,400 yuan/mt to an average of 122,450 yuan/mt amid geopolitical tensions triggered by tariff announcements. This sharp decline reflects market sensitivity to trade policy developments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On October 13, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 121,000–123,900 yuan/mt, with an average price of 122,450 yuan/mt, down 1,400 yuan/mt from the previous day</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103565195/</link><description>The refined nickel price on October 13 averaged 122,450 yuan/mt, marking a decrease of 1,400 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. This price movement aligns with broader market reactions to trade and economic factors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Fire at Indonesia Nickel Hub Raises Safety Concerns</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/indonesia-nickel-hub-fire-2025-safety-concerns/</link><description>A fire occurred at Indonesia's largest nickel processing facility, the Morowali Industrial Park, causing minor injuries and affecting a scrubber tower under construction. While the incident had minimal immediate impact on production, it raises concerns about safety and potential regulatory impacts on Indonesia's nickel supply chain, which could influence global nickel markets.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Persistent Supply Disruptions Sustain Upward Pressure on LME Nickel Prices</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-27046.html</link><description>Ongoing supply disruptions in the nickel market continue to exert upward pressure on London Metal Exchange (LME) nickel prices. These disruptions contribute to market volatility and reflect tight supply conditions in the global nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia emerging as strategic hub in critical minerals supply chain</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/icc-indonesia-emerging-as-strategic-hub-in-critical-minerals-supply-chain</link><description>Indonesia is increasingly recognized as a strategic hub in the global critical minerals supply chain, particularly for nickel. The country's role is expanding due to its large reserves and government policies supporting the sector, which impacts global nickel production capacity and supply security.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>