<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:14:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stevens Environmental Engineering Researchers are Using Plants to Extract Nickel</title><link>https://www.stevens.edu/news/environmental-engineering-plants-nickel-mining</link><description>Researchers at Stevens are advancing phytomining, using hyperaccumulator plants to extract nickel from ultramafic mine tailings and serpentine soils. This approach offers a cleaner, sustainable alternative to traditional mining by recovering nickel while remediating contaminated soils, potentially supporting greener clean energy technologies.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali signs Memorandum of Understanding with CVA for new photovoltaic plants in Sicily</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will benefit from four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily with a total capacity of over 20 MW, enhancing energy performance and reducing environmental impact. The agreement with CVA supports the company's decarbonisation goals and economic competitiveness through stable energy pricing and incentives under the Energy Release scheme.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>BofA Sees Growth Potential for Prysmian from US Tariffs</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/bofa-sees-growth-potential-for-prysmian-from-us-tariffs-ce7d59dddf88f323</link><description>Bank of America estimates Prysmian could benefit significantly from US copper tariffs, potentially raising copper cable prices by 10%, which could add up to EUR1 billion to 2026 EBITDA. Prysmian's copper cable production is largely US-based after acquiring Encore Wire, positioning it well against imports subject to high tariffs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME Week base metals: Challenges and opportunities</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/lme-week-2025-base-metals-market-challenges/</link><description>Fastmarkets reports that the aluminium P1020A premium prices in Rotterdam have risen notably over the past month, with the daily premium assessed at $185-200 per tonne on October 9, up from $150-170 a month earlier. Market participants are monitoring trade talks between the US and Canada, which could affect tariffs and trade tensions, while weak demand in China and slowing global growth pose challenges to the aluminium market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali signs Memorandum of Understanding with CVA for renewable energy projects</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will benefit from four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily with a total capacity of over 20 MW, enhancing energy performance and reducing environmental impact. The agreement with CVA supports the company’s decarbonisation goals and economic competitiveness through stable energy pricing and incentives under the Energy Release scheme.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>The Italian Antitrust Authority has launched an investigation into major low voltage copper cable manufacturers in Italy, including Prysmian, for allegedly fixing prices since 2005. Inspections were conducted at the companies' offices following a clemency request that provided detailed information on the illicit practices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Secures €460m Contract For Italy–Tunisia Subsea Power Link</title><link>https://www.wireworld.com/wirenews/prysmian-secures-460m-contract-for-italytunisia-subsea-power-link.html</link><description>Prysmian has won a €460 million contract to build a submarine power cable connecting Italy and Tunisia. This project highlights Prysmian's continued leadership in subsea cable infrastructure.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Why new EU steel tariffs to curb Chinese imports are giving carmakers a headache</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3328372/new-eu-steel-tariffs-meant-curb-chinese-imports-giving-carmakers-migraine</link><description>The EU's proposal to cut tariff-free quotas and double duties on imported steel, mainly targeting Chinese imports, has caused a sell-off in European auto stocks and increased cost pressures on car manufacturers. China is the EU's largest steel import partner, accounting for 37.3% of total imports, valued at €12.5 billion in 2024.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Finnish company turns steel waste into innovative materials</title><link>https://www.eib.org/en/stories/steel-innovation-recycling</link><description>Tapojärvi, a Finnish company, is innovating by recycling steel slag waste at a stainless steel plant in Umbria, Italy. Their process recovers more metal from slag than traditional methods and repurposes the remaining slag for other products, reducing noise, dust, transportation costs, and carbon emissions, thus benefiting the local community and environment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME trading volumes rebound, new Saudi hubs for nickel</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/turbulent-markets-fuel-lmes-recovery-nickel-crisis-2025-10-10/</link><description>Il LME ha visto crescere i volumi su nickel dopo la crisi 2022-23, apertura nuovi magazzini in Arabia Saudita rafforza liquidità globale.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Test Article - Aluminum News Integration</title><link>https://example.com/test</link><description>This is a test article to verify the Notion integration is working correctly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Current Aluminum Prices - US Metal Prices</title><link>https://www.recycleinme.com/freepricedetailedlisting/US%20Metal%20Prices/Aluminum/6</link><description>Aluminum prices in the US have shown a steady increase over the past days, reaching $1.27 per pound on October 10, 2025, up 1.60% from the previous day. This reflects a gradual upward trend in aluminum pricing in the US market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Major Fire at US Aluminum Plant Exposes Supply Chain Weak Link</title><link>https://eu.36kr.com/en/p/3502905415015299</link><description>A major fire at an American aluminum plant has highlighted vulnerabilities in the U.S. aluminum supply chain. The U.S. produced only 670,000 tons of aluminum in 2024, less than 1% of global production, heavily reliant on imports. China remains the dominant producer with 43.385 million tons, accounting for over 60% of global output.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium's Low-Carbon Revolution in Action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminium industry is undergoing a transformation with a focus on sustainability and low-carbon production. Companies are adopting renewable energy, recycling technologies, and circular practices to meet environmental standards. Initiatives like Taural India's low-carbon techniques are reducing emissions significantly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China steel prices poised for rebound in October</title><link>https://www.seaisi.org/details/27329?type=news-rooms</link><description>Chinese steel prices are expected to rise in October after two months of decline, driven by improved fundamentals and anticipated government stimulus. Despite weaker-than-expected demand before the National Day holiday, actual demand is forecast to grow this month due to resilient domestic consumption and strong exports, with construction and appliance sectors entering a high season.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel prices fell to $811.06 per tonne on October 10, 2025, down 0.48% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen slightly by 0.13%, but remain near their lowest levels since February 2025, reflecting ongoing market volatility.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Needle Coke Market Forecasts 2025-2030: Key Drivers Include Asia-Pacific's Dominance, Particularly China's Steel and EV Sectors</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/10/3164726/0/en/Needle-Coke-Market-Forecasts-2025-2030-Key-Drivers-Include-Asia-Pacific-s-Dominance-Particularly-China-s-Steel-and-EV-Sectors.html</link><description>The shift toward electric arc furnace (EAF) steelmaking, driven by stricter environmental regulations, is increasing demand for needle coke, a critical raw material for graphite electrodes. This trend is supported by government policies promoting zero-emission vehicles and is expected to significantly reduce emissions in steel production by 2030.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper fell to 4.92 USD/Lbs on October 10, 2025, down 3.74% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices dropped to 4.92 USD per pound on October 10, 2025, a decline of 3.74% from the previous day. Despite this daily fall, copper prices have risen 6.75% over the past month and are up 10.58% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect copper to trade at 5.18 USD/Lb by the end of the quarter and 5.66 USD/Lb in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 4.14% Lower at $4.8485</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510105682/comex-copper-ends-the-week-414-lower-at-48485-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for October delivery lost 20.95 cents per pound, or 4.14%, closing at $4.8485 this week. This marks a significant weekly decline in copper prices, reflecting recent market volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold Higher Following a Historic Week</title><link>https://www.admis.com/gold-higher-following-a-historic-week/</link><description>The International Copper Study Group (ICSG) forecasts a surplus of approximately 178,000 tons in the global refined copper market for 2025, down from an earlier forecast of 289,000 tons. Refined copper production is expected to rise by 3.4% in 2025 but slow to 0.9% growth in 2026. Copper usage is predicted to increase by about 3% in 2025 and 2.1% in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Eroding trust in US dollar behind gold, silver and copper price rally, says TD Securities</title><link>https://www.mining.com/eroding-trust-in-us-dollar-behind-gold-silver-and-copper-price-rally-says-td-securities/</link><description>Copper prices are surging as investors lose faith in the US dollar, driving a rush into hard assets. Copper surged toward $11,000 a tonne, with the price rally attributed to declining confidence in the dollar as a reliable store of value. This trend is part of a broader move into real assets.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 4-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/492274</link><description>Nickel prices decreased to 15,151 USD/T, marking the lowest level since September 2025. Over the past four weeks, nickel lost 0.43%, and over the last 12 months, it decreased by 15.33%.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On October 10, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 122,400–125,300 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103561993/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 122,400 and 125,300 yuan/mt, with an average price of 123,850 yuan/mt, up 250 yuan/mt from the previous day, indicating a slight price increase.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Rise to 11-Week High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/491793</link><description>Nickel futures rose to $15,540 per tonne, the highest in eleven weeks, driven by supply concerns from Indonesia. The Indonesian government cut nickel production quotas significantly and introduced stricter permit renewal rules, raising uncertainty in the mining sector despite subdued demand due to weak electric vehicle battery output.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Weekly Review of Indonesian Nickel Market</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103563186/smm-analysisweekly-review-of-indonesian-nickel-market---oct-10</link><description>Indonesian nickel ore prices showed an upward trend in early October, supported by dry season conditions improving ore production. New regulations require annual approval of production quotas starting 2026, revoking previous multi-year quotas and causing some supply sentiment disruption due to ongoing compliance inspections.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Centaurus Metals Secures Mining Lease for Jaguar Nickel Project</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/10/centaurus-metals-secures-mining-lease-for-jaguar-nickel-project/</link><description>Centaurus Metals has been granted the mining lease for its Jaguar Nickel Sulphide Project in Brazil, completing key approvals needed for a Final Investment Decision. The company is progressing financing discussions and aims to commence construction and operation soon, highlighting the project's strong economics even at current nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Aluminum Price Weekly Review: Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cuts Heat Up and Fundamentals Remain Solid, Aluminum Prices Fluctuate at Highs</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>SMM provides real-time aluminum price data showing the SMM A00 Aluminum Ingot price at around $2,598 per metric ton on October 10, 2025, with premiums and discounts fluctuating slightly. The report highlights stable premiums for Indonesian and South Korean aluminum and notes that fundamentals remain solid amid expectations of US Federal Reserve interest rate cuts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Current Aluminum Prices - US Metal Prices</title><link>https://www.recycleinme.com/freepricedetailedlisting/US%20Metal%20Prices/Aluminum/6</link><description>Aluminum prices in the US have shown a steady increase, with the price reaching $1.27 per pound on October 10, 2025, marking a 1.60% rise from the previous day. Prices have been gradually climbing over the past week, reflecting ongoing market strength.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel and aluminum tariffs drive up costs for everyday nuts and bolts</title><link>https://www.scrippsnews.com/life/money/steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-drive-up-costs-for-everyday-fasteners</link><description>The 50% tariffs on steel and aluminum products are causing a 30-50% increase in costs for small metal fasteners like screws, nails, and bolts, impacting construction projects and consumer goods prices. These tariffs contribute to a nearly 2% rise in core goods prices, slowing down parts of the economy and causing delays in large projects, especially in construction and electrical sectors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Mill Fire Threatens to Put Big Dent in Ford's Auto Production</title><link>https://www.industrialinfo.com/news/abstract/aluminum-mill-fire-threatens-to-put-big-dent-in-fords-auto-production--347190</link><description>A September fire at Novelis Incorporated's aluminum plant in Oswego, New York, has halted about 40% of the aluminum sheet used by U.S. automakers until early next year, with Ford Motor Company—the plant's largest customer—facing significant production impacts. The disruption is expected to affect other major automakers as well.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Small Fire breaks out inside Novelis plant late Thursday night</title><link>https://cnycentral.com/news/local/small-fire-breaks-out-inside-novelis-plant-late-thursday-night</link><description>A small debris fire occurred at the Novelis aluminum plant in Scriba, New York, shortly after midnight on October 10; it was quickly extinguished, but the cause and extent of damage remain under investigation. This incident follows a major September fire that severely damaged the facility and halted production, with ripple effects across the automotive industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ford Faces $1B Earnings Blow After Aluminum Plant Fire Halts F-150 Production</title><link>https://theautowire.com/2025/10/10/ford-faces-1b-earnings-blow/</link><description>The September 16 fire at Novelis’ Oswego, New York plant has disrupted nearly 40% of the U.S. auto industry’s aluminum sheet supply, potentially costing Ford up to $1 billion in lost operating earnings and forcing temporary production pauses at key truck plants. Ford, the plant's largest customer, may lose 20,000 to 50,000 trucks through year-end, with the plant expected to remain offline until early 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Fire at aluminium plant to hit Ford's bottom line by up to USD 1 billion</title><link>https://www.balajialuminium.com/fire-at-aluminium-plant-to-hit-fords-bottom-line-by-up-to-usd-1-billion-10-october-2025/</link><description>Analysts warn that the September 16 fire at Novelis' New York plant may disrupt aluminum supply for Ford's F-150 production through the end of the year, with significant financial repercussions for the automaker.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ford Could Lose Up to $1 Billion as Plant Fire Hobbles F-150 Production</title><link>https://www.ien.com/operations/video/22952281/ford-could-lose-up-to-1-billion-as-plant-fire-hobbles-f150-production</link><description>A major fire at Novelis' Oswego plant threatens Ford's F-150 production, potentially causing up to $1 billion in losses and exposing vulnerabilities in the automotive supply chain.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>China steel prices poised for rebound in October</title><link>https://www.seaisi.org/details/27329?type=news-rooms</link><description>After a steady decline over the previous two months, Chinese steel prices are expected to rise in October due to improved fundamentals and likely economic stimulus policies. Demand is anticipated to grow supported by resilient domestic consumption, strong exports, and a high construction season following favorable weather.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AISI Applauds USTR Leadership At Global Steel Forum</title><link>https://www.steel.org/2025/10/aisi-applauds-ustr-leadership-at-global-steel-forum/</link><description>Kevin Dempsey, president and CEO of the American Iron and Steel Institute, praised remarks by U.S. leaders at the Global Steel Forum. The event highlights international cooperation on steel excess capacity issues. This support is crucial for maintaining a competitive steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmakers and Steelworkers Call on Government to Support Canadian Steel</title><link>https://usw.ca/friday-steelmakers-and-steelworkers-call-on-government-to-stand-up-for-canadian-steel/</link><description>The United Steelworkers union is urging the Canadian government to support domestic steel production by helping to 'repatriate' the market. This would stabilize Canadian steel production and protect jobs. The call for support is part of ongoing efforts to strengthen the Canadian steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>2025 Ministerial Meeting of the Global Forum on Steel Excess Capacity</title><link>https://www.oecd.org/en/events/2025/10/2025-ministerial-meeting-of-the-global-forum-on-steel-excess-capacity.html</link><description>The Global Forum on Steel Excess Capacity held its 2025 Ministerial Meeting in Gqeberha, South Africa. The meeting focuses on addressing global steel excess capacity issues and promoting sustainable steel production practices. It brings together international leaders to discuss solutions to the challenges facing the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hydrogen steel plant: voestalpine X Mitsubishi Heavy Industries</title><link>https://www.eu-japan.eu/publications/hydrogen-steel-plant-voestalpine-x-mitsubishi-heavy-industries</link><description>Mitsubishi Heavy Industries and voestalpine are developing a hydrogen-fueled steelmaking process that operates at lower temperatures and includes a heat recovery system to increase energy efficiency. The pilot plant in Austria aims to produce 25,000 tons of steel annually using hydrogen, with the goal of achieving zero-emission steel through renewable hydrogen sources.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>STEEL TECH - International Seminar '25 - Tenova</title><link>https://tenova.com/newsroom/upcoming-events/steel-tech-international-seminar-25</link><description>The 2025 STEEL TECH International Seminar in Kolkata, India, focuses on integrating AI and advanced technologies to enhance efficiency and sustainability in steel production. Praveen Chaturvedi from Tenova Technologies presented on 'Intelligent EAF,' a technology designed to optimize furnace process efficiency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fortune Global 500 Steelmaker Shagang Group Celebrates 50 Years of Growth and Innovation</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/10/10/fortune-global-500-steelmaker-shagang-group-celebrates-50-years-of-growth-and-innovation/</link><description>Shagang Group emphasizes innovation, efficiency, and sustainability as it pursues becoming a world-class steel enterprise. The company focuses on smart, environmentally responsible growth and strengthening its steelmaking operations and industrial ecosystem.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Commission publishes Terms and Conditions for the first pilot auction for industrial heat decarbonisation</title><link>https://climate.ec.europa.eu/news-other-reads/news/commission-publishes-terms-and-conditions-first-pilot-auction-industrial-heat-decarbonisation-budget-2025-10-10_en</link><description>The European Commission launched the first pilot auction to support industrial heat decarbonisation, aiming to close the cost gap between renewable heat or electrification and fossil fuel alternatives. This initiative supports clean industry competitiveness and helps achieve climate neutrality by 2050.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>European Green Steel Summit 2025: shaping the future of the steel industry</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/european-green-steel-summit-2025-shaping-the-future-of-the-steel-industry/</link><description>The European Green Steel Summit 2025 will address carbon emission reduction, green steel production, and innovative technologies, focusing on sustainable advancements in the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper fell to 4.87 USD/Lbs on October 10, 2025, down 4.80% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices dropped to 4.87 USD per pound on October 10, 2025, marking a 4.80% decline from the previous day. Despite this recent fall, copper prices have risen 5.58% over the past month and are up 9.37% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect copper to trade at 5.18 USD/Lb by the end of the current quarter and 5.66 USD/Lb in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 4.14% Lower at $4.8485 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510105682/comex-copper-ends-the-week-414-lower-at-48485-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for October delivery lost 20.95 cents per pound, or 4.14%, closing at $4.8485 this week. This represents the largest one-week net and percentage decline since early August 2025, snapping a two-week winning streak. The price is down 16.33% from its 52-week high of $5.795 hit in July 2025 but remains up 8.92% from 52 weeks ago.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Goldman Sachs expects copper price to remain in $10,000-$11,000 range in 2026/2027</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/metals-research-goldman-sachs-zero</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts copper prices to stay within the $10,000 to $11,000 per metric ton range during 2026 and 2027 due to an expected market surplus. This outlook reflects anticipated supply and demand dynamics influencing the copper market in the medium term.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold Higher Following a Historic Week</title><link>https://www.admis.com/gold-higher-following-a-historic-week/</link><description>The International Copper Study Group (ICSG) forecasts a surplus of approximately 178,000 tons in the global refined copper market for 2025, down from an earlier forecast of 289,000 tons. Refined copper production is expected to rise by 3.4% in 2025 but slow to 0.9% growth in 2026. Copper usage is predicted to increase by about 3% in 2025 and 2.1% in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Eroding trust in US dollar behind gold, silver and copper price rally, says TD Securities</title><link>https://www.mining.com/eroding-trust-in-us-dollar-behind-gold-silver-and-copper-price-rally-says-td-securities/</link><description>Copper prices are surging as investors lose faith in the US dollar, driving a rush into hard assets. This trend is attributed to a breakdown in confidence in the dollar as a reliable store of value. Copper surged toward $11,000 a tonne amidst this market shift.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anglo American moving forward with SandLix™ heap leach innovation</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2025/10/10/anglo-american-moving-forward-with-sandlix-heap-leach-innovation/</link><description>Anglo American is advancing the SandLix™ heap leaching process, which can reduce the cut-off grade for copper extraction by up to 20%, improving resource efficiency and sustainability. This innovative technology aims to optimize copper recovery while minimizing environmental impact in mining operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Falls to 15,168 USD/T, Down 2.05% from Previous Day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped to 15,168 USD per ton on October 10, 2025, marking a 2.05% decline from the previous day. Over the past month, nickel has fallen 0.34%, and is down 15.25% compared to a year ago.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 4-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/492274</link><description>Nickel decreased to 15,151.00 USD per ton, the lowest level since September 2025. Over the past four weeks, nickel lost 0.43%, and it has declined 15.33% in the last 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price Update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103561993/</link><description>On October 10, the SMM #1 refined nickel price in China was 122,400–125,300 yuan per metric ton, with an average price of 123,850 yuan/mt, up 250 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>NexMetals Announces Continuance into British Columbia</title><link>https://nexmetalsmining.com/investors/news-releases/nexmetals-announces-continuance-into-british-colum-11528/</link><description>NexMetals Mining Corp., a company focused on copper, nickel, and cobalt resource redevelopment in Botswana, announced its legal continuance from Ontario to British Columbia. The move includes updated corporate articles under the British Columbia Business Corporations Act but retains its stock symbols and CUSIP/ISIN numbers. The company emphasizes its experienced team and commitment to governance in advancing its nickel-related mining projects.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Exane BNP favors Vallourec over Tenaris</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L5N3VR0CX:0-exane-bnp-favors-vallourec-over-tenaris/</link><description>Exane BNP Paribas downgraded its rating on Tenaris to 'neutral' from 'outperform' due to a challenging outlook for oil country tubular goods makers amid weaker prices and tariff uncertainties. The brokerage prefers Vallourec over Tenaris, citing Vallourec's better market positioning and revenue exposure in less risky regions.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S.A. Reports Shareholder Update on Ownership Stake and Planned Share Sales</title><link>https://www.quiverquant.com/news/Tenaris+S.A.+Reports+Shareholder+Update+on+Ownership+Stake+and+Planned+Share+Sales</link><description>Tenaris's controlling shareholders plan to sell some shares while maintaining at least 67% ownership, responding to the company's share repurchase program. The shareholders have no current plans to reduce their stake below 67%, indicating confidence in Tenaris's governance and stock value.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Daily Aluminum price, LME Comex Shfe Price of Aluminum live</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>SMM reports current aluminum prices with the SMM A00 Aluminum Ingot priced between $2,595.78 and $2,600.73 per metric ton. Premiums for aluminum in various regions remain stable, with Yangshan Aluminum Premium at $90 per metric ton. Expectations for US Fed interest rate cuts are influencing market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel and aluminum tariffs drive up costs for everyday fasteners</title><link>https://www.scrippsnews.com/life/money/steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-drive-up-costs-for-everyday-fasteners</link><description>Tariffs on steel and aluminum are significantly increasing costs for fasteners like screws and bolts, impacting construction and consumer goods. These tariffs have led to price hikes of 30-50% for some items, affecting both distributors and consumers. The broader economic impact includes delayed projects and higher consumer prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Falls to 811.06 USD/T, Down 0.48% from Previous Day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel prices dropped to 811.06 USD per tonne on October 10, 2025, marking a 0.48% decrease from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have seen a modest 0.13% increase, but remain near their lowest levels since February 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>MMI Daily Iron Ore Index Report October 10 2025</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/mmi-daily-iron-ore-index-report-october-10-2025/</link><description>The most-traded iron ore contract (I2601) closed at 795, up 1.02% from the previous day, as traders adjusted positions in line with market conditions. The report highlights ongoing activity among steel mills and traders in response to current market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Delayed Publication of Flat Steel Reduced Carbon Emissions Inferred Price</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/delayed-publication-of-flat-steel-reduced-carbon-emissions-inferred-price/</link><description>Fastmarkets announced a delay in the publication of its flat steel reduced carbon emissions price assessment for China, now scheduled for October 17. The previous assessment ranged from 3,360 to 3,870 yuan per tonne.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>STEEL TECH - International Seminar '25</title><link>https://tenova.com/newsroom/upcoming-events/steel-tech-international-seminar-25</link><description>The STEEL TECH International Seminar 2025 in Kolkata, India, focuses on integrating AI and advanced technologies to enhance efficiency and sustainability in steel production. Praveen Chaturvedi from Tenova Technologies presented a paper on 'Intelligent EAF,' an expert technology aimed at maximizing furnace process efficiency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BIR warns that a proposed regulation could lay groundwork for trade limitations on ferrous scrap</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/bir-warns-that-proposed-regulation-could-lay-groudwork-for-trade-limitations-on-ferrous-scrap/</link><description>The Bureau of International Recycling (BIR) highlights concerns over a new EU regulation aimed at protecting the steel industry from global overcapacity. The regulation could impact investments in green steel projects, threatening the EU's decarbonization goals and risking job losses in the steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>MSCI Announces Annual Safety Innovation and Culture Improvement Award Winners</title><link>https://www.msci.org/msci-announces-annual-safety-innovation-and-culture-improvement-award-winners-4/</link><description>MSCI honored Metallus, Steel Services, Inc., and Worthington Steel with its annual Safety Innovation and Culture Improvement awards, recognizing advancements in safety practices within the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Near 10-Week High on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/492245</link><description>Copper futures slipped below $5.1 per pound amid profit-taking but stayed near ten-week highs due to supply disruptions in Chile and Indonesia. Chile's state miner Codelco reported its lowest monthly output in over two decades following a fatal accident that halted operations. Indonesia's Grasberg mine also faces limited output after a recent fatal accident, with full capacity not expected until early 2027.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>After a rally to $11,000/t, copper prices fall on the back of profit-taking</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/10/10/after-a-rally-to-11000t-copper-prices-fall-on-the-back-of-profittaking</link><description>Copper prices fell on October 10, 2025, as investors took profits following a rally to a 16-month high of $11,000 per tonne the previous session. The decline reflects typical market corrections after sharp price increases.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Near 10-Week High on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/491990</link><description>Copper futures remain near ten-week highs despite a slight slip due to profit-taking, driven by ongoing mine disruptions in Chile and Indonesia that are tightening global supply. Chile's state miner Codelco reported its lowest monthly output in over 20 years for August, and Indonesia’s Grasberg mine is operating below capacity after a fatal accident. Additionally, Canada's Teck Resources lowered its annual production outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>TNR Gold NSR Royalty Update – Los Azules Feasibility Study Confirms Economically Robust Copper Project With Leading ESG Performance</title><link>https://tnrgoldcorp.com/2025-news/tnr-gold-nsr-royalty-update-los-azules-feasibility-study-confirms-economically-robust-copper-project-with-leading-esg-performance/</link><description>The Los Azules copper project in Argentina is confirmed as a long-life, low-cost producer with strong economic returns and sustainability credentials. The project advances toward construction readiness with a design that reduces environmental footprint and aligns with the global energy transition toward a low-carbon future.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price on October 10</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103561993/</link><description>On October 10, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 122,400 and 125,300 yuan per metric ton, with an average price of 123,850 yuan/mt, which is an increase of 250 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Update: High-Grade NPI Prices Under Pressure with Limited Downside</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103562889/SMM-Update:-High-Grade-NPI-Prices-Under-Pressure-with-Limited-Downside</link><description>Nickel prices have fluctuated significantly, with domestic inventory seeing a substantial buildup. The market dynamics are influenced by supply and demand factors, impacting high-grade nickel pig iron (NPI) prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Constructs Photovoltaic Plants</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is involved in a project to construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily, enhancing its energy performance and reducing environmental impact. This aligns with its partnership with CVA to support regional decarbonization targets. The project contributes to the competitiveness of the local steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Launches Green Hydrogen Pilot Plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has launched a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, Italy. This initiative is part of the company's efforts to innovate and reduce its environmental impact.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Completes $85 Million Exhaust System Upgrade</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-completes-85-million-exhaust-system-upgrade-to-boost-sustainability</link><description>Tenaris has completed an $85 million exhaust system upgrade at its steel mill in Koppel, Pennsylvania. The new system aims to improve air quality by more effectively collecting and separating dust and particulates. This investment is part of a broader $140 million upgrade since 2020.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Celebrates 25 Years of Seamless Pipe Production in Canada</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-marks-25-years-of-seamless-pipe-production-in-canada-and-commitment-to-its-long-term-i-ce7d5adbdb8ff725</link><description>Tenaris marked 25 years of seamless pipe production in Canada, highlighting its role in supporting the energy industry. The company has expanded its capabilities with both seamless and electric resistance welded (ERW) pipe manufacturing. This milestone underscores Tenaris's commitment to industrial growth.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Exane BNP Favors Vallourec Over Tenaris</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L5N3VR0CX:0-exane-bnp-favors-vallourec-over-tenaris/</link><description>Exane BNP Paribas prefers Vallourec over Tenaris due to a weaker price environment for oil country tubular goods (OCTG). It downgraded Tenaris's rating to 'neutral' while maintaining 'outperform' for Vallourec. The decision reflects Vallourec's diversified market exposure.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Shareholder Update on Ownership Stake and Planned Share Sales</title><link>https://www.quiverquant.com/news/Tenaris+S.A.+Reports+Shareholder+Update+on+Ownership+Stake+and+Planned+Share+Sales</link><description>Tenaris's controlling shareholders plan to sell shares while maintaining at least a 67% ownership stake. This decision is in response to Tenaris's ongoing share repurchase program. The move aims to stabilize long-term investment in the company.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Week | October 10</title><link>https://www.aluminum.org/news/aluminum-week-october-10</link><description>The U.S. Aluminum Industry Sector Snapshot report released during Aluminum Week highlights positive environmental impact trends, showcasing the industry's progress in sustainability and innovation. The event provides access to technical articles, standards, and data to support sustainable aluminum solutions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Korea to unveil policy plan for EU steel tariffs in October</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-10-10/business/industry/Korea-to-unveil-policy-plan-for-EU-steel-tariffs-in-October/2417248</link><description>The Korean government plans to release a comprehensive policy package by late October to address the European Union's tightened steel tariffs. The strategy includes enhanced incentives, strengthened antidumping measures, support for hydrogen-based steelmaking, and efforts to leverage the Korea-EU FTA to protect domestic producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany's SPD Proposes Strategic Measures to Strengthen Europe's Steel Industry</title><link>https://millichronicle.com/2025/10/56782.html</link><description>Germany's Social Democrats (SPD) are advancing proposals to support sustainable growth and fair competition in Europe's steel sector. The plan includes a tariff-quota system to manage imports, promote a 'buy European' approach, and enhance oversight of steel imports to protect domestic production and jobs while fostering innovation in clean steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Trump Tariffs on China Cause Seismic Shift in Copper Markets</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/trump-tariffs-china-impact-copper-2025/</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange fell 4.9%, marking the largest single-day decline in five months, amid tariff threats against China. The market is already constrained by supply issues due to ESG barriers and major mine transitions, and new trade barriers risk disrupting the complex global copper supply chain, potentially delaying projects and causing inventory buildups.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices, Charts, Analysis &amp; Forecast</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper spot prices on major exchanges including SHFE, LME, and COMEX showed a price range around $10,700 per metric ton on October 10, 2025, with premiums and discounts fluctuating slightly. The market reflects ongoing adjustments amid supply constraints and tariff-related uncertainties.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price tumbles as Trump threatens massive new tariffs on China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-tumbles-as-trump-threatens-massive-new-tariffs-on-china/</link><description>Copper prices dropped significantly after President Donald Trump threatened to impose new tariffs on Chinese goods. This move reversed recent gains fueled by production setbacks at major copper mines. The tariffs could impact global copper demand and supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Gold Mine: 7 Innovations In Copper Mining 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-gold-mine-7-innovations-in-copper-mining-2025</link><description>This article explores how copper mining innovations in 2025 are driving sustainable infrastructure and green technologies. It highlights advanced ore beneficiation, AI-driven digital monitoring, and sustainability frameworks that are revolutionizing copper mining to support renewable energy systems, electric vehicles, and telecommunications.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Lithium &amp; Copper Mining Companies: 2025 Outlook</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/chinese-lithium-copper-mining-companies-2025-outlook</link><description>Chinese copper mining companies are leading in both production and technological innovation, with output expected to reach nearly 10 million metric tons in 2025. The sector focuses on resource efficiency, digital twin modeling, hydro-metallurgical extraction, and strict environmental mandates, while expanding overseas assets in Africa, South America, and Central Asia to secure supply and support sustainable mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Future of copper mining: global demand, strategic alliances</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/future-of-copper-mining-addressing-global-demand-with-strategic-alliances-and-sustainable-innovations-andrea-hotter/</link><description>The article discusses innovations in copper mining such as Anglo American's hydraulic dry stacking technology to address tailings capacity challenges, aiming for more sustainable production. It also covers ongoing environmental compliance efforts near the Chagres copper smelter and the potential for scaling new technologies industry-wide to meet global demand sustainably.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Resources at the Forefront of North America's Critical Minerals Security Push</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-10-teck-resources-at-the-forefront-of-north-americas-critical-minerals-security-push</link><description>Teck Resources, in a proposed merger with Anglo American, is central to North America's strategy to secure critical minerals like copper for clean energy and advanced technologies. The merger aims to create a resilient supply chain with sustainable mining practices, though challenges remain in investment, regulation, and workforce development to ensure long-term self-sufficiency and ESG compliance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices fluctuate amid inventory buildup and policy disruptions</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Nickel</link><description>Nickel prices showed significant volatility this week, initially rising due to disruptions in Indonesian mining policies but later pulling back. The SHFE nickel contract closed at 122,180 yuan/mt, up 0.49% from pre-National Day levels, while LME nickel prices fell to $15,320/mt, down 0.68% week-over-week. Domestic inventory also saw a substantial buildup during this period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to $15,215 USD/T on October 10, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped 1.74% from the previous day to $15,215 USD/T. Over the past month, prices remained nearly flat with a slight 0.03% decline and are down 14.99% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect nickel to trade around $15,184.79 USD/T by the end of the current quarter.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel 28 Confirms US$1.4M Cash Distribution from Ramu JV</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CONXF/nickel-28-announces-confirmation-of-cash-distribution-from-ramu-bnjb88y6mg2h.html</link><description>Nickel 28 Capital Corp. announced a cash distribution of approximately US$1.4 million from its Ramu joint venture for H1 2025, alongside a US$2.5 million partner debt repayment. The first half of 2025 was impacted by reduced production due to mechanical failures, but full production is expected in the second half, potentially improving future results.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel 28 Confirms US$1.4M Cash Distribution from Ramu JV</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CONXF/nickel-28-announces-confirmation-of-cash-distribution-from-ramu-bnjb88y6mg2h.html</link><description>Nickel 28 Capital Corp. announced a cash distribution of approximately US$1.4 million from its Ramu joint venture for the first half of 2025. The distribution was impacted by reduced production due to mechanical issues, but full production is expected in the second half of the year. Projects within Nickel 28's royalty portfolio are progressing positively.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia Targets 71,234 Tons of Nickel Production in 2025</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/vale-indonesia-inco-targets-71234-tons-of-nickel-production-in-2025</link><description>Vale Indonesia aims to produce 71,234 tons of nickel-in-matte in 2025, exceeding its 2024 target. This increase is part of the broader production trends in Indonesia.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : marks 25 years of seamless pipe production in Canada and commitment to its long-term industrial growth</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-marks-25-years-of-seamless-pipe-production-in-canada-and-commitment-to-its-long-term-i-ce7d5adbdb8ff725</link><description>Tenaris celebrated 25 years of seamless pipe production at its Canadian facility in Sault Ste. Marie, highlighting its role in supporting the domestic energy industry with high-quality steel pipes. The company also noted recent upgrades including electric resistance welded pipe manufacturing, reinforcing its unique capabilities in Canada.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Steel Prices Poised for Rebound in October</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/analysis/5100433-mysteel-china-steel-prices-poised-for-rebound-in-october</link><description>After declining over the past two months, Chinese steel prices are expected to rise in October due to improved market fundamentals. The article suggests that this rebound could stabilize the market, but details are available only with a subscription.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Eyeing China, EU unveils sweeping measures to shield struggling steel industry</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/aseanplus/aseanplus-news/2025/10/11/eyeing-china-eu-unveils-sweeping-measures-to-shield-struggling-steel-industry</link><description>The EU has introduced measures to protect its steel industry from global overcapacity, particularly focusing on steel of Chinese origin. Proposals include a 'melt and pour requirement' to prevent circumvention via other countries and ongoing investigations into China's trade practices. EU leaders emphasize the need for balanced trade and long-term solutions to overcapacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper fell to 4.80 USD/Lbs on October 10, 2025, down 6.16% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices dropped 6.16% to $4.80 per pound on October 10, 2025, despite a 4.07% rise over the past month and a 7.81% increase year-over-year. Analysts expect copper to trade at $5.18 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.66 in 12 months, reflecting ongoing market volatility and supply-demand dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Resources lowers copper production guidance for 2025</title><link>https://www.townandcountrytoday.com/national-business/teck-resources-lowers-copper-production-guidance-for-2025-11320351</link><description>Teck Resources has reduced its copper production forecast for 2025 due to operational challenges at key mining assets. The company now expects to produce between 415,000 and 465,000 tonnes of copper. Strong copper prices are partially offsetting the financial impact of reduced production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 10-week High at $15,551 USD/T</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/491774</link><description>Nickel prices increased to $15,551 USD/T, marking the highest level since July 2025. Over the past four weeks, nickel gained 2.42%, although it remains down 11.47% over the last 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia Nickel Matte Production Down 0.05% MoM in Sep</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5100658-indonesia-nickel-matte-production-down-005-mom-in-sep</link><description>Indonesia's nickel matte production decreased by 0.05% month-over-month in September, totaling 28,800 tonnes in Ni content. This slight decrease reflects ongoing supply dynamics in the region.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Enters New Period in Steel Production with Green Hydrogen Facility</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/haber/cogne-located-in-aosta-has-entered-a-new-period-in-steel-production-with-a-green-hydrogen-facility/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is advancing sustainable steel production by integrating green hydrogen into its processes. The company aims to reduce carbon emissions by using green hydrogen, produced from renewable sources, in its industrial heat treatment processes. This innovation also positions Cogne as a material partner in the hydrogen value chain.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian was awarded the tender by Terna and STEG for the submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia under the Elmed Project. The contract could reach a value of around €460 million and involves laying cables at depths up to 800 meters, enhancing energy security between Europe and Africa.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy awards Prysmian $539mn contract for Tunisia-Europe power cable</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/italy-awards-prysmian-539mn-contract-for-tunisia-europe-power-cable/</link><description>Prysmian Group won a contract worth up to €460 million ($539 million) to build a submarine power cable linking Italy to Tunisia. This project is part of efforts to enhance power interconnections between Europe and Africa, supporting energy transition goals.</description><category>general</category></item></channel></rss>