<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 05:14:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scientists Create Wood 10 Times Stronger Than Steel</title><link>https://greekreporter.com/2025/10/15/scientists-create-wood-ten-times-stronger-steel/</link><description>Researchers have developed a new type of wood, known as Superwood, which is ten times stronger than steel and six times lighter. This innovation could revolutionize construction by offering a sustainable alternative to steel. The production process has a lower carbon footprint compared to steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>IEA Issues Warning on Oil Supply Surplus, LME Copper Plunged Sharply Last Night</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103568754/</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated significantly overnight, closing at $10,598.5/mt, down 1.88%. The trading volume reached 29,000 lots. This volatility comes amid broader market concerns about supply disruptions and global economic uncertainties.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Producer Aurubis Held Talks with US on Support for New Smelter</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-producer-aurubis-held-talks-with-us-on-support-for-new-smelter-ceo-says/</link><description>Aurubis, a German copper producer, has engaged in preliminary discussions with the US regarding support for a new smelter. This move reflects ongoing efforts to enhance copper production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices remained in the doldrums on October 15 as the US Fed may cut interest rates again in October</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103569973/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-remained-in-the-doldrums-on-October-15-as-the-US-Fed-may-cut-interest-rates-again-in-October</link><description>On October 15, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,300 yuan/mt, slightly up from the previous day. Market sentiment is cautious due to risks like a potential US government shutdown and Sino-US trade tensions, with nickel prices expected to remain subdued in the short term amid weak fundamentals and uncertain Fed policy.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>NPI smelters caught between rising costs and tepid demand, while October prices have upside potential</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103560694/npi-smelters-caught-between-rising-costs-and-tepid-demand-while-october-prices-have-upside-potential-</link><description>Nickel Pig Iron (NPI) smelters face challenges from rising costs and weak demand, with prices declining slightly after the National Day holiday in China. Market participants are cautious, awaiting October consumption and price trends to determine future direction, as stainless steel prices remain subdued, limiting NPI price increases.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Institute seminar and cocktail reception - 2025</title><link>https://nickelinstitute.org/en/resources/articles/nickel-institute-seminar-and-cocktail-reception-2025</link><description>The Nickel Institute is hosting a seminar and cocktail reception focused on how circularity, evolving recycling practices, and sustainability frameworks are reshaping the future of nickel. The event highlights innovations in nickel technology and sustainability efforts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>'A blind spot at COPs': NGOs call for equity in transition minerals ahead of COP30</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/news/a-blind-spot-at-cops-ngos-call-for-equity-in-transition-minerals-ahead-of-cop30/</link><description>NGOs urge governments to recognize human rights, environmental protection, and equity in mineral value chains, including nickel, during climate negotiations at COP30. They emphasize the importance of just transition frameworks to ensure sustainable development and local job creation in the mining sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,747.05 per tonne on October 15, 2025, marking a 0.03% increase from the previous day and reaching the highest level in over three years. The price has increased 1.20% over the past month and 6.15% year-over-year, driven by tight supply and bullish demand expectations, with Chinese authorities lowering their base metals output growth targets.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CPI Rebound Coupled with Inventory Drawdown, Aluminum Prices Hold Up Well in the Short Term</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>Technical analysis of SHFE aluminum contracts shows limited price fluctuations with short-term pressure but a medium to long-term bullish trend supported by inventory drawdowns and CPI rebound. Market participation remains low with a wait-and-see sentiment prevailing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Surge Approaches Record Highs in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-price-surge-market-indicators-2025/</link><description>Copper prices have surged toward record highs, reaching $10,866.25 per tonne and approaching the previous peak of $11,400 per tonne from May 2024. The market shows strong institutional interest and technical momentum, driven by structural supply deficits, declining ore grades, and growing demand linked to the global energy transition and electric vehicle adoption.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Export Avalanche Reshapes Global Markets Amidst Arbitrage Frenzy</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-10-15-chinese-copper-export-avalanche-reshapes-global-markets-amidst-arbitrage-frenzy</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are exporting unprecedented volumes due to arbitrage opportunities between international and domestic prices, reshaping global supply chains. This export surge comes amid persistent global supply deficits and strong demand from the energy transition, temporarily easing LME inventory shortages but not resolving underlying structural tightness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Commodity Radar: Copper prices cool off after Monday's sharp rally</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/commodity-radar-copper-prices-cool-off-after-mondays-sharp-rally-time-to-buy-on-dips-for-16-potential-gains-says-religare-expert/articleshow/124548572.cms</link><description>Copper prices fell sharply on Tuesday after a strong rally on Monday, with MCX October futures dropping 2.4% amid profit taking and international price declines. Supply disruptions in major mines and expectations of US interest rate cuts had previously pushed prices to a 16-month high near $11,000 per ton, supported by robust demand from green energy and electric vehicles.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Weaker dollar, Fed cut bets drive copper up</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40387650</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.9% to $10,675 per metric ton, supported by a weaker US dollar and expectations of Federal Reserve interest rate cuts. These macroeconomic factors are contributing to upward pressure on copper prices amid ongoing supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Export Avalanche Reshapes Global Markets Amidst Arbitrage Frenzy</title><link>http://markets.chroniclejournal.com/chroniclejournal/article/marketminute-2025-10-15-chinese-copper-export-avalanche-reshapes-global-markets-amidst-arbitrage-frenzy</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are capitalizing on near-record LME prices and a premium for immediate delivery outside China, causing an unprecedented surge in exports. This export wave temporarily replenishes LME inventories but does not resolve underlying supply deficits caused by mine disruptions and strong long-term demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Japan, Spain and South Korea warn over unsustainable copper processing fees</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/japan-spain-and-south-korea-warn-over-unsustainable-copper-processing-fees/</link><description>Japan, Spain, and South Korea issued a joint statement expressing concern over falling copper treatment and refining charges (TC/RCs), which threaten the sustainability of copper smelting operations. The decline in fees, partly due to expanding Chinese smelting capacity and tight concentrate supply, is causing some smelters to consider scaling back or exiting the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel mine using smelting and leaching processes to extract nickel</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/mining-innovation-takes-centre-stage-during-sudbury-mining-week/attachment/nickel-mine-using-smelting-and-leaching-processes-to-extract-nickel/</link><description>A nickel mine is utilizing both smelting and leaching processes to extract nickel, highlighting innovation in mining techniques. The article does not provide specific details about new production capacities but emphasizes the use of advanced extraction methods. This approach can improve efficiency and reduce environmental impact.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Releases Positive Results from Crawford Nickel Project Economic Impact Study</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/pr-newswire/20251015to98247/canada-nickel-releases-positive-results-from-crawford-nickel-project-economic-impact-study</link><description>Canada Nickel Company announced positive results from an economic impact study for its Crawford Nickel Project. The project is expected to contribute significantly to Canada's GDP and generate substantial tax revenues and employment opportunities. While not directly addressing current production capacity, it highlights future potential.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, northern Italy, marking a significant step in replacing fossil natural gas with green hydrogen in its industrial heat treatment process. This initiative aims to reduce CO₂ emissions substantially and supports the company's commitment to climate-neutral industrial processes.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne, located in Aosta, has entered a new period in steel production with a green hydrogen facility</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/haber/cogne-located-in-aosta-has-entered-a-new-period-in-steel-production-with-a-green-hydrogen-facility/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is pioneering the use of green hydrogen in steel production by replacing fossil natural gas in its heat treatment process. The company also develops specialized stainless steels designed for hydrogen transport infrastructure, contributing to the energy transition and climate neutrality goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US aluminum industry seeks export curbs on some scrap material</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/us-aluminum-industry-seeks-export-curbs-on-some-scrap-material/</link><description>The US Aluminum Association has called for restrictions on exports of certain aluminum scrap materials to strengthen domestic supply. The proposal includes an immediate ban on exports of used beverage containers outside North America and improved tracking to enforce restrictions, aiming to support US manufacturers amid high import tariffs and global competition.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market Size to Cross USD 84.49 Billion by 2034</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/15/3166862/0/en/Nickel-Market-Size-to-Cross-USD-84-49-Billion-by-2034.html</link><description>The global nickel market is projected to grow significantly, driven by innovations including AI that optimize the nickel value chain from exploration to processing. AI technologies are enhancing sustainability by reducing waste, improving yield, enabling predictive maintenance, and supporting ESG monitoring to lower carbon footprints in nickel projects.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SLAM Drills 81 and 74 Meter Core Intervals at the Goodwin Copper-Nickel-Cobalt Project</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/accesswire/1086977msn/slam-drills-81-and-74-meter-core-intervals-at-the-goodwin-copper-nickel-cobalt-project</link><description>SLAM reports significant drilling results at the Goodwin Copper-Nickel-Cobalt Project, intersecting 81 and 74 meter core intervals. The results highlight the potential for substantial nickel and cobalt mineralization at the site.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Drops by 1,600 mt to 54,800 mt on Oct 16</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103572172/SMM-Flash-News:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Drops-by-1600-mt-to-54800-mt-on-Oct-16</link><description>China's domestic secondary aluminum ingot inventory decreased by 1,600 metric tons to 54,800 metric tons as of October 16, 2025, according to SMM data. This reflects ongoing adjustments in secondary aluminum supply within the Chinese market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Gov't invites feedback on $2B plan to support green aluminium manufacturing</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/govt-invites-feedback-on-2b-plan-to-support-green-aluminium-manufacturing/</link><description>The Australian Government has launched a public consultation for its $2 billion Green Aluminium Production Credit to boost domestic aluminium manufacturing and support the transition to renewable energy. The initiative aims to help aluminium smelters shift to renewable electricity, reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and strengthen Australia's position in sustainable aluminium production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Dutch Nouryon completes metal alkyls capacity expansion in China</title><link>https://www.icis.com/explore/resources/news/2025/10/16/11146273/dutch-nouryon-completes-metal-alkyls-capacity-expansion-in-china</link><description>Nouryon has doubled its production capacity of triethyl aluminum (TEAL), a metal alkyl used in plastics manufacturing, at its Jiaxing facility in China. The company also plans to start producing modified methylaluminoxane (MMAO) in China by 2027, a catalyst used in solar panel materials, reflecting Nouryon's commitment to innovation in polymer specialties.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Can circular aluminium provide a blueprint for a post-plastic world?</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/can-circular-aluminium-provide-a-blueprint-for-a-post-plastic-world/61691/</link><description>This article explores the sustainability benefits of circular aluminium, highlighting its infinite recyclability and low energy requirements for remanufacturing compared to virgin aluminium. It discusses aluminium's potential to reduce reliance on plastics and support a circular economy, emphasizing the need for increased recycling infrastructure and stakeholder engagement to drive adoption.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Recycled aluminium for sustainable shipbuilding</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/recycled-aluminium-for-sustainable-shipbuilding/54273/</link><description>Speira’s VIA Maris recycled aluminium alloys offer improved mechanical properties and a lower CO2 footprint, making them ideal for maritime and offshore applications. London-based yacht builder Arksen is using these marine-grade recycled aluminium alloys for its new hybrid propulsion yachts, advancing sustainability in shipbuilding.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>Chinese buyers are seeking alternative sources, leading to increased price premiums for non-BHP cargoes. There is growing volatility in spot market prices and inventory movements as traders reposition their stocks. Chinese steel producers face the urgent task of securing alternative supply sources, potentially benefiting other major iron ore producers like Vale and Rio Tinto.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Kallanish Global Flat Steel 2025 Conference</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/announcement-kallanish-global-flat-steel-2025/</link><description>The Kallanish Global Flat Steel 2025 conference will discuss current issues affecting the global flat steel market. The event addresses concerns over US tariffs and their impact on global trade, as well as rising Chinese exports and potential trade cases. The EU is reviewing its safeguard measures and adjusting the CBAM ahead of its full launch in 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>InfraBuild wins Innovation of the Year at World Steel Association awards</title><link>https://www.aumanufacturing.com.au/infrabuild-wins-innovation-of-the-year-at-world-steel-association-awards</link><description>InfraBuild was recognized for its innovative contributions to steel technology at the World Steel Association awards, highlighting advancements that support sustainable steel production and industry transformation.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Smelters Plan Exports After Surge in LME Prices</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/utilities/2025/october/chinese-copper-smelters-plan-exports-after-surge-in-lme-prices/</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are increasing exports due to near-record London Metal Exchange (LME) prices, arranging up to 25,000 tons of spot shipments to bonded warehouses and Asian depots. This surge follows global mine disruptions and US monetary easing, which have boosted copper prices, while domestic Chinese demand slows amid higher costs and weaker margins.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Saudi Aramco Expands into Metal Trading, LME Copper Edged Down Slightly Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103570980/Saudi-Aramco-Expands-into-Metal-Trading-LME-Copper-Edged-Down-Slightly-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Saudi Aramco is entering the metal trading market by hiring copper traders, signaling a strategic diversification amid the energy transition. Meanwhile, LME copper prices showed volatility, opening at $10,681/mt and closing slightly down at $10,576/mt, reflecting mixed market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Smelters Plan Exports After Surge in LME Prices</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/utilities/2025/october/chinese-copper-smelters-plan-exports-after-surge-in-lme-prices/</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are increasing exports due to near-record London Metal Exchange (LME) prices, arranging up to 25,000 tons of spot shipments to bonded warehouses and Asian depots. This surge is driven by a rally in copper prices following global mine disruptions and US monetary easing, despite weakening domestic demand in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Smelters Export Surge: Global Impact</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/chinese-copper-exports-surge-2025-investment-arbitrage/</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are exporting over 25,000 tons of copper in spot shipments, with monthly volumes potentially reaching 50,000 tons. The surge is due to softening domestic demand amid rising production costs and a significant decline in the Yangshan copper premium, making foreign sales more attractive.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper demand to rise 24% by 2035, says Wood Mackenzie</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-india.com/2025/10/16/copper-demand-to-rise-24-by-2035-says-wood-mackenzie/</link><description>Wood Mackenzie forecasts a 24% increase in global copper demand by 2035, driven by economic development and structural demand from electrification and digitalization. The energy transition is a key factor, with electric vehicle-related copper demand expected to double by 2035, highlighting copper's critical role in the global energy shift.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mining innovation takes centre stage during Sudbury Mining Week</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/mining-innovation-takes-centre-stage-during-sudbury-mining-week/</link><description>Sudbury Mining Week 2025 focuses on innovation and sustainability in mining, featuring industry leaders and educational events. The event promotes mining's role in modern society and sustainable development, with interactive exhibits and workshops aimed at inspiring youth and strengthening industry-community partnerships.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices continued to fluctuate on October 16</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103572103/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-continued-to-fluctuate-on-October-16-with-broad-money-M2-up-84-YoY-in-September</link><description>Nickel prices continued to fluctuate due to broad money supply increases and ongoing market uncertainties. The SMM #1 refined nickel price was between 120,700-123,600 yuan/mt. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract edged higher during the session.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 4-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel decreased to 15,151.00 USD/T, marking a four-week low. Over the past month, nickel's price has fallen 1.68%, and it is down 10.86% compared to the same time last year. Nickel futures previously rose to an eleven-week high due to supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market Trends</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/commodity-insights/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/101425-trade-review-global-nickel-market-eyes-oversupply-in-q4-as-shifting-trade-policy-feeds-uncertainty</link><description>The global nickel market is expected to face oversupply in Q4 due to shifting trade policies and increased inventory levels. Despite this, African mining projects continue to advance. Nickel prices have fallen significantly since 2022 due to supply outpacing demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103572103/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-continued-to-fluctuate-on-October-16-with-broad-money-M2-up-84-YoY-in-September</link><description>Nickel prices continued to fluctuate, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 122,150 yuan/mt. The market is influenced by broader economic factors, including changes in social financing and money supply. However, there is no specific mention of new production capacities in this report.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Queensland university $2.2 million grant win promises boost to battery supply chain</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/2025/10/16/queensland-university-2-2-million-grant-win-promises-boost-to-battery-supply-chain/</link><description>Researchers at the Queensland University of Technology have secured a $2.2 million grant to develop a more efficient process for manufacturing battery cathode materials using Australian critical minerals like nickel. The project aims to reduce costs and emissions in cathode production. This innovation could enhance energy security in the Indo-Pacific region.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Africa-Europe Power Bridge Moves Ahead As Contract Awarded for Submarine Cable</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news/0110-49154-first-africa-europe-power-bridge-moves-ahead-as-contract-awarded-for-submarine-cable</link><description>Prysmian has won the contract to build a high-voltage submarine power cable connecting Italy and Tunisia, marking the first interconnector between Europe and North Africa. The 220 km cable will have a capacity of 600 MW and is a key component of the ELMED project.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian wins 460 mln euros power cable deal connecting Italy to Tunisia</title><link>https://newsprobe.io/news/01d389a9-75b1-47df-aaa5-b71d2cd2da23/prysmian-wins-460-mln-euros-power-cable-deal-connecting-italy-to-tunisia</link><description>Prysmian has secured a €460 million contract to build a submarine power cable linking Italy and Tunisia, advancing energy interconnection between the two countries.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit 3-Year High: Is It the Next Key Metal in the Clean Energy Shift?</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-hit-3-year-high-is-it-the-next-key-metal-in-the-clean-energy-shift/</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged to a three-year high driven by demand from electric vehicles, solar, and grid upgrades, with new low-carbon aluminum smelting projects underway globally. Automakers and tech companies are securing long-term contracts for low-carbon aluminum, while policies like the EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism push producers toward decarbonization and improved recycling infrastructure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium's real paradox – energy use vs carbon saving</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminiums-real-paradox-energy-use-vs-carbon-saving-uncover-the-role-of-recycling-in-this-from-our-latest-magazine-115858</link><description>Recycling aluminium scrap is the most effective sustainability approach, saving up to 95% energy compared to primary production and reducing CO2 emissions by nine tonnes per tonne recycled. Increasing renewable energy use and advanced technologies like AI-driven cell efficiency improvements are critical to further emission reductions, with the industry having achieved 25% of its 2030 carbon reduction target so far.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>7 Critical Threats Facing the Global Aluminum Industry</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/aluminum-industry-threats-environmental-production-costs-2025/</link><description>The aluminum industry faces significant challenges from tightening environmental regulations, rising production costs, and supply chain disruptions. The energy-intensive Hall-Héroult process contributes heavily to emissions, prompting regulatory scrutiny such as the EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism. Companies are responding with strategic investments in emissions monitoring, policy engagement, and industry coalitions to balance compliance and competitiveness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel awarded worldsteel Safety and Health Excellence Recognition 2025</title><link>https://www.tatasteel.com/newsroom/press-releases/india/2025/tata-steel-awarded-worldsteel-safety-and-health-excellence-recognition-2025-for-process-safety-management/</link><description>Tata Steel has received the World Steel Association's Safety and Health Excellence Recognition for its process safety management. This is the company's third consecutive recognition, highlighting its commitment to safety and innovation in preventing high-risk operational scenarios.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SHS Group Secures $1.8B Financing for Power4Steel, Advancing Germany’s Green Steel Transition</title><link>https://esgnews.com/shs-group-secures-1-8b-financing-for-power4steel-advancing-germanys-green-steel-transition/</link><description>Germany’s SHS–Stahl-Holding-Saar Group secured €1.7 billion financing for its Power4Steel project, one of Europe’s largest steel decarbonization initiatives. The project aims to cut CO₂ emissions by 55% by 2030 and achieve climate neutrality by 2045 through hydrogen-based production and electric arc furnace technology, supported by federal and regional governments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM Exclusive: Overview of Metal Production in September 2025 and Forecast for October</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103560133/SMM-Exclusive:-Overview-of-Metal-Production-in-September-2025-and-Forecast-for-October</link><description>China's copper cathode production in September 2025 decreased by 4.31% month-on-month due to increased smelter maintenance and tight copper anode supply, despite a year-on-year increase of 11.62%. Production is expected to decline further in October and November as maintenance continues and supply constraints persist, with operating rates dropping especially for large smelters.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Update: Q2 2025 in Review</title><link>https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/base-metals-investing/copper-investing/copper-forecast/</link><description>Copper prices were volatile in Q2 2025 but remained elevated overall, influenced by tariffs, global economic uncertainty, and trade tensions. The market may have entered a supply deficit due to disruptions such as the shutdown at Ivanhoe-Zijin Kakula-Kamoa mine in the DRC, with production guidance lowered significantly, highlighting tight copper supply against growing demand from structural growth sectors like AI data centers and energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mining companies make stunning discovery that could be crucial for sustainable nickel production</title><link>https://www.thecooldown.com/green-tech/nickel-mining-improvements-sustainable-practices/</link><description>Eagle Mine is piloting D-Solve technology to increase nickel purity by reducing magnesium impurities by 40%, which could extend mine life and improve process efficiencies. This innovation reduces waste and energy use in nickel mining, supporting lower production costs and advancing clean energy transition goals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italy awards Prysmian $539mn contract for Tunisia-Europe power cable</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/italy-awards-prysmian-539mn-contract-for-tunisia-europe-power-cable/</link><description>Italy has awarded Prysmian a contract worth $539 million to build a submarine power cable connecting Italy and Tunisia as part of the Elmed Project. The cable will run from the Partanna substation in Sicily to the Mlaabi substation in Tunisia, supporting cleaner energy integration between the two countries.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel Involving Prysmian and Others</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>The Italian Antitrust Authority has launched an investigation into alleged anti-competitive practices among major low voltage copper cable manufacturers in Italy, including Prysmian. The probe focuses on coordinated pricing and sales conditions dating back to 2005, with inspections conducted at company offices and distributors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Stabilizes as Supply Risks Persist</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures steadied above $4.90 per pound amid ongoing supply risks, with output disruptions in Chile and Indonesia tightening global production. The market also reacted to expectations of additional US Federal Reserve rate cuts and persistent deflationary pressures in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises on US Rate Cut Bets</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures climbed back above $5 per pound as dovish remarks from the Fed reinforced expectations for more US rate cuts, improving the global demand outlook. Supply concerns remain elevated due to recent output disruptions in major producing countries.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventories in Key Cities Drop on Oct 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103573342/%E3%80%90SMM-Flash-News%E3%80%91Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventories-in-Key-Cities-Drop-on-Oct-17</link><description>Secondary aluminum enterprises maintained flat quotations amid a wait-and-see market stance. The SMM ADC12 price held steady at 21,050 yuan/mt, while inventories of secondary aluminum ingots in key Chinese cities declined, indicating tightening supply conditions in the secondary aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Japan Q4 aluminium talks drag out in effort to bridge gap, say sources</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/japan-q4-aluminium-talks-drag-out-in-effort-to-bridge-gap-say-sources-156356/</link><description>Quarterly pricing talks between Japanese aluminium buyers and global producers have extended unusually long due to a wide gap in price expectations amid sluggish demand and high inventories. Japanese aluminium stocks rose slightly, while producers hold out for higher premiums influenced by rising prices in the US and Europe.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Consultation opens for $2 billion green aluminium production credit</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/press-releases/consultation-opens-for-2-billion-green-aluminium-production-credit/</link><description>The Australian government has opened consultation on a $2 billion Green Aluminium Production Credit aimed at decarbonizing aluminium smelters by promoting production using renewable energy. The initiative supports Australia's ambition to lead in low-carbon aluminium production, which is critical for the energy transition and reducing greenhouse gas emissions from this energy-intensive industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Extrusion Market CAGR to be at 5.2% from 2025 to 2029</title><link>https://www.einpresswire.com/article/858599334/aluminum-extrusion-market-cagr-to-be-at-5-2-from-2025-to-2029-115-59-billion-industry-revenue-by-2029</link><description>The aluminum extrusion market is projected to grow robustly to $115.59 billion by 2029, driven by government support, urbanization, and increased demand in automotive and packaging sectors. Growth is also fueled by trends in green building construction, where aluminum's sustainability and recyclability are highly valued.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Market to Reach USD $243.04 Billion by 2029 at 6.4% CAGR</title><link>https://www.brusselsnewsnetwork.com/article/858596581-aluminum-market-to-reach-usd-243-04-billion-by-2029-at-6-4-cagr</link><description>The global aluminum market is expected to grow to $243.04 billion by 2029, with a CAGR of 6.4%, driven by advances in recycling, electric vehicle demand, construction, and aerospace sectors. Innovations such as 3D printing and new aluminum alloys, along with increased use in packaging and renewable energy projects, are key growth factors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Jinshi Futures Morning Update - October 17, 2025</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/63406043/jinshi-futures-morning-update-october-17-2025-friday</link><description>The update discusses various market trends, including ferrosilicon prices from Hebei Steel, which were set at RMB 5,660/ton for October, down RMB 140/ton. However, it does not specifically focus on steel prices. Precious metals have seen significant volatility, with gold and silver hitting record highs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Share Price Live Updates</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/stock-liveblog/tata-steel-stock-price-today-live-17-oct-2025/liveblog/124618753.cms</link><description>Tata Steel's share price closed at Rs 173.24 in the previous trading session and is experiencing a slight gain today. The update focuses on stock market dynamics rather than steel prices specifically.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-17-oct-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's stock price increased by 0.29%, reaching ₹1,173.10 per share. This update is about stock performance rather than steel market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Taiwan's Tung Ho Steel Keeps H-Beam Prices Flat</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/taiwans-tung-ho-steel-keeps-h-beam-prices-flat-for-second-half-of-oct/157289</link><description>Tung Ho Steel has maintained stable H-beam prices for the second half of October, continuing a trend of price stability throughout most of 2025. This decision reflects a consistent approach to pricing in the Taiwanese market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Update</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel prices rose to $815/ton on October 16, 2025, marking a slight increase from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen by 0.25%, and are up 15.60% year-over-year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>India's Steel Giants Risk Locking in 12 Billion Tonnes of CO₂</title><link>https://carbontracker.org/indias-steel-giants-risk-locking-in-12-billion-tonnes-of-co%E2%82%82/</link><description>India's major steel companies are planning significant capacity expansions, which could hinder the country's climate goals and expose them to EU carbon tariffs. The expansion relies heavily on traditional blast furnace technology due to the high cost of low-carbon alternatives. This poses a risk to achieving India's net-zero targets by 2070.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Jindal Stainless Doubles Slag Capacity to Boost Circular Production</title><link>https://www.constructionworld.in/steel-news/jindal-stainless-doubles-slag-capacity-to-boost-circular-production/80241</link><description>Jindal Stainless, India's largest stainless steel producer, has doubled its slag processing capacity to enhance circular production. This move aims to improve sustainability and efficiency in its operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Miners Plunge Amid US-China Tensions</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/17/copper-miners-plunge-amid-us-china-tensions/</link><description>Shares in Australian copper mining companies fell significantly due to a drop in copper prices driven by escalating US-China tensions. Concerns about reduced demand from China, a major copper consumer, have pressured prices and impacted copper producers' market valuations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Market Trends: Volatility and Supply Pressures Shape 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-market-trends-2025-demand-growth/</link><description>Copper prices are forecasted to remain elevated through 2026 due to structural supply-demand imbalances and rising demand from the energy transition. Price scenarios range from $9,000 to $15,000 per tonne depending on supply disruptions and demand growth, with risks including economic slowdowns and trade tensions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price rebounds as traders see $12,000 within reach after rally</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-rebounds-as-traders-see-12000-within-reach-after-rally/</link><description>Copper prices have rebounded recently, with traders optimistic about reaching $12,000 per tonne following a strong rally. This reflects bullish sentiment amid ongoing supply constraints and demand from energy transition sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Japan, the West, and South Korea Report Continued Decline in TC/RC; LME Copper Slightly Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103573294/Japan-the-West-and-South-Korea-Report-Continued-Decline-in-TCRC-LME-Copper-Slightly-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Copper futures on the LME showed slight gains after fluctuating overnight, closing at $10,620/mt. Japan, Spain, and South Korea warned that the sharp decline in copper concentrate treatment and refining charges threatens the mining and smelting industry chain, potentially forcing some smelters to scale back or exit.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 0.28% Lower at $4.9580 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510167118/comex-copper-settles-028-lower-at-49580-data-talk</link><description>Comex copper prices declined by 0.28% to $4.9580 per pound, marking a third consecutive session of losses and the largest three-day decline since October 10, 2025. Despite recent drops, copper remains up over 24% from its 52-week low earlier this year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper slips as US govt shutdown, trade tensions weigh - Markets</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40387843</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange fell 0.7% to $10,566 per metric ton amid concerns over a US government shutdown and ongoing trade tensions. These factors contribute to market uncertainty despite tight supply conditions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Daily Nickel price, Lme Comex Shfe Price of Nickel live | SMM</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Nickel</link><description>The latest SMM spot price for #1 Nickel is USD 15,000.3–15,335.02 per metric ton, with an average of USD 15,167.66, up 25.85 from the previous day. Nickel briquettes and JinChuan Nickel also saw slight increases, while Indonesian refined nickel prices dropped by USD 260 per tonne.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Maintain Fluctuating Trend on October 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103574518/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Maintain-Fluctuating-Trend-on-October-17-US-and-Russian-Presidents-Hold-Phone-Conversation-After-Nearly-Two-Months</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices in China ranged from 121,000 to 123,700 yuan per metric ton, averaging 122,350 yuan, up 200 yuan from the previous day. The market continues to experience fluctuations amid ongoing global economic and political developments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME WEEK: Nickel market could stay in oversupply until 2030</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/lme-week-nickel-market-could-stay-in-oversupply-until-2030-macquarie/</link><description>According to Macquarie, the global nickel market is expected to remain in surplus until 2030, indicating prolonged oversupply conditions. This outlook aligns with recent projections of continued excess production relative to demand in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel touts $70B GDP boost from Timmins mine project</title><link>https://www.northernontariobusiness.com/industry-news/mining/canada-nickel-touts-70b-gdp-boost-from-timmins-mine-project-11350020</link><description>Canada Nickel highlights that its proposed Crawford open-pit nickel mine near Timmins is expected to generate over $70 billion in GDP benefits. This project represents a significant investment in nickel production capacity in Canada, contributing to economic growth and mining sector expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Asia faces P7 million penalty as Mindoro geothermal deal ends</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/business/2025/10/17/2480334/nickel-asia-faces-p7-million-penalty-mindoro-geothermal-deal-ends</link><description>Nickel Asia Corporation is facing a penalty of 7 million Philippine pesos following the conclusion of its geothermal deal in Mindoro. The company disclosed this development to the Philippine Stock Exchange, reflecting operational and contractual changes impacting its business.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>PT Vale and PAMA Officially Launch Nickel Mining Project in Kolaka</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/pt-vale-and-pama-officially-launch-nickel-mining-project-in-kolaka</link><description>PT Vale and PAMA have officially launched a new nickel mining project in Kolaka, Indonesia. This development marks an expansion of nickel production capacity in the region, supporting Indonesia's position as a major nickel producer.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Falls Slightly After Recent Rally, But Up Over Past Month and Year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped to $2,774.55 per tonne on October 17, 2025, down 0.88% from the previous day, but remain up 2.89% over the past month and 6.06% year-on-year. The market outlook suggests prices could reach $2,784.44 per tonne by the end of the quarter and $2,907.92 in 12 months, reflecting ongoing bullish sentiment amid tight supply and strong demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Summary: Bullish Trend Intact, But Volume Divergence Signals Caution</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>Domestic and international macro environments remain favorable, supporting aluminum prices. Technical indicators show a bullish trend, but lower-than-average trading volume suggests potential for a correction. Resistance is seen at 21,150–21,250 yuan/mt, with support at 20,850–20,950 yuan/mt.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME Explores Sustainable Metal Premia as Aluminum Demand Grows</title><link>https://www.lme.com/en/metals/non-ferrous/lme-aluminium</link><description>The LME is considering the introduction of price premia for sustainable metals, including aluminum, as part of efforts to meet rising demand for low-carbon materials. Aluminum remains a key metal for global industries due to its recyclability and strength-to-weight ratio, with the LME Official Price serving as the global benchmark.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Golden Triangle builds on Steel Dynamics growth with new Kloeckner aluminum plant</title><link>https://www.newsfromthestates.com/article/golden-triangle-builds-steel-dynamics-growth-new-kloeckner-aluminum-plant</link><description>The Golden Triangle is expanding its industrial capacity with a new Kloeckner aluminum plant, building on the growth of Steel Dynamics. This development aims to enhance regional economic and industrial activities.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LIXIL Standardizes Low-Carbon PremiAL Across Its Product Line</title><link>https://newsroom.lixil.com/2025091701</link><description>LIXIL Corporation is standardizing the use of PremiAL, its recycled low-carbon aluminum that reduces CO₂ emissions by approximately 50%, across its product line at no extra cost starting October 2025. This initiative leverages nearly 30 years of aluminum recycling expertise to significantly lower embodied carbon in building materials, supporting the decarbonization of the construction industry in Japan.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Update and Forecast</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices decreased to $789/tonne, the lowest since February 2025, down 0.48% from the previous day. Prices have fallen 2.40% over the past month but remain 15.05% higher than a year ago. Analysts expect prices to rise to $831/tonne by the end of the quarter and $894/tonne within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMU Survey: Current Sentiment Sinks to Lowest Level Since May 2020</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/17/smu-survey-current-sentiment-sinks-to-lowest-level-since-may-2020/</link><description>Steel buyers report steady to slightly higher prices but weak demand and slow inventories. U.S. domestic sheet prices remain rangebound amid supply tightness and weak demand, with scrap prices falling in October. Tariffs continue to cloud market outlook as the industry heads into the final quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMU flat-rolled market survey results now available</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/17/smu-flat-rolled-market-survey-results-now-available-18/</link><description>Steel mill lead times have decreased across most sheet and plate products in the US, according to the latest SMU survey. Current steel buyer sentiment has dropped to its lowest level since May 2020, reflecting weak demand and rangebound domestic prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to $4.96 per pound on October 17, 2025, up 0.33% from the previous day, with a 9.32% increase over the past month and a 13.92% rise year-over-year. Trading Economics forecasts copper to trade at $4.93 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.40 in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 1.71% Higher at $4.9315 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510176093/comex-copper-ends-the-week-171-higher-at-49315-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for October delivery gained 1.71% this week to $4.9315 per pound, despite a recent four-session losing streak and a 3.31% drop over the last four sessions. Copper remains up 23.72% from its 52-week low but is down 14.9% from its 2025 high.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Pulled Back This Week Due to Fundamental Pressure</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575414/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-pulled-back-this-week-due-to-fundamental-pressure-and-inventory-levels-increased-further</link><description>Nickel prices have retreated due to fundamental pressures and increased inventory levels. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 121,160 yuan/mt, down 1.89% week-over-week. LME nickel prices also fell to $15,140/mt, showing synchronized weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alaska Energy Metals Provides Corporate Update On Nikolai Nickel Project, Alaska And Announces Amendment To Restricted Share Plan And Grants Of Stock Options And Restricted Share Units</title><link>https://www.webdisclosure.com/press-release/alaska-energy-metals-provides-corporate-update-on-nikolai-nickel-project-alaska-and-announces-amendment-to-restricted-share-plan-and-grants-of-stock-options-and-restricted-share-units-0QbQl3fiVKg</link><description>Alaska Energy Metals reports that first-pass metallurgical testing at the Eureka deposit of the Nikolai nickel project is nearing completion, with results expected in November 2025. The company is also advancing an internal options study and pursuing US government grant funding, with a Preliminary Economic Assessment planned for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME WEEK: US aluminum price rise spurs deliveries from Canada</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/lme-week-us-aluminum-price-rise-spurs-deliveries-from-canada/</link><description>The rise in US aluminum prices has led to an increase in deliveries from Canada, though not yet at full pace. The Midwest premium has hit a record high, effectively pricing in the 50% tariff. This has also influenced European duty-paid aluminum premiums, which have jumped significantly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump's tariffs spur US aluminum industry to boost recycling</title><link>https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/clean-aluminum/trump-tariffs-spur-metal-recycling</link><description>President Trump's tariffs have prompted the US aluminum industry to increase recycling efforts. This shift is part of broader trends in the US aluminum market, which has seen changes in inventories and production strategies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Chart and Historical Data</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose slightly to 3,044 CNY/tonne on October 17, 2025, up 0.03% from the previous day. However, steel prices have fallen 1.07% over the past month and are down 6.34% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect steel to trade around 3,047 CNY/tonne by the end of the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China rose slightly to 3,044 CNY/T on October 17, 2025, up 0.03% from the previous day, but are down 1.07% over the past month and 6.34% year-over-year. Trading Economics forecasts steel to trade at 3047.39 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter, with a further decline expected over the next 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP's Copper Boom: Sustainable Mining to Meet Soaring Global Demand</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/bhps-copper-boom-sustainable-mining-to-meet-soaring-global-demand/</link><description>BHP is investing in sustainable mining practices to meet the growing demand for copper, driven by electric vehicles, renewable energy, and data centers. The company aims to support a lower-carbon future with strong operations and clean energy goals. Recycled copper will also play a significant role in meeting rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anaconda Copper Mine 2025: Innovations &amp; Sustainability</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/anaconda-copper-mine-2025-innovations-sustainability</link><description>The Anaconda Copper Mine is embracing innovations like AI, digital monitoring, and eco-rehabilitation to meet sustainability and economic goals. The mine serves as a model for responsible resource extraction, balancing environmental stewardship with community resilience. Advances in technology are crucial for the future of mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, Silver &amp; Copper: Tech and Sustainability Trends</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_ca/insights/mining-metals/gold-silver-and-copper-tech-and-sustainability-trends</link><description>Copper companies are leveraging digital innovations and sustainability practices to address supply gaps. Technologies like AI and satellite imaging are being used to enhance exploration and production. Recycling and circular economy principles are also key strategies to ensure long-term value and reduce environmental impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Glut Persists but African Mining Ambitions Remain Strong</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/1410-49523-nickel-glut-persists-but-african-mining-ambitions-remain-strong</link><description>The global nickel market is expected to remain oversupplied in 2026, with a projected surplus of 261,000 tons. Despite weak prices, African mining projects continue to advance. Nickel prices have fallen significantly since 2022.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>