<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:16:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gunnison Copper Announces That Rio Tinto's Nuton Technology Produces First Copper</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/276917/Gunnison-Copper-Announces-That-Rio-Tintos-Nuton-Technology-Produces-First-Copper</link><description>After over 30 years of R&amp;D, Rio Tinto's Nuton bioleaching technology produced its first copper cathode at Gunnison Copper's Johnson Camp mine. The technology achieves up to 80% less water usage and 60% lower carbon emissions than conventional methods, aiming to produce copper with the lowest carbon footprint in the U.S.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto's Nuton tech makes first-ever copper cathode at Gunnison mine</title><link>https://www.mining.com/rio-tintos-nuton-tech-makes-first-ever-copper-cathode-at-gunnison-mine/</link><description>Nuton's proprietary bioleaching technology produced the first copper cathode at Gunnison Copper's Johnson Camp mine, demonstrating cleaner, faster, and more efficient copper production at industrial scale. The technology reduces water use by up to 80% and carbon emissions by up to 60%, while shortening supply chains by producing copper cathode directly at the mine.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Vale–Glencore Sudbury Venture Aims to Unlock 880,000-Ton Copper Volume for North America</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/vale-glencore-sudbury-venture-aims-to-unlock-880000-ton-copper-volume-for-north-america/</link><description>Vale and Glencore plan to deepen and extend an existing mine shaft in Canada's Sudbury Basin to unlock about 880,000 metric tons of copper over 21 years. This brownfield approach reduces environmental impacts and capital expenses, supporting North America's critical minerals supply for clean energy technologies and the global low-carbon transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>High cash flow enables dividend uplift: Aurubis confirms sustainable growth strategy</title><link>https://www.aurubis.com/en/media/press-releases/press-releases-2025/high-cash-flow-enables-dividend-uplift-aurubis-confirms-sustainable-growth-strategy</link><description>Aurubis started production of phase one of its Richmond project in the US, the first secondary smelter for complex multimetal recycling in North America. The plant will process around 180,000 tons of complex recycling materials annually once phase two is completed, contributing to sustainable copper supply and reducing reliance on imports in the US market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Expands Phase 2X Drilling at Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project</title><link>https://investingnews.com/first-atlantic-nickel-expands-phase-2x-drilling-at-pipestone-xl-nickel-alloy-project-four-additional-holes-targeting-1-4-kilometer-strike-length-and-850-meter-width-at-rpm-zone/</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel is expanding its Phase 2X drilling program at the Pipestone XL project, targeting a 1.4-kilometer strike length and 850-meter width at the RPM zone. The project aims to provide a secure, low-energy, and environmentally sustainable nickel supply chain for North America by bypassing traditional smelting and roasting processes. Updates on recovery and concentrate products for nickel, chromium, and cobalt are expected in early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>US Minerals Projects Seek 'Industrial Vision' from Washington to Compete with China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/us-minerals-projects-seek-industrial-vision-from-washington-to-compete-with-china/</link><description>Executives from US minerals companies are urging the government to develop a comprehensive industrial plan to build a critical minerals supply chain including nickel. They advocate for pressuring Indonesia to limit nickel production, which currently accounts for about 60% of global supply and has depressed prices. The goal is to support domestic nickel refining capacity, such as Westwin Elements' planned refinery in Oklahoma, and stabilize nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Foresees Higher Iron Ore, Copper &amp; Nickel Production Next Year</title><link>https://www.industrialinfo.com/news/article.jsp?newsitemID=350106</link><description>Vale projects a 10% increase in nickel production for the upcoming year, alongside modest increases in iron ore and copper output. This forecast reflects the company's plans to expand its mining operations and meet growing demand for nickel in various industries.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>TECH Project high-grade nickel is primed to fuel the global green transition</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/tech-project-high-grade-nickel-is-primed-to-fuel-the-global-green-transition/32893/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals’ TECH Project aims to become the world’s premier source of high-grade, ethically derived nickel to support the green transition. The project uses an environmentally-friendly DNi Process with over 98% nitric acid recycling and no tailings dam requirements, promising a carbon-negative, sustainable nickel production for EV batteries and energy storage industries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industry News, Views and Commentary - Chronickels</title><link>https://nickelinstitute.org/en/blog/</link><description>NOVONIX’s patented all-dry, zero-waste cathode synthesis technology is expected to reduce costs and environmental impact in nickel-based cathode production. The article discusses nickel’s sustainability potential across its value chain, emphasizing the importance of responsible mining, manufacturing, and recycling to support the expanding electric vehicle battery market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China Built Indonesia's Nickel Boom: Market Analysis</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/indonesia-nickel-strategy-geopolitical-2025-china/</link><description>China controls about 75% of Indonesia’s nickel operations, crucial for EV battery supply chains. The article highlights shifts in battery chemistry preferences, supply chain diversification away from China, and the growing importance of sustainable nickel production methods as key factors shaping the global nickel market and energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Carrascal Nickel Corporation Strengthens Its Position as a Responsible Mining Leader in APAC Through Sustainability and Community-Focused Initiatives</title><link>https://vietnamnews.vn/media-outreach/1731104/carrascal-nickel-corporation-strengthens-its-position-as-a-responsible-mining-leader-in-apac-through-sustainability-and-community-focused-initiatives.html</link><description>Carrascal Nickel Corporation, a Philippine mining company, emphasizes responsible mining, environmental sustainability, and community partnership in its nickel and iron ore operations. The company is reinforcing its commitment to sustainable practices in the Asia-Pacific region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Climate-friendly metals can come from deep-sea ores</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-climate-friendly-metals-deep-sea.html</link><description>A new process using hydrogen reduction to extract nickel, cobalt, and copper from deep-sea ores significantly reduces CO2 emissions by over 90% compared to carbon-based methods. This innovative approach requires less energy and fewer steps, offering a more sustainable alternative for sourcing critical metals needed for batteries and clean technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Reports 7% Drop in Quarterly Net Sales Amid Weakness in Europe and Brazil</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-reports-7-drop-in-quarterly-net-sales-amid-weakness-in-europe-and-brazil-ce7c5fdcd18af421</link><description>Italian steel pipe manufacturer Tenaris posted a 7% decline in net sales for the second quarter of 2025, mainly due to lower deliveries in Europe and Brazil. The report highlights challenges in the European market impacting the company's performance.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Year-end consumption weakened coupled with high aluminum price suppression, the operating rate of aluminum processors came under pressure and pulled back to 61.9%: Aluminum Processing Weekly Survey</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103655695/year-end-consumption-weakened-coupled-with-high-aluminum-price-suppression-the-operating-rate-of-aluminum-processors-came-under-pressure-and-pulled-back-to-619-smm-aluminum-processing-weekly-survey</link><description>The operating rate of leading domestic aluminum downstream processing enterprises fell to 61.9% due to high aluminum prices suppressing spot order transactions and cautious demand. Structural divergence persists with declines in construction and packaging sectors, and no significant improvement in demand is expected before the Chinese New Year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits All-Time Highs! Scrap Prices Surge Heading ...</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N_Bbz3_wyiU</link><description>Copper futures have broken all-time price records, driven primarily by speculative buying and algorithm-driven trades rather than stronger demand. The rally surprised market professionals, with investor flows, thin London inventories, and uncertainty around U.S. trade policy cited as key factors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>RIO Boosts Copper Innovation With First Copper Output Using Nuton Tech</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/rio-boosts-copper-innovation-first-copper-output-using-nuton-tech</link><description>Rio Tinto produced the first copper using its Nuton Technology at the Johnson Camp mine in Arizona. Nuton combines biology, chemistry, engineering, and digital tools to enable cleaner, faster, and more efficient copper production with up to 80% less water usage and 60% lower carbon emissions compared to traditional methods. The technology shortens supply chains by producing copper cathode directly at the mine and can extend mine life by extracting value from previously uneconomic ores.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals Gap Widens As U.S. Delays Key Decisions</title><link>https://stratnewsglobal.com/world-news/critical-minerals-gap-widens-as-u-s-delays-key-decisions/</link><description>U.S. executives urge faster government action on critical minerals projects, including nickel, to compete with China's dominance. Westwin Elements' CEO calls for pressure on Indonesia to limit nickel production, which has surged to about 60% of global supply and caused nickel prices to drop nearly 50%.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tartisan Nickel Corp Closes $1.05M Flow-Through Private Placement</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/TTSRF/tartisan-nickel-corp-closes-1-050-000-flow-through-private-ksh64a5vfzcn.html</link><description>Tartisan Nickel Corp closed a $1.05 million flow-through private placement to fund exploration and development of its Kenbridge Nickel-Copper-Cobalt Project in Northwestern Ontario. The financing supports advancing the company's nickel production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel to restart second blast furnace at Granite City Works</title><link>https://www.stlpr.org/economy-business/2025-12-04/u-s-steel-restart-second-blast-furnace-granite-city-works</link><description>U.S. Steel announced plans to restart its second blast furnace at the Granite City Works plant, aiming to hire 400 workers to operate it. The decision is seen as a positive development for the local steel community amid concerns about the plant's future following Nippon Steel's takeover. The company did not specify investment amounts for this restart but emphasized the importance of continuing high-quality steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ArcelorMittal France to Launch New Electrical Steel Production Line</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>ArcelorMittal France announced that the first three lines of its new electrical steel production line at the Mardyck industrial site will come online by the end of 2025. This development marks a significant expansion in their steel production capacity focused on electrical steel products.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>October Steel Shipments Down 4.2 Percent From Prior Month</title><link>https://www.steel.org/2025/12/october-steel-shipments-down-4-2-percent-from-prior-month/</link><description>Steel shipments in the U.S. decreased by 4.2% in October compared to the previous month but remain up 5.1% year-to-date compared to the same period in 2024. This data reflects ongoing fluctuations in steel demand and production capacity utilization.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US minerals projects seek 'industrial vision' from Washington to compete with China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/us-minerals-projects-seek-industrial-vision-from-washington-to-compete-with-china/</link><description>US nickel industry leaders urge the government to implement a comprehensive minerals plan, including pressuring Indonesia to limit nickel production, which currently accounts for about 60% of global supply and has depressed prices. The US aims to accelerate domestic nickel refining capacity, with a refinery planned in Oklahoma by 2030.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Supply Chains Struggle as Energy Transition Drives Surging Demand for Metals: BloombergNEF Finds</title><link>https://about.bnef.com/insights/commodities/supply-chains-struggle-as-energy-transition-drives-surging-demand-for-metals-bloombergnef-finds/</link><description>BloombergNEF reports that rising demand for critical metals including nickel is outpacing supply chain capacity amid the global energy transition. Southeast Asia, particularly Indonesia and the Philippines, has expanded nickel production, but refining capacity remains concentrated in China, posing supply chain risks.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian shares rise as Italian cable maker seen as winner amid US copper tariffs</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/UK-USA-TRUMP-TARIFFS-PRYSMIAN-8455abd0-fcd3-4332-ab84-5a5ef0d855ca/</link><description>Prysmian's shares rose nearly 4% following the announcement of a 50% US tariff on imported copper. The Italian cable maker is considered a relative winner due to its vertical integration in the US copper supply chain, sourcing copper domestically and operating its own copper rod mill, which gives it a competitive edge. The company is well positioned to benefit from the tariff despite ongoing assessment of its final impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME Aluminium Holds Steady at USD 2,854/t and Alumina Platts Stays Flat at USD 313.5/t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-holds-steady-at-usd-2-854-t-and-alumina-platts-stays-flat-at-usd-313-5-t-116453</link><description>LME aluminium prices remained steady at around USD 2,854 per tonne on December 4, with minor fluctuations in 3-month bids and offers. Alumina prices also stayed flat at USD 313.5 per tonne. Inventory levels saw slight decreases, indicating stable market conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking decarbonisation</title><link>https://www.bhp.com/news/bhp-insights/2025/12/steelmaking-decarbonisation</link><description>BHP highlights the ongoing challenge of decarbonising steel production as demand rises globally. The company supports multiple technology pathways, including carbon capture and renewable energy, to achieve near zero emissions steel production, despite project delays due to high costs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World's First General Design Approval (GDA) for Developed Steel and Post-Weld Heat Treatment (PWHT) Exemption based on ECA for Low-pressure LCO2 Tanks</title><link>https://www.mhi.com/news/251205.html</link><description>Mitsubishi Shipbuilding and Nippon Steel received the world's first General Design Approval for a new high-strength steel that allows exemption from post-weld heat treatment in large low-pressure LCO2 tanks. This innovation is expected to reduce costs and improve productivity in steel manufacturing for CO2 transport.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AI Startup Leads UK Steel Towards Net Zero</title><link>https://www.azom.com/news.aspx?newsID=65086</link><description>Deep.Meta, a UK manufacturing startup, demonstrated it can reduce steel production emissions by nearly 10% at Spartan UK's steel plant, advancing efforts toward net zero emissions in the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking decarbonisation - BHP</title><link>https://www.bhp.com/news/bhp-insights/2025/12/steelmaking-decarbonisation</link><description>BHP is supporting multiple technology pathways to reduce greenhouse gas emissions in steelmaking, including carbon capture and renewable energy integration. The company aims to help the industry achieve a 30% reduction in emissions intensity relative to conventional blast furnace steelmaking, with widespread adoption expected after 2030.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World's First General Design Approval (GDA) for Developed Steel and Post-Weld Heat Treatment (PWHT) Exemption based on ECA for Low-pressure LCO2 Tanks</title><link>https://www.mhi.com/news/251205.html</link><description>Mitsubishi Shipbuilding and Nippon Steel have achieved the world's first General Design Approval for a new steel and manufacturing process exempting post-weld heat treatment for large low-pressure liquid CO2 tanks. This breakthrough enhances economic viability and productivity while supporting carbon neutrality goals through advanced steel solutions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Alumbrera mine is expected to commence production in 2028</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103655842/The-Alumbrera-mine-is-expected-to-commence-production-in-2028-Overnight-LME-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-lower-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>The Alumbrera mine is slated to start production in 2028. Kamoa-Kakula set copper production targets of 380,000 to 420,000 mt for 2026 and 500,000 to 540,000 mt for 2027, maintaining a medium-term target of 550,000 mt. The Kamoa-Kakula copper smelter began operations on December 1, 2025, with copper sales in 2026 expected to exceed production due to inventory reductions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Glencore eyes $2.4b copper push</title><link>https://australianminingreview.com.au/news/glencore-eyes-2-4b-copper-push/</link><description>Glencore announced plans to increase copper output to about 1 million tonnes by 2029 and 1.6 million tonnes by 2035, up from 850,000–875,000 tonnes in 2025. The company plans a $2.4 billion capital investment for a project expected to yield 880,000 tonnes of copper over 21 years, with a final investment decision expected in the first half of 2027. This expansion is driven by rising copper prices and demand from electric vehicles and data centers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price won't stay above $11,000 for long, says Goldman</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-wont-stay-above-11000-for-long-says-goldman/</link><description>Goldman Sachs analysts predict that despite recent supply disruptions tightening copper availability, global demand growth has softened, and they do not foresee a global copper shortage until at least 2029. Copper prices recently hit a record high due to supply concerns and US-bound shipments ahead of potential tariffs, but demand weakness, especially in China, may limit price sustainability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP becomes global copper barometer</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/05/bhp-becomes-global-copper-barometer/</link><description>BHP shares rose over 3% amid signs of a tentative rebound in Chinese copper demand, with Chinese producers increasing operating rates in November. Despite high copper prices causing some substitution with aluminum, BHP remains a key indicator of global copper activity, producing over two million tonnes in FY25 and contributing nearly 45% of group EBITDA. The company’s valuation is closely tied to Chinese market movements and copper demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Adani, Hindalco seek Peru copper assets as demand surges</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/metals-mining/adani-hindalco-seek-peru-copper-assets-as-demand-surges/articleshow/125780821.cms</link><description>India's copper imports rose 4% to 1.2 million metric tons in the fiscal year ending March 2025, with demand expected to climb to 3-3.3 million tons. In response, Indian companies Adani and Hindalco are seeking copper assets in Peru to secure supply amid surging demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 5, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103656760/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 117,400 and 122,700 yuan per metric ton on December 5, with an average price of 120,050 yuan/mt, marking a decrease of 350 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] SMM December 5: Domestic high-grade NPI ex-factory price observed</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103657371/</link><description>According to SMM, the domestic high-grade nickel pig iron (NPI) ex-factory price was recently observed at 910-920 yuan per nickel unit on December 5, reflecting current market conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>USGS Director Champions Domestic Mining</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/12/05/news/usgs-director-champions-domestic-mining/9388.html</link><description>The US Geological Survey director emphasized the importance of domestic mining to meet the growing demand for critical minerals including nickel. Expanding mining capacity is essential to support the generation and transmission infrastructure needed for energy and technology sectors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, northern Italy, marking a significant step towards sustainable steel production. This initiative aligns with the company's ongoing commitment to innovation and environmental responsibility in the steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rebounds from 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK rose above $2,850 per tonne, recovering from a near one-month low of $2,790 on November 18. The rebound was supported by macroeconomic tailwinds, including favorable monetary policies and fresh stimulus signals from Beijing to combat its property crisis.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rusal Cuts Aluminum Production by Over 6% to Combat Rising Alumina Prices and Macroeconomic Risks</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103058180/Rusal-Cuts-Aluminum-Production-by-Over-6-to-Combat-Rising-Alumina-Prices-and-Macroeconomic-Risks</link><description>Rusal announced a reduction of over 6% in aluminum production to address the surge in alumina prices and macroeconomic risks. This move reflects the company's response to cost pressures and uncertain market conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Futures Rise Amid Supply Constraints and Production Challenges</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,909.20 per ton due to supply decreases from production cuts in China and disruptions such as equipment failure at Iceland’s Grundartangi smelter. China’s output cap and setbacks in new smelter projects in Indonesia contribute to tightening market conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Constellium's Incoming CEO Discusses Scrap Bans, National Security, and Growth Plans</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/12/05/amu-2/</link><description>Constellium's CEO highlights the industry's fragmentation and the importance of recycling and scrap retention in Europe amid lost primary capacity and sanctions on Russian metal imports. The company sees growth opportunities in automotive, aerospace, and sustainable packaging sectors, emphasizing national security concerns.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>EU Risks Slow Demise of Aluminum Industry if Carbon Tax Not Scrapped, Constellium CEO Says</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/eu-risks-slow-demise-of-aluminum-industry-if-carbon-tax-not-scrapped-constellium-ceo-says/</link><description>The upcoming EU carbon tax (CBAM) is expected to increase costs for aluminum producers and push European premiums to a 10-month high. The tax could lead to gradual capacity shutdowns and investment shifts outside Europe, threatening the region's aluminum industry sustainability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum stabilizes high-nickel cathodes, curbing rapid capacity loss in EV batteries</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-12-aluminum-stabilizes-high-nickel-cathodes.html</link><description>Research shows that substituting a small amount of nickel with aluminum in high-nickel cathodes stabilizes the battery structure by reducing oxygen hole formation, significantly enhancing EV battery lifespan and safety. This innovation addresses capacity degradation and thermal runaway risks, offering a key strategy for next-generation high-performance batteries.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>World's first high-power aluminum-ion battery system for energy storage</title><link>https://www.ess-news.com/2025/12/05/worlds-first-high-power-aluminum-ion-battery-system-for-energy-storage/</link><description>A new high-power aluminum-ion battery system has been developed focusing on sustainable, lithium-free cell chemistry, wireless battery management, and recyclability. The INNOBATT demonstrator integrates advanced pouch cells with a novel diamond-based quantum sensor for precise current measurement, proving stability and innovation in aluminum battery technology.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Trends and Market Update</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China rose above CNY 3,100 per tonne in early December, reaching a three-month high amid lower supply and government support measures to address the property market crisis. Despite a 0.93% price drop on December 5, steel prices have risen 2.24% over the past month but remain 5.13% lower than a year ago. Crude steel output in China fell 12% annually in October 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Update and Forecast</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) Steel prices fell slightly to 903.04 USD/T on December 5, 2025, down 0.33% from the previous day. Over the past month, HRC prices have risen 6.62%, and are up 31.49% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect HRC Steel to trade at around 911.59 USD/T by the end of Q1 2026 and 992.41 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US Steel to resume production at Illinois plant shut 3 years ago</title><link>https://abcnews.go.com/Business/wireStory/us-steel-resume-steel-production-illinois-plant-shut-128146494</link><description>U.S. Steel announced it will restart steel slab production at its Granite City Works plant in Illinois, which had its last blast furnace shut down in 2023. The decision follows increased customer demand and pressure from the White House, with plans to resume production in the first half of 2026 after hiring and training workers. Domestic steel shipments have increased, supported by tariffs and a rebound in automaking and construction.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US Steel to resume steel production at Illinois plant shut 2 years ago</title><link>https://www.clickorlando.com/news/2025/12/05/us-steel-to-resume-steel-production-at-illinois-plant-shut-2-years-ago/</link><description>U.S. Steel will restart steel making at its Granite City Works plant in Illinois by reopening the blast furnace idled two years ago amid strikes. The company cited strong customer demand and expects to resume production in early 2026 after hiring 400 workers. The U.S. steel market is bolstered by tariffs and growth in automaking and construction, with plans to invest $14 billion in U.S. steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Fresh Record on Fears of Global Supply Squeeze</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512053945/copper-hits-fresh-record-on-fears-of-global-supply-squeeze-commodities-roundup</link><description>Copper prices climbed to a fresh record driven by fears of a global supply shortage as traders stockpile in the U.S. and optimism around Federal Reserve interest-rate cuts. Futures on the London Metal Exchange rose 1.6% to $11,617 a metric ton after hitting an intraday high of $11,705, with prices up more than 32% so far this year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Surge on Global Supply Squeeze and Tariff Speculation: A Tailwind for Australian Miners</title><link>https://smallcaps.com.au/article/copper-price-surge-on-global-supply-squeeze-and-tariff-speculation-a-tailwind-for-australian-miners</link><description>Copper has surged more than 30% on the LME this year amid supply disruptions from major mine outages and speculation of U.S. tariffs on refined copper. Heavy shipments to the U.S. and widening price arbitrage between U.S. and global markets are driving stockpiling and pushing premiums higher in Europe and Asia, signaling a tightening market expected to intensify in early 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, Silver Hit New Weekend Records as Copper Market 'Fractures'</title><link>https://www.bullionvault.com/gold-news/gold-price-news/silver-copper-deficit-markets-120520251</link><description>Copper is caught in a tug of war between bullish and cautious outlooks despite prices above $11,000, with inventories elevated. Citigroup forecasts copper could reach a record $13,000 per ton by mid-2026 due to stronger growth expectations, tightening physical balances, and tariff-driven stockpiling, highlighted by a recent large withdrawal of copper from LME warehouses.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures in the U.S. climbed to around $5.4 per pound on December 5, 2025, the highest in over four months, amid ongoing supply disruptions and a large withdrawal of metal from LME warehouses. Copper prices have risen over 8% in the past month and nearly 30% compared to the previous year, driven by fears of U.S. levies on refined copper next year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Fresh Record on Fears of Global Supply Squeeze</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512053945/copper-hits-fresh-record-on-fears-of-global-supply-squeeze-commodities-roundup</link><description>Copper prices reached a new record high driven by concerns over a global supply shortage, with futures on the London Metal Exchange rising 1.6% to $11,617 per metric ton. The price surge is fueled by disrupted supply chains and strong demand for refined copper in the U.S., with prices up more than 32% this year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Quest Closes $1,927,000 Private Placement</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/12/06/3201019/0/en/Copper-Quest-Closes-1-927-000-Private-Placement.html</link><description>Copper Quest Exploration Inc. announced the closing of a $1.927 million private placement to support its North American critical mineral projects. The company focuses on copper exploration and development, highlighting copper's strategic importance amid rising global demand and supply challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto's Nuton technology produces first copper</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2025/rio-tintos-nuton-technology-produces-first-copper</link><description>Rio Tinto successfully produced its first copper using Nuton technology at the Johnson Camp mine in Arizona. This marks a technological advancement in copper production, potentially improving efficiency and sustainability in mining operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Reaches All-Time High Amid Weaker Dollar, Supply Concerns</title><link>https://mexicobusiness.news/mining/news/copper-reaches-all-time-high-amid-weaker-dollar-supply-concerns</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange briefly hit an all-time high of $11,434.50 per metric ton, rising 1.7% amid a weaker U.S. dollar and ongoing supply concerns. The market remains bullish despite some indicators of weakening industrial demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Dropped Slightly on December 5</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103657188</link><description>Nickel prices on the SHFE slightly declined, with the most-traded contract closing at 117,700 yuan/mt, down 0.03%. Market expectations for a US Fed interest rate cut in December rose to about 89%, but nickel prices are expected to fluctuate in the short term due to recent inventory declines and economic data.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel rose to 14,970 USD/T on December 5, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices increased by 0.57% on December 5, reaching 14,970 USD per ton. Despite the recent rise, nickel prices have fallen about 0.56% over the past month and are down 6.51% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in December period I</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5106036-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-december-period-i</link><description>Indonesia's Nickel Miners Association set benchmark prices for nickel ore for early December 2025, with prices decreasing by about 2.21% from late November. Prices for different nickel content grades were lowered, reflecting a slight market softening.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Poised to Exit $15K Range as Seasonal Supply Constraints Hit Market</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-prices-poised-to-exit-15k-range-as-seasonal-supply-constraints-hit-market</link><description>Nickel prices have been range-bound between $15,000 and $15,800 per ton since April 2025, but seasonal supply drops in the Philippines and regulatory crackdowns in Indonesia are creating upward pressure. Growing electric vehicle demand and government support in Canada may further support price increases.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum stabilizes high-nickel cathodes, curbing rapid capacity loss in EV batteries</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-12-aluminum-stabilizes-high-nickel-cathodes.html</link><description>Researchers have identified that lattice structural distortion causes capacity fading in high-nickel cathodes used in electric vehicle batteries. By substituting a small amount of nickel with aluminum, they successfully stabilized the cathode structure, significantly enhancing battery lifespan and safety, which could impact next-generation high-performance battery design.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ZincFive Raises $30M for AI Data Center Batteries</title><link>https://insidehpc.com/2025/12/zincfive-raises-30m-for-ai-data-center-batteries/</link><description>ZincFive secured $30 million to advance its patented nickel-zinc battery technology, which offers superior power density, safety, and sustainability compared to lead-acid and lithium-ion batteries. The technology is gaining traction for AI data center infrastructure due to its compact size, low maintenance, and environmental benefits.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Next-Gen Battery Chemistries Shift to Silicon and Nickel</title><link>https://environmentenergyleader.com/stories/next-gen-battery-chemistries-shift-to-silicon-and-nickel,106090</link><description>A new report highlights the growing adoption of silicon-enhanced anodes and high-nickel cathodes in battery technology, especially for electric vehicles requiring high energy density. These innovations aim to reduce cobalt reliance and improve battery capacity, though challenges remain in thermal management and manufacturing complexity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Buy-back transactions - Weekly Report (December 1, 2025 – December 5, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-buy-back-transactions-weekly-report-december-1-2025-a-december-5-2025-on-the-s-ce7d51dcd080f125</link><description>Tenaris reported buy-back transactions as part of the second tranche of its share buyback program. The company purchased shares on multiple trading venues with the intention to cancel treasury shares acquired under the program.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian has been awarded the tender by Terna S.p.A. and STEG for the construction of a submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia as part of the Elmed Project. The project aims to create an energy bridge between Europe and Africa, enhancing energy security and supporting the shift toward cleaner energy. The submarine cable will run between Sicily and Tunisia, with installation operations carried out by the Prysmian Monna Lisa vessel.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian SpA Outlook Revised To Negative On High Leverage</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/ratings/pt/regulatory/article/-/view/type/HTML/id/3156833</link><description>S&amp;P Global revised Prysmian SpA's outlook to negative due to high leverage concerns. The Italy-based cable manufacturer recently entered into a definitive agreement to acquire U.S.-based cable manufacturer Encore, which impacts its financial profile.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Rise Amid Supply Constraints and Production Caps</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,909.20 per ton, driven by supply decreases and China's efforts to curb overcapacity in metal production. China plans to slow output next year due to a 45 million ton cap and faces setbacks in building smelters in Indonesia due to energy costs and regulations. Additional supply disruptions include a potline suspension at Iceland’s Grundartangi smelter and Alcoa's closure of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>MADMEC winners develop spray-on coating to protect power lines from ice</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2025/madmec-winners-develop-spray-coating-protect-power-lines-ice-1205</link><description>The MIT team developed a spray-on coating for aluminum power lines that prevents ice formation, enhancing durability and reducing outage costs. Tested under simulated freezing conditions, the coating accommodates strain and could save millions in repair costs, supporting sustainable infrastructure resilience in cold climates.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel rebar futures in China rise above CNY 3,100 per tonne, highest in three months</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China rose above CNY 3,100 per tonne in early December, marking the highest level in three months. This rise is attributed to lower supply and government support measures, despite weak near-term demand. The Chinese government is considering new measures to support the property market, which is the largest source of global rebar demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel price trends and recent fluctuations</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) Steel prices rose slightly to 908 USD/T on December 5, 2025, up 0.22% from the previous day, but also fell to 903.04 USD/T the same day, showing volatility. Over the past month, HRC Steel prices increased by 6.62% and are up 31.07% compared to the previous year, reflecting ongoing market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel to resume steel production at Illinois plant shut 3 years ago</title><link>https://www.cbsnews.com/chicago/news/us-steel-to-resume-steel-production-at-illinois-plant-shut-3-years-ago/</link><description>U.S. Steel announced it will restart steel slab production at its Granite City Works plant in Illinois, reversing its previous shutdown decision from 2023. The company cited strong customer demand and plans to resume production in the first half of 2026 after hiring and training workers. This move follows pressure from the White House and reflects a robust U.S. steel market strengthened by tariffs and increased demand in automaking and construction.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking Decarbonisation</title><link>https://www.bhp.com/news/bhp-insights/2025/12/steelmaking-decarbonisation</link><description>BHP highlights the challenge of decarbonizing steel production while meeting rising global demand. The company supports multiple technology pathways, including carbon capture and renewable energy, aiming for a 30% reduction in greenhouse gas emissions intensity by post-2030 adoption.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 3.79% Higher at $5.3820</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512055949/comex-copper-ends-the-week-379-higher-at-53820-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for December delivery gained 3.79% this week, reaching $5.3820 per pound. This marks the largest one-week net and percentage gain since early October 2025, with prices up six of the past eight sessions and the highest settlement since July 30, 2025. Year-to-date, copper is up 35.02%, though still 7.13% off its 52-week high.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price extends record run as Citi makes bullish call</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-extends-record-run-as-citi-makes-bull-call/</link><description>Copper futures on the London Metal Exchange rose as much as 2.2% to $11,705 a ton, surpassing previous records amid expectations of a global supply shortage. Citigroup forecasted prices could reach $13,000 a ton by Q2 2026, driven by a US inventory buildup and supply squeeze. However, some analysts warn prices above $11,000 may not be sustainable due to market volatility and uncertain end-use demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Touches another Record High</title><link>https://www.admis.com/copper-touched-another-record-high/</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the LME hit an all-time peak of $11,705 before settling slightly lower at $11,616. Citi raised its price outlook to an average of $13,000 in Q2 2026, citing supply shortages and expectations of a Fed rate cut. Glencore also lowered its 2026 copper production guidance, supporting the bullish market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to $5.37 per pound on December 5, 2025, up 1.96% from the previous day and up 8.45% over the past month. The price increase is linked to supply disruptions and a large withdrawal of metal from LME warehouses, fueling speculation of a supply squeeze. Copper is up nearly 30% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Touches another Record High</title><link>https://www.admis.com/copper-touched-another-record-high/</link><description>Copper prices reached a new record high, supported by Citi's raised price outlook and expectations of a US Federal Reserve rate cut. Supply concerns and structural support from tight supply outside the US contributed to the price surge. Meanwhile, Glencore lowered its 2026 copper production guidance, and Chinese copper smelters plan to cut production by over 10% in 2026 to address industry overcapacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chile, Peru, Brazil and Argentina Look to the Copper Boom with Optimism</title><link>https://www.panorama-minero.com/en/news/chile-peru-brazil-and-argentina-look-to-the-copper-boom-with-optimism</link><description>South American copper producers Chile, Peru, Brazil, and Argentina are optimistic about the copper boom driven by global demand for energy transition metals. Traditional producers like Chile and Peru are well positioned, while Brazil and Argentina aim to become major suppliers. The market shows a clear upward trend in copper prices amid volatility and rising inventories, with strong demand expected to grow exponentially by 2050.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Recycled Copper Market - Forecasts from 2025 to 2030: Opportunities in Rising Demand from Rapid Infrastructural Developments</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/12/05/3200593/0/en/Recycled-Copper-Market-Forecasts-from-2025-to-2030-Opportunities-in-Rising-Demand-from-Rapid-Infrastructural-Developments-Particularly-in-Asia-Pacific-and-the-Middle-East.html</link><description>The global recycled copper market is growing due to its environmental benefits, using approximately 85% less energy than primary copper production. Rising infrastructure development, especially in Asia-Pacific and the Middle East, and government regulations promoting recycled copper use are driving demand. Recycling copper reduces landfill waste and conserves fossil fuels, supporting sustainable resource management.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Critical metals innovator pH7 raises $25.6M to scale copper extraction technology</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/critical-metals-innovator-ph7-raises-25-6m/</link><description>pH7 Technologies secured $25.6 million to commercialize its organo-electrochemical copper extraction technology that recovers metals from lower-grade ores and uneconomic feedstocks. The closed-loop process reduces energy consumption and wastewater generation, offering a sustainable alternative to traditional high-waste extraction methods and supporting domestic critical metals supply chains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (December 1, 2025 - December 5, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-december-1-2025-a-december-5-2025-on-the-s-ce7d51dcd080f025</link><description>Tenaris announced its intention to cancel treasury shares purchased under its share buyback programs. The report details recent transactions involving share purchases on various trading venues and provides insights into the company's financial management and outlook amid market uncertainties.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance after reporting better-than-expected Q3 results, driven by strong growth in Renewable Transmission and Power Grids segments. The company noted steady performance in North America and Europe, with a stable high-voltage backlog of about €16 billion. Analysts suggest Prysmian has not yet fully realized benefits from copper tariffs but expects positive impacts in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM weekly survey: Aluminium processing industry strained by off-season and high aluminium prices, with structural divergence persisting</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/smm-weekly-survey-aluminium-processing-industry-strained-by-off-season-and-high-aluminium-prices-with-structural-divergence-persisting-116468</link><description>High aluminum prices above RMB 22,000 per tonne and off-season effects have dampened downstream enthusiasm and suppressed operations in the aluminum processing industry. Structural order differences remain significant, with declines in construction and packaging sectors, and weak year-end stockpiling expected to continue into December.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices Hold Steady Ahead of 2025</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2024/12/11/steel-prices-hold-steady/</link><description>Steel prices have fallen 2.4% from the end of Q3 2025, with the Raw Steels Monthly Metals Index showing a modest 1.78% decline from November to December. Buyers noted flexible pricing from mills, and a seasonal pickup in demand is expected in Q1 2026. Chinese steel slab prices and LME steel scrap prices fell, while Comex HRC futures rose 4.64% as of early December.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chile to reach milestones in 13 copper projects worth US$14.8bn in 2026, amid a bull market</title><link>https://www.bnamericas.com/en/features/chile-to-reach-milestones-in-13-copper-projects-worth-us148bn-in-2026-amid-a-bull-market</link><description>Chile is set to achieve significant milestones in 13 copper projects valued at $14.8 billion in 2026, reflecting a strong bull market for copper. These projects encompass various mining activities including open pit mining, exploration, and underground mining, contributing to increased production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices on Dec 6th rebound amid strong US job data</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/nickel-prices-on-dec-6th-rebound-amid-strong-us-job-data-declining-lme-inventories/151703</link><description>LME nickel futures prices rebounded by $73/ton to close at $16,047/ton on December 6, supported by strong US employment data and declining LME inventories, indicating renewed market strength.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Trend Charts 2025: Global Analysis &amp; Forecasts</title><link>https://www.accio.com/business/steel-price-trend-chart</link><description>Steel prices have shown volatility in 2025, with U.S. Hot-Rolled Coil futures trading around $860/ton in December 2025 and a 52-week range of $778 to $888/ton. Chinese steel rebar futures were up 5.74% month-over-month in August 2025 but face downward pressure from tariffs and oversupply. A price recovery is forecasted for 2027, contingent on demand rebound and supply rationalization.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chile to reach milestones in 13 copper projects worth US$14.8bn in 2026 amid a bull market</title><link>https://www.bnamericas.com/en/features/chile-to-reach-milestones-in-13-copper-projects-worth-us148bn-in-2026-amid-a-bull-market</link><description>Chile is set to achieve milestones in 13 copper projects valued at US$14.8 billion in 2026, reflecting a strong bull market for copper. These developments underscore Chile's role as a leading copper producer amid rising global demand and favorable market conditions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>RIO Boosts Copper Innovation With First Copper Output Using Nuton Technology</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/rio-boosts-copper-innovation-first-copper-output-using-nuton-tech</link><description>Rio Tinto announced the first copper production from the Johnson Camp mine in Arizona using its Nuton Technology, which combines biology, chemistry, engineering, and digital tools to enable cleaner, faster, and more efficient copper production. Nuton eliminates traditional concentration, smelting, and refining steps, reducing water use by up to 80% and carbon emissions by up to 60%, aiming to produce copper with the lowest carbon footprint in the U.S.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto advances Nuton copper processing technology at Johnson Camp mine</title><link>https://www.mining-technology.com/news/rio-tinto-advances-nuton-copper-processing-technology-at-johnson-camp-mine/</link><description>Rio Tinto achieved a milestone with the first copper produced using Nuton technology, which uses bioleaching to extract copper directly at the mine, bypassing traditional smelting and refining. Nuton can recover up to 85% from primary sulphides, extend mine life, and reduce environmental impact with a projected carbon footprint of 0.82 kg CO₂-e/kg copper and water usage of 71 liters/kg copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chile, Peru, Brazil and Argentina Look to the Copper Boom with Optimism</title><link>https://www.panorama-minero.com/en/news/chile-peru-brazil-and-argentina-look-to-the-copper-boom-with-optimism</link><description>Latin American countries are optimistic about copper's role in clean technologies and the energy transition, with copper being essential for solar panels, wind turbines, and electrical grids. New copper projects in the region emphasize ESG (Environmental, Social, and Governance) principles to ensure sustainability and minimize environmental and social impacts, aligning with carbon market requirements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices were in the doldrums this week, with domestic inventory increasing slightly</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103657838/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-were-in-the-doldrums-this-week-with-domestic-inventory-increasing-slightly</link><description>Nickel prices showed sideways movement this week, oscillating between $14,700/mt and $14,900/mt on the LME and SHFE markets. Despite weak demand and sluggish trading, expectations of a US Fed interest rate cut and progress in geopolitical conflicts provided some support, while LME nickel inventory remained high at over 250,000 mt.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Breakthrough Tech Yields 99% Pure Nickel, Cobalt</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/breakthrough-tech-yields-99-pure-nickel-cobalt-1566990/</link><description>A research team at UNIST developed an innovative electrochemical recycling technology that recovers over 95% of nickel and cobalt from waste batteries with purity exceeding 99%. This sustainable method reduces chemical use and wastewater generation, potentially transforming the battery recycling industry by enabling a more efficient and environmentally friendly recovery process.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Critical metals innovator pH7 raises $25.6M</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/critical-metals-innovator-ph7-raises-25-6m/</link><description>pH7 has raised $25.6 million to advance its closed-loop organo-electrochemical extraction technology that recovers metals like nickel from lower-grade ores and uneconomic feedstocks. The process reduces energy consumption and wastewater generation, supporting resilient domestic supply chains and sustainable metal recovery for the energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Unilever, Ball and Alcoa unveil “first” carbon-free aluminum aerosol can</title><link>https://www.packaginginsights.com/news/carbon-free-aluminum-aerosol-can.html</link><description>Ball Corporation, Unilever, and Alcoa introduced the first aerosol can made using Elysis carbon-free smelting technology, combining 50% Elysis aluminum with 50% recycled content. This innovation eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions from smelting by producing oxygen instead of CO2, marking a significant step in decarbonizing aluminum packaging for personal care products.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Recycling Market to Reach US$91.3 Billion by 2032 as Global Demand for Low-Carbon Metals &amp; Circular Manufacturing Surges</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/aluminum-recycling-market-to-reach-us91-3-billion-by-2032-as-global-demand-for-low-carbon-metals--circular-manufacturing-surges-302630210.html</link><description>The aluminum recycling industry is rapidly evolving with technological innovations such as hydrogen-powered remelting furnaces and AI-guided scrap sorting systems to reduce carbon emissions and increase efficiency. Recycling aluminum uses 95% less energy than primary production, supporting circular economy principles and meeting growing demand, especially in electric vehicles requiring high aluminum content.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price rises for 2 consecutive days due to falling US dollar</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-price-rises-for-2-consecutive-days-due-to-falling-us-dollar/145240</link><description>LME nickel futures rose by US$290 on December 7, closing at US$16,508/ton, while the spot price increased by US$291.5 to US$16,306/ton. The price rise is attributed to the falling US dollar, supporting nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME's nickel price soars on Dec 7 on crisis concerns &amp; Indonesia's policy</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lmes-nickel-price-soars-on-dec-7-on-crisis-concerns-indonesias-policy/138142</link><description>The LME nickel price surged by US$2,170/ton on December 7, closing at US$31,441/ton amid crisis concerns and policy developments in Indonesia affecting the nickel market. The nickel spot price also saw a significant increase.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>