<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Beijing Moves to Rein in Steel Exports With New Licensing Rule</title><link>https://www.caixinglobal.com/2025-12-13/beijing-moves-to-rein-in-steel-exports-with-new-licensing-rule-102392857.html</link><description>China's Ministry of Commerce and General Administration of Customs announced export licensing requirements for most steel products starting January 1, 2026, to curb surging low-priced shipments and illicit trade. Steel exports reached 110 million tons in 2024, forecasted at 110-130 million tons in 2025, with first-10-months 2025 exports at 97.7 million tons and prices down 8.7% to $695.4/ton. The measure covers crude iron, billets, coils, plates, pipes, and scrap, amid rising global trade remedy investigations against Chinese steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper eases after nearing $12,000, set for 3rd straight weekly jump</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-eases-after-nearing-12000-set-for-3rd-straight-weekly-jump/</link><description>Copper prices eased after earlier touching near $12,000 per tonne but remained on track for a third consecutive weekly gain, pressured by demand uncertainty out of top consumer China even as Chinese policymakers signalled measured economic support for 2026. The piece highlights the tension between strong recent rallies and short‑term profit‑taking or demand concerns that have driven intraday swings[7].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tight supply and AI demand drive copper prices higher</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-rally-forces-2025-supply-demand-imbalance/</link><description>The article attributes recent copper strength to tightening physical supply and rising demand tied to AI and energy‑transition trends, reporting prices around $11,952 per metric tonne as of December 12, 2025. It frames the rally as supported by structural demand growth (EVs, renewables, AI infrastructure) alongside inventory movements that have tightened availability[3].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME metal inventories update — Copper inventories reported (December 13)</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103087911/LME-Metal-Inventories-Updates-on-December-13</link><description>Metal.com’s inventory update shows LME copper stock movements on December 13, 2025, signaling ongoing shifts in exchange inventories that market participants watch for clues on near‑term physical tightness. The update provides transaction price ranges and inventory figures that help explain short‑term price volatility and regional flows affecting LME balances[8].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Metal Mania: Reuters on Copper, Tin, Zinc, Lithium, Cobalt and More</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/metal-mania-reuters-on-copper-tin-zinc-lithium-cobalt-and-more</link><description>Recycling and technological innovation are key to addressing growing metal demand, particularly for copper. In China, increased scrap copper from aging infrastructure could offset shortages through 'urban mining.' This reduces reliance on primary mining and supports supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[December 13 Morning Meeting Summary] Refined Nickel: Spot Premiums Update, Nickel Futures Rise</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103085889/%5BDec-13-Morning-Meeting%5D-Nickel-Spot-Premiums-Update-Nickel-Futures-Rise</link><description>Domestic refined nickel closed at 117,080 yuan/mt on Friday, up 1.99% week-over-week. LME nickel prices rebounded significantly to $14,850/mt on Friday. Spot premiums and futures showed upward movement in the morning meeting.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Had Slightly Increased This Week</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-21909.html</link><description>Shanghai nickel warehouse receipts inventory stood at 30,564 tons as of December 13th, up 985 tons week-over-week. Nickel prices showed a slight increase amid inventory buildup. Market trends indicate modest upward pressure despite ongoing supply dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 13 Dec 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/12/13/the-market-in-numbers-13-dec-2025/</link><description>Nickel price per pound recorded at 6.6005, down 0.90% as of December 13, 2025. This reflects broader metals market movements, with nickel under slight downward pressure. Part of daily metals and minerals pricing update.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries (ASX: NIC) Soars with Quota Approval: Is It a Buy?</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/nickel-industries-surges-on-quota-approval/</link><description>Indonesian authorities approved an increase to Nickel Industries' 2025 nickel ore sales quota from 9 million to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes. This allows resumption of deliveries from the Hengjaya Mine to the Indonesia Morowali Industrial Park, supported by a five-year AMDAL permit and in-pit tailings system. The approval addresses ongoing oversupply pressures amid rapid capacity expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. Announces Closing of Oversubscribed $1.96m Flow-Through Financing</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/6264300</link><description>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. closed an oversubscribed $1.96 million flow-through financing. This follows a news release on December 4, 2025, providing funds likely for critical minerals exploration including nickel-related activities. The financing supports the company's development in the critical minerals sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. Announces Closing of Oversubscribed $1.96m Flow-Through Financing</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/12/13/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/north-american-niobium-and-critical-minerals-corp-announces-closing-of-oversubscribed-196m-flow-through-financing/2242758</link><description>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. announced the closing of its oversubscribed $1.96 million flow-through financing. The update references a prior release from December 4, 2025. Funds will advance critical minerals projects, potentially including nickel production capacities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion titled “Nuclear: the future of the Italian boilermaking industry” at Fondazione Dalmine in Italy, partnering with UCC. Experts from industry and institutions discussed nuclear energy's role in Europe’s energy transition and Italy’s manufacturing potential, including small modular reactors. Tenaris’s Italian mill recently obtained accreditation for nuclear materials under ASME III standards.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (December 8, 2025 - December 12, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-december-8-2025-a-december-12-2025-on-the-ce7d50d8dd8df324</link><description>Tenaris published its weekly share buyback report for December 8-12, 2025, detailing purchases like 497,790 shares on MTA at a weighted average price. As of December 12, the company holds 51,262,421 treasury shares, equal to 4.78% of issued capital, with plans to cancel them. The report is available on Tenaris's IR website.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Electricity Scarcity Meets Aluminum Tariffs, and American Citizens Pick Up the Bill</title><link>https://cleantechnica.com/2025/12/13/electricity-scarcity-meets-aluminum-tariffs-and-american-citizens-pick-up-the-bill/</link><description>US Midwest aluminum premium surged to $1,300-$1,900 per ton after 2025 tariff escalations, 2.5-4 times higher than the prior $450-$550 range, driven by policy amid electricity constraints and import dependence. This diverges sharply from global LME prices, raising costs for US buyers and complicating new smelter investments due to higher WACC from policy volatility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 14.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel exchanges, including Shanghai Futures rebar prices as of December 12, 2025, showing no change at 0.00%. The platform covers indices, prices, and news for various futures terms across regions like China, Turkey, Europe, and North America. Latest sections include rebar news, scrap news, and iron and steel markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Semiconductors, Displays 'Clear'; Petrochemicals, Steel 'Cloudy'</title><link>https://www.chosun.com/english/industry-en/2025/12/14/FB35MN3WGJH4LLSAMPAWYIDMLU/</link><description>South Korea's steel industry faces 'cloudy' prospects in 2026 due to Chinese oversupply and U.S./EU import restrictions, with exports expected to drop 2.1%. The Korea Iron and Steel Association notes declining shipments to traditional markets despite gains in emerging ones like Latin America. This contrasts with 'clear' outlooks for semiconductors and displays.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper gives up record highs near $12,000 at the London Exchange</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/copper-news/copper-gives-up-record-highs-near-$12,000-at-the-london-exchange-47936</link><description>Three-month copper futures on the LME fell 0.35% to $11,829 per ton after touching an all-time high of $11,952, amid concerns that elevated prices could weigh on demand. The metal remains on track for weekly gains for the third consecutive week. In contrast, Shanghai Futures Exchange copper closed up 1.95% at 94.08 thousand yuan per ton.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>How tight supply, AI demand propelled copper price towards $12,000</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/how-tight-supply-ai-demand-propelled-copper-price-towards-12000/</link><description>Copper prices are up 35% this year, nearing $12,000 per metric ton, due to mining disruptions, US stockpiling, and soaring demand from AI data centers. Valued for its electrical conductivity, copper is vital for power grids, EVs, and energy transition infrastructure. Bullish sentiment is driven by tight supply narratives and macro news flows.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper eases after nearing USD12,000</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40397323</link><description>Copper prices eased after approaching $12,000 per ton, with ANZ expecting prices to remain above $11,000 in 2026 and potentially near $12,000 by year-end amid supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chile's weekend runoff puts Codelco future at stake</title><link>https://www.mining.com/chiles-weekend-runoff-puts-copper-future-at-stake/</link><description>Chile's presidential runoff on December 14 will impact the future of state copper giant Codelco, which faces over $20 billion in debt, aging infrastructure, and production declines to a 25-year low in 2022. Legal obligations to remit profits to the government limit reinvestment, threatening Chile's mining-driven economy projected to grow 2.5% in 2025. The election outcome could balance resource nationalism with economic pragmatism for the world's top copper producer.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM: Secondary Aluminum Alloy Ingot Social Inventory Dips to 48,862 mt on Dec 15</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103670223/SMM:-Secondary-Aluminum-Alloy-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-to-48862-mt-on-Dec-15</link><description>SMM statistics show the combined daily social inventory of secondary aluminum alloy ingots dipped to 48,862 mt on December 15. SMM expects aluminum prices to pull back slightly from high levels in the short term.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Aluminium Advances India's Low-Carbon Manufacturing Push with 1.57 Billion Units of Renewable Energy in FY25</title><link>https://solarquarter.com/2025/12/15/vedanta-aluminium-advances-indias-low-carbon-manufacturing-push-with-1-57-billion-units-of-renewable-energy-in-fy25/</link><description>Vedanta Aluminium consumed 1.57 billion units of renewable energy in FY25, reducing GHG emissions intensity by 8.96% since FY21 as part of its 2030 decarbonization roadmap. The company implemented energy-saving technologies like patented potlining, achieving 378 million units in savings, and plans to source 1,500 MW of renewable power. Partnerships and 'Communities of Practice' support goals for 30% low-carbon aluminum products.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US OCTG imports down 10.0 percent in August 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-octg-imports-down-100-percent-in-august-2025-1424489.htm</link><description>US imports of Oil Country Tubular Goods (OCTG) decreased by 10.0 percent in August 2025. This decline reflects ongoing trends in the steel import market, potentially influencing domestic pricing and supply dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Declines After China Moves to License Steel Exports</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-15/iron-ore-declines-after-china-moves-to-license-steel-exports</link><description>Iron ore futures declined as much as 1.6% after China announced a licensing system for exporting certain steel products starting January 1, 2026. The Ministry of Commerce requires exporters to seek permission for a broad range of steel used in construction, cars, and consumer goods. This comes as China's steel exports are on track for a 2025 record.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China November crude steel output hits a 23-month low</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/china-november-crude-steel-output-hits-a-23-month-low-ce7d50d8d188f126</link><description>China's crude steel output in November fell 3% from October, marking six straight months of declines due to thinner margins. This represents the lowest output in 23 months. The reduction impacts global steel supply dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Claws Back Gains With Base Metals After Friday's 3% Tumble</title><link>https://www.fxleaders.com/news/2025/12/15/copper-claws-back-gains-with-base-metals-after-fridays-3-tumble/</link><description>Copper prices rebounded by up to 1.5% on the London Metal Exchange after dropping 3% on Friday due to a selloff in AI-related shares. The recovery reflects a shift in focus to a tighter market outlook for 2026 amid mine disruptions, green energy demand, and potential US tariffs. As of 12:42 p.m. in Shanghai, copper was priced at $11,656.50 a ton after hitting a record near $12,000.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises on 2026 Supply Concerns Amid Tariff Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-rises-2026-supply-concerns-tariff-uncertainty-2512/</link><description>Copper prices climbed as much as 1.5% on the London Metal Exchange on Monday, recovering from Friday's 3% losses as investors refocused on long-term supply tightness. Demand from AI infrastructure and renewable energy, along with potential US tariffs and mine constraints, supports expectations for higher prices in 2026. Goldman Sachs forecasts prices between $10,000–$11,000 per ton next year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Plummets Amid Risk-Off Market Sentiment</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/15/copper-plummets-amid-risk-off-market-sentiment/</link><description>Copper prices fell more than 3% on Friday amid a risk-off sentiment triggered by profit-taking in AI stocks, reversing earlier weekly gains. ANZ analysts maintain a bullish outlook due to robust fundamentals, including supply disruptions, strong demand from EVs, energy infrastructure in China, and AI investments in the US. The pullback is seen as temporary, not derailing the upward trajectory.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>How tight supply, AI demand propelled copper towards $12,000</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/how-tight-supply-ai-demand-propelled-copper-towards-12000/</link><description>Copper prices approached $12,000 per metric ton driven by tight supply conditions and surging demand from AI applications. The rally highlights structural market imbalances favoring higher prices. Ongoing supply constraints and technology-driven consumption are key propellants.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Fortescue Bolsters Copper Pipeline with Alta Copper Buy</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/15/fortescue-bolsters-copper-pipeline-with-alta-copper-buy/</link><description>Fortescue Metals Group acquired the remaining 64% stake in Alta Copper for $C139 million to strengthen its long-term copper pipeline. Analysts at RBC Capital Markets view it as a low-risk, low-cost addition with minimal near-term impact on cash flow or earnings. The move diversifies Fortescue's portfolio toward copper for the energy transition while maintaining iron ore focus.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On December 15, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103671012/</link><description>On December 15, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 114,500–120,200 yuan/mt, averaging 117,350 yuan/mt, down 850 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects ongoing weakness in the Chinese nickel market. The update is part of non-ferrous metals pricing coverage.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Investing In Innovation: GBCCA Showcases New Technology To Close The Recycling Loop For Aluminium Cans</title><link>https://international-aluminium.org/investing-in-innovation-gbcca-showcases-new-technology-to-close-the-recycling-loop-for-aluminium-cans/</link><description>The Global Beverage Can Circularity Alliance (GBCCA) showcased robotics, AI, deposit return systems and home recycling equipment at Climate Week NYC as technologies to boost aluminium beverage-can recycling and help reach targets of ~100% recycling by 2050 (80% by 2030). The piece highlights how advanced sorting and household-level solutions can unlock lost material streams and accelerate circularity for aluminium cans.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Giants Hit Major Milestone with Low-Carbon Production</title><link>https://www.theenergymix.com/aluminium-giants-hit-major-milestone-with-low-carbon-production/</link><description>Elysis (Alcoa–Rio Tinto JV) reported scaling its carbon‑free "inert anode" technology to a 450‑kA cell, a step toward commercial low‑carbon aluminium production that could eliminate CO2 emissions from anodes if sustained at scale. The article discusses technical changes (including a vertical cell design), potential climate benefits, and questions about full‑scale cost and sustained operation.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>GMG Unveils Graphene Aluminium‑Ion Battery That Fully Charges In 6 Minutes</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/15/gmg-unveils-graphene-aluminium-ion-battery-that-fully-charges-in-6-minutes/</link><description>GMG announced a graphene aluminium‑ion battery using aluminium foil substrates and a chloride‑free hybrid electrolyte that reportedly enables very fast charging (full charge in ~6 minutes) and avoids lithium and copper, targeting automotive, grid and specialty applications as it advances toward scale‑up and patents. The story emphasizes potential cost/weight benefits and ongoing work to validate reliability, safety and manufacturability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Korea to overhaul steel industry, pledges $139 million in specialty steel R&amp;D subsidies</title><link>https://www.kedglobal.com/steel/newsView/ked202512150005</link><description>South Korea unveiled plans to overhaul its steel industry, including government-backed production cuts and increased output of high-value specialty steel. The government pledged $139 million in R&amp;D subsidies during a roundtable with steel executives. This addresses weakening exports due to global construction slump and Chinese supply pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US Copper Stakes Additional Claims to Accommodate Future Surface Facilities at the Moonlight-Superior Copper Project</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/278046/US-Copper-Stakes-Additional-Claims-to-Accommodate-Future-Surface-Facilities-at-the-MoonlightSuperior-Copper-Project</link><description>US Copper filed new claims to secure land for future surface facilities at its Moonlight-Superior project as it prepares for a prefeasibility study and permitting; the company projects average annual production of about 60 million pounds of copper if developed and highlights ongoing metallurgical studies leading into a 2026 PFS timetable.[4] The release positions the project as a potential domestic supplier to the U.S. market and outlines recent technical and economic work referenced in earlier studies.[4]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chile copper mining costs highest in Americas, threatening new investment, report says</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/chile-copper-mining-costs-highest-in-americas-threatening-new-investment-report-says/</link><description>A Cochilco report found Chile has the highest copper mining costs in the Americas for medium-capacity processing plants and the second-highest for large-scale operations, which could threaten new investment despite Chile’s large resource base and plans to expand capacity at major mines.[6] The story warns that elevated capital intensity and operating costs may limit the country’s ability to attract greenfield projects even as demand outlook supports expansion.[6]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Drop Amid Oversupply</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures fell to 14,295 USD/T on December 15, 2025, down 2.22% from the previous day due to persistent oversupply. Global inventories remain elevated, with LME stockpiles exceeding levels that continue to pressure market sentiment. Over the past month, prices have fallen 2.59%, and are down 8.77% year-over-year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel presents metals market review - 15 December 2025</title><link>https://nornickel.com/news-and-media/press-releases-and-news/nornickel-presents-metals-market-review-15-12-2025/</link><description>Nornickel forecasts the global nickel market to stay in surplus over 200 kt Ni in both 2025 and 2026. The base-case scenario highlights continued oversupply amid strong production growth. This review aligns with broader market data on elevated inventories.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel sharply hikes nickel surplus forecasts for this year and next</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-sharply-hikes-nickel-surplus-forecasts-for-this-year-and-next/</link><description>Russian mining giant Nornickel doubled its nickel surplus forecast for 2025 to 240,000 tons from 120,000 tons previously and more than doubled the 2026 forecast to 275,000 tons. The global nickel market has been in surplus for four years due to rapid supply growth, particularly from Indonesia. Nornickel attributes the surplus to continued production expansion outpacing demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel expects global nickel market surplus in 2025-2026</title><link>https://tass.com/economy/2058767</link><description>Nornickel forecasts a global nickel market surplus exceeding 200,000 tons in both 2025 and 2026, driven by production growth to 3.86 million tons in 2025 and 4.1 million tons in 2026, outpacing demand growth to 3.62 million and 3.83 million tons respectively. Over 66% of output will come from Indonesia, despite recent government measures to curb excess supply. The company notes that only Indonesia's production restraint can balance the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Gov. Beshear: AKFA Aluminum Solutions To Establish New Manufacturing Operation in Bowling Green, Creating 331 Quality Jobs</title><link>https://lexingtonky.news/2025/12/15/gov-beshear-akfa-aluminum-solutions-to-establish-new-manufacturing-operation-in-bowling-green-creating-331-quality-jobs/</link><description>AKFA Aluminum Solutions is establishing a new manufacturing operation in Bowling Green, Kentucky, creating 331 quality jobs. This development supports aluminum production expansion potentially tied to innovative and sustainable practices. Governor Beshear announced the project as a boost to the local economy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>High aluminium prices to lift Press Metal earnings</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/16/high-aluminium-prices-to-lift-press-metal-earnings</link><description>High aluminum prices are set to drive record profits for Press Metal amid foreign expansions and resilient market conditions. London Metal Exchange prices have strengthened to US$2,800 per tonne, the highest since 2022, supported by supply tightness, while low alumina costs provide a margin tailwind. HLIB Research raised earnings forecasts, maintained a 'buy' rating, and expects continued aluminum deficits into 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 16.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar prices listed as flat at 0.00 change on December 15, 2025. Various futures contracts for rebar and other steel products across regions like Turkey, China, Europe, and North America are tracked. The platform offers analyses and comments on industry trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673677/SMM:-High-Grade-NPI-Price-Falls-in-Dec-16-Sentiment-Dips</link><description>The SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI fell to 886.5 yuan/nickel unit (ex-factory, tax included) on December 16. Sentiment in the nickel pig iron market dipped amid price declines. This reflects ongoing trends in ferrous metals pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China, S Korea companies investigated for dumping</title><link>https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/biz/archives/2025/12/16/2003848943</link><description>Taiwan's Ministry of Finance launched anti-dumping investigations into cold-rolled, flat-rolled non-oriented electrical steel products from China and South Korea. The probe, prompted by China Steel Corp, targets companies like POSCO, Baoshan Iron &amp; Steel, and others amid rising imports harming local industry since 2023. This follows existing duties on stainless steel from the same countries.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper fell to 5.28 USD/Lbs on December 16, 2025, down 0.93% from the previous day, amid weak Chinese economic data including slowing industrial output and declining home prices. Despite this, prices rose to 5.34 USD/Lbs on December 15, up 1.14%, with monthly gains of 7.35%. Futures hovered around $5.3 per pound, pressured by soft demand in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Supply Shortages Coupled with the Federal Reserve's Interest Rate Cuts Pushed Copper Prices to a 15-Year High</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28829.html</link><description>Copper prices rose sharply last week to 93,903.33 RMB/ton as of December 12, a 15-year high, driven by global supply shortages from mine disruptions and a 'pull effect' into the US market. The Federal Reserve's interest rate cuts amplified bullish sentiment. Forecasts predict LME copper above $11,000 per ton in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/16/copper-prices-rise-on-supply-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices increased due to potential supply constraints in 2026, with strong demand from Chinese EV and energy sectors offsetting weak economic data like slower retail sales and industrial output. US demand remains robust from AI investments and reduced trade tensions. Other base metals like nickel and zinc declined.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Korea Zinc to Build Integrated Smelter; LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103672447/Korea-Zinc-to-Build-Integrated-Smelter-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Korea Zinc plans to build an integrated smelter, while LME copper prices showed intraday volatility and closed higher on the reported session; the report also notes changes in Chinese spot premiums, secondary copper market activity, and inventory movements that could constrain upside for prices in the near term.[1] The article discusses supply-side selling driven by year-end funding and weaker demand from high prices, and reports recent LME and SHFE inventory figures that affect market balance.[1]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/16/copper-prices-rise-on-supply-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices increased as markets focused on potential supply constraints for the coming year, with ANZ citing persistent disruptions and strong demand—particularly from Chinese imports tied to EVs and energy infrastructure—as supporting prices despite softer macro data from China.[3] The piece also notes weakness in other base metals and contextualizes copper strength with demand from the US (including AI-related investments).[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>World's largest copper mine drives Chile investment</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/16/worlds-largest-copper-mine-drives-chile-investment/</link><description>Coverage highlights Chile’s upgraded mining-investment outlook—driven largely by an expansion at BHP’s Escondida—boosting Cochilco’s estimate of mining investment through 2034 and underpinning expectations for future copper production capacity as Chile aims to capitalise on rising global demand.[5] The article links the Escondida expansion to broader investment in copper and lithium projects and cites forecasts of strong long-term copper demand growth.[5]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 16, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673145/</link><description>On December 16, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 111,700–117,800 yuan/mt, averaging 114,750 yuan/mt. This represents a decline of 2,650 yuan/mt from the previous day. The drop reflects ongoing market pressures in the refined nickel segment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI was 886.5 yuan/nickel unit</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673677/SMM:-High-Grade-NPI-Price-Falls-in-Dec-16-Sentiment-Dips</link><description>On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI fell to 886.5 yuan/nickel unit (ex-factory, tax included). This decline indicates dipping sentiment in the high-grade nickel pig iron market. Prices reflect broader base metals trends amid supply abundance.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel sees continued nickel surplus and tightening copper supply</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nornickel-sees-continued-nickel-surplus-and-tightening-copper-supply</link><description>Global metals producer Nornickel anticipates ongoing nickel market surplus amid rapid supply expansion. The article highlights Nornickel's outlook on nickel dynamics alongside tightening copper supply. It references Indonesia's significant role in nickel production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Hyundai Steel and POSCO Accelerate $5.8 Billion U.S. Steel Mill Project in Louisiana</title><link>http://koreabizwire.com/hyundai-steel-and-posco-accelerate-5-8-billion-u-s-steel-mill-project-in-louisiana/340298</link><description>Hyundai Steel and POSCO are advancing a $5.8 billion electric arc furnace steel mill in Louisiana, targeting 2.7 million tons annual capacity by 2029 to supply Hyundai Motor Group's U.S. operations. The project integrates direct reduced iron production to cut carbon emissions by 70% and includes equity investments from Hyundai Steel (50%), POSCO (20%), and Hyundai Motor/Kia (15% each). Construction is expected to complete by 2028, financed through internal cash flow and borrowing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hyundai Steel and POSCO Accelerate $5.8 Billion U.S. Steel Mill Project in Louisiana</title><link>http://koreabizwire.com/hyundai-steel-and-posco-accelerate-5-8-billion-u-s-steel-mill-project-in-louisiana/340298</link><description>Hyundai Steel and POSCO are advancing a $5.8 billion electric arc furnace (EAF) steel mill in Louisiana, targeting 2.7 million tons of annual production by 2029 to supply Hyundai Motor Group's U.S. operations. The project integrates direct reduced iron (DRI) with EAF, using DRI and steel scrap to cut carbon emissions by about 70% compared to traditional blast furnaces. This supports low-carbon steel production while addressing U.S. market demands and trade policies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>America's copper grab is powering a record surge in prices</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/copper-price-forecast-outlook-us-stockpiling-global-supply-surplus-ai-2025-12</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper hit a record high of $11,952 per metric ton on the London Metal Exchange on Friday, now trading around $11,655, up 33% this year. US stockpiling ahead of potential tariffs is tightening global supplies, despite an expected 300,000-ton surplus next year. Production disruptions in Indonesia, Congo, and Chile, plus speculative AI-related bets, are driving premiums and vulnerability to reversals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper eases in cautious trade ahead of US data</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40397812</link><description>Copper prices retreated on Tuesday amid cautious trading ahead of US jobs data and year-end thinning liquidity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Glencore purchase is latest in flurry of Peru copper dealmaking</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/glencore-purchase-is-latest-in-flurry-of-peru-copper-dealmaking/</link><description>Mining.com reports Glencore’s acquisition of the Quechua project from Pan Pacific Copper as part of a broader push to nearly double its global copper output, noting the deal comes amid a wave of Peru copper transactions and high copper prices driven by supply constraints and difficulty bringing new mines online[3].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Tightens the World: Why This Metal Is Driving a New Market Phase</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/news/market-updates/copper-tightens-the-world-why-this-metal-is-driving-a-new-market-phase</link><description>Kalkine Media explains that global copper markets are in a structural reset caused by electrification, infrastructure demand and constrained mine supply, arguing these forces are tightening available copper and reshaping market dynamics going forward[4].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel hesitates under pressure from Chinese data, oversupply concerns</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-hesitates-under-pressure-from-chinese-data,-oversupply-concerns-47954</link><description>LME nickel hovered near $14,295 per ton, down 2.22%, while SHFE nickel fell 2.36% amid weakness in Chinese economy and supply surpluses. Prices tested multi-month lows with LME closing at $14,346, down 1.65%. Morgan Stanley forecasts nickel drifting toward $15,500 per ton in 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of its 'Green Hydrogen in Cogne' project at the Aosta plant, deploying a 1.008 MW AEM electrolyzer to produce about 165 tonnes of green hydrogen per year to decarbonise part of its operations and power one furnace fully; the project is supported by €7.9 million from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan (NRRP).</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Yieh reports that Cogne Acciai Speciali has begun operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, using electrolysis to produce hydrogen for emissions reduction in its stainless and specialty steel production processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Outokumpu sells remaining longs business to Cogne</title><link>https://www.stainless.club/industry-news/read/outokumpu-sells-remaining-longs-business-to-cogne.html</link><description>Outokumpu has divested its remaining long products operations in Degerfors and Storfors (Sweden) to Italy’s Cogne Acciai Speciali, completing Outokumpu's exit from the longs business and allowing Cogne to expand its footprint in the Nordic and Baltic markets as part of a broader growth strategy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Introducing the Minerals Stewardship Consortium at MIT</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2025/introducing-minerals-stewardship-consortium-1216</link><description>MIT launched the Minerals Stewardship Consortium to convene industry, academia and policy leaders to develop responsible, scalable strategies for critical‑minerals production and stewardship, including copper. The consortium will pursue systems‑level innovation—digital mining tools, environmental monitoring, and social/ecological integration—to reduce environmental and social impacts while enabling resilient copper supply chains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Macro sentiment gradually cools, SHFE aluminum mainly drops back slightly at high levels [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103674703/Macro-sentiment-gradually-cools-SHFE-aluminum-mainly-drops-back-slightly-at-high-levels-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME aluminum settled at $2,882.5/mt, up 0.26%, while SHFE aluminum closed down 0.09% amid cooling macro sentiment. Aluminum scrap supply remains tight with resilient secondary prices due to high costs, but weakening demand and fluctuating prices lead to sluggish trading. Overall fundamentals lean bearish with rising inventories and declining alumina costs, expecting prices to hover at highs but pull back slightly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum US Midwest Premium reaches 90 cents/lb for the first time</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/aluminum-us-midwest-premium-reaches-90-cents-lb-for-the-first-time/</link><description>The US Midwest Premium for primary aluminum has reached 90 cents/lb for the first time, signaling strong regional demand and supply tightness in the US market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto adds aluminum markups as Trump tariffs drive up consumer costs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/rio-tinto-adds-aluminum-markups-as-trump-tariffs-drive-up-consumer-costs/</link><description>Rio Tinto introduced aluminum markups of 1-3 cents above the US Midwest premium amid Trump’s 50% tariffs, pushing total premiums to over 70% on top of the $2,830/ton base price. US LME warehouses are depleted, domestic stockpiles at 35 days of consumption, distorting the market structure. Analysts expect global benchmark prices above $3,000/ton amid supply shortages and policy impacts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Secondary Aluminum Alloy Ingot Inventories Decline on Dec 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103675387/SMM:-Secondary-Aluminum-Alloy-Ingot-Inventories-Decline-on-Dec-17</link><description>Secondary aluminum alloy ingot inventories declined on December 17, amid expectations of aluminum prices pulling back slightly from high levels in the short term.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>10 Thai Steel Associations urge government to tighten regulations</title><link>https://www.nationthailand.com/business/manufacturing/40059913</link><description>Ten Thai Steel Industry Associations are urging the government to enforce strict TIS standards before allowing induction furnace steel factories to reopen, prioritizing public safety amid low capacity utilization. They presented data to the Industry Minister proposing structural changes and confirm no market shortages or price hikes have occurred since closures. Factories must adopt refining processes like Ladle Furnace and gain approval to resume operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Worthington Steel Named a 2025 Supplier of the Year by Schaeffler Group USA Inc.</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251124926350/en/Worthington-Steel-Named-a-2025-Supplier-of-the-Year-by-Schaeffler-Group-USA-Inc.</link><description>Worthington Steel received Schaeffler's 2025 Supplier of the Year award for operational excellence, innovation, and collaboration in advancing sustainable motion technology. The company specializes in carbon flat-roll steel processing, electrical steel laminations, and value-added solutions like galvanizing and lightweighting to drive steel toward a more sustainable future. This recognition highlights Worthington's role in building resilient supply chains and supporting customers' strategic sustainability goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>New roadmap shows how to cut a surprisingly big source of emissions</title><link>https://www.japantimes.co.jp/environment/2025/12/17/climate-change/electrification-emissions-cut-roadmap/</link><description>A new University of California at Santa Barbara report outlines electrification strategies for the U.S. industrial sector, the third-largest source of carbon emissions, including steel production. Electrifying overlooked industries like steel, cement, ethanol, and others could reduce emissions by 26% by 2050, equivalent to about 1 billion tons from 2023 levels. The roadmap emphasizes ready-made climate solutions beyond high-profile sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On December 17, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103675604/</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged 111,900-118,700 yuan/mt, averaging 115,300 yuan/mt, up 550 yuan/mt from previous day. This reflects daily price assessment amid ongoing market activity.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] On December 17, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103675834/SMM:-High-grade-NPI-Price-Dips-Market-Sentiment-Factor-Declines-on-Dec-17</link><description>SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI was 885 yuan/nickel unit (ex-factory, tax included), down 1.5% on December 17. Market sentiment declined, impacting high-grade nickel pig iron pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>EV giants' supply chains tied to nickel mining damage in PH</title><link>https://thephilbiznews.com/2025/12/17/ev-giants-supply-chains-tied-to-nickel-mining-damage-in-ph/</link><description>A Global Witness investigation links nickel mining in the Philippines, the world's largest raw nickel exporter, to deforestation, river pollution, and food insecurity in Cantilan, Surigao del Sur. Nickel ore from Marcventures Mining traces to Chinese traders supplying battery makers for Tesla, Volkswagen, Mercedes-Benz, BMW, and Audi. The report highlights risks in EV supply chains despite no alleged legal breaches.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to 2,902.40 USD/T on December 17, 2025, up 0.72% from the previous day, with a 4.07% increase over the past month and 14.81% year-over-year. UK aluminum futures hovered around $2,870 per tonne near a one-month high, supported by improving demand prospects, tight global supply, and China's stimulus measures against its property crisis.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[SMM Aluminum Express] Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Down 12,56 mt WoW on Dec 18</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103678358/SMM:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Down-1256-mt-WoW-on-Dec-18</link><description>Domestic secondary aluminum ingot inventory decreased by 12,56 mt week-over-week on December 18, 2025. SMM expects aluminum prices to mainly hover at highs in the short term.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>U.S. Recycled Steel Prices Rise in December 2025 After Subdued Period</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/metal-recycling/u.s.-recycled-steel-prices-rise-in-december-2025-after-subdued-period-2025-12-17/98018</link><description>Davis Index data showed U.S. recycled steel bids rose in December after a subdued May–November period, with prime grades up about $10/ton and some shredded and heavy melting scrap up $20/ton versus November; export prices for No.1/No.2 HMS cargoes from New York to Turkey climbed from roughly $305/ton in early November to about $331 by Dec. 10. Analysts note an oversupply of billets and slabs from China tempering activity in Turkey and India, while measures in the EU and other markets have tried to limit low-cost Chinese exports.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Correction to EU flat steel price assessments on December 17</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/correction-to-eu-flat-steel-price-assessments-on-december-17/</link><description>Fastmarkets issued a correction to several EU flat-steel domestic price assessments published for Dec. 17, adjusting cold-rolled coil and galvanized coil ranges (e.g., cold-rolled coil ex-works Southern Europe corrected to €730–750/ton). The notice updates Fastmarkets’ pricing database and invites market participants to provide feedback or price submissions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Dynamics forecasts Q4 earnings of $1.65-$1.69 per share</title><link>https://au.investing.com/news/company-news/steel-dynamics-forecasts-q4-earnings-of-165169-per-share-93CH-4175435</link><description>Steel Dynamics issued Q4 2025 guidance of $1.65–$1.69 per diluted share, attributing weaker sequential profitability to lower average selling values and reduced volumes driven by seasonal demand and extended maintenance outages that cut production by ~140–150k tons. The company noted recent improvements in flat-rolled steel prices as import volumes declined, while recycling and fabrication segments faced lower seasonal shipments and softer ferrous pricing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 1.1 percent - week 51, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-11-percent-week-51-2025-1424937.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending December 13, 2025, reached 1.753 million net tons, up 1.1% from the previous week and 5.3% from the same week in 2024, with capacity utilization at 76.5%. Adjusted year-to-date production through December 13, 2025, was 85.881 million net tons at 76.8% capacity utilization, a 3.4% increase year-over-year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>India's iron ore production rises just 0.5% y-o-y in 8MFY'26 even as crude steel output jumps 11%</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5107310-indias-iron-ore-production-rises-just-05-y-o-y-in-8mfy26-even-as-crude-steel-output-jumps-11</link><description>India's iron ore production grew only 0.5% year-over-year in the first eight months of FY2026, lagging behind an 11% rise in crude steel output to 109.491 million tons, causing supply shortfalls and higher prices. JSW Steel saw a 32% drop to 11.2 million tons due to mine issues, while NMDC surged 21% to 31.5 million tons; industry groups call for policy changes to boost domestic supply.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 1.45% Higher at $5.3635 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512176530/comex-copper-settles-145-higher-at-53635-data-talk</link><description>Front‑month Comex copper for December delivery gained 7.65 cents per pound (1.45%) to settle at $5.3635, marking its largest one‑day dollar and percentage gain since Dec. 11, 2025; the piece notes copper is up roughly 34.6% year‑over‑year and remains below its 2025 high of $5.795 set in July 2025.[1] The report summarizes short‑term session performance, month‑to‑date and year‑to‑date moves and provides settlement‑price based statistics for market context.[1]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper steadies near multi‑month highs as demand from China and US supports prices</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>TradingEconomics reports copper futures around $5.35/lb, near multi‑month highs, supported by strong demand from China and the US—citing EV and energy infrastructure growth in China and AI‑driven investment in the US—while noting month and year gains of roughly 5–33% depending on the series.[3] The page also records a Dec. 16 note that copper rebounded on short covering and contract rollovers ahead of expiry, despite softer Chinese underlying data.[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper higher on potential mine shortfalls, risk‑on sentiment</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40397997/copper-higher-on-potential-mine-shortfalls-risk-on-sentiment</link><description>Business Recorder reports copper rose amid worries about potential mine shortfalls that spurred speculative buying, with the piece citing London‑based benchmark moves and general risk‑on market sentiment as drivers of the gains.[7] The article emphasizes supply concerns as a key near‑term influence on copper prices.[7]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto’s Nuton technology produces first copper</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2025/rio-tintos-nuton-technology-produces-first-copper</link><description>Rio Tinto announced that its Nuton copper-processing technology has produced its first copper product; the company says Nuton will deliver materially lower environmental impacts versus conventional processing, including up to 80% less water use and up to 60% lower greenhouse‑gas intensity. The release frames Nuton as a scalable, lower‑footprint processing route intended to reduce water and emissions footprints for future copper projects.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco &amp; Hexagon sign MoU on collaboration from CAS to autonomy</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2025/12/17/codelco-hexagon-sign-mou-on-collaboration-from-cas-to-autonomy/</link><description>Chilean state miner Codelco and technology group Hexagon signed a memorandum of understanding to collaborate across Codelco Automation System (CAS) and autonomy initiatives aimed at improving operational efficiency and safety in copper operations. The partnership focuses on digitalization, autonomy and remote‑operation technologies to advance productivity and sustainability in large‑scale copper mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Climate‑friendly metals from deep‑sea ores</title><link>https://www.mpg.de/25794327/1127-eifo-sustainable-metals-from-deep-sea-mining-152925-x</link><description>Max Planck researchers described a process reported in Science Advances for extracting copper, nickel and cobalt from deep‑sea manganese nodules using smelting and hydrogen reduction; the method reportedly reduces CO2 emissions by over 90% (when using green hydrogen) and cuts energy use by nearly 20% compared with conventional carbon‑based reduction. The team frames deep‑sea ore processing as a potentially lower‑impact source of metals needed for electrification, while noting broader environmental considerations of seabed mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Prices Supported By Demand From EVs, Construction &amp; Renewable Energy Sectors</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NydAVFdv9Fc</link><description>Aluminum prices are being supported by strong demand from electric vehicles (EVs), construction, and renewable energy sectors. The video discusses current market dynamics driving these trends.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Aluminium scales Lanjigarh Refinery to 5 MTPA</title><link>https://news.webindia123.com/news/Articles/India/20251218/4395720.html</link><description>Vedanta Aluminium, India's largest producer, has scaled its Lanjigarh Refinery to 5 million tonnes per annum capacity. This expansion marks a key milestone in the company's growth and bolsters India's self-reliance in aluminium production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[SMM Aluminum Express] Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Down 1,256 mt WoW on Dec 18</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103678358/SMM:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Down-1256-mt-WoW-on-Dec-18</link><description>SMM statistics show social inventory of secondary aluminum ingots in China's mainstream consumption areas at 53,400 mt on December 18, down 1,256 mt week-on-week. This continues a slight destocking trend in the secondary aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US hot-rolled bar exports down 7.0 percent in August 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-hot-rolled-bar-exports-down-70-percent-in-august-2025-1425168.htm</link><description>SteelOrbis reports U.S. hot-rolled bar (rebar) export volumes fell year-on-year in August 2025, with rebar imports also notably lower in that month; the article is part of the site’s ongoing steel-news feed covering trade flows and market movements relevant to supply and price dynamics. The item highlights trade-volume changes that feed into broader pricing and market trend analysis.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Indian steelmakers face slower export outlook as new orders fade</title><link>https://indiaseatradenews.com/indian-steelmakers-face-slower-export-outlook-as-new-orders-fade/</link><description>Indian steelmakers are facing a slower export outlook due to fading new orders. Steel production in the country grew by 6% amid these challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Indian steel exports expected to moderate as global orders dry up</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/steel/indian-steel-exports-expected-to-moderate-as-global-orders-dry-up-elara-capital/amp_articleshow/126032627.cms</link><description>Indian steel exports are expected to moderate in coming months as global orders dry up, according to Elara Capital. This follows slower growth in overseas demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Glencore Acquires Peruvian Copper Project, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103676980/Glencore-Acquires-Peruvian-Copper-Project-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>SMM reports LME copper opened around $11,715/mt, fluctuated intraday and closed at $11,742.5/mt (up ~1.06%), with ample spot supply and average transactions noted on the spot market while end‑of‑year demand was weak; the note expects the price center to continue moving higher today and also highlights Glencore’s acquisition of a Peruvian copper project.[2] The bulletin also details domestic Chinese spot/import premiums, secondary copper indicators and macro commentary including Fed survey and Governor Waller remarks affecting expectations for rate cuts.[2]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Dec. 18</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20251218/044f1fd1ee064a8da1149293c1996436/c.html</link><description>Xinhua’s price snapshot at 0200 GMT lists copper at $5.36 per pound as part of a wider metals price update, providing a concise market quote to gauge intraday levels across exchanges.[4] The brief release is a data update rather than a narrative market analysis.[4]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Metals surge as rate‑cut hopes rise</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/18/metals-surge-as-rate-cut-hopes-rise/</link><description>ShareCafe reports a broad base‑metals rally led by copper, driven by rising expectations for interest‑rate cuts and signals of tightening supply; the article highlights strong Chinese import figures and US AI infrastructure investment as demand drivers, while noting market participants are watching upcoming US economic data for Fed policy direction.[5] It frames the rally within broader precious‑ and base‑metals moves and commentary from ANZ on rate cuts benefiting the sector.[5]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 18, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103678257/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price reached 113,100-120,100 yuan/mt on December 18, with an average of 116,600 yuan/mt, marking an increase of 1,300 yuan/mt from the previous day. This uptick reflects recent market movements in refined nickel pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Govt to revise nickel benchmark pricing, cobalt to face royalties: APNI</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/govt-to-revise-nickel-benchmark-pricing-cobalt-to-face-royalties-apni</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources plans to revise the nickel benchmark price formula in early 2026, introducing royalties on associated minerals like cobalt. APNI supports this, noting it could generate up to US$600 million in state revenue despite cobalt's low content in nickel ore, while urging focus on associated minerals over raising primary nickel royalties.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>