<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:17:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>3 ASX copper shares soaring amid 28% surge in commodity price this year</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/11/11/3-asx-copper-shares-soaring-amid-28-surge-in-commodity-price-this-year/</link><description>ASX copper shares are benefiting from a 28% surge in the commodity price this year to US$5.08 per pound on Tuesday, driven by higher demand amid the global energy transition. Copper has been supported by its designation as a critical material for the US economy and national security, as well as a weaker US dollar.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>ARENA commits $25.3 million to continue SunDrive's copper solar cell breakthrough</title><link>https://arena.gov.au/news/arena-commits-25-3-million-to-continue-sundrives-copper-solar-cell-breakthrough/</link><description>Australia’s ARENA has committed $25.3 million to advance SunDrive’s copper metallisation technology for solar cells, aiming to provide a silver-free alternative amid rising silver prices. This investment supports scaling up production of copper-based solar technology, contributing to clean energy innovation.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Collapse Forces Market Repricing as Oversupply Weak Demand Challenge Producers</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-price-collapse-forces-market-repricing-as-oversupply-weak-demand-challenge-producers</link><description>The nickel market is undergoing severe structural adjustment with prices collapsing to around US$15,000 per tonne in mid-2025 due to oversupply and weak demand. Macroeconomic factors such as US dollar strength and tariffs on imports from major producers like Indonesia and Russia are adding complexity, driving supply chain realignment and creating distinct pricing mechanisms based on source jurisdiction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 11, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 119,400-123,200 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103614036/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 119,400 to 123,200 yuan per metric ton on November 11, with an average price of 121,300 yuan/mt, marking a slight increase of 100 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Sulphate Daily Review] November 11 Nickel Salt Prices Slightly Declined</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103614820/%5BSMM-Nickel-Sulphate-Daily-Review%5D-November-11-Nickel-Salt-Prices-Slightly-Declined</link><description>On November 11, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price was 28,285 yuan/mt, with a slight decline in the quotation range for battery-grade nickel sulphate.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price hikes slightly on Nov 11, remaining stable</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/NewsItem/130109</link><description>The international nickel price remained stable on November 11, with the three-month futures price on the London Metal Exchange (LME) slightly rising, reflecting a steady market condition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries targets US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-targets-us-1-billion-ebitda-by-2026</link><description>Australia-listed nickel miner and processor Nickel Industries Limited aims to achieve US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026, signaling strong growth ambitions amid current market conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries targets US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-targets-us-1-billion-ebitda-by-2026</link><description>Nickel Industries aims to achieve US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026, reflecting growth ambitions in the nickel sector. The company is expanding production capacity amid strong demand for nickel, particularly for battery and stainless steel applications.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S.A. Announces Share Buyback Reaching 5.01% of Voting Rights</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/story/news/29731024/tenaris-sa-announces-share-buyback-reaching-501-of-voting-rights</link><description>Tenaris announced that the company is expected to report earnings on November 11, 2025, before market open. This earnings report serves as a clear catalyst for traders and investors.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>US flat steel pricing recovers previous weekly dip with steady November scrap, HRC futures rally</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-prices/steel-prices-market-analyses/flats-and-slab/us-flat-steel-pricing-recovers-previous-weekly-dip-with-steady-november-scrap-hrc-futures-rally-1418865.htm</link><description>US flat steel prices rebounded after a recent dip, supported by bullish November scrap pricing and steel futures. Market movements show cautious outlooks with mixed price changes in various regions, including stable or slightly down ex-China HRC prices and shifts in Turkey's import HRC segment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMU Price Ranges: Sheet and plate products inch higher</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/11/smu-price-ranges-sheet-and-plate-products-inch-higher/</link><description>Sheet and plate steel prices increased by $5-15 per short ton, reaching multi-month highs. Hot-rolled coil prices rose for the fifth consecutive week to $830/st, cold rolled steel prices hit the highest average since July, and galvanized and plate prices also saw notable gains amid cautious buyer sentiment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Why copper is 'a ticking time bomb for explosive price action'</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/marketwatch/2025111191/why-copper-is-a-ticking-time-bomb-for-explosive-price-action</link><description>Copper prices have dropped approximately 15% from record highs achieved less than four months ago, though tariff uncertainty continues to impact the market. The real growth driver for copper demand is AI data centers, which are expected to consume 6.7% to 12% of total U.S. electricity by 2028, compared to 4.4% in 2023. Global copper markets are likely to remain dislocated until final tariff decisions are made, which will limit downside pressure on prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why copper is 'a ticking time bomb for explosive price action'</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/marketwatch/2025111191/why-copper-is-a-ticking-time-bomb-for-explosive-price-action</link><description>The global copper market may face a 30% supply shortfall by 2035 due to mining challenges and rising demand, especially from AI data centers. Despite recent price drops, tariffs and supply-demand imbalances keep copper prices supported, with market dislocations expected until tariff decisions are finalized.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Japan’s JX, partners to merge Mitsubishi’s refined copper unit into Pan Pacific</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/japans-jx-partners-to-merge-mitsubishi-materials-refined-copper-unit-into-pan-pacific/</link><description>Japan’s JX Advanced Metals and partners plan to integrate Mitsubishi Materials’ copper concentrates procurement and refined copper sales into Pan Pacific Copper to boost profitability amid deteriorating conditions in copper concentrate procurement and smelting margins. JX may cut copper production by tens of thousands of tons in fiscal 2025 and reduce smelting capacity by March.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Historic 2025 Rally: A Global Economy in the Red Metal's Grip</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-11-11-coppers-historic-2025-rally-a-global-economy-in-the-red-metals-grip</link><description>The STOXX Global Copper Miners index surged 55% in 2025, driven by heightened earnings expectations and green transition demand. The article discusses strategic pivots needed across mining, manufacturing, and recycling sectors, with the recycling industry presenting significant opportunities for expanded capacity and technological advancements in secondary copper recovery.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>$25.3 million finance to advance SunDrive copper solar cell technology</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/2025/11/11/25-3-million-finance-to-advance-sundrive-copper-solar-cell-technology/</link><description>The Australian Renewable Energy Agency committed an additional $25.3 million to SunDrive to scale up its copper metallisation technology for solar cells. The innovation replaces expensive silver with more abundant and cheaper copper while achieving higher cell and module efficiencies, supporting global decarbonisation efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Project boosts ethically responsible exploration of critical raw materials</title><link>https://phys.org/news/2025-11-boosts-ethically-responsible-exploration-critical.html</link><description>The VECTOR project, coordinated by the Helmholtz Institute Freiberg, developed efficient and low-impact exploration methods for critical raw materials including copper across Europe. The research integrates geosciences with data and social sciences to enable responsible supply of raw materials while addressing environmental and social concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel Prices Dropped Slightly on November 11</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103614704/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-dropped-slightly-on-November-11-as-a-US-Fed-governor-suggested-continuing-to-cut-interest-rates-in-December</link><description>On November 11, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 119,400–123,000 yuan/mt, averaging 121,300 yuan/mt, up 100 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. The slight increase came amid expectations of continued interest rate cuts by the US Fed.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Greenland grants 30-year permit to EU-backed Molybdenum mine involving Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://www.mining.com/greenland-grants-30-year-permit-to-eu-backed-molybdenum-mine/</link><description>Greenland Resources secured a 30-year permit for the Malmbjerg molybdenum project, supported by the EU and involving Cogne Acciai Speciali through off-take agreements. The mine will supply critical molybdenum used to strengthen steel, benefiting sectors like aerospace and energy.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Forget Rare Earths: Aluminum Is the Metal of the Moment</title><link>https://www.streetwisereports.com/article/2025/11/11/forget-rare-earths-aluminum-is-the-metal-of-the-moment.html</link><description>Aluminum is trading near a three-year high, close to US$2,900 per metric ton, driven by supply constraints in China and recovering global demand. Investment positioning has turned strongly bullish, with analysts forecasting potential supply deficits in 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Surge Amid U.S. Government Reopening Hopes</title><link>https://www.gurufocus.com/news/3198766/aluminum-prices-surge-amid-us-government-reopening-hopes</link><description>Aluminum prices on the London Metal Exchange surged 1.7% to $2,895 per ton, fueled by optimism over a potential U.S. government reopening. This positive sentiment has contributed to recent price strength in the aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Forget Rare Earths Aluminum Is the Metal of the Moment</title><link>https://www.streetwisereports.com/article/2025/11/11/forget-rare-earths-aluminum-is-the-metal-of-the-moment.html</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged to their highest since May 2022 due to supply constraints in China and renewed optimism for global demand after a tentative US-China trade truce. China has imposed production limits tightening supply, while demand rebounds in construction, automotive, and consumer goods sectors. The market expects higher shipment volumes and notes aluminum demand could grow 40% by 2030 driven by infrastructure and energy efficiency trends.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Dynamics Inc. Promotes Matt Bell to President of OmniSource</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>Steel Dynamics Inc. has promoted Matt Bell to president of OmniSource, the company's metals recycling platform. This leadership change reflects the industry's growing emphasis on recycling and sustainable steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Primetals Technologies, Deutsche Bank Extend ESG Initiative and Set Gender Diversity Goal</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>Primetals Technologies and Deutsche Bank have extended their agreement linking financial trading to sustainability, social responsibility, and gender diversity goals. This partnership demonstrates the steel industry's commitment to environmental and social governance standards.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>FNI income triples to P1.5B as prices climb</title><link>https://tribune.net.ph/2025/11/11/fni-income-triples-to-p15b-as-prices-climb</link><description>Filipino Nickel Industry (FNI) reported a tripling of income to P1.5 billion, driven by a 16.6% revenue increase due to higher average realized nickel ore prices amid strong demand and tight supply conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Glencore Cuts Century Aluminum Stake in $276M Deal</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/glencore-divestment-century-aluminum-2025/</link><description>Glencore has reduced its shareholding in Century Aluminum through a $276 million strategic block trade, with implications for U.S. domestic aluminum production capacity and supply chain resilience. The transaction highlights evolving ownership structures in the critical domestic aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel prices rises 0.6–2.5 pct in October 2025</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025-11-12:newsml_BER4Brcjs:0-steel-prices-rises-0-6-2-5-pct-in-october-2025-dosm-screen/</link><description>The unit price index of steel increased by 0.6 to 2.5 percent in October 2025 compared to September 2025, indicating a general upward trend in steel prices during that period.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Surging Copper Price Drives Historic 2025 Rally</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-prices-2025-supply-demand-record/</link><description>Copper prices have climbed to record levels of US$11,200 per tonne on the London Metal Exchange in 2025, with a recent pullback to approximately US$10,800 per tonne. JPMorgan Chase forecasts copper reaching US$12,000 per tonne in Q1 2026, representing approximately 11% additional upside, driven by widening global supply deficits and accelerating energy transition infrastructure investment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Surging copper price shines light on BHP shares and 3 other ASX 200 mining stocks</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/11/12/surging-copper-price-shines-light-on-bhp-shares-and-3-other-asx-200-mining-stocks/</link><description>Copper has risen 27% since the start of 2025, reaching record highs of US$11,200 per tonne before pulling back to US$10,800 per tonne. JPMorgan Chase's head of base and precious metals research predicts copper will reach US$12,000 per tonne in Q1 2026, which could benefit ASX 200 mining stocks with significant copper exposure like BHP Group.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Commodities Lift as US Dollar Weakens</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/12/commodities-lift-as-us-dollar-weakens/</link><description>Copper prices gained support from a weaker US dollar and improved market risk appetite following expectations that the US government shutdown would conclude. The premium on US to LME copper has climbed back to approximately US$1,000 per tonne, driven by expectations that the Commerce Department will decide next year on phased tariffs of 15% increasing to 30% on refined copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price falls on Fed uncertainty, Codelco supply relief</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-falls-on-fed-uncertainty-codelco-supply-relief/</link><description>Copper prices dropped as much as 2.4% amid broader declines in base metals, with three-month copper trading at roughly US$10,855 per tonne by 1 p.m. ET. The decline was driven by Federal Reserve uncertainty and supply relief from Codelco.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Star Copper dives into unlocking Copper Creek's potential</title><link>https://mining.com.au/star-copper-dives-into-unlocking-copper-creeks-potential/</link><description>Star Copper's 2025 exploration campaign in British Columbia has advanced the Copper Creek target towards identifying a large-scale porphyry copper deposit. The company has completed soil sampling, mapping, and started first-pass drilling to validate their structural-geochemical model, aiming to extend drilling in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price on November 12</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103617049/</link><description>On November 12, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 118,400 to 122,500 yuan/mt, with an average of 120,450 yuan/mt, down 850 yuan/mt from the previous day. The price decline reflects ongoing market adjustments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/492981</link><description>Nickel futures dropped to 15,078.00 USD/ton, the lowest level since September 2025, as oversupply from Indonesia continues to pressure prices. LME inventories have reached record highs, with Chinese-origin nickel now making up 65% of stocks.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>PE eyes BHP's Nickel West as China tightens rare earth grip</title><link>https://www.marketsgroup.org/news/pe-eyes-bhps-nickel-west-as-china-tightens-rare-earth-grip</link><description>China's tightening control over rare earth exports has renewed global interest in nickel, especially in Australia. BHP's Nickel West, running at a loss, is up for sale with private equity and local miners showing interest. Japanese firms have also acquired stakes in Australian nickel projects aiming for competitive production costs.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel ore stockpiles rise as smelters cut output, import from Philippines</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-ore-stockpiles-rise-as-smelters-cut-output-import-from-philippines</link><description>Indonesia's nickel ore stockpiles are increasing as domestic smelters reduce production and boost imports from the Philippines. This shift reflects adjustments in supply amid changing production dynamics in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Cables and Systems to close Schuylkill Haven facility</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/PlvOdwvbSh4</link><description>Prysmian Cables and Systems announced the closure of its Schuylkill Haven facility, which will affect 150 employees.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian shares rise as Italian cable maker seen as winner amid US copper tariffs</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/prysmian-shares-rise-as-italian-cable-maker-seen-as-winner-amid-us-copper-tariffs-4127785</link><description>Prysmian shares rose as much as 4% on expectations that the world's largest cable maker's large US business could benefit from US tariffs on copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>European Aluminum Duty-Paid Premium Hits $324 Per Ton</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/european-aluminum-premium-2025-dynamics/</link><description>The European aluminum duty-paid premium reached $324 per metric ton, up from a recent low, driven by supply disruptions, carbon tax preparations, and freight cost pressures. The premium hit $330 on November 3, the highest since late January, signaling renewed upward pressure on regional pricing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump's Tariffs Send US Aluminum Prices to Record Highs</title><link>https://oilprice.com/Energy/Energy-General/Trumps-Tariffs-Send-US-Aluminum-Prices-to-Record-Highs.html</link><description>US all-in aluminum prices hit a record $4,816 per ton, nearly double 2023 lows, due to sharply tightening inventories and Trump administration tariffs. The Midwest premium surged, reflecting significant cost increases for US buyers.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Prices Are On The Rise As US Premium At Record High</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZdDnECeL4Zs</link><description>Aluminum prices are up 13% in 2025, with the US premium hitting record highs. China reiterated its commitment to preventing overcapacity in metal production, supporting global price increases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa Says High US Aluminum Prices Offset Trump Tariff Costs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/alcoa-sees-tariff-costs-on-aluminum-shipments-continuing-to-rise/</link><description>Alcoa reported that higher US aluminum prices have offset the increased costs from Trump’s tariffs on Canadian aluminum. The company expects further tariff-related costs but sees domestic price strength helping to mitigate the impact.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits Three-Year High as US-China Truce Boosts Market Confidence</title><link>https://www.channelchek.com/news-channel/aluminum-hits-three-year-high-as-us-china-truce-boosts-market-confidence</link><description>Aluminum prices surged to their highest level since May 2022, driven by supply constraints in China and renewed optimism following a tentative US-China trade truce. The rally reflects the market’s sensitivity to geopolitical developments and production policies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Premium for Aluminum in the US Spot Market Has Hit a Record High</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103615477/</link><description>The US spot market aluminum premium reached a record high, with buyers paying $4,792 per ton. The surge is attributed to high import tariffs and tight supply conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rod Production Cut Wave Hits - Nearly 800,000 MT of Capacity Undergoes Concentrated Maintenance Shutdowns in November</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103617727/aluminum-rod-production-cut-wave-hits-nearly-800000-mt-of-capacity-undergoes-concentrated-maintenance-shutdowns-in-november-smm-analysis</link><description>China's aluminum rod production declined to 381,000 mt in October 2025, with operating rates falling to 53.56%. Production cuts affecting nearly 792,000 mt of capacity emerged in November across multiple regions, with Inner Mongolia leading reductions at 252,000 mt, representing approximately 10% of total sample capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>European Aluminum Premium Soars to Nine-Month High of $324 Per Tonne Amid Supply Disruptions and CBAM Anticipation</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-11-12-european-aluminum-premium-soars-to-nine-month-high-of-324tonne-amid-supply-disruptions-and-cbam-anticipation</link><description>The European aluminum duty-paid premium reached $324 per metric ton in November 2025, marking a nine-month high driven by supply disruptions including the Grundartangi smelter outage in Iceland and front-loading of imports ahead of CBAM implementation. European downstream manufacturers in automotive, construction, and packaging sectors face significantly increased input costs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>European Aluminum Duty-Paid Premium Hits $324 Per Ton</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/european-aluminum-premium-2025-dynamics/</link><description>The European aluminum duty-paid premium currently stands at $324 per metric ton, with a peak of $330 reached on November 3, the highest level since late January. The Grundartangi smelter in Iceland experienced a critical electrical equipment failure in late October, reducing production capacity by approximately two-thirds or 213,000 tons annually.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Prices Are On The Rise As US Premium At Record High</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZdDnECeL4Zs</link><description>Aluminum prices have risen 13% in 2025 with LME prices near three-year highs, driven by supply concerns and China's reiteration of preventing overcapacity in metal production. Reports suggest the aluminum market faces a deficit for the current year and potentially 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SS Breaks Downward Through 12,500 yuan/mt, Stainless Steel Spot Trading Weak with Insufficient Market Confidence</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Finished-Steel</link><description>Stainless steel futures broke below 12,500 yuan/mt, reaching an intraday low of 12,460 yuan/mt, driven by further declines in SHFE nickel and weak stainless steel fundamentals. The SS2601 contract was quoted at 12,560 yuan/mt, down 5 yuan/mt from the previous trading day, with market sentiment turning bearish.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel fell to 3,038 CNY/T on November 12, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices declined to 3,038 CNY/T, down 0.16% from the previous day. Over the past month, steel prices have fallen 0.69%, and are down 7.09% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel fell to 844.05 USD/T on November 12, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) steel fell to 844.05 USD/T, down 0.93% from the previous day. Over the past month, HRC steel prices have risen 3.69%, and are up 23.22% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>European carbon prices exceeded €80/t in November</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>European carbon prices surpassed the €80 per ton threshold in November, reflecting market conditions affecting steel production costs in the region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Flat Steel Market Size to Hit USD 1,157.84 Billion by 2034</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/12/3186658/0/en/Flat-Steel-Market-Size-to-Hit-USD-1-157-84-Billion-by-2034.html</link><description>The global flat steel market is projected to grow from USD 724.33 billion in 2025 to USD 1,157.84 billion by 2034. Major developments include AM/NS India's capacity expansion with a new 7 MTPA integrated flat steel mill in Andhra Pradesh, and the industry's significant transition toward low-carbon steel production through electric arc furnaces and hydrogen-based technologies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/copper-cables-antitrust-launches-investigation-into-alleged-cartel-prysmian-and-nexans-stock-market-drops/</link><description>The Italian Antitrust Authority has opened an investigation into major low voltage copper cable manufacturers in Italy, including Prysmian, for alleged price fixing since 2005. Inspections were conducted at company offices and distributors, impacting Prysmian's stock price negatively. Analysts believe the investigation will have a negligible impact on Prysmian due to the small market share of low voltage copper cables in its revenue.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium price dips slightly to USD 2,878.55/t amid mixed market signals</title><link>https://www.balajialuminium.com/aluminium-price-dips-slightly-to-usd-2878-55-t-amid-mixed-market-signals-12-november-2025/</link><description>Aluminum futures were quoted at around USD 2,878.55 per ton on November 12, 2025, marking a slight daily drop of 0.15%. The market remains volatile with mixed signals, but prices are still near recent highs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SSAB gains SEA funds for steel mill</title><link>https://www.globaltrailermag.com/ssab-gains-sea-funds-for-steel-mill/</link><description>SSAB has received approximately €28.67 million in funding from the Swedish Energy Agency to complete processes at its €4.5 billion electrified steel mill in Luleå, Sweden. The funding will support the development of technical solutions for electrification and energy efficiency in finishing processes, replacing natural gas and propane usage. The project is expected to reduce SSAB's carbon dioxide emissions by approximately 90 percent.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Firms Up as China Tackles Overcapacity</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel/news/496605</link><description>Steel rebar futures climbed to around CNY 3,100 per ton following China's announcement of new measures to curb steelmaking capacity in key regions. Beijing proposed a stricter capacity swap plan that would prohibit adding new steel capacity in key areas to rebalance supply and demand and improve profit margins.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Oman Poised to Lead Global Green Steel Revolution: IEEFA Report</title><link>https://solarquarters.com/2025/11/13/oman-poised-to-lead-global-green-steel-revolution-ieefa-report/</link><description>An IEEFA report highlights Oman's potential to become a leader in green steel production, leveraging its integrated steelmaking supply chain and renewable energy resources. The report emphasizes that transitioning from gas-based direct reduced iron production to green hydrogen is essential for Oman to capture the green premium in global markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Iron Process Revolutionising Zero-Carbon Steel Manufacturing</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/green-iron-technology-zero-carbon-2025/</link><description>Green iron technology uses clean electricity and hydrogen gas instead of coal and natural gas to convert iron ore into high-grade steel products. The process can reduce steelmaking emissions by over 90% compared to traditional methods while maintaining cost competitiveness. Market projections suggest 15-25% of global steel production could convert to green iron processes by 2035, with potential capacity reaching 50-100 million tonnes annually.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Taseko Florence Copper Production: Arizona ISCR Mining 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/florence-copper-mining-difference-2025/</link><description>Taseko Florence Copper has achieved major construction milestones in 2025, with the solvent extraction and electrowinning plant substantially completed in September and wellfield operations commencing in mid-October. The project is now ramping up production using in-situ recovery technology, with a phased approach to ensure sustainability and efficiency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Taseko Reports Stronger Copper Output, Nears First Production at Florence Copper 2025</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/taseko-reports-stronger-copper-output-nears-first-production-at-florence-copper-2025-11-13</link><description>Taseko's Gibraltar mine saw increased copper production, reaching 27.6 million pounds, including 895,000 pounds of cathode, as mining moved into higher-grade areas. The company is nearing first production at its Florence Copper project, marking a significant milestone for the company.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Taseko Announces Improved Third Quarter Financial and Operational Results</title><link>https://tasekomines.com/investors/news/taseko-announces-improved-third-quarter-financial-and-operational-results</link><description>Taseko reported improved copper production for the third quarter, with expectations for 2025 output between 100 and 105 million pounds. The company anticipates further increases in copper head grades and recoveries in the fourth quarter.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>DPM Metals Announces Preliminary Third Quarter Production Results</title><link>https://dpmmetals.com/news-media/news-releases/dpm-metals-announces-preliminary-third-quarter-pro-11525/</link><description>DPM Metals reported increased gold and copper production in the third quarter, with both mines on track to meet 2025 guidance. The company highlighted the integration of the Vareš asset and its growth potential for copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Asia Q3 profit jumps to P3.09B on higher ore prices, exports</title><link>https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2025/11/13/711926/nickel-asia-q3-profit-jumps-to-p3-09b-on-higher-ore-prices-exports/</link><description>Nickel Asia Corp. reported a more than twofold increase in attributable net income for Q3, reaching P3.09 billion, driven by higher nickel ore prices and strong export performance. The company's operating mines sold 13.89 million WMT of nickel ore in the first nine months, with exports of saprolite and limonite ore totaling 8.32 million WMT at an average price of $37.52 per WMT, marking a 51.66% increase in export prices. The company expects nickel ore price tightness to persist as Indonesia enforces stricter policies on production permits.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 15,025.25 USD/T on November 13, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 15,025.25 USD/T on November 13, 2025, down 0.13% from the previous day, with prices down 0.53% over the past month and 4.50% compared to the same time last year. Nickel futures in the UK fell to $15,000 per tonne in November, trading at the lower end of their narrow range since June and significantly underperforming other base metals amid views of an oversupplied market. The decline is attributed to ample output from Indonesia's over-expanded nickel sector following the country's ore export ban in 2020.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Asia Q3 profit jumps to P3.09B on higher ore prices, exports</title><link>https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2025/11/13/711926/nickel-asia-q3-profit-jumps-to-p3-09b-on-higher-ore-prices-exports/</link><description>Nickel Asia Corporation (NAC) reported a 10.95% increase in share price following a Q3 profit of P3.09 billion, driven by higher nickel ore prices and exports. The company sold 13.89 million WMT of nickel ore in the first nine months, with export prices rising 51.66% amid tight supply due to stricter Indonesian production permit policies. NAC is also diversifying into copper and gold through its joint venture and expanding renewable energy projects.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On November 13, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103618599/</link><description>The Shanghai Metals Market (SMM) reported that the #1 refined nickel price ranged from 118,600 to 122,700 yuan per metric ton on November 13, with an average price of 120,650 yuan/mt, marking a slight increase of 200 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel mine, hydroelectric project to be added to major projects list</title><link>https://energynow.ca/2025/11/nickel-mine-hydroelectric-project-to-be-added-to-major-projects-list/</link><description>Canada plans to add the Crawford Nickel Project in Ontario and a hydroelectric project in Nunavut to its major projects list, highlighting the growing importance of nickel mining and renewable energy infrastructure in the country.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alcoa says high US aluminum prices offset Trump tariff costs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/alcoa-sees-tariff-costs-on-aluminum-shipments-continuing-to-rise/</link><description>Alcoa reported that US tariffs on Canadian aluminum increased costs by $69 million compared to the previous quarter, but higher domestic aluminum prices have more than offset these tariff costs. The company expects tariff-related costs to rise further by $50 million in the current quarter, reflecting declining inventory and imports, while shipments from Canada to the US are returning to normal.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Linktour's 'Can-to-Car' Aluminum Tech Sets New Standard</title><link>https://www.openpr.com/news/4269924/linktour-s-can-to-car-aluminum-tech-sets-new-standard</link><description>Linktour has developed a proprietary WQAL Registered technology that uses post-consumer aluminum to minimize waste and energy consumption, significantly reducing the carbon footprint in vehicle manufacturing. Their all-aluminum monocoque body reduces vehicle weight by 45% compared to steel, enhancing performance and energy efficiency while promoting sustainability in EV production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>IEEFA: Oman a Frontrunner in the Green Steel Transition</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>A report from the Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis (IEEFA) indicates that Oman is positioned to become a global leader in the green iron and steel industry. The country is making significant progress in the transition toward sustainable steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel to Build DRI Plant on Big River Steel Works Campus</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>United States Steel Corporation confirmed plans to construct a direct reduced iron (DRI) plant on the Big River Steel Works campus in Osceola, Arkansas. This investment represents a significant step toward cleaner steel production methods.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel holds steady as U.S. government shutdown ends amid persistent market caution</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-holds-steady-as-us-government-shutdown-ends-amid-persistent-market-caution/157756</link><description>LME nickel prices remained steady following the end of the U.S. government shutdown, but market caution persists amid uncertain economic conditions. The cautious sentiment continues to influence nickel trading dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia limits new nickel permits to add value to production</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/indonesia-limits-new-nickel-permits-to-add-value-to-production/</link><description>Indonesia, the world's largest nickel producer, has stopped approving new permits for nickel plants producing certain intermediate products without plans for further processing. This move aims to push the industry up the value chain and address oversupply, potentially causing delays or cancellations of new projects. The regulation affects plants finishing after 2027 and emphasizes investment in downstream processing for electric vehicle battery materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Fathom Nickel expands Gochager Lake footprint</title><link>https://mining.com.au/fathom-nickel-expands-gochager-lake-footprint/</link><description>Fathom Nickel is advancing exploration at its Gochager Lake Project in Saskatchewan, Canada, aiming to establish a significant nickel district. Recent soil geochemistry and portable x-ray fluorescence results indicate expanding scale, with further assay results expected soon. Winter conditions favor upcoming drilling activities supported by infrastructure development like ice roads.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Homeland Nickel Enters Agreement with USA Company, Amplifying Exposure to Strategic Holdings</title><link>https://investingnews.com/homeland-nickel-enters-agreement-with-usa-company-amplifying-exposure-to-strategic-holdings/</link><description>Homeland Nickel Inc. announced the formation of Patriot Nickel Corp, a U.S.-based company aimed at building domestic nickel supply in Southern Oregon. Homeland will option key nickel properties to Patriot and receive a 20% equity stake, enhancing shareholder value and aligning with the 'America First' trend in critical mineral supply. The partnership is expected to facilitate regulatory progress and investor interest in the U.S. nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italian Expertise Fuels Prysmian Innovation</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/italian-expertise-fuels-prysmian-innovation</link><description>Prysmian is advancing its R&amp;D activities in Italy with over €5.5 million funding from Italian authorities for projects focused on high-voltage terrestrial and submarine transmission systems and renewable energy integration. The company is also involved in national initiatives like the Green New Deal and the RESTART Extended Partnership to drive innovation in energy and telecommunications.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Inert Anode Aluminium Technology: Revolutionary Breakthrough</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/aluminium-production-inert-anode-technology-2025/</link><description>Rio Tinto has successfully implemented a 450 kiloampere inert anode cell at its Alma smelter in Quebec, eliminating direct CO₂ emissions from aluminium production. This technology is a key part of Rio Tinto's decarbonisation strategy and is being scaled with a demonstration plant under construction at the Arvida smelter, promising a transformative impact on sustainable aluminium production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ELYSIS Hits Milestone: First Inert Anode Aluminum Cell</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/elysis-hits-milestone-first-inert-anode-1569913/</link><description>ELYSIS has started up a 450 kiloampere inert anode cell at Rio Tinto's Alma smelter, marking the first commercial-scale use of this technology that produces aluminium without direct carbon emissions. This breakthrough supports large-scale low-carbon aluminium production and is central to Rio Tinto's long-term decarbonization plans, with a demonstration plant underway at Arvida.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ball, Unilever show green aluminium can work</title><link>https://minesandmoney.com/news/industry/ball-unilever-show-green-aluminium-can-work</link><description>Ball and Unilever are using aluminium produced with Alcoa's ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology, which employs inert anode technology to eliminate greenhouse gas emissions. This collaboration combines low-carbon primary aluminium with high recycled content, representing a significant advancement in sustainable aluminium packaging and supply chain innovation.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Manufacturer unveils innovative product that could transform future brake calipers</title><link>https://www.thecooldown.com/green-tech/brembo-brake-calipers-recycled-aluminum/</link><description>Brembo has launched brake calipers made from 100% recycled aluminum, reducing lifecycle carbon emissions by 70%. After five years of R&amp;D, this innovation demonstrates that high-performance automotive components can be produced sustainably without compromising quality, marking a significant step in the industry's sustainability efforts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Revolutionizing Industries: The Rising Impact of Lightweight Metal Tubing</title><link>https://techbullion.com/revolutionizing-industries-the-rising-impact-of-lightweight-metal-tubing/</link><description>Lightweight aluminum-based metal tubing is driving industrial transformation by offering high strength-to-weight ratios that improve efficiency and sustainability in automotive, aerospace, and construction sectors. Innovations in low-carbon manufacturing and closed-loop recycling are enhancing environmental performance, supporting global sustainability goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Major step forward for emissions-free aluminium smelting</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/major-step-forward-for-emissions-free-aluminium-smelting-2025-11-14</link><description>ELYSIS is advancing aluminium production by replacing carbon anodes with inert materials that generate oxygen instead of greenhouse gases. This technology aims to revolutionize the industry by enabling emissions-free smelting, contributing significantly to global decarbonization efforts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Turkey billet prices increased in the second half of October, affecting imports and domestic supplies</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>In Turkey, billet prices rose in late October, impacting both domestic supplies and imports from Russia. However, Russian companies face limited price increases due to weak demand outside Turkey, and Turkish steel producers have struggled to raise rebar prices, limiting further cost increases for scrap and semi-finished products.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>NDRC: China's steel prices to rally in November</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103780-ndrc-chinas-steel-prices-to-rally-in-november</link><description>China's steel prices are expected to rebound in November amid cautious optimism among market participants. Recent reports indicate a rangebound rebar market with some softening, but overall bullish sentiment is supported by macroeconomic signals and capacity adjustments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>American rebar producers have raised prices by $60/t</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>American rebar producers have increased prices by $60 per ton, reflecting ongoing cost pressures and market dynamics. This price adjustment is part of broader trends in steel production and consumption observed globally.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Proposal to amend publication deadline for Germany, Italy steel scrap price assessments</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/proposal-to-amend-publication-deadline-for-germany-italy-steel-scrap-price-assessments/</link><description>Fastmarkets proposed changing the publication deadline for Germany and Italy domestic steel scrap price assessments from the second Friday to the final Friday of each month. This amendment aims to ensure all key market participants have finalized monthly prices before assessments are published.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices, Charts, Analysis &amp; Forecast</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper prices showed slight fluctuations with the LMEselect Copper 3 Month price at around $10,859/mt on November 14, 2025. Downstream procurement remains weak, but spot discounts for SHFE copper are unlikely to widen as delivery dates approach, keeping transactions near parity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper retreats on weak China data, US caution</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3WQ03C:0-copper-retreats-on-weak-china-data-us-caution/</link><description>Copper prices retreated after a four-session winning streak due to weak economic data from China raising demand concerns, alongside cautious investor sentiment in the US. This pullback reflects ongoing sensitivity of copper prices to global economic indicators.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Grasberg Mine Suspension Creates Major Copper Production Crisis</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/grasberg-underground-catastrophe-copper-supply-2025/</link><description>The Grasberg mine suspension has caused a significant disruption in copper production, with Freeport McMoRan reporting a 13.2% decline in Q3 2025 output compared to Q3 2024. The suspension could reduce 2025 copper production by approximately 262,000 metric tons, a 35% decrease from original forecasts, driving copper prices to 15-month highs of $10,485 per metric ton due to tightened supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>DPM Metals Reports Record Third Quarter 2025 Financial Results</title><link>https://dpmmetals.com/news-media/news-releases/dpm-metals-reports-record-third-quarter-2025-finan-11656/</link><description>DPM Metals reported strong copper production of 7.8 million pounds in Q3 2025, a 6% increase over Q3 2024, driven by higher ore volumes and copper grades. However, copper production for the first nine months of 2025 was 8% lower than 2024 due to lower grades and recoveries, consistent with the mine plan.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>American Pacific Announces Sale of Palmer Copper-Zinc VMS Project to Vizsla Copper</title><link>https://americanpacificmining.com/news-releases-2025/american-pacific-announces-sale-of-palmer-copper-zinc-vms-project-to-vizsla-copper/</link><description>American Pacific Mining sold its Palmer Copper-Zinc VMS Project to Vizsla Copper for $15 million in equity plus up to $15 million in milestone payments. The project is seen as a critical metals opportunity in Alaska, with Vizsla Copper planning to advance exploration and development in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Vizsla Copper to buy Palmer VMS project</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/11/14/news-nuggets/vizsla-copper-to-buy-palmer-vms-project/9359.html</link><description>Vizsla Copper announced the acquisition of the Palmer VMS project, a significant copper-zinc deposit in Alaska. The acquisition is expected to enhance Vizsla's portfolio of critical mineral assets and support year-round exploration activities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tivan Ltd News Today, Nov 14: Gold and Copper Discoveries Boost Timor</title><link>https://meyka.com/blog/tivan-ltd-news-today-nov-14-gold-and-copper-discoveries-boost-timor-1411/</link><description>Tivan Ltd announced significant gold and copper discoveries in Timor-Leste, marking an important development for the region's mining sector. These discoveries could enhance future copper production potential in the area.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fell sharply on November 14 as concerns over the US Fed's hawkish stance triggered cautious market sentiment</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103621463/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fell-sharply-on-November-14-as-concerns-over-the-US-Feds-hawkish-stance-triggered-cautious-market-sentiment</link><description>On November 14, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 119,600 yuan/mt, down 1,050 yuan/mt from the previous day. The decline was driven by market caution due to the US Federal Reserve's hawkish stance and uncertainty from divergent Fed officials' views on interest rates, pressuring nickel prices to remain weak in the near term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in November Period I</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103862-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-november-period-i</link><description>The Indonesia Nickel Miners Association announced benchmark prices for nickel ore for the first half of November 2025, with the reference price set at $15,075.33/wmt, down 0.44% from late October. Prices for various nickel grades also saw slight decreases compared to the previous period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/base-metals-investing/nickel-investing/nickel-forecast/</link><description>Nickel prices were volatile in the first half of 2025 but stabilized in Q3 amid ongoing oversupply concerns driven mainly by rapid production growth in Indonesia. Despite rising consumption, structural oversupply pressured prices, with a forecast of temporary price support due to seasonal output declines in the Philippines from October to early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 14, the price range for SMM #1 refined nickel was</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103621443/</link><description>The price range for SMM #1 refined nickel on November 14, 2025, was between 117,400 and 121,800 yuan per metric ton, averaging 119,600 yuan/mt, marking a decrease of 1,050 yuan/mt. This reflects current market pricing trends for refined nickel in China.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's Top Cable Maker Sees US Copper Tariff as Opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Prysmian, the world's largest copper cable maker, views the US copper tariff as an opportunity to strengthen its local supply chain and competitive position. The company benefits from sourcing copper domestically and is in close contact with US authorities regarding the tariff implementation.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>