<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 05:16:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Column: China steel exports surge but aluminum shipments slide</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/column-china-steel-exports-surge-but-aluminum-shipments-slide/</link><description>China's steel production is informally capped below last year's 1.005 billion metric tons, likely dipping below 1 billion tons in 2025 for the first time since 2019. Weak domestic demand due to a sluggish property sector has led mills to increase exports, which are on track to reach a record high of approximately 117 million tons in 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel declines as dollar rises on Fed rate outlook</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-declines-as-dollar-rises-on-fed-rate-outlook-47760</link><description>Nickel prices fell as the US dollar strengthened amid uncertainty over Federal Reserve policy and rate cuts. Goldman Sachs forecasts nickel prices to decline by 6% to $14,500 per metric ton by December 2026, reflecting cautious market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Peregrine Hydrogen and Tasmania Energy Metals Sign LOI for Nickel Processing Plant in Bell Bay</title><link>https://newshub.medianet.com.au/2025/12/peregrine-hydrogen-and-tasmania-energy-metals-sign-loi-for-nickel-processing-plant-in-bell-bay/132735/</link><description>Peregrine Hydrogen and Tasmania Energy Metals signed a Letter of Intent to develop a nickel processing plant in Bell Bay, Tasmania. This initiative aims to advance nickel processing capabilities, supporting sustainable supply chains and innovation in nickel technology.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's first AlN‑based high‑frequency transistor for post‑5G applications</title><link>https://group.ntt/en/newsrelease/2025/12/09/251209a.html</link><description>NTT reported the first demonstration of high‑frequency signal amplification using aluminum nitride (AlN)‑based transistors, showing millimeter‑wave power amplification with high Al composition (&gt;75%). While focused on AlN semiconductor technology rather than metallic aluminum, the announcement highlights aluminum‑compound advances relevant to energy‑efficient, high‑frequency electronics and future wireless infrastructure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper prices drop from record highs; Market awaits Fed policy</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/12/09/copper-prices-drop-from-record-highs-market-awaits-fed-policy</link><description>Report describes copper slipping from a record high amid market focus on upcoming US Fed policy and economic data, with benchmark three‑month LME copper quoted around $11,450/ton at one point while Shanghai contract moved lower; the report highlights investor attention on US payrolls and unemployment for Fed signals and records moves in other metals like silver and palladium.[2] It frames price dynamics as sensitive to rate expectations and Chinese demand indicators.[2]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Australia's biggest aluminium smelter gets promise of cheaper renewable power from feds and state</title><link>https://reneweconomy.com.au/australias-biggest-aluminium-smelter-gets-promise-of-cheaper-renewable-power-from-feds-and-state/</link><description>RenewEconomy reports that the Australian federal and NSW state governments have agreed support measures to keep the Tomago aluminium smelter operating amid high energy costs, securing more than 1,000 jobs and protecting production of up to 590,000 tonnes per year from the plant[3]. The article emphasizes that electricity is a major cost (about 40% of operating costs) for Tomago and that the support will underwrite new renewable generation, storage and transmission to reduce smelter power costs[3].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Affected by transportation disruptions in Xinjiang, social inventory — SMM Spot Aluminium</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103669167/%5BSMM-Spot-Aluminium%5D</link><description>Shanghai Metals Market (SMM) commentary (carried on metal.com) notes that recent transportation disruptions in Xinjiang have constrained aluminum movements and that newly announced capacity takes time to translate into production, limiting output growth in December[5]. The piece indicates near-term supply-side tightness due to logistical issues despite new capacity coming online more slowly than expected[5].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Meadow pushes aluminum circularity with US production partnership</title><link>https://www.packaginginsights.com/video/meadow-us-aluminum-circularity.html</link><description>Packaging Insights covers Meadow’s collaboration with a U.S. production partner to scale aluminum circularity and onshoring of aluminum packaging production in the U.S., driven by rising extended producer responsibility (EPR) laws and demand for recycled or circular aluminum packaging[6]. The report discusses implications for expanding U.S. production capacity for recycled aluminum in packaging supply chains[6].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory in Two Regions Rises to 77,500 mt on Dec 10, 2025: SMM</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103662934/Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Rises-to-77500-mt-on-Dec-10-2025:-SMM</link><description>Inventory of aluminum billet in two domestic regions increased to 77,500 metric tons as of December 10, 2025. Despite this rise, ADC12 aluminum alloy prices are expected to continue fluctuating weakly in the short term due to supply-demand dynamics and cost factors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Benteler expands its casthouse at Raufoss plant in Norway for more sustainable production</title><link>https://www.marklines.com/en/news/337170</link><description>Benteler Group completed modernization of its casthouse in Norway, increasing recycled aluminum use from 30% to 40%, aiming for 50% by 2030. This upgrade is part of the 'BAR Green' project to reduce CO₂ emissions and enhance sustainable aluminum production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel unit price index falls 0.1 to 3.2 % in Nov - DoSM</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/10/steel-unit-price-index-falls-01-to-32--in-nov---dosm</link><description>The unit price index of steel in Malaysia recorded a decrease ranging from 0.1 to 3.2 percent in November 2025 compared to the previous month, with the highest decreases in Miri and Kota Kinabalu. Year-on-year, the steel price index declined between 2.7 to 7.9 percent across most areas. Despite this, the cement price index increased in the same period.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Decision to discontinue domestic price assessments for steel rebar and billet in India</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/decision-to-discontinue-domestic-price-assessments-for-steel-rebar-billet-exw-india/</link><description>Fastmarkets has discontinued its price assessments for Indian domestic steel rebar and billet produced via the induction furnace route, as most quality long steel in India is now produced via the blast furnace route. This change took effect from December 10, 2025, following a consultation period. The discontinued prices included weekly assessments for rebar and billet in India.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Leading Indian companies collaborate with Sweden's innovators to drive decarbonisation in steel, cement sectors</title><link>https://www.ibef.org/news/leading-indian-companies-collaborate-with-sweden-s-innovators-to-drive-decarbonisation-in-steel-cement-sectors</link><description>Several leading Indian companies, including Tata Steel and Jindal Steel, are partnering with Swedish technology leaders and Indian academic institutions to launch seven projects focused on reducing greenhouse gas emissions in steel and cement industries. This collaboration supports India's net-zero carbon emissions goal by 2070 through pre-pilot feasibility assessments of emerging technologies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Why 2026 could be copper's breakout year</title><link>https://www.marketindex.com.au/news/why-2026-could-be-coppers-breakout-year</link><description>Production guidance for the QB2 copper project shows output of 170,000-190,000 tonnes in 2025, increasing to 220,000-255,000 tonnes by 2028. This gradual capacity growth is part of broader expectations that 2026 could mark a breakout year for copper due to supply constraints and rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Chemicals Market — Global Growth, Segmentation, Forecast Through 2032</title><link>https://www.einnews.com/pr_news/874084786/copper-chemicals-market-global-growth-segmentation-forecast-through-2032</link><description>The global copper chemicals market is expanding steadily, supported by increasing demand in various industrial applications. Growth projections extend through 2032, reflecting ongoing investments and capacity expansions in copper-related chemical production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Fluor Awarded Engineering, Procurement and Integrated Construction Management Services Contract for Teck Resources Highland Valley Copper Mine Life Extension Project</title><link>https://newsroom.fluor.com/news-releases/news-details/2025/Fluor-Awarded-Engineering-Procurement-and-Integrated-Construction-Management-Services-Contract-for-Teck-Resources-Highland-Valley-Copper-Mine-Life-Extension-Project/default.aspx</link><description>Fluor has been awarded a contract to provide engineering, procurement, and construction management services for the Highland Valley Copper Mine life extension project in British Columbia. This project reflects ongoing investment in extending the operational capacity of one of Canada's key copper mines.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 14,753 USD/T on December 10, 2025, down 0.15% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices decreased slightly to $14,753 per ton, continuing a downward trend over the past month with a 1.81% fall and a 6.81% decline year-over-year. The price is expected to trade around $14,909 by the end of the quarter and $14,119 in 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] December 10 news: Nickel prices extended their decline</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103664113/SMM-Nickel-Flash:-Deepening-Market-Contradiction-as-Upstream-Holds-Firm-amid-Weak-Demand</link><description>Nickel prices continued to decline on December 10 amid expectations around the US Federal Reserve's upcoming policy meeting. The market faces contradictions with firm upstream supply but weak demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's top cable maker sees US copper tariff as opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Prysmian views the U.S. copper tariff as an opportunity to strengthen the American supply chain. The company, which acquired Texas-based Encore Wire, expects the tariff to benefit local players due to its domestic copper sourcing and vertical integration.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rebounds from 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK rose to $2,861.20 per tonne on December 10, 2025, rebounding from a near one-month low of $2,790 on November 18. The price increase was supported by macroeconomic tailwinds favoring manufacturing and fresh stimulus signals from Beijing to address its property crisis.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>December Steel Price Outlook: Macro &amp; Fundamental Drivers</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103643800/december-steel-price-outlook-macro-emfundamentalem-drivers-smm-analysis</link><description>Steel prices have been volatile recently with hot metal production slightly down but still high. Inventory is expected to decline in December, though destocking for sheets and plates will be slow. Macro factors, including domestic policy meetings, may support limited price rises, but persistent destocking and weak sales could constrain gains.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Drops on Weak Demand</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel/news/508042</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China fell to a two-week low amid weakening demand, prompting mills to reduce production. Only 35% of Chinese steel mills were profitable at the end of November. Meanwhile, steel exports rose 2% month-on-month to 9.98 million tons in November, marking a record 107.72 million tons for the year to date.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Assessing Copper's Supply-Demand Dynamics as Prices Soar and ...</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/commodity-news/petail-28708.html</link><description>Global copper mine production grew from January to September 2025, with about 558 mines operating worldwide and a total capacity of 29.3 million tons. Despite new projects, supply-side bottlenecks and geopolitical factors constrain resource availability, leading to a projected 30% supply gap by 2035. China is advancing 'Smart Mine' technology to increase mining efficiency and reduce energy consumption, aiming for 800,000 tons of refined copper output in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The world needs a lot more copper. But will there be enough supply?</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/international/global/world-needs-lot-more-copper-will-there-be-enough-supply</link><description>Several key copper mines experienced operational setbacks in 2025, including flooding and tunnel collapses, leading to lowered production guidance. The copper market is expected to enter a supply deficit as early as 2026 due to these disruptions and increasing demand driven by clean energy transitions and electric vehicles. Smelters face profit margin pressures, and any reduction in smelting could further tighten supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Myriad ups stake in Copper Mountain uranium project in Wyoming to 75%</title><link>https://www.mining.com/myriad-ups-stake-in-copper-mountain-uranium-project-in-wyoming-to-75/</link><description>Myriad Uranium increased its stake to 75% in the Copper Mountain uranium project in Wyoming, highlighting the project's potential to become one of America's largest uranium sources. The project has benefited from new permits and significant past investments, with ongoing drilling exceeding expectations. Wyoming is becoming a hub for uranium activity in the US.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel prices extended their decline</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103663964</link><description>Nickel prices declined with the most-traded SHFE nickel contract closing down 0.7% at 116,920 yuan/mt. The market showed cautious sentiment ahead of the US Fed FOMC meeting, with prices expected to fluctuate between 114,000-118,000 yuan/mt in the short term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in December period I</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5106036-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-december-period-i</link><description>Indonesia's Nickel Miners Association set the benchmark price for nickel ore at $14,666.67/wmt for early December, down 2.21% from late November. Prices for different nickel grades also declined slightly, reflecting a softening market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices dropped to a four-year low due to a weak Federal Reserve outlook despite potential mining quota cuts in Indonesia. Futures on the London Metal Exchange fell as much as 2.3%, with nickel trending 8% lower this year amid concerns over supply and electric vehicle sales slowdown.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China nickel sulfate production down 9.14% MoM in Nov</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5106500-china-nickel-sulfate-production-down-914-mom-in-nov</link><description>China's nickel sulfate production fell to 206,500 tonnes in November, down 9.14% month-on-month, mainly due to production cuts and weak downstream demand in the ternary precursor industry. Despite this reduction, overall supply remained ample with sufficient inventories, leading to a continued downward trend in nickel sulfate prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper price rally resumes on supply warning</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-rally-resumes-on-supply-warning/copper_2025-12-10_12-11-06/</link><description>Copper price rally resumes amid supply warnings, with the Cobre Mendocino mine expected to produce 40,000 tonnes of copper concentrates annually. Broader market notes highlight record prices on US economic outlook. Supply constraints continue to drive volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM: Domestic Secondary Aluminum Alloy Ingot Inventory Drops 602 mt WoW to 54,700 mt on Dec 11</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103666144/SMM:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Alloy-Ingot-Inventory-Drops-602-mt-WoW-to-54700-mt-on-Dec-11</link><description>Domestic inventory of secondary aluminum alloy ingots in China dropped by 602 metric tons week-over-week to 54,700 metric tons as of December 11, 2025. This decline indicates ongoing production growth and tightening supply in the secondary aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Raw Steels MMI: Steel Prices Hold Steady Ahead of 2025</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2024/12/11/steel-prices-hold-steady/</link><description>Steel prices remained consolidated with a slight 1.78% decline from November to December. Lead times lengthened slightly, and mills showed pricing flexibility. The steel price trend is sideways with a notable 37% drop in hot-rolled coil prices year-over-year, while some futures saw modest gains.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Drops on Weak Demand</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China fell below CNY 3,050 per ton, hitting a near one-month low due to weakening demand and production scale-backs. Only 35% of Chinese steel mills were profitable at the end of November, down from 45% previously, indicating pressure on the market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Trade minister raises concerns over Canada's steel industry safeguard plan</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-12-11/business/economy/Trade-minister-raises-concerns-over-Canadas-steel-industry-safeguard-plan/2475329</link><description>South Korea's Trade Minister expressed concerns to Canada about its plan to reduce steel tariff rate quotas (TRQs) from 100% to 75% of 2024 levels, which could impact Korean steel exports. The move aims to protect Canada's steel industry amid global oversupply but is seen as violating WTO rules and existing free trade agreements.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ode to Noble Laborers</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/11/ode-to-noble-laborers/</link><description>This report highlights innovations in steel technology at Baosteel, including the integration of artificial intelligence in hot-rolling steel processes and breakthroughs in laminar cooling technology that boosted steel product yields. The article emphasizes the role of skilled workers and AI in transforming traditional steel manufacturing towards smarter, more efficient production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise Amid China Slowdown</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/11/copper-prices-rise-amid-china-slowdown/</link><description>Despite weak economic indicators from China, copper prices have increased as traders focus on tightening physical markets and long-term demand prospects driven by renewable energy, electric vehicles, and data centers. Supply challenges persist due to mine disruptions and difficulties in increasing output, particularly from major producers like Codelco.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anglo American and Teck Resources Merge, US Fed Cuts Interest Rate by 25 Basis Points as Expected [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103665057/Anglo-American-and-Teck-Resources-Merge-US-Fed-Cuts-Interest-Rate-by-25-Basis-Points-as-Expected-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper futures opened at $11,632/mt and fluctuated during the session, closing with a gain of 0.78%. Spot prices in Shanghai showed a mixed trend with discounts and premiums varying, while imported copper prices saw slight increases. The report highlights ongoing market volatility and supply-demand dynamics in the copper market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices fell slightly to $5.30 per pound on December 11, 2025, retreating from four-month highs amid demand uncertainties from China. Over the past month, copper prices have risen over 4%, with a year-on-year increase of about 27%, reflecting strong market momentum despite recent volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Assessing Copper's Supply-Demand Dynamics as Prices Soar and Inventories Drop</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/commodity-news/petail-28708.html</link><description>Copper prices have continuously hit historical highs with a year-on-year increase exceeding 30% on the LME. Global copper inventories have dropped below 1 million tons, intensifying concerns about a copper shortage driven by long-term supply-demand imbalances. Forecasts indicate increasing copper consumption and a growing supply gap by 2035.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise Amid China Slowdown</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/11/copper-prices-rise-amid-china-slowdown/</link><description>Copper prices have risen despite weak economic indicators from China, driven by tightening physical markets and strong long-term demand from renewable energy and electric vehicles. Supply challenges persist with mine disruptions, including difficulties faced by Codelco, the world's largest copper producer. The structural imbalance between demand and constrained supply supports copper prices amid short-term economic concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anglo American and Teck Resources Merge, US Fed Cuts Interest Rate by 25 Basis Points as Expected [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103665057/Anglo-American-and-Teck-Resources-Merge-US-Fed-Cuts-Interest-Rate-by-25-Basis-Points-as-Expected-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Anglo American and Teck Resources shareholders approved an all-share merger to form Anglo Teck, expected to become the world's fifth-largest copper producer with annual production of about 1.2 million metric tons. The merger aims to achieve $800 million in annual cost synergies within four years. Copper futures showed price fluctuations but closed with a slight gain on December 10.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 11, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103663100</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 116,400 to 121,900 yuan/mt with an average of 119,150 yuan/mt, down 1,200 yuan/mt from the previous trading day, indicating a continued decline in nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Morning Post of Nickel on December 11th</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-21819.html</link><description>Nornickel, a major Russian nickel producer, announced that the global nickel surplus is expected to remain around 150,000 tons by 2025, signaling ongoing oversupply concerns in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's nickel matte output rises in November, MHP production edges lower</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-s-nickel-matte-output-rises-in-november-mhp-production-edges-lower</link><description>Indonesia saw an increase in nickel matte output in November while production of mixed hydroxide precipitate (MHP) slightly declined. This reflects ongoing shifts in Indonesia's nickel production dynamics amid regulatory and market changes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Peregrine Hydrogen and Tasmania Energy Metals Sign LOI for Nickel Processing Plant in Bell Bay</title><link>https://hydrogen-central.com/peregrine-hydrogen-and-tasmania-energy-metals-sign-loi-for-nickel-processing-plant-in-bell-bay/</link><description>Peregrine Hydrogen and Tasmania Energy Metals have signed a letter of intent to develop a nickel processing plant in Bell Bay, Tasmania. This project aims to enhance local nickel processing capacity and support the growing demand for nickel in energy transition technologies.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nippon Steel lifts stainless steel prices for December on higher costs, recovering demand</title><link>https://www.stainless.club/industry-news/read/nippon-steel-lifts-stainless-steel-prices-for-december-on-higher-costs-recovering-demand.html</link><description>Nippon Steel announced higher stainless-steel contract prices for December, citing rising alloy costs and signs of recovering local demand; the piece notes the move reflects input-cost pressures and tentative market improvements in the region.[1]  The article indicates the pricing change is part of seasonal/contract adjustments and links it to broader stainless market dynamics and recent industry commentary.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Rebounds on Demand Hopes</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Rebar futures climbed above CNY 3,080/ton on optimism that an improving macro backdrop and expectations of a US Fed rate cut could support demand, while market participants simultaneously awaited policy signals from China’s Central Economic Work Conference.[2]  The report contrasts the rebound with recent weakness and notes ongoing demand uncertainty in China weighing on sentiment.[2]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Prices for rebar reached local highs at the end of the year</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>GMK Center reports that rebar prices climbed to local year-end highs, reflecting late-season demand and regional supply factors; the note places recent price moves in the context of seasonal demand and producer behavior.[5]  The item is presented alongside other short market updates and regional production/news briefs in GMK's steel news feed.[5]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC futures were stable first and then declined today, with the most-traded contract closing at 3,238, down 1.19% for the day</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103667167</link><description>SMM reported that hot-rolled coil (HRC) futures initially held steady but later fell, with the most-traded contract closing down about 1.19%, signaling short-term weakness in finished-steel futures amid fluctuating demand and inventory updates.[7]  The coverage includes contract prices and commentary on market-moving factors for HRC trading that day.[7]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>This week, social HRC inventory was 2.598 million mt; finished steel prices fluctuated downward</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103666784/</link><description>Metal News summarized weekly HRC inventory at about 2.598 million mt and noted finished-steel prices fluctuated downward amid increased blast furnace maintenance plans and reduced hot-metal production, highlighting supply-side factors influencing near-term price pressure.[8]  The brief places the inventory and production developments alongside demand trends to explain recent price volatility.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Thyssenkrupp pauses steel production at two sites citing Asian pressure</title><link>https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20251211-thyssenkrupp-pauses-steel-production-at-two-sites-citing-asian-pressure</link><description>Europe's largest steelmaker Thyssenkrupp is pausing steel production at its Gelsenkirchen, Germany, and Isbergues, France, sites for about two weeks due to a surge in low-cost Asian imports, leading to underutilized capacity. The French site will also operate at 50% capacity for at least four months starting January. The company calls for swift EU trade protection measures to restore sustainable operations, amid ongoing challenges from high energy costs and competition.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Imports Down 16.7% In September vs. August</title><link>https://www.steel.org/2025/12/steel-imports-down-16-7-in-september-vs-august/</link><description>US steel imports dropped 16.7% in September compared to August, with year-to-date finished import market share at 19%. The decline reflects ongoing tariff impacts and market dynamics affecting import volumes. This data highlights a continued reduction in reliance on foreign steel supplies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Weyerhaeuser and Aymium Enter Agreement to Rapidly Scale Biocarbon Market</title><link>https://investor.weyerhaeuser.com/2025-12-11-Weyerhaeuser-and-Aymium-Enter-Agreement-to-Rapidly-Scale-Biocarbon-Market</link><description>Weyerhaeuser and Aymium have partnered to expand biocarbon manufacturing, providing a sustainable alternative for steel production to replace traditional coal-based carbon. This initiative scales production of biocarbon derived from wood residuals, supporting decarbonization in the steel industry. The agreement accelerates the market for low-emission materials in heavy industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price rally resumes on supply warning</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-rally-resumes-on-supply-warning/</link><description>Copper rebound pushed three‑month LME futures toward a near record as warnings of a sizable supply shortfall and mine disruptions supported prices, with LME three‑month futures settling at $11,556.50/ton after an intraday gain; the article cites structural supply concerns and demand drivers such as EVs, data centers and renewable energy boosting the bullish case.[4][6] It also notes a prior record near $11,771/ton and that short‑term moves were influenced by China demand data and the US interest‑rate decision.[4][6]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rises with Fed rate cut, worries about outflows to US stocks</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-rises-with-fed-rate-cut-worries-about-outflows-to-us-stocks/</link><description>Copper prices rose after a US Federal Reserve rate cut, with buying supported by flows out of US copper stocks and continued concern about supply tightness; the article links the rate decision to the rally and notes movements across related metals.[7] It reports market reaction to monetary policy alongside physical market flows as drivers of price moves.[7]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rises to record high on rate cut - Markets</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40397059</link><description>Markets report that copper hit an all‑time high following a US Fed rate cut, with continuing flows into copper stocks cited as supporting the price surge and market commentary emphasizing tight fundamentals and demand from electrification and tech sectors.[8] The short item summarizes the market reaction to monetary policy and flow dynamics underlying the rally.[8]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[Nickel Midday Market Review] Nickel Prices Plunge Sharply</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103666272</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices averaged 118,850 yuan/mt on December 11, down 300 yuan/mt from the prior day amid Fed rate cut news overshadowed by weak fundamentals. SHFE nickel futures closed down 0.7% at 116,920 yuan/mt. Short-term prices expected in 114,000-118,000 yuan/mt range.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>ZincFive Wins Multiple Categories in the 2025 Power Technology Excellence Awards</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/business-wire/20251211321353/zincfive-wins-multiple-categories-in-the-2025-power-technology-excellence-awards</link><description>ZincFive has won awards in Innovation, Product Launch, Safety, and Environmental Excellence for its nickel-zinc battery technology, which offers high power density, inherent safety, and 25-50% lower lifetime greenhouse gas emissions than lead-acid or lithium-ion alternatives. The technology supports sustainability through recyclable materials and is deployed in nearly 2 gigawatts of systems for AI-driven data centers. This recognition underscores ZincFive's leadership in safe, sustainable power solutions for mission-critical infrastructure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>ZincFive Secures $30M in Oversubscribed Series F Financing to Power the Data Center Infrastructure Behind the AI Boom</title><link>https://theaiinsider.tech/2025/12/11/zincfive-secures-30m-in-oversubscribed-series-f-financing-to-power-the-data-center-infrastructure-behind-the-ai-boom/</link><description>ZincFive raised $30 million in oversubscribed Series F financing to expand its nickel-zinc battery technology, which provides superior power density, safety, and sustainability for data centers powering the AI boom. The funding supports scaling production of these environmentally friendly batteries as an alternative to traditional chemistries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Trading Economics summarizes recent aluminum market moves and notes that China — the world’s top producer — is expected to approach its 45-million-ton annual cap, limiting room for further production growth and affecting global supply expectations[2]. The page also highlights recent supply disruptions and planned smelter setbacks (for example in Indonesia) that are influencing prices and capacity outlooks[2].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trojan Horse</title><link>https://www.fdd.org/analysis/2025/12/11/trojan-horse/</link><description>FDD’s analysis highlights China’s dominant role in primary aluminum production (nearly 60% of global primary supply) and discusses strategic vulnerabilities tied to global dependence on Chinese aluminum capacity for defense‑relevant manufacturing[9]. The piece links production concentration to geopolitical and industrial-policy risks rather than immediate daily capacity changes[9].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[SMM High-grade NPI] Prices Edge Up Slowly, Yet Market Transactions Remain Sluggish</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103669774/High-grade-NPI-Prices-Rebound-Short-lived-Amid-Weak-Fundamentals-in-December</link><description>High-grade NPI prices edged up slowly on December 11 amid weak fundamentals in December's off-season. The average price of 10-12% high-grade NPI saw a rebound, but market transactions remained sluggish. This reflects ongoing challenges in the nickel pig iron segment tied to steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Australia Pledges Deal to Keep Giant Rio Tinto Aluminum Smelter Open</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2025121110462/australia-pledges-deal-to-keep-giant-rio-tinto-aluminum-smelter-open</link><description>Australian federal and state governments have agreed to collaborate with Rio Tinto's Tomago Aluminium, the country's largest smelter producing nearly 40% of Australia's aluminum (up to 590,000 metric tons yearly), to secure affordable power post-2028 and prevent closure due to high energy costs exceeding 40% of operations. The deal includes at least A$1 billion in investments over the next decade. Tomago, operational since 1983, is Australia's biggest electricity user.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum melted with Annular Fresnel solar at over 700°C</title><link>https://www.solarpaces.org/aluminum-melted-with-annular-fresnel-solar-at-over-700c/</link><description>Researchers demonstrated an annular Fresnel solar furnace capable of reaching temperatures above 700°C to melt and cast aluminum, showing a practical, low‑cost route for solar-driven aluminum recycling and production of branded ingots during field trials conducted in 2024–2025. The team argues the approach could enable near‑zero‑carbon aluminum recycling at scale in high‑DNI regions such as northern Chile, supporting circular-economy goals and interest from multinationals seeking ‘green aluminum’.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tomago Aluminium welcomes continued collaboration on future operations</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2025/tomago-aluminium-welcomes-continued-collaboration-on-future-operations</link><description>Tomago Aluminium and partners confirmed ongoing collaboration regarding the smelter's future operations, reflecting discussions about operational strategy and the site’s long‑term viability amid evolving energy and sustainability considerations. The release underscores stakeholder engagement around the aluminum operation’s future and potential transitions tied to decarbonization pathways.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Panasonic Group to showcase AI driven business solutions and circular‑design recycling advances</title><link>https://news.panasonic.com/global/press/en251212-2</link><description>Panasonic described BIPV developments and next‑generation recycling infrastructure that enable precise disassembly and high‑purity separation of materials (including metals), aiming to produce high‑quality recycled materials and advance circularity by fiscal 2028. The announcement emphasizes design for maintainability and material recovery that can support sustainable metal (including aluminum) recycling streams.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 12.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>Steel Radar's market page compiles the latest prices, indices and short market notes for global iron and steel exchanges, providing snapshot price data (including Shanghai rebar futures) and links to recent price movements and news updates relevant to traders and analysts.[3]  The page is structured as a running market bulletin with dated price lines and short topical items for rebar, scrap and iron markets.[3]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Utility Global and Kyocera Join Forces to Scale H2Gen® Manufacturing Globally for Economic Industrial Decarbonization</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/12/utility-global-and-kyocera-join-forces-to-scale-h2gen-manufacturing-globally-for-economic-industrial-decarbonization/</link><description>Utility Global and Kyocera are partnering to scale production of H2Gen systems, combining Utility's electrochemical cell technology with Kyocera's manufacturing expertise for hydrogen production using industrial off-gases. This enables economic decarbonization in hard-to-abate sectors like steel by producing clean hydrogen without electricity, lowering costs and emissions. The technology targets blast furnace steel production, which accounts for over 70% of global steel output and 85% of industry emissions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Whyalla Steelworks Hydrogen Integration Transforms Australian Green Steel Production</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/direct-reduction-australia-steelmaking-revolution-2025/</link><description>Whyalla Steelworks is integrating hydrogen-based direct reduction iron (DRI) technology to revolutionize green steel production in Australia. This innovation aims to reduce carbon emissions through sustainable steelmaking processes. The development marks a significant step toward low-emission steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Capital demands soar for new copper supply</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/market-intelligence/en/news-insights/research/2025/12/capital-demands-soar-for-new-copper-supply</link><description>Development costs for copper projects have escalated, with delays in 13 of 22 analyzed projects; Capstone Copper's Santo Domingo saw a 55% capex increase to boost annual output to 68,500 metric tons. Barrick's Reko Diq in Pakistan targets 377,000 metric tons annually from 2028 with high capex. Capital intensity averages high across regions, underscoring supply challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 14,602.75 USD/T on December 12, 2025, down 0.05% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have declined 2.39%, and are down significantly year-over-year. Forecasts indicate prices at 14,909.70 USD/MT by quarter-end.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] Upstream-Downstream Contradictions Surface as NPI Market Stagnates</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103668628/SMM-Nickel-Flash:-Upstream-Downstream-Contradictions-Surface-as-NPI-Market-Stagnates</link><description>On December 12, upstream nickel offers increased but sales remained difficult, with most transactions at average levels. Supply side challenges highlight contradictions between upstream and downstream markets. NPI market shows stagnation.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries lifts 2025 nickel sales and receives green light for growth</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/12/12/nickel-industries-lifts-2025-nickel-sales-and-receives-green-light-for-growth/</link><description>Nickel Industries received approval to raise its 2025 nickel ore sales quota from 9 million to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes, restarting sales from Hengjaya Mine. A five-year environmental permit supports 2026 growth targeting 19 million wmt annually. This boosts near-term revenue to Indonesia Morowali Industrial Park.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Boosts Nickel-Ore Sales Quota</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/12/nickel-industries-boosts-nickel-ore-sales-quota/</link><description>Nickel Industries boosted its 2025 nickel ore sales quota from 9 to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes from Hengjaya Mine, resuming stockpiled ore sales to Indonesia Morowali Industrial Park. Five-year AMDAL environmental approval underpins 2026 quota expansion. Expected to enhance revenue streams.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries lifts 2025 nickel sales and receives green light for growth</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/12/12/nickel-industries-lifts-2025-nickel-sales-and-receives-green-light-for-growth/</link><description>Nickel Industries has increased its 2025 nickel ore sales quota to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes and secured a five-year environmental permit enabling innovative in-pit tailings storage and a limonite slurry pipeline for its ENC HPAL plant. This technology aims to position ENC as the lowest carbon and cost-intensive HPAL globally while improving traceability and reducing environmental impact. The company anticipates approval for a 2026 quota of 19 million wmt and focuses on commissioning the Excelsior Nickel Cobalt project for EV battery supply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China wins the race against the US in aluminum recycling output, capacity and expansion</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5106786-china-wins-the-race-against-the-us-in-aluminum-recycling-output-capacity-and-expansion</link><description>Mysteel reports that China has more than doubled its secondary (recycled) aluminum output since 2010 and now accounts for roughly 38–40% of global recycled aluminum production; the piece notes significant new secondary projects in 2024 that added over 2.05 million tonnes of planned capacity and brought total secondary capacity to about 17.62 million tonnes[1]. The article contrasts China’s rapid expansion of recycled aluminum with the US, where secondary production growth has been modest and the economy has become secondary-dominant rather than primary-focused[1].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3045 CNY/T on December 12, 2025, down 0.03% from the previous day, amid demand uncertainties in China. Steel rebar futures dropped toward CNY 3,040 per ton, the lowest in a month, despite Beijing's reaffirmation of broad economic support measures. Over the past month, prices have fallen 0.10%, and are down 7.36% year-over-year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 906.07 USD/T on December 12, 2025, down 0.10% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 5.97%, and are up 34.37% compared to the same time last year. The update reflects trading on a contract for difference tracking the benchmark market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Canada Says Tighter Limits on Steel Imports to Take Effect on Dec. 26</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512125888/canada-says-tighter-limits-on-steel-imports-to-take-effect-on-dec-26-update</link><description>Canada's finance department announced that new limits on steel imports will take effect on December 26 to support the domestic steel sector amid U.S. tariffs. The measures reduce imports from non-free-trade countries like China, Turkey, and Brazil to 20% of 2024 levels before a 50% tariff applies, and limit FTA countries (excluding U.S. and Mexico) to 75% of 2024 levels. This follows Algoma Steel's plan to cut 1,000 jobs due to unsustainable blast furnace production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>New Delhi Supports Tata Steel Indo–Sweden Partnership For Cleaner Industry, Innovation</title><link>https://urbanacres.in/new-delhi-supports-tata-steel-indo-sweden-partnership-for-cleaner-industry-innovation/</link><description>The article reports that New Delhi has extended support to Tata Steel under the Indo–Sweden Industry Transition Partnership to advance low‑carbon steel technologies and circular processes, including projects that recover metals from steel slag and convert residues into low‑carbon cement additives, presented at COP30 and launched at the Swedish Embassy in New Delhi.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green steel innovation: Tata Steel to establish HIsarna technology plant in Jamshedpur; Aims for sustainable production with 1 MTPA capacity</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/ranchi/green-steel-innovation-tata-steel-to-establish-hisarna-technology-plant-in-jamshedpur-aims-for-sustainable-production-with-1-mtpa-capacity/articleshow/125916951.cms</link><description>Tata Steel has approved engineering and regulatory work to build a ~1 million tonnes per annum HIsarna demonstration plant in Jamshedpur, deploying a low‑carbon ironmaking route that can use lower‑grade ore and eliminate coke while integrating slag reuse to cut emissions.[2]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest News &amp; Updates (industry perspectives on decarbonisation, hydrogen pilots, circularity)</title><link>https://www.responsiblesteel.org/news</link><description>ResponsibleSteel's news update highlights industry progress and challenges in steel decarbonisation: hydrogen‑based pilots, increased integration of renewable electricity, and a stronger focus on circular scrap‑based production, while noting barriers such as green hydrogen cost and infrastructure constraints.[3]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Steel Tracker — recent entries and analysis on low‑carbon investments and technology needs</title><link>https://www.industrytransition.org/green-steel-tracker/</link><description>LeadIT's Green Steel Tracker continues to log public announcements of low‑carbon steel investments and publishes analyses (including hydrogen and renewable electricity demand for EU transition), tracking industry commitments and gaps in net‑zero targets among major producers.[4]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>How technology is reshaping metal recycling</title><link>https://www.recyclingproductnews.com/article/44035/how-technology-is-reshaping-metal-recycling</link><description>The piece explains how digitalisation, sensors and advanced analytics are improving metal recycling quality and efficiency for the steel supply chain, citing technologies such as laser‑induced plasma spectroscopy for material composition analysis and control systems that reduce downtime and energy use.[5]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Weyerhaeuser and Aymium to rapidly scale biocarbon market (metallurgical‑grade biocarbon for iron &amp; steel)</title><link>https://www.pulpapernews.com/20251212/17289/weyerhaeuser-and-aymium-rapidly-scale-biocarbon-market</link><description>Weyerhaeuser and Aymium announced plans to scale production of metallurgical‑grade biocarbon as a drop‑in replacement for coal and coke in iron and steel production, targeting up to 1.5 million tonnes annually at full scale to reduce carbon intensity of metallurgical processes.[6]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex copper ends the week 1.83% lower at $5.2835 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512125886/comex-copper-ends-the-week-183-lower-at-52835-data-talk</link><description>Front‑month Comex copper for December delivery fell 9.85 cents per pound (1.83%) for the week, closing at $5.2835, marking the largest one‑week percentage decline since early November and snapping a two‑week winning streak. The report notes copper remains well above its 52‑week low and up roughly 32% year‑on‑year, while intraday volatility included a larger single‑day drop that was the biggest since late October[4].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper — Price, Chart, Historical Data, News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Trading Economics reports copper fell to $5.28 per pound on December 12, 2025 (down ~2.4% from the prior day) after reaching multi‑month highs earlier; the site also notes copper is up roughly 27–32% year‑on‑year and reached an all‑time high in July 2025. The page synthesizes price moves, recent drivers including Chinese stimulus expectations and a U.S. Fed rate cut, and includes linked short market updates on rallies and pullbacks[1].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Beijing Moves to Rein in Steel Exports With New Licensing Rule</title><link>https://www.caixinglobal.com/2025-12-13/beijing-moves-to-rein-in-steel-exports-with-new-licensing-rule-102392857.html</link><description>China's Ministry of Commerce and General Administration of Customs announced export licensing requirements for most steel products starting January 1, 2026, to curb surging low-priced shipments and illicit trade. Steel exports reached 110 million tons in 2024, forecasted at 110-130 million tons in 2025, with first-10-months 2025 exports at 97.7 million tons and prices down 8.7% to $695.4/ton. The measure covers crude iron, billets, coils, plates, pipes, and scrap, amid rising global trade remedy investigations against Chinese steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper eases after nearing $12,000, set for 3rd straight weekly jump</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-eases-after-nearing-12000-set-for-3rd-straight-weekly-jump/</link><description>Copper prices eased after earlier touching near $12,000 per tonne but remained on track for a third consecutive weekly gain, pressured by demand uncertainty out of top consumer China even as Chinese policymakers signalled measured economic support for 2026. The piece highlights the tension between strong recent rallies and short‑term profit‑taking or demand concerns that have driven intraday swings[7].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tight supply and AI demand drive copper prices higher</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-rally-forces-2025-supply-demand-imbalance/</link><description>The article attributes recent copper strength to tightening physical supply and rising demand tied to AI and energy‑transition trends, reporting prices around $11,952 per metric tonne as of December 12, 2025. It frames the rally as supported by structural demand growth (EVs, renewables, AI infrastructure) alongside inventory movements that have tightened availability[3].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME metal inventories update — Copper inventories reported (December 13)</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103087911/LME-Metal-Inventories-Updates-on-December-13</link><description>Metal.com’s inventory update shows LME copper stock movements on December 13, 2025, signaling ongoing shifts in exchange inventories that market participants watch for clues on near‑term physical tightness. The update provides transaction price ranges and inventory figures that help explain short‑term price volatility and regional flows affecting LME balances[8].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Metal Mania: Reuters on Copper, Tin, Zinc, Lithium, Cobalt and More</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/metal-mania-reuters-on-copper-tin-zinc-lithium-cobalt-and-more</link><description>Recycling and technological innovation are key to addressing growing metal demand, particularly for copper. In China, increased scrap copper from aging infrastructure could offset shortages through 'urban mining.' This reduces reliance on primary mining and supports supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[December 13 Morning Meeting Summary] Refined Nickel: Spot Premiums Update, Nickel Futures Rise</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103085889/%5BDec-13-Morning-Meeting%5D-Nickel-Spot-Premiums-Update-Nickel-Futures-Rise</link><description>Domestic refined nickel closed at 117,080 yuan/mt on Friday, up 1.99% week-over-week. LME nickel prices rebounded significantly to $14,850/mt on Friday. Spot premiums and futures showed upward movement in the morning meeting.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Had Slightly Increased This Week</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-21909.html</link><description>Shanghai nickel warehouse receipts inventory stood at 30,564 tons as of December 13th, up 985 tons week-over-week. Nickel prices showed a slight increase amid inventory buildup. Market trends indicate modest upward pressure despite ongoing supply dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 13 Dec 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/12/13/the-market-in-numbers-13-dec-2025/</link><description>Nickel price per pound recorded at 6.6005, down 0.90% as of December 13, 2025. This reflects broader metals market movements, with nickel under slight downward pressure. Part of daily metals and minerals pricing update.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries (ASX: NIC) Soars with Quota Approval: Is It a Buy?</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/nickel-industries-surges-on-quota-approval/</link><description>Indonesian authorities approved an increase to Nickel Industries' 2025 nickel ore sales quota from 9 million to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes. This allows resumption of deliveries from the Hengjaya Mine to the Indonesia Morowali Industrial Park, supported by a five-year AMDAL permit and in-pit tailings system. The approval addresses ongoing oversupply pressures amid rapid capacity expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. Announces Closing of Oversubscribed $1.96m Flow-Through Financing</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/6264300</link><description>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. closed an oversubscribed $1.96 million flow-through financing. This follows a news release on December 4, 2025, providing funds likely for critical minerals exploration including nickel-related activities. The financing supports the company's development in the critical minerals sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. Announces Closing of Oversubscribed $1.96m Flow-Through Financing</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/12/13/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/north-american-niobium-and-critical-minerals-corp-announces-closing-of-oversubscribed-196m-flow-through-financing/2242758</link><description>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. announced the closing of its oversubscribed $1.96 million flow-through financing. The update references a prior release from December 4, 2025. Funds will advance critical minerals projects, potentially including nickel production capacities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion titled “Nuclear: the future of the Italian boilermaking industry” at Fondazione Dalmine in Italy, partnering with UCC. Experts from industry and institutions discussed nuclear energy's role in Europe’s energy transition and Italy’s manufacturing potential, including small modular reactors. Tenaris’s Italian mill recently obtained accreditation for nuclear materials under ASME III standards.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (December 8, 2025 - December 12, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-december-8-2025-a-december-12-2025-on-the-ce7d50d8dd8df324</link><description>Tenaris published its weekly share buyback report for December 8-12, 2025, detailing purchases like 497,790 shares on MTA at a weighted average price. As of December 12, the company holds 51,262,421 treasury shares, equal to 4.78% of issued capital, with plans to cancel them. The report is available on Tenaris's IR website.</description><category>general</category></item></channel></rss>