<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 05:17:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HRC Steel Price Falls Slightly to $844.04/T on November 3, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>The price of hot-rolled coil (HRC) steel fell by 0.82% to $844.04 per ton on November 3, 2025. Despite the recent dip, HRC steel prices have risen over 5% in the past month and are up more than 20% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts suggest prices may rise to $864.45 by the end of the quarter and $934.57 within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cut in December Decline, LME Copper Fluctuates and Closes Lower Last Friday</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated, opening at $10,857.5/mt and closing slightly lower at $10,891.5/mt, down 0.35%. Shanghai copper contracts also declined marginally. Market sentiment shows copper prices retreating with procurement sentiment rising and spot premiums narrowing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices were in the doldrums on November 3</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103601324</link><description>Nickel prices on the SHFE moved sideways with slight gains amid positive China-US trade developments easing market concerns. LME nickel inventory increased to a nearly five-year high, suggesting continued market oversupply and sideways price movement expected in the near term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel and the University of Texas at Austin Launch Carbon Sequestration Pilot at Crawford Nickel Project</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/canada-nickel-and-the-university-of-texas-at-austin-launch-carbon-sequestration-pilot-at-crawford-nickel-project-302601882.html</link><description>Canada Nickel and the University of Texas at Austin have launched a one-month in-situ carbon sequestration pilot at the Crawford Nickel Project in Ontario. The pilot, supported by the U.S. DOE ARPA-E, tests rapid CO2 mineralization in ultramafic rock and aims to inform post-mining sequestration and the development of a Zero-Carbon Industrial Cluster.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel And The University Of Texas At Austin Launch Carbon Sequestration Pilot At Crawford Nickel Project</title><link>https://decarbonfuse.com/posts/canada-nickel-and-the-university-of-texas-at-austin-launch-carbon-sequestration-pilot-at-crawford-nickel-project</link><description>Canada Nickel Company Inc. is collaborating with the University of Texas at Austin on a carbon sequestration pilot at its Crawford Nickel Project. The initiative, backed by the U.S. DOE ARPA-E, explores innovative methods to store CO2 and reduce costs in nickel processing, supporting sustainable mining practices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel and the University of Texas at Austin Launch Carbon Sequestration Pilot at Crawford Nickel Project</title><link>https://www.newswire.ca/news-releases/canada-nickel-and-the-university-of-texas-at-austin-launch-carbon-sequestration-pilot-at-crawford-nickel-project-876443143.html</link><description>Canada Nickel and the University of Texas at Austin have initiated a one-month pilot for in-situ carbon injection at the Crawford Nickel Project. The pilot is independent of Canada Nickel’s other carbonation initiatives and supports the vision for a Zero-Carbon Industrial Cluster in Northeastern Ontario.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Reach Highest Level Since May 2022</title><link>https://www.indexbox.io/blog/aluminum-prices-reach-highest-level-since-may-2022/</link><description>Aluminum futures settled at $2,902 a metric ton on the London Metal Exchange, marking the highest price since May 2022. The price increase is attributed to supply tightening in China and an improved demand outlook amid easing US-China trade tensions, despite ongoing risks such as a slowdown in China's manufacturing sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Germany Proposes Full Ban on Russian Steel Imports Ahead of Industry Summit</title><link>https://united24media.com/latest-news/germany-proposes-full-ban-on-russian-steel-imports-ahead-of-industry-summit-13068</link><description>German Vice Chancellor Lars Klingbeil called for a complete ban on Russian steel imports to support domestic production and climate-friendly steel manufacturing. The proposal comes ahead of a steel industry summit aimed at addressing overcapacity, energy costs, and strengthening local production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Costs down and prices up, the aluminium industry's average profit broke through RMB 5,000 per tonne in October</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/costs-down-and-prices-up-the-aluminium-industry-s-average-profit-broke-through-rmb-5-000-per-tonne-in-october-116066</link><description>The aluminum industry saw average profits exceed RMB 5,000 per tonne in October due to stable electricity prices and declining alumina costs, despite expected increases in power costs in November. Overall, aluminum production costs are forecast to slightly decrease in November, supporting profitability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Costs down and prices up, the aluminium industry's average profit broke through RMB 5,000 per tonne in October</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/costs-down-and-prices-up-the-aluminium-industry-s-average-profit-broke-through-rmb-5-000-per-tonne-in-october-116066</link><description>The aluminum industry saw average profits exceed RMB 5,000 per tonne in October 2025 due to stable electricity prices and declining alumina costs. However, power costs are expected to rise in November with increasing coal prices and seasonal factors, while overall aluminum production costs may slightly decrease.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd Stock Update: Slight Decline on November 4, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-04-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's stock price experienced a minor drop of 0.07%, trading at ₹1,191.90 per share. This slight decline has sparked discussions among investors about the company's short-term performance amid current market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Ltd Stock Remains Unchanged on November 4, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/tata-steel-ltd-04-nov-2025-500470</link><description>Tata Steel Ltd's share price remained stable at ₹182.10 with no change reported. This stability may influence investor sentiment as the steel market navigates ongoing economic factors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Strategic Steel Revival Without Mandating Supply Cuts</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/china-steel-industry-transformation-2025-environmental-innovation/</link><description>China is reviving its steel industry by focusing on market-driven production adjustments rather than government-mandated supply cuts. Mills are adjusting output based on demand and margins, with annual production likely to fall below 1 billion tons for the first time in six years due to weak domestic demand and strong export opportunities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Government Launches 4 Billion Won Steel Export Guarantee for SMEs</title><link>https://www.chosun.com/english/industry-en/2025/11/04/AICA6HLQQFDKPN2S5HOE5MLNRE/</link><description>The South Korean government has introduced a 4 billion won steel export guarantee program to support small and medium-sized steel companies facing global oversupply and export barriers. The initiative aims to strengthen the industry's resilience and encourage high value-added and low-carbon transitions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>South Korea to Restructure Steel Industry Hit by Tariffs, Oversupply</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/south-korea-to-restructure-steel-industry-hit-by-tariffs-oversupply/</link><description>South Korea plans to restructure its steel industry in response to higher tariffs from the US and EU and ongoing oversupply issues. The government will adjust production capacity for oversupplied products and expand financial and policy support for exporters.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Aims to Revive Steelmaking Without Ordering Cuts to Supply</title><link>https://theedgemalaysia.com/node/777421</link><description>China is adopting a measured approach to reviving its steel industry, focusing on improving the outlook for high-end companies without mandating supply cuts. The strategy emphasizes market-driven adjustments and selective demand growth.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Gov't Unveils Steps to Support Restructuring of Steel Industry to Overcome Supply Glut</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-11-04/business/economy/Govt-unveils-steps-to-support-restructuring-of-steel-industry-to-overcome-supply-glut/2436062</link><description>The South Korean government has announced measures to support the restructuring of the steel industry to address the supply glut. The steps include capacity adjustments and expanded support for exporters facing international trade barriers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>German Social Democrats Push for Full EU Ban on Russian Steel Imports</title><link>https://eualive.net/germanys-rulling-socialists-push-for-full-eu-ban-on-russian-steel-imports/</link><description>Germany's ruling Social Democrats are urging the EU to impose a full ban on Russian steel imports, arguing that continued imports undermine sanctions and threaten Europe's industrial base. The move is part of broader measures to safeguard European steel production and employment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Australian Steel Supply to Protect Sovereignty of Hunter Class Frigate Program</title><link>https://www.baesystems.com/en/article/australian-steel-supply-to-protect-sovereignty-of-hunter-class-frigate-program</link><description>Australia is securing domestic steel supply for the Hunter Class Frigate Program to ensure national sovereignty. The initiative highlights the importance of local steel production for strategic defense projects.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Australian steel supply to protect sovereignty of Hunter Class Frigate Program</title><link>https://www.baesystems.com/en/article/australian-steel-supply-to-protect-sovereignty-of-hunter-class-frigate-program</link><description>Australia's largest steelworks is supplying steel to support the Hunter Class Frigate Program, emphasizing domestic steel production's role in national sovereignty and security. This initiative highlights the strategic importance of sustainable and reliable steel supply chains for critical defense infrastructure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Macquarie tips 23% upside for resurgent ASX 200 copper stock riding the red metals bull run</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/11/04/macquarie-tips-23-upside-for-resurgent-asx-200-copper-stock-riding-the-red-metals-bull-run/</link><description>Capstone Copper shares have surged 32.5% year-to-date, outperforming the ASX 200 index, supported by operational successes and rising copper prices currently around US$10,855 per tonne. The copper price is up 23.8% year-to-date, fueling optimism for further gains in copper stocks.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Macquarie tips 23% upside for resurgent ASX 200 copper stock riding the red metals bull run</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/11/04/macquarie-tips-23-upside-for-resurgent-asx-200-copper-stock-riding-the-red-metals-bull-run/</link><description>Capstone Copper reported a 16.5% year-on-year increase in copper production to 55,280 tonnes in Q3 2025, with a 6% rise in average realized copper price to US$4.49 per pound. The company achieved record adjusted EBITDA of US$249.2 million, up 106% year on year, driven by increased sulphide copper production and lower costs, with C1 cash costs down 15% from Q3 2024. Management reconfirmed full-year 2025 production and cost guidance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>ASX Copper Stock Capstone Shows Strong 23% Upside Potential</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-mining-stocks-commanding-attention-2025/</link><description>Capstone Copper's Q3 2025 results showed a 16.5% increase in copper production to 55,280 tonnes, a 6% improvement in average realized price to US$4.49 per pound, and a 15% reduction in C1 cash costs to $2.42 per pound. The company’s operational improvements and increased sulphide copper production contributed to record earnings, despite geopolitical and environmental challenges affecting global copper supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Highlights Progress on Quebrada Blanca Ramp up, Pathway to Full Potential, and Value Delivery to Shareholders from Merger</title><link>https://www.teck.com/news/news-releases/2025/teck-highlights-progress-on-quebrada-blanca-ramp-up,-pathway-to-full-potential,-and-value-delivery-to-shareholders-from-merger</link><description>Teck reported that mill throughput and recoveries at Quebrada Blanca are on track, with ongoing construction and technology upgrades progressing as planned. The proposed merger with Anglo American aims to create a top five global copper producer with combined production of 1.2 million tonnes, expected to grow to approximately 1.35 million tonnes by 2027, supported by operational synergies and growth opportunities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Hot Stocks: True North Copper, Trigg Minerals, 29Metals</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/04/hot-stocks-true-north-copper-trigg-minerals-29metals/</link><description>29Metals reported new high-grade copper intercepts from its 2025 drilling campaign at the Golden Grove mine, indicating potential for mine life extension and improved mining economics. Trigg Minerals identified a large antimony-bearing hydrothermal system in Utah, defining several high-priority drill targets. These developments highlight ongoing exploration and resource expansion efforts in copper and associated minerals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Glencore said to consider shutting Canada's largest copper plant</title><link>https://www.mining.com/glencore-considers-shutting-canadas-largest-copper-plant/</link><description>Glencore is reportedly planning to wind down its Horne Smelter, Canada's largest copper-metal producing plant, due to the need for steep environmental upgrades. This potential closure could impact copper production capacity in Canada and reflects increasing regulatory pressures on mining operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell 1.8% to $15,235 a ton on the London Metal Exchange, reaching a four-year low due to a gloomy outlook from the Federal Reserve and concerns over higher financing costs. Despite Indonesia considering deep cuts to nickel mining quotas to support prices, the market remains pressured by a wave of new supply and slowing electric-vehicle sales.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's nickel smelters struggle amid oversupply, weak prices</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-s-nickel-smelters-struggle-amid-oversupply-weak-prices</link><description>The Indonesian Nickel Industry Forum (FINI) warns that domestic nickel smelter operators are facing difficulties due to oversupply and weak nickel prices. This reflects broader market challenges as Indonesia is a dominant nickel producer grappling with price pressures.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 4, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103603691/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 120,300 and 123,300 yuan/mt with an average price of 121,800 yuan/mt, down 200 yuan/mt from the previous day, indicating a slight decline in refined nickel prices in China.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 4-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/492274</link><description>Nickel prices decreased to 15,151 USD/T, the lowest since September 2025, reflecting a 0.43% loss over the past four weeks and a 15.33% decline over the last 12 months, highlighting ongoing downward pressure on nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Pacific Nickel to sell Solomon Islands assets, exit Kolosori nickel project</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/pacific-nickel-to-sell-solomon-islands-assets-exit-kolosori-nickel-project-2025-11-04</link><description>Pacific Nickel Mines agreed to sell its Solomon Islands subsidiaries, including the Kolosori nickel project, signaling a strategic exit from these assets amid challenging market conditions for nickel.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's nickel smelters struggle amid oversupply, weak prices</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-s-nickel-smelters-struggle-amid-oversupply-weak-prices</link><description>The Indonesian Nickel Industry Forum (FINI) has warned that domestic nickel smelter operators are facing increasing difficulties due to oversupply and weak nickel prices. This situation is linked to Indonesia's booming nickel intermediate production, which has flooded global markets and pressured prices downward.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel futures fall to over 1-month low amid oversupply from Indonesia</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures dropped below $15,100 per tonne, marking the lowest price in over a month, driven by oversupply from Indonesia. Indonesian nickel production has surged, pushing LME inventories to record highs, with a significant share of Chinese-origin nickel in stocks. In response, Indonesia has tightened production quotas and mining permit regulations to stabilize prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Pacific Nickel to sell Solomon Islands assets, exit Kolosori nickel project</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/pacific-nickel-to-sell-solomon-islands-assets-exit-kolosori-nickel-project-2025-11-04</link><description>Base metals company Pacific Nickel Mines has agreed to sell its subsidiaries in the Solomon Islands, including the Kolosori nickel project, signaling an exit from this nickel production asset. This move reflects strategic adjustments in the company's portfolio amid changing market conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Group urges stronger oversight of PH nickel mining impact</title><link>https://insiderph.com/group-urges-stronger-oversight-of-ph-nickel-mining-impact</link><description>An advocacy group has called for stronger government oversight of nickel mining in the Philippines, highlighting environmental and social impacts such as deforestation, water contamination, and increased climate vulnerability. The group demands that nickel companies address pollution and properly manage mine waste to mitigate harm to local communities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Macro and Fundamentals Present Mixed Signals, SHFE Aluminium Maintains Fluctuating Trend</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/macro-and-fundamentals-present-mixed-signals-shfe-aluminium-maintains-fluctuating-trend-116080</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices remain high amid macroeconomic support and tight supply, but demand weakens due to high prices and environmental production restrictions. Inventories in key domestic regions show slight increases, and downstream purchasing remains weak despite active selling from holders. The market sentiment indexes indicate a decline in both selling and purchasing enthusiasm.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Colorado's Ball Corp. Weathering Trump's Trade War</title><link>https://www.cpr.org/2025/11/04/colorado-ball-corp-trumps-trade-war-tariffs/</link><description>Ball Corp., a major aluminum can producer, reported meeting earnings targets despite challenges from increased aluminum tariffs under Trump's trade policies. The company is raising aluminum can prices by 25-30% to offset tariffs and is managing supply chain disruptions, particularly at its Mexico manufacturing plant. The CEO expressed confidence in managing tariff-related uncertainties while sustaining business momentum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Steel details plans to invest $11B by 2028 across all business segments</title><link>https://abcnews.go.com/Business/wireStory/us-steel-details-plans-invest-11-billion-2028-127184791</link><description>United States Steel, now under Nippon Steel ownership, has announced an $11 billion investment plan to modernize and expand its operations by 2028, aiming to unlock $2.5 billion in savings from capital investments and $500 million from operational efficiencies. The plan includes over 200 cost-saving initiatives, modernization of key facilities, and a focus on higher-value, lower-emission steel production, with the goal of protecting and creating more than 100,000 jobs nationwide.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ero Copper Reports Third Quarter 2025 Operating and Financial Results</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/04/3180959/0/en/Ero-Copper-Reports-Third-Quarter-2025-Operating-and-Financial-Results.html</link><description>Ero Copper announced a record consolidated copper production of 16,664 tonnes in concentrate for Q3 2025, with a blended C1 cash cost of $2.00 per pound. Production increased quarter-on-quarter at the Tucumã operation by 19%, while Caraíba maintained consistent output.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Pacific Nickel Mines to sell Kolosori nickel project to Green Rock</title><link>https://www.mining-technology.com/news/pacific-nickel-mines-sell-kolosori-nickel/</link><description>Pacific Nickel Mines announced the sale of its Kolosori nickel project, a direct shipping ore nickel laterite project on Isabel Island in the South Pacific. This transaction reflects ongoing strategic shifts in nickel project ownership amid evolving market and sustainability considerations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel &amp; Nippon Steel forge $14 billion growth partnership to transform American steel industry</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/us-steel-nippon-steel-forge-14-billion-growth-partnership-to-transform-american-steel-industry/157594</link><description>U.S. Steel and Nippon Steel announced a $14 billion partnership aimed at transforming the American steel industry, marking a new growth era. The collaboration focuses on innovation and expansion to strengthen the domestic steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany Convenes Steel Summit Amid Sector Crisis</title><link>https://www.seaisi.org/details/27464?type=news-rooms</link><description>Germany is holding a steel summit on November 6, 2025, to address the ongoing crisis in the steel sector, focusing on energy prices, trade relations, and sustainability. The meeting aims to protect jobs and ensure the competitiveness of national steel production amid challenges like high energy costs and green transition pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Higher Ahead of Trump-Xi Meeting</title><link>https://www.admis.com/copper-prices-higher-ahead-of-trump-xi-meeting/</link><description>Copper prices rose 0.6% to $11,026/mt on optimism about a US-China trade deal and strong industrial profit growth in China. Despite gains, the Yangshan copper premium shrank, indicating that physical purchases have yet to accelerate significantly. Other base metals also saw gains amid supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>South Africa Approves $708 Million Zeb Nickel Mine Amid Price Slump</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/0511-50146-south-africa-approves-708-million-zeb-nickel-mine-amid-price-slump</link><description>Uru Metals secured a 30-year mining right for its Zeb Nickel Project in South Africa, with a preliminary estimate suggesting an annual capacity of 20,000 metric tons of nickel. The project advances despite a global nickel surplus and falling prices, with the company planning to update its resource estimate and refine exploration targets.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel industry - Part 4 Sustainability considerations for nickel production</title><link>https://nickelinstitute.org/en/blog/?topics=bd913f5b02574bf09aee1b66da7b8ec8%2C0ec099b1b59b4ba6849fa932fa12b47e</link><description>This article discusses sustainability considerations in nickel production, categorizing the mining industry's approaches and highlighting ongoing efforts to improve environmental and social outcomes in nickel extraction and processing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's top cable maker sees US copper tariff as opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Italy's Prysmian, the world's largest copper cable maker, views the US copper tariff as a positive development that supports the American supply chain. Following its acquisition of Texas-based Encore Wire, Prysmian is in close contact with the US administration and expects the tariff to apply to both semi-finished products and raw metal.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Fear of High Prices Intensifies, Secondary Aluminum Trading Turns Sluggish but Cost Support Keeps Prices Firm [SMM Cast Aluminum Alloy Morning Comment]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103604535/Fear-of-High-Prices-Intensifies-Secondary-Aluminum-Trading-Turns-Sluggish-but-Cost-Support-Keeps-Prices-Firm-%5BSMM-Cast-Aluminum-Alloy-Morning-Comment%5D</link><description>The most-traded cast aluminum alloy futures contract showed slight price fluctuations with a closing price down 0.33% amid reduced bullish positions. Despite sluggish secondary aluminum trading, cost support factors maintain firm prices, with regional warrant volumes increasing, indicating ongoing market activity and supply considerations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Macro and Fundamentals present mixed signals, SHFE aluminium maintains fluctuating trend</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/macro-and-fundamentals-present-mixed-signals-shfe-aluminium-maintains-fluctuating-trend-116080</link><description>SHFE aluminum futures showed a fluctuating trend with a slight price pullback but maintained an overall upward trend supported by technical indicators. Macro factors include China's central bank liquidity operations and mixed signals from US Federal Reserve officials regarding interest rate cuts, contributing to cautious market sentiment.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Fear of High Prices Intensifies, Secondary Aluminum Trading Turns Sluggish but Cost Support Keeps Prices Firm</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103604535/Fear-of-High-Prices-Intensifies-Secondary-Aluminum-Trading-Turns-Sluggish-but-Cost-Support-Keeps-Prices-Firm-%5BSMM-Cast-Aluminum-Alloy-Morning-Comment%5D</link><description>Secondary aluminum trading has slowed due to fears of high prices, with the most-traded cast aluminum alloy futures contract showing slight declines. Despite reduced bullish positions and weakening technical indicators, cost support has kept prices relatively firm. Inventory data shows regional variations, with some increases in registered warrants across major Chinese regions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Fully optimised for sustainability - BMW Group PressClub</title><link>https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/global/article/detail/T0409378EN/fully-optimised-for-sustainability?language=en</link><description>BMW Group's light metal foundry in Landshut has been recertified by the Aluminium Stewardship Initiative for sustainable aluminum use, with over one-third of its aluminum sourced from solar power and nearly two-thirds from recycling. This certification highlights BMW's commitment to reducing CO2 emissions and promoting circular economy practices in aluminum production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>First brake caliper made from 100% recycled aluminium sets a benchmark in sustainability</title><link>https://www.aftermarketinternational.com/en/news/latest-news/9552-first-brake-caliper-made-from-100-recycled-aluminium-sets-a-benchmark-in-sustainability.html</link><description>Brembo introduced the first brake caliper made entirely from recycled aluminum, achieving a 70% reduction in CO2 emissions over the component's lifecycle without compromising performance or design. This innovation marks a significant advancement in sustainable automotive parts manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Middle East Iron Steel Conference 2025 Dubai Nov 17-19</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/middle-east-iron-steel-conference-2025/</link><description>The conference highlights the MENA region's steel decarbonisation efforts leveraging natural gas infrastructure and renewable energy for hydrogen-based production. Major projects include Emirates Steel's electric Process-Gas Heater pilot and green hydrogen demonstrations, Oman's Vulcan Green Steel Project targeting 85% CO2 reduction, and Algeria's Tosyali DRI capacity expansion with renewable energy partnerships.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Scaling Near Zero Emissions Iron and Steel</title><link>https://rmi.org/steel/</link><description>RMI is accelerating the transition to low-emissions steel production by improving emissions data transparency and supporting hydrogen-based technologies. Efforts include facilitating clean hydrogen infrastructure, publishing decarbonization roadmaps, and enhancing supply chain emissions reporting to help steel producers meet climate commitments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Breakthrough technologies for steel decarbonisation - OECD</title><link>https://www.oecd.org/en/events/2024/11/breakthrough-technologies-for-steel-decarbonisation.html</link><description>The OECD Steel Committee workshop focuses on emerging steel decarbonisation technologies such as Hydrogen-based Direct Reduced Iron, Carbon Capture and Storage, and Iron Ore Electrolysis. The event addresses challenges like infrastructure, cost, and policy support to enable adoption and diffusion of these technologies globally.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Quality Decline Challenges Green Steel Ambitions</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/iron-ore-quality-decline-green-steel-ambitions-2025/</link><description>Declining iron ore quality poses challenges for green steel production as stricter carbon emissions standards increase the cost of impurities. The industry must adopt integrated strategies including selective mining, processing upgrades, and supply chain partnerships to meet premium material demands and sustainability goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ESAB x Urban Steel Rockstars 2025 - Making Innovation Possible</title><link>https://esab.com/gb/eur_en/about/news-folder/esab-x-urban-steel-rockstars-2025-making-innovation-possible/</link><description>ESAB partners with Urban Steel Rockstars for the 2025 convention in Frankfurt, focusing on innovation in steel technology. The event will showcase advancements and foster collaboration in steel manufacturing and sustainability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 2.40% Lower at $4.9260 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511049592/comex-copper-settles-240-lower-at-49260-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for November delivery dropped 2.40% to $4.9260 per pound, marking a four-day losing streak and the largest four-day decline since August 5, 2025. The price is down 15% from its 52-week high but up 23.58% from its 52-week low, reflecting recent volatility in the copper market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices fall for 5th consecutive day</title><link>https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/business/copper-prices-fall-for-5th-consecutive-day/tldr</link><description>Copper prices have declined for five straight days, currently at $10,625 per ton after reaching a record high last week. The drop is attributed to a global market selloff, cautious investor sentiment, and a stronger US dollar putting pressure on metal prices, alongside concerns about US interest rate cuts and stock market uncertainty.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices fall for the fifth day running after hitting a record high last week</title><link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/commodities/copper-prices-fall-for-the-fifth-day-running-after-hitting-a-record-high-last-week-19742723.htm</link><description>Copper prices fell 0.4% to $10,625 a ton in Shanghai trading, down about 5% from the record high of $11,200 reached on October 29, 2025. The decline continues a five-day losing streak amid a stronger dollar and market caution.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Trump Administration Plans Military Action Against Venezuela Overnight; LME Copper Plummets [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103604522/The-Trump-Administration-Plans-Military-Action-Against-Venezuela-Overnight-LME-Copper-Plummets-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices opened at $10,630.5/mt and closed down 1.57% at $10,649/mt amid geopolitical tensions involving the US and Venezuela. Additionally, Glencore plans to gradually shut down its Horne Smelter in Quebec due to high environmental and operating costs, which may impact copper supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco cuts copper output guidance for 2025 despite higher production through September 2025</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/codelco-cuts-copper-output-guidance-for-2025-despite-higher-production-through-september-2025-11-05</link><description>Codelco, the state-owned copper miner, lowered its copper production guidance for 2025 to between 1.31 million and 1.34 million metric tons, down from previous estimates, despite reporting higher production through September 2025. This adjustment reflects ongoing challenges in the copper market and operational considerations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco cuts copper output guidance for 2025 despite higher production through September</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/codelco-cuts-copper-output-guidance-for-2025-despite-higher-production-through-september-2025-11-05</link><description>Codelco, the state-owned copper miner, lowered its copper production guidance for 2025 to between 1.31 million and 1.34 million metric tons, down from its previous estimate. This revision comes despite reporting higher production through September 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Holds Bearish Momentum</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/499019</link><description>Nickel prices fell to $15,078 per tonne, the lowest since September 2025, continuing a downtrend amid oversupply concerns driven by Indonesia's expanded production. LME stockpiles have risen significantly this year, while demand remains mixed, with weak stainless steel purchasing offset by higher nickel use in electric vehicles.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices dropped to $15,029.50 per tonne, down 0.20% from the previous day and 7.25% year-over-year, reflecting persistent bearish sentiment. The market expects prices to remain subdued, with forecasts suggesting further declines over the next year due to ongoing oversupply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME's nickel price increases by 1.5% on Nov 5</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lmes-nickel-price-increases-by-15-on-nov-5/129989</link><description>The London Metal Exchange (LME) nickel price rose to around $19,434 per tonne, up 1.53% from the previous day, marking a short-term rebound. This contrasts with broader bearish trends seen in other nickel price benchmarks.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fell sharply on November 5 once again approaching the 119,000 yuan/mt mark</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103605685/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fell-sharply-on-November-5-once-again-approaching-the-119000-yuanmt-mark</link><description>On November 5, SMM #1 refined nickel prices in China dropped to a range of 119,400–122,500 yuan/mt, with the average down 850 yuan/mt from the previous day. The decline was attributed to a stronger US dollar and internal Fed disagreements, while spot premiums for domestic brands showed mixed trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Watchdog seeks tighter regulations on nickel mining</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/business/2025/11/05/2484839/watchdog-seeks-tighter-regulations-nickel-mining</link><description>Climate Rights International released a report titled 'Broken Promises,' calling for stricter regulations on nickel mining due to environmental and social concerns. The report highlights ongoing issues with mining practices and their impacts on local communities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Eases from 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/499462</link><description>Aluminum prices eased from their recent three-year high, falling to $2,862 per tonne on November 4, 2025, amid a rebound in the dollar and uncertain demand. Despite the dip, prices remain up 7.63% compared to the same period last year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer slips to USD 2,838.5/t as market steadies</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-slips-to-usd-2-838-5-t-as-market-steadies-for-next-move-116095</link><description>The LME aluminium 3-month Asian Reference Price slipped by USD 9 per tonne to USD 2,850 on November 5, 2025, as the market steadied after recent volatility. The price movement reflects a period of consolidation ahead of the next market move.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel prices fell to 841.98 USD/T on November 5, 2025, down 0.71% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 5.38%, and are up 19.55% compared to the same time last year. The forecast expects HRC Steel to trade at 864.45 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 934.57 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Decline on Fed Uncertainty and Supply Relief</title><link>https://www.indexbox.io/blog/copper-prices-decline-on-fed-uncertainty-and-supply-relief/</link><description>Copper prices dropped as much as 2.4% amid uncertainty over US Federal Reserve monetary policy and easing concerns about global supply. The US dollar strengthened to its highest since May, pressuring metals. Despite a rally earlier in the year due to supply disruptions, expectations of increased output from major producers like Chile's Codelco are easing supply tensions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Decline Driven by Dollar Strength and Supply Shifts</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-price-decline-2025-demand-supply-currency-dynamics/</link><description>Copper prices have experienced a sustained decline due to a stronger US dollar, demand uncertainties, and evolving supply conditions. The correction follows a period of strength driven by infrastructure optimism and supply disruptions, highlighting copper's sensitivity to global economic sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Firm Dollar, Worries About Demand in China Weigh on Copper</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/firm-dollar-worries-about-demand-in-china-weigh-on-copper/</link><description>Copper is expected to trade in a $10,000 to $11,000 range in the near term as a strong US dollar and concerns about Chinese demand weigh on prices. Risk sentiment deterioration and macroeconomic factors continue to influence market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>DRC: Kamoa-Kakula Copper Mine to Get 50 MW from Inga II in November</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/0511-50137-drc-kamoa-kakula-copper-mine-to-get-50-mw-from-inga-ii-in-november</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced that its Kamoa-Kakula copper complex in the DRC will begin receiving 50 MW of power from the Inga II hydroelectric dam this November, with further increases planned as grid upgrades progress. This marks a key step in securing stable energy supply for one of the world's largest copper producers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals for a Sustainable Transition Report</title><link>https://www.sydney.edu.au/sydney-environment-institute/news-analysis/news/2025/11/05/-critical-minerals-for-a-sustainable-transition-report-.html</link><description>This report examines how critical minerals like nickel are essential for the renewable energy transition but also pose environmental, social, and governance challenges. It emphasizes balancing energy security with ecosystem and community protection, advocating for equitable benefit sharing and ecological limits in mineral extraction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali acquisition by Mannesmann Stainless Tubes is complete</title><link>https://stainless-steel-world.net/cogne-acciai-speciali-acquisition-by-mannesmann-stainless-tubes-is-complete/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes GmbH from Salzgitter AG, expanding its production of seamless stainless steel and nickel alloy tubes. The acquisition includes facilities in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, and will strengthen Cogne’s market presence globally. The acquired company will be renamed DMV to emphasize excellence and entrepreneurship.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Dips Slightly to 622,000 mt on Nov 6</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103606812/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-Slightly-to-622000-mt-on-Nov-6</link><description>Social inventory of aluminum ingots in China dipped slightly to 622,000 metric tons on November 6, 2025. Prices closed above most short-term moving averages despite a pullback from intraday highs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Backing in Bell Bay Aluminium</title><link>https://www.premier.tas.gov.au/latest-news/2025/november/backing-in-bell-bay-aluminium</link><description>The Tasmanian government has secured a 12-month power agreement to ensure the immediate future of Bell Bay Aluminium, preserving 550 jobs and $700 million in annual economic activity. The agreement allows time for further negotiations with Rio Tinto and the federal government on a long-term plan for the smelter, which is highlighted as one of Australia's greenest due to its hydroelectric power sourcing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bell Bay Aluminium Deal: Tasmanian Gov 12-Month Agreement</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/tasmanian-government-bell-bay-aluminium-deal-2025/</link><description>Tasmania's government has reached a 12-month emergency deal for Bell Bay Aluminium, safeguarding jobs and the smelter's economic impact. The article compares Bell Bay's 190,000-tonne annual capacity and 94% hydroelectric energy profile favorably against mainland Australian smelters, emphasizing its low-carbon, premium market positioning amid national energy transition challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Secondary Aluminium: Powering India's Green Growth, Circular Economy, and Global Competitiveness</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/secondary-aluminium-powering-indias-green-growth-circular-economy-and-global-competitiveness-116096</link><description>A press release highlights the growing role of secondary (recycled) aluminium in India's green growth strategy and circular economy. It underscores how recycled aluminium is enhancing India's global competitiveness in the metals sector, though specific production or capacity figures are not provided.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Russel Metals Announces 2025 Third Quarter Results</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=690bd77a36ca8728810b704e</link><description>Steel prices increased substantially in early 2025 due to U.S. tariffs, but margins moderated in the third quarter as higher inventory costs impacted profitability. The company expects fourth quarter margins to remain consistent with the end of the third quarter, with seasonal reductions in shipments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Products Market Expanding With $523.49 Billion at 3.8% CAGR by 2029</title><link>https://www.einpresswire.com/article/864489154/steel-products-market-expanding-with-523-49-billion-at-3-8-cagr-by-2029</link><description>The steel products market is projected to grow from $437.06 billion in 2024 to $450.21 billion in 2025, with a CAGR of 3.0%. Growth is expected to continue, reaching $523.49 billion by 2029, driven by infrastructure development, automotive industry demand, and technological advances.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices in the First Week of November 2025</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/37765/</link><description>Steel coil prices showed overall stability in the first week of November 2025, with wire rod prices at $555–565 per ton FOB Turkey and hot-rolled flat steel at $455–460 per ton. The market remains steady with little fluctuation in regional pricing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nucor Increases Hot-Rolled Coil Prices for Second Week</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/germany-convenes-steel-summit-in-light-of-ongoing-crisis-in-the-sector/</link><description>Nucor raised its hot-rolled coil prices to $890 per ton in early November 2025, marking the second consecutive weekly increase. This signals market stabilization and could influence broader price trends in the U.S. steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany Convenes Steel Summit in Light of Ongoing Crisis in the Sector</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/germany-convenes-steel-summit-in-light-of-ongoing-crisis-in-the-sector/</link><description>Germany held a steel summit on November 6, 2025, to address the ongoing crisis in the sector. Government and business leaders discussed support measures for the struggling steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nippon Steel US Market Challenges: $15B Acquisition Losses</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/nippon-steel-us-market-challenges-2025/</link><description>Nippon Steel reported a 356.8 billion yen loss amid challenging US market conditions, excluding American operations from guidance. The steel industry faces a perfect storm of demand weakness and structural changes, with declining construction activity, shifts in automotive steel requirements due to electric vehicles, and energy sector preferences for alternative materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Pipe and Steel Industrial Fabricators Announces Second Expansion in Two Years to Further Strengthen Louisiana’s Industrial Manufacturing Base</title><link>https://www.opportunitylouisiana.gov/news/pipe-and-steel-industrial-fabricators-announces-second-expansion-in-two-years-to-further-strengthen-louisianas-industrial-manufacturing-base</link><description>Pipe and Steel Industrial Fabricators is investing $5.1 million to expand its steel processing and fabrication facility in Livingston Parish, Louisiana, increasing beam-cutting capacity and creating 56 new jobs. The expansion aims to enhance efficiency, safety, and production capacity, supporting growth in Louisiana’s manufacturing sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Baosteel has reduced its steel production targets</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/baosteel-has-reduced-its-steel-production-targets/</link><description>Baosteel has lowered its steel production targets despite a 10.9% increase in production to 5.17 million tons in the first nine months of 2025. The company is likely to exceed the stated target for the year but is adjusting goals in response to market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany convenes steel summit in light of ongoing crisis in the sector</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/germany-convenes-steel-summit-in-light-of-ongoing-crisis-in-the-sector/</link><description>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz has invited government and business leaders to a steel summit on November 6 to discuss support measures for the struggling steel industry amid ongoing crises. The summit aims to find solutions for energy costs, overcapacity, and industry sustainability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World Steel Association: Climate Change and Steel Production</title><link>https://worldsteel.org</link><description>The World Steel Association released a policy paper on November 6, 2025, outlining pathways to reduce CO2 emissions and promote sustainable practices in steel production. The association emphasizes transparent data disclosure, resource efficiency, and a commitment to a low-carbon future.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Just Set a Record. The Market's Already Having Second Thoughts</title><link>https://m.fastbull.com/news-detail/copper-just-set-a-record-the-markets-already-news_4200_0_2025_4_4963_3/4200_GC2511</link><description>Copper prices recently hit a record high but declined 2.6% to $10,897/mt amid concerns that supply shortfalls may be offset by scrap exports and increased mine supply from marginal producers. Analysts from Goldman Sachs suggest copper prices may remain within the $10,000 to $11,000 range without a sustained breakout higher.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Pumpkin Hollow Copper Mine Production Resumption Receives Support, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103606685/Pumpkin-Hollow-Copper-Mine-Production-Resumption-Receives-Support-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Kinterra Capital and Southwest Critical Materials LLC received a non-binding letter of interest from the U.S. Export-Import Bank for up to $220 million to support the restart of the Pumpkin Hollow copper mine, with $180 million earmarked for underground operations and $20 million for technical work on the southern open-pit project. Meanwhile, LME copper futures closed higher at $10,733/mt, up 0.79%, amid active trading.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Kenadyr Provides Operational Update on the Adelita Copper-Gold-Silver Project and Status Update of Reactivation Transaction</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/KNDYF/kenadyr-provides-operational-update-on-the-adelita-copper-gold-wir6mh8avw4r.html</link><description>Kenadyr announced that Phase 1 exploration at the Adelita Copper-Gold-Silver Project in Mexico will begin in November 2025, including drilling and geophysical surveys, as the project prepares for reactivation under new ownership. The project is fully permitted, with final transaction approvals pending.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices were in the doldrums on November 6</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103607793/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-were-in-the-doldrums-on-November-6-as-the-US-ADP-employment-figure-for-October-increased-by-42000-exceeding-market-expectations</link><description>On November 6, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 118,900 and 122,100 yuan per metric ton, averaging 120,500 yuan/mt, which is down 450 yuan/mt from the previous day. The price decline reflects ongoing weakness in the nickel market amid broader economic factors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME's nickel price goes up on Nov 6</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/ru/NewsItem/144578</link><description>Nickel futures prices at the London Metal Exchange increased by over $200 per ton on November 6, closing at $18,445 per ton. The nickel spot price also saw gains, indicating some short-term upward movement despite broader market weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME's nickel prices slightly increase on Nov 6</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lmes-nickel-prices-slightly-increase-on-nov-6/151128</link><description>Nickel futures prices on the London Metal Exchange slightly increased by $4 per ton, closing at $16,127 per ton on November 6. This modest rise contrasts with other reports of price declines, suggesting some volatility in nickel pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103608007/</link><description>Nickel prices remained weak on November 6, 2025, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 120,500 yuan/mt, down 450 yuan/mt from the previous day. The market sentiment was subdued following stronger-than-expected US employment data.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>BofA Sees Growth Potential for Prysmian from US Tariffs</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/bofa-sees-growth-potential-for-prysmian-from-us-tariffs-ce7d59dddf88f323</link><description>Bank of America estimates Prysmian could raise copper cable prices by 10% due to US tariffs, potentially increasing 2026 EBITDA by up to EUR1 billion. Prysmian's copper cable production is largely US-based after acquiring Encore Wire, benefiting from tariffs on imports, especially in medium- and low-voltage segments.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance after reporting Q3 revenue of €5.03 billion, beating expectations. Growth was driven by strong performance in Renewable Transmission and Power Grids units, with a stable high-voltage backlog of about €16 billion supporting future prospects.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>