<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:26:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BHP bets big on Chile's copper boom</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/11/28/bhp-bets-big-on-chiles-copper-boom/</link><description>BHP's Escondida mine increased copper output by 4% to 494,000 tonnes in FY26, driven by record throughput and improved recoveries. Copper demand is forecast to rise 70% between 2021 and 2050, positioning Chile as a key supplier. The ramp-up of new projects like the Full SaL project supports production growth amid strong market demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper breaks above USD11,000 on increased likelihood of US rate cut</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40394482/copper-breaks-above-usd11000-on-increased-likelihood-of-us-rate-cut</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rose 1.3% to $10,963 per metric ton amid growing expectations of a US Federal Reserve rate cut. The price surge reflects optimism about softer monetary policy supporting industrial metals demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Cascabel Copper-Gold Mine Is Expected to Commence Production in 2028</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103644055/The-Cascabel-Copper-Gold-Mine-Is-Expected-to-Commence-Production-in-2028-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>SolGold has accelerated development of its Cascabel copper-gold project in northern Ecuador, with preliminary engineering set to begin in 2026 and first production expected in 2028. The news comes amid fluctuating copper prices and shifting global supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP bets big on Chile's copper boom</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/11/28/bhp-bets-big-on-chiles-copper-boom/</link><description>BHP's Escondida mine in Chile started the 2025–26 financial year with a 4% increase in copper output, reaching 494,000 tonnes. The company is expanding production amid rising global demand and ongoing infrastructure developments.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper smelters idle as China slows</title><link>https://mining.com.au/copper-smelters-idle-as-china-slows/</link><description>Global copper smelting activity declined in October, with inactive capacity rising to 15.1% of world nameplate—the highest this year. China drove most of the decline, with inactivity jumping to 13.8%, while other regions saw modest improvements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's overcapacity crackdown reaches copper, but market impact unlikely</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/chinas-overcapacity-crackdown-reaches-copper-but-market-impact-unlikely-2025-11-28</link><description>China has shelved several planned copper smelters as part of its overcapacity crackdown, but the move is not expected to significantly impact the market. The government's actions are aimed at curbing excess industrial capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On November 28, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 117,000-122,000 yuan/mt, with an average price of 119,500 yuan/mt, up 500 yuan/mt from the previous day</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103644263/</link><description>Nickel prices rebounded slightly on November 28, with the SMM #1 refined nickel average price rising by 500 yuan/mt to 119,500 yuan/mt. This indicates a short-term recovery following the previous day's decline, reflecting ongoing market fluctuations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Base Metal Prices Face Growth Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/28/base-metal-prices-face-growth-uncertainty/</link><description>TD Securities forecasts nickel prices to plateau in 2026 amid global economic growth concerns and potential delays in US interest rate cuts. While Beijing’s stimulus measures may support demand, nickel faces oversupply worries. A modest price rebound is expected in 2027, reflecting cautious market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Base Metal Prices Face Growth Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/28/base-metal-prices-face-growth-uncertainty/</link><description>Financial firm TD Securities forecasts nickel prices to plateau in 2026 with a modest rebound expected in 2027. The outlook reflects concerns about oversupply and cautious market sentiment amid various economic and supply-demand factors affecting base metals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China's Nickel-Free EV Batteries Hit Indonesia's Nickel Plan</title><link>https://chinaglobalsouth.com/2025/11/28/chinas-nickel-free-ev-batteries-hit-indonesias-nickel-plan/</link><description>A new report from Energy Shift Institute highlights how China's development of nickel-free electric vehicle batteries is impacting Indonesia's nickel strategy, potentially affecting demand and market dynamics for nickel producers.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Low-Carbon Metal Premiums: Market Trends &amp; Price Evolution</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/low-carbon-metal-price-premiums-trends-2025/</link><description>The London Metal Exchange (LME) is advancing initiatives to establish low-carbon price premiums for nickel and other metals, incentivizing sustainable production. This market-based mechanism supports decarbonization by financially rewarding environmentally friendly production methods, driven by demand from automotive and battery manufacturing sectors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance after reporting third-quarter revenue and earnings above forecasts, driven by strong growth in Renewable Transmission and Power Grids segments. The company’s performance in North America and Europe, along with a stable high-voltage backlog, supports optimism for future growth, with analysts noting potential benefits from copper tariffs in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rose to 2,873.60 USD/T on November 28, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices increased to $2,873.60 per tonne on November 28, 2025, up 1.42% from the previous day. The rise was driven by macroeconomic tailwinds as key Fed officials signaled support for additional rate cuts and Beijing announced fresh stimulus measures. Over the past month, aluminum prices have fallen 0.38%, but remain 9.51% higher than a year ago.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price hits three-year high as US-China truce buoys outlook</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-hits-three-year-high-as-us-china-truce-buoys-outlook/</link><description>Aluminum futures on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.6% to settle at $2,902 per metric ton, reaching the highest level since May 2022. The rally is supported by tightening supply in China due to state-imposed production caps and an improving demand outlook as trade tensions ease between the US and China.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global alumina production in Oct up 4% on month, says Aluminium Institute</title><link>https://informistmedia.com/CommodityWire/39856/Alumina-Output-Global-alumina-production-in-Oct-up-4-37-on-month-says-Aluminium-Institute</link><description>Global alumina production rose nearly 4% month-on-month to 13.37 million tonnes in October, with China accounting for 62% of global output at 8.21 million tonnes. Production across regions showed growth, with Oceania up over 5%, Africa and Asia (excluding China) up nearly 4%, and global primary aluminium production up nearly 4% to 6.3 million tonnes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rod: Inventory Drawdown, Fees Bottoming Out; Cable Operating Rate Up</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646544/aluminum-rod-inventory-drawdown-fees-bottoming-out-cable-operating-rate-up-demand-weakness-persistent-smm-analysis</link><description>Domestic aluminum rod producers' inventory days decreased to 6.68 days as of November 28, 2025, indicating an inventory drawdown trend with eased supply-side pressure. Aluminum cable operating rate rose to 63%, continuing its moderate recovery trend, though demand weakness persists with year-end approaching and winter temperatures constraining project progress.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Rebounds to Highest in November</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China rose above CNY 3,100 per tonne, reaching the highest level so far in November as lower supply returned to buyers' attention. Crude steel output in China fell 12% annually in October, the lowest for the month since 2021, consistent with China's pledges to cap industries suffering from overcapacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.19 USD/Lbs on November 28, 2025, up 2.15% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices reached 5.19 USD per pound, marking a 2.15% increase from the previous day and a four-week high. The rise is attributed to record-high premiums offered by Chilean producer Codelco to US buyers and expectations of aggressive US Federal Reserve rate cuts, reinforcing a bullish market outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Month 2.37% Higher at $5.1855 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511285171/comex-copper-ends-the-month-237-higher-at-51855-data-talk</link><description>Front-month Comex Copper for December delivery closed at $5.1855 per pound, up 2.37% for the month and marking its fourth consecutive monthly gain. The price remains below its 2025 high but is up nearly 30% from the previous year, reflecting strong market momentum.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco offers US clients copper at record premiums above $500/t</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2025-11-28/codelco-offers-us-clients-copper-record-premiums-above-500t-over-lme</link><description>Chilean copper producer Codelco has offered US customers copper at record premiums exceeding $500 per metric ton, signaling a shift in supply priorities and reinforcing market expectations of a tightening copper market. This move is seen as a response to shifting global trade flows and robust demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Taseko Mines (TGB) Posts Mixed Q3 Performance with Increased Copper Production</title><link>https://stockstotrade.com/news/tasekominesltd-tgb-news-2025_11_28/</link><description>Taseko Mines reported increased copper production and revenue in Q3 2025 despite a slight decrease in adjusted EPS. Operational improvements, reduced costs, and successful equity financing have strengthened the company's financial position, with positive outlooks for production growth and efficiency in 2026 amid strong copper market conditions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's Jiangxi Copper Rejected by SolGold in $1 Billion Takeover Approach</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511284079/chinas-jiangxi-copper-rejected-by-solgold-in-1-billion-takeover-approach</link><description>SolGold's $1 billion takeover bid for China's Jiangxi Copper was rejected, indicating ongoing strategic positioning and consolidation attempts within the copper industry. This development reflects competitive dynamics in copper production and corporate control in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 14,822.63 USD/ton on November 28, down 0.12% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have declined by 3.78%, and are down 7.41% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel inches down ahead of Fed's decision</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-inches-down-ahead-of-feds-decision-47634</link><description>Nickel prices edged lower on November 28 as the US dollar strengthened and Goldman Sachs forecast a further decline to $14,500 per metric ton by December 2026. Market expectations for a Fed rate cut in December remain high.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,873.60 per tonne on November 28, 2025, up 1.42% from the previous day, rebounding from a near one-month low. Despite a slight monthly decline of 0.38%, prices remain 10.48% higher than a year ago, supported by macroeconomic factors including potential rate cuts and stimulus measures in China.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rod: Inventory Drawdown, Fees Bottoming Out; Cable Operating Rate Up, Demand Weakness Persistent (SMM Analysis)</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646544/aluminum-rod-inventory-drawdown-fees-bottoming-out-cable-operating-rate-up-demand-weakness-persistent-smm-analysis/</link><description>As of late November 2025, aluminum rod inventory days decreased to 6.68, signaling a drawdown trend and easing supply pressure. Processing fees remain low, and while cable operating rates improved slightly, demand remains weak due to seasonal and year-end factors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AI Data Centers Crush Aluminum Industry with Power Demand</title><link>https://rollingout.com/2025/11/28/ai-data-centers-crush-aluminum-industry/</link><description>US aluminum smelters are struggling to compete for electricity as tech giants pay premium rates to power AI data centers, increasing pressure on aluminum production capacity and raising concerns about future supply.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 31-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel prices rose to 904 USD/T on November 28, 2025, up 0.33% from the previous day, with a 6.73% monthly increase and a 29.14% year-on-year rise. However, the price recently hit a 31-week low, reflecting ongoing volatility in the global steel market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Firms on Codelco Premium Push</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to 5.19 USD/lb on November 28, 2025, up 2.15% from the previous day, as Chilean producer Codelco offered record-high premiums to Chinese buyers, signaling a shift in market dynamics. The move reinforces a bullish outlook due to a fragile supply-demand balance and expectations of further US Federal Reserve rate cuts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price in London hits new high amid bullish calls</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-in-london-hits-new-high-amid-bullish-calls/</link><description>Copper prices in London reached a record high of $11,210.50 per ton amid bullish sentiment from industry leaders at an Asia gathering, citing tightening supply and the risk of global copper cathode shortages. US copper futures also surged, reflecting strong demand and supply disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US November PCE Lower than Expected, Copper Price Running at Highs</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/102544732</link><description>LME copper prices rose overnight to a high of $10,450 per metric ton, supported by weaker-than-expected US PCE data and expectations of rate cuts. The market remains tight, with prices reflecting ongoing supply constraints and strong demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Market Outlook</title><link>https://www.jpmorgan.com/insights/global-research/commodities/copper-outlook</link><description>J.P. Morgan forecasts copper prices to rise to $12,500 per metric ton in Q2 2026, driven by severe supply disruptions and a projected global refined copper deficit. The market is expected to remain tight, with higher prices likely to persist through 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Market Outlook</title><link>https://www.jpmorgan.com/insights/global-research/commodities/copper-outlook</link><description>Severe supply disruptions, including a fatal mudslide at Indonesia's Grasberg mine and downgraded production at Chile's Quebrada Blanca mine, have tightened the copper market and driven prices higher. J.P. Morgan projects copper prices to reach $12,500/mt in Q2 2026, with a global refined copper deficit of approximately 330,000 metric tons expected in 2026. The report highlights ongoing supply challenges and potential constraints on Chinese refined copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Foran Mining advances rare tier-one copper asset in Saskatchewan</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/video/2025-11-28/foran-mining-advances-rare-tier-one-copper-asset-in-saskatchewan</link><description>Foran Mining is progressing its tier-one copper asset in Saskatchewan, with plans for feasibility studies and construction targeted for 2027 and 2028 respectively, highlighting ongoing development in copper production capacity in North America.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell 1.8% to $15,235 a ton on the London Metal Exchange, hitting a four-year low. The decline is driven by a gloomy outlook from the Federal Reserve and concerns over oversupply despite Indonesia's potential mining quota cuts. The metal has dropped about 8% this year due to new supply from Indonesia and slower electric vehicle sales.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel has a future despite low prices</title><link>https://www.coface.com/news-economy-and-insights/nickel-has-a-future-despite-low-prices</link><description>Nickel prices are at a five-year low, down 9.5% year-on-year, reaching levels not seen since October 2020. Oversupply remains a key issue despite government regulations restricting new smelter investments and planned ore output quota cuts for 2026. Stainless steel demand remains subdued, especially in Asia, but the long-term outlook is supported by growth in electric vehicle markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Hits Highest Since July 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices increased to $904 USD per ton on November 28, 2025, marking a 0.33% daily rise and a 6.73% increase over the past month. Prices are up 29.14% compared to the previous year, with forecasts predicting further increases to $911.59 USD/T by the end of the quarter and $992.41 USD/T within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Samsung's T7 Resurrected SSD Uses 100% Recycled Aluminum</title><link>https://www.techbuzz.ai/articles/samsung-s-t7-resurrected-ssd-uses-100-recycled-aluminum</link><description>Samsung has launched the T7 Resurrected portable SSD, the first in the storage industry to use 100% recycled aluminum sourced from Galaxy smartphone production scraps. The product eliminates the coloring process, showcasing the natural aluminum finish and reducing chemical use, while packaging is made from 100% recycled paper and soy ink. The SSD has already won the 2026 CES Innovation Award in the Sustainability &amp; Energy category.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Samsung Launches New SSD T7 Resurrected</title><link>https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-launches-new-ssd-t7-resurrected</link><description>Samsung's new T7 Resurrected SSD features a body case made entirely from recycled aluminum generated during Galaxy smartphone production, promoting cross-division resource circulation. The manufacturing process avoids coloring, highlighting the natural luster of aluminum and minimizing chemical use, with packaging made from 100% recycled paper and soy ink. The product received the 2026 CES Innovation Award in the Sustainability &amp; Energy category.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Green Steelmaking Innovation: Tech &amp; Climate Impact 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/green-steel-technology-2025-industrial-decarbonisation/</link><description>Green steelmaking using hydrogen technology is revolutionizing manufacturing by cutting emissions by 85-95%. Innovations include electric arc furnace optimization, molten oxide electrolysis, and advanced material handling systems, supported by government investments such as Australia's $500 million Green Iron Investment Fund. Leading countries like those in Europe are advancing commercial-scale hydrogen-based steel production through initiatives like HYBRIT.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>How decarbonizing steel build a greener future</title><link>https://alj.com/en/spotlight-by-fady-jameel/steel-deal-how-could-decarbonizing-steel-help-build-a-greener-future/</link><description>Steel production is undergoing significant innovation to reduce carbon emissions, including electric arc furnaces using less fossil fuel and green hydrogen-based processes. The UAE's Masdar and EMSTEEL have launched a pilot project producing green steel with up to 95% CO₂ emission reduction. Government support and market education are key to overcoming the higher costs of green steel and driving demand for sustainable steel products.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Building a sustainable metals industry</title><link>https://steeltech.bilbaoexhibitioncentre.com/en/building-a-sustainable-metals-industry/</link><description>The steel industry is advancing sustainability through electrification, automation, and digitalization to reduce environmental impact. Events like STEEL TECH 2025 highlight innovations such as the world's first 100% green hydrogen ladle preheater and new electric arc furnace projects, demonstrating industry commitment to sustainable steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Canada Steel Industry Gets Boost, New Protective Measures</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/canada-steel-industry-gets-boost-new-protective-1580087/</link><description>Canada is investing over $100 million starting in 2025-2026 to support its steel industry through modernization, skills development, and protection against foreign steel dumping. Measures include enhanced border controls, ending tariff remissions on imported steel by January 2026, and initiatives to reduce freight costs for Canadian steel transport. The government also plans to implement a Buy Canadian Policy to prioritize domestic steel in large contracts.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Secretary of State Belanger highlights new measures to protect and transform Canada's steel industry</title><link>https://themalaysianreserve.com/2025/11/29/secretary-of-state-belanger-highlights-new-measures-to-protect-and-transform-canadas-steel-industry/</link><description>Secretary of State Belanger announced new measures aimed at protecting and transforming Canada's steel industry, focusing on strengthening domestic production and competitiveness amid global trade challenges. These efforts align with broader government strategies to build a resilient and sustainable steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>NTT DATA partners with Codelco on AI‑driven copper mining</title><link>https://news.outsourceaccelerator.com/ntt-data-partners-with-codelco-on-ai%E2%80%91driven-copper-mining/</link><description>NTT DATA has partnered with Codelco to implement AI-driven technologies in copper mining, aiming to enhance operational efficiency and sustainability. This collaboration represents a significant step in integrating advanced digital solutions to optimize copper extraction and processing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price rebounds on Nov 29</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/nickel-price-rebounds-on-nov-29/99539</link><description>On November 29, the three-month futures price of nickel on the London Metal Exchange surged by US$250/ton to US$11,055/ton, with the spot price also rising. This rebound comes amid ongoing volatility and fluctuating market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Analysis: Nickel giants under pressure</title><link>https://www.thejakartapost.com/opinion/2025/11/29/analysis-nickel-giants-under-pressure.html</link><description>Nickel futures prices have trended downward, reaching US$14,550 in November, one of the lowest levels since early 2021. Despite government efforts to cut mining quotas, oversupply persists, with LME inventories rising significantly.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>BUMA International posts weaker 9M25, stronger 3Q recovery</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/buma-international-posts-weaker-9m25-stronger-3q-recovery</link><description>BUMA International reported weaker financial results for the first nine months of 2025, but showed a stronger recovery in the third quarter. The article covers the company's performance in mining and coal operations, though specific nickel production details are not highlighted.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>TGEM Targets 3,200 Tons of Class 1 Nickel MHP Production in 2025 with Enhanced STAL Technology Capabilities</title><link>https://tgem.group/category/tgem-press-release/</link><description>Trinitan Green Energy Metals announced a strategic target to produce 3,200 tons of sustainable Class 1 nickel Mixed Hydroxide Precipitate (MHP) in 2025, leveraging enhanced STAL technology. This production ramp-up supports sustainable nickel supply for electric vehicle and high-tech industries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (November 24, 2025 - November 28, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-november-24-2025-a-november-28-2025-on-the-ce7d51dbda8ff122</link><description>Tenaris published its weekly report covering share buyback activities from November 24-28, 2025. As of November 28, 2025, the company held 41,950,073 ordinary shares in treasury equal to 3.91% of total issued share capital. The report details share purchases across multiple trading venues with weighted average prices around EUR 17.17-17.31.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Sortera Raises $45 Million to Scale AI Driven Aluminum Upcycling</title><link>https://esgnews.com/sortera-raises-45-million-to-scale-ai-driven-aluminum-upcycling/</link><description>Sortera secured $45 million to expand its AI-enabled aluminum sorting platform and build a second U.S. facility in Tennessee by summer 2026. The technology transforms mixed aluminum scrap into targeted alloys, reducing energy demand by up to 95% compared to virgin metal production, significantly lowering carbon emissions and supporting domestic circular manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Rise of AI-Driven Aluminum Recycling and Sortera's Path to a $10B Market Opportunity</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/rise-ai-driven-aluminum-recycling-sortera-path-10b-market-opportunity-2511/</link><description>Sortera Technologies leads AI-driven aluminum recycling achieving 98% purity and 95% energy savings over primary production. Supported by $45M funding and partnerships, the company targets aerospace and automotive sectors with high-value alloy sorting, positioning the market to grow at 4.83% CAGR to 49.82 million tons by 2030, driven by ESG mandates and carbon pricing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Belgium increased steel production by 3.4% m/m in October 2025</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Belgium's steel production rose by 3.4% month-over-month in October 2025. Other notable steel market developments include Spain's 5.4% year-over-year production increase in the first half of 2025, Turkey's 8.3% production decrease in June, and ArcelorMittal's temporary blast furnace shutdown in Poland due to import pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Steel at a Crossroads: IEEFA Says India Needs Smarter Public Financing to Drive Decarbonisation and Energy Security</title><link>https://solarquarter.com/2025/11/29/green-steel-at-a-crossroads-ieefa-says-india-needs-smarter-public-financing-to-drive-decarbonisation-and-energy-security/</link><description>India requires strategic deployment of public capital to bridge the financing gap for green steel projects and prevent carbon lock-in. The article emphasizes the importance of targeted public finance mechanisms to scale green steel production and promote sustainable steelmaking for the country's future energy security.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Super Copper and MetaFLO Announce Joint Venture to Develop Biopolymer Solutions for Copper Mining</title><link>https://www.metaflotech.com/super-copper-and-metaflo-announce-joint-venture-to-develop-biopolymer-solutions-for-copper-mining/</link><description>Super Copper and MetaFLO have formed a joint venture to co-develop innovative, eco-friendly biopolymer solutions aimed at improving copper extraction and remediation. These biopolymers are designed to reduce environmental impact, optimize operational efficiency, and support regulatory compliance in copper mining, with pilot testing planned in Chile.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>QMB nickel project in Indonesia is back to normal output</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3X702T:0-qmb-nickel-project-in-indonesia-is-back-to-normal-output-shareholder-gem-says/</link><description>The QMB nickel-cobalt project in Indonesia has resumed normal production after being forced to slash output by at least half in November due to safety checks on ore-waste storage. The project, with an annual capacity of 96,000 metric tons of nickel equivalent, is proceeding with its December output plan as scheduled.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Off-season atmosphere deepens, proportion of liquid aluminum expected to drop further in December</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/off-season-atmosphere-deepens-proportion-of-liquid-aluminum-expected-to-drop-further-in-december-116385</link><description>Domestic aluminum production in November 2025 increased 1.47% year-on-year but fell 2.82% month-on-month as the industry transitioned into the off-season. The proportion of liquid aluminum dropped to 77.3%, with a forecasted further decline to 76.6% in December due to lower downstream demand and new processing capacity coming online.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SSAB Americas Raises Prices for Rolled Steel by at Least $40/t</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/ssab-americas-raises-prices-for-rolled-steel-by-at-least-40-t/</link><description>For the week of November 24-30, 2025, spot prices for HRC in the U.S. increased to $915/t, up from $910/t the previous week, with thick sheet offered at $1015/t. The increase reflects tightening supply and strong demand in the North American market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaker Nam Kim to explore tin-nickel coated steel production for EV battery shells</title><link>https://theinvestor.vn/steelmaker-nam-kim-to-explore-tin-nickel-coated-steel-production-for-ev-battery-shells-d17743.html</link><description>Vietnamese steelmaker Nam Kim plans to develop tin-nickel coated steel for electric vehicle battery shells through joint ventures with technologically capable partners. The company reported a revenue decline of 27% in Q3 2025 due to weaker market demand but is focusing on innovation in steel products for EV applications.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaker Nam Kim to explore tin-nickel coated steel production for EV battery shells</title><link>https://theinvestor.vn/steelmaker-nam-kim-to-explore-tin-nickel-coated-steel-production-for-ev-battery-shells-d17743.html</link><description>Vietnamese steelmaker Nam Kim has approved a plan to assess the feasibility of producing tin-nickel coated steel for electric vehicle battery shells. The company aims to leverage existing production capabilities and invest in new equipment, with future plans to collaborate with technically capable partners through joint ventures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Re-energising the nickel industry through sustainable battery production</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/re-energising-nickel-industry-through-sustainable-battery-production/29252/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals is advancing sustainable nickel production through its TECH Project, which will process high-grade nickel laterite ore imported from New Caledonia using the patented DNi Process™. The project aims to be carbon negative and supply ethically derived nickel and cobalt for EV and energy storage industries, with binding offtake agreements in place with LG Energy Solution and POSCO.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Future of Nickel Alloy Innovations in Sustainable Manufacturing</title><link>https://www.eraumalloy.com/blog/nickel-alloy-innovations-in-sustainable-manufacturing/</link><description>Nickel alloys are driving sustainable manufacturing by improving battery performance and longevity, reducing environmental footprints in industries such as automotive, aerospace, and energy. Innovations focus on advanced processing and recycling to create lighter, stronger, and corrosion-resistant alloys, which help reduce resource consumption and carbon emissions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Strengthen Indonesia's Global Nickel Leadership, PT Vale Indonesia and Huayou Commits to Climate-Aligned Technology Pathways at COP30</title><link>https://vale.com/w/strengthen-indonesia-s-global-nickel-leadership-pt-vale-indonesia-and-huayou-commits-to-climate-aligned-technology-pathways-at-cop30</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia is implementing technological innovations such as heat recovery, off-gas utilization, and electrification to reduce absolute emissions by 33% and carbon intensity by 50% by 2030. These efforts support climate goals and operational efficiencies, positioning Indonesia as a leader in responsible, low-carbon nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>BYD's Blade Battery: Reducing Reliance on Nickel and Cobalt</title><link>https://miningdigital.com/news/how-byds-blade-battery-could-shift-mineral-demand</link><description>BYD's Blade Battery innovation reduces reliance on nickel and cobalt, lowering ecological damage from mining and supporting sustainability goals. The company aims for carbon neutrality by 2045 and significant carbon intensity reductions by 2030, with initiatives including recycling and reuse of packaging materials to reduce industrial waste.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Climate-friendly metals can come from deep-sea ores</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-climate-friendly-metals-deep-sea.html</link><description>A new process using hydrogen reduction to extract nickel, cobalt, and copper from deep-sea ores can reduce CO2 emissions by over 90% compared to traditional carbon-based methods. This technology also requires less energy and fewer steps, offering a more sustainable approach to meeting the growing demand for critical metals in battery production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>New research could revolutionize the global aluminum industry - UNB</title><link>https://blogs.unb.ca/newsroom/2025/10/aluminum-industry.php</link><description>Researchers at the University of New Brunswick developed a closed-loop, low-energy aluminum digestion process that improves aluminum smelting efficiency and sustainability while generating clean hydrogen gas. This innovation supports decarbonizing the aluminum industry and aims to create a circular economy by using waste and salvage aluminum as source materials.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Jiangxi Copper Shares Climb After SolGold Rejects $1 Billion Takeover Bid</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511301274/jiangxi-copper-shares-climb-after-solgold-rejects-1-billion-takeover-bid</link><description>Shares of Jiangxi Copper rose after its $1 billion bid to acquire U.K.-listed SolGold was rejected. The dealmaking reflects ongoing efforts by mining companies to secure copper supplies amid a tight market. Jiangxi Copper holds a 12.2% stake in SolGold and plans to announce its intentions by December 26.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Breakthrough Tech Yields 99% Pure Nickel, Cobalt</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/breakthrough-tech-yields-99-pure-nickel-cobalt-1566990/</link><description>A UNIST research team has developed an innovative recycling technology that recovers over 95% of nickel and cobalt from waste batteries with purity exceeding 99%. This selective electrochemical separation process is environmentally friendly, reducing chemical use and wastewater compared to conventional methods, promising a sustainable revolution in battery recycling.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>CVA and Cogne Acciai Speciali sign first Energy Release contract in Aosta Valley</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali (CAS) and CVA Group signed an Energy Release contract, the first in the Aosta Valley and among the first nationally. The agreement involves CAS requesting an advance of 272,075 MWh of electricity from a total of 593,600 MWh expected by 2026, supporting energy transition goals and reducing environmental impact in line with regional and European plans.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of its green hydrogen production project at its Aosta plant. The project uses a 1.008 MW Anion Exchange Membrane electrolyzer to produce 165 tons of green hydrogen annually, aiming to reduce carbon emissions and power one of its 70 furnaces entirely. The initiative is supported by €7.9 million from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Macro Sentiment Dominates Marginal Improvement in Fundamentals; Aluminum Prices Expected to Fluctuate at Highs in Short-Term</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103647032/Macro-Sentiment-Dominates-Marginal-Improvement-in-Fundamentals-Aluminum-Prices-Expected-to-Fluctuate-at-Highs-in-Short-Term-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME aluminum prices closed at $2,865/mt, up 1.18%, with trading volumes increasing as year-end demand from automakers and policy-driven front-loading support prices. Despite sluggish market activity, secondary aluminum demand remains resilient, supported by full order books in the automotive sector and high raw material costs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory in Two Regions Remains Flat at 83,500 mt on Dec 1, 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103647181/SMM:-Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Remains-Flat-at-83500-mt-on-Dec-1-2025</link><description>Secondary aluminum alloy prices are expected to fluctuate within a range in the short term with resilient price support. Inventory levels remain stable, and market activity shows cautious optimism with increased downstream stocking and year-end demand pushes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingots Inventory Remains Flat WoW on Dec 1 – SMM Stats Show</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646973/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Remains-Flat-WoW-on-Dec-1-SMM-Stats-Show</link><description>On December 1, 2025, the inventory of aluminum ingots in major domestic consumption areas in China was recorded at 596,000 metric tons, remaining flat week-on-week. Domestic aluminum production in November 2025 increased 1.47% year-on-year but decreased 2.82% month-on-month.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory in Two Regions Remains Flat at 83,500 mt on Dec 1, 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103647181/SMM:-Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Remains-Flat-at-83500-mt-on-Dec-1-2025</link><description>On December 1, 2025, domestic aluminum billet inventory in two major regions stood at 83,500 metric tons, unchanged from the previous week. Production data for November 2025 showed a year-on-year increase of 1.47% but a month-on-month decrease of 2.82%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum – Price – Chart – Historical Data – News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to 2,873.60 USD/tonne on November 28, 2025, up 1.42% from the previous period. The market continues to face supply pressures due to China’s output cap and production disruptions in Iceland and Australia.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Macro Sentiment Dominates; Marginal Improvement in Fundamentals – Aluminum Prices Expected to Fluctuate at Highs in Short Term [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103647032/Macro-Sentiment-Dominates-Marginal-Improvement-in-Fundamentals-Aluminum-Prices-Expected-to-Fluctuate-at-Highs-in-Short-Term-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Aluminum prices fluctuated upward in early December, supported by year-end demand and high raw material costs. Inventory levels remained stable, while production in China saw a slight year-on-year increase but a month-on-month decline.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Constellium SE to Showcase Innovations in Aluminum Products at the 2025 Paris Air Show</title><link>https://www.quiverquant.com/news/Constellium+SE+to+Showcase+Innovations+in+Aluminum+Products+at+the+2025+Paris+Air+Show</link><description>Constellium SE will present innovative aluminum products emphasizing sustainability and performance, including its first aluminum ingot made from end-of-life aircraft in collaboration with TARMAC Aerosave and Airbus. The company highlights advancements in sustainable aviation and next-generation wing technologies, promoting a circular economy in aerospace.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>IAI Reports Progress In Greenhouse Gas Reduction Initiative</title><link>https://international-aluminium.org/iai-reports-progress-in-greenhouse-gas-reduction-initiative/</link><description>The International Aluminium Institute announced progress in its greenhouse gas reduction initiative, with 80% of members setting long-term net-zero targets and many aiming for a 50% reduction in emissions by 2030. The industry is investing in technologies like inert anode technology, carbon capture, and renewable energy to achieve decarbonization goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ball, Unilever show green aluminium can work</title><link>https://miningbeacon.com/industry/ball-unilever-show-green-aluminium-can-work</link><description>Ball and Unilever demonstrated the use of green aluminum combining 50% ELYSIS low-carbon primary aluminum and 50% post-consumer recycled content for aerosol cans. The ELYSIS process, developed by Alcoa and Rio Tinto, eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions from smelting using inert anode technology, marking a significant step in decarbonizing aluminum packaging.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Net Zero Innovation Hub for Data Centers and Phinergy Sign Strategic Collaboration to Validate Clean Aluminum-Air Generator (AAG) for Energy Resilience in Large-Scale Data Centers</title><link>https://www.netzerodatacenters.com/hub-and-phinergy-sign-strategic-collaboration-to-validate-clean-aluminum-air-generator-aag-for-energy-resilience-in-large-scale-data-centers</link><description>The Net Zero Innovation Hub and Phinergy partnered to validate aluminum-air generator technology that produces clean, zero-emission electricity from aluminum for data centers. This recyclable energy vector offers high energy density and grid resilience, supporting the transition to net-zero operations in cloud and AI-driven data centers.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vice trade minister expresses regret over Canada's stronger steel safeguard plan</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-12-01/business/economy/Vice-trade-minister-expresses-regret-over-Canadas-stronger-steel-safeguard-plan/2466844</link><description>South Korea's Vice Trade Minister Park Jung-sung expressed regret over Canada's announcement of stronger steel safeguard measures, which reduce tariff rate quotas for steel imports from countries with free trade agreements, including Korea. The measures, effective December 26, 2025, may burden Korea's steel industry amid global oversupply and trade protectionism, potentially affecting Korean investments in Canada.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fire Occurs at Nippon Steel's Hokkaido Plant; No One Injured</title><link>https://www.nippon.com/en/news/yjj2025120100215/</link><description>A fire occurred at Nippon Steel Corp.'s North Nippon Works in Muroran, Hokkaido, Japan, early Monday morning after an explosion at a hot-air stove. The fire was brought under control around 8 a.m., and no injuries were confirmed, though the company suspended blast furnace operations to ensure safety and is assessing potential damage to other facilities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vice trade minister expresses regret over Canada's stronger steel safeguard plan</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-12-01/business/economy/Vice-trade-minister-expresses-regret-over-Canadas-stronger-steel-safeguard-plan/2466844</link><description>South Korea's Vice Trade Minister Park Jung-sung expressed concern over Canada's new steel safeguard measures announced this week, which will reduce tariff rate quotas for Korean steel imports starting December 26. The measures include a 25 percent tariff on steel derivative imports and represent additional trade protectionism affecting Korea's already struggling steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Arab Steel Summit 2025: MENA steel demand yet to reflect record project activity</title><link>https://metalexpert.com/en/latestissue?select=MK_WSNPLUS&amp;issue=3996</link><description>The Arab Steel Summit 2025 highlighted a disconnect between record project activity in the Middle East and North Africa region and actual steel demand levels. The report suggests ongoing challenges in converting project announcements into sustained demand for regional steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cut in December Rise, LME Copper Surged Significantly</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646957/Expectations-for-US-Fed-Interest-Rate-Cut-in-December-Rise-LME-Copper-Surged-Significantly-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper closed at $11,175.5/mt with a 2.25% gain, driven by expectations of a US Federal Reserve interest rate cut in December and concerns about tight copper supply following Chile's 7% YoY production decline in October. The US dollar came under pressure as markets priced in dovish Fed policy, providing support for copper prices amid long-term contract negotiations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.23 USD/Lbs on December 1, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices reached 5.23 USD/Lbs, up 0.89% from the previous day and 27.74% year-over-year, as US futures tested their highest level in four months amid supply concerns. Mine disruptions from major producers including Freeport-McMoRan's Grasberg mine in Indonesia and production slowdowns in Chile and Peru have driven sellers to raise prices, while markets price in an 85% probability of a 25 basis point Fed rate cut in December.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold prices rise modestly, silver and copper hit record highs</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/59218/gold-prices-rise-modestly-silver-and-copper-hit-record-highs</link><description>Copper reached record highs alongside silver as precious and industrial metals rallied on December 1, 2025, reflecting broader market strength driven by supply constraints and monetary policy expectations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper sets record high as top Chinese smelters plan to cut output</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3X701R:0-copper-sets-record-high-as-top-chinese-smelters-plan-to-cut-output/</link><description>Copper prices reached new record highs as major Chinese copper smelters agreed to cut production by over 10% in 2026 to address negative processing fees. Chile's Codelco, the world's largest copper producer, also raised copper premiums significantly, influencing market dynamics and contributing to the price surge.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cut in December Rise, LME Copper Surged Significantly Last Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646957/Expectations-for-US-Fed-Interest-Rate-Cut-in-December-Rise-LME-Copper-Surged-Significantly-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices rose sharply last Friday, closing at $11,175.5/mt, supported by expectations of a US Federal Reserve interest rate cut in December and a weaker US dollar. Chile's copper production fell 7% year-on-year in October, intensifying concerns about tight supply and supporting bullish copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Asia Market Quick Take – December 1, 2025</title><link>https://www.home.saxo/en-sg/content/articles/macro/asia-market-quick-take--december-1-2025-01122025</link><description>Copper prices surged to record levels amid concerns over global operational disruptions in mining and smelting. LME copper futures hit a record $11,210.50 per tonne, driven by supply tightness and bullish market sentiment following meetings of miners, smelters, and traders in Shanghai.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper hits record high as global supply concerns intensify</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/copper-hits-record-high-as-global-supply-concerns-intensify</link><description>Copper prices surged to a record high on the London Metal Exchange due to intensifying global supply concerns. The market is reacting to production cuts and supply disruptions, pushing prices to unprecedented levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Announces Leadership Appointments</title><link>https://www.ivanhoemines.com/news-stories/news-release/ivanhoe-mines-announces-leadership-appointments/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced leadership appointments as it prepares to issue copper production guidance for its Kamoa-Kakula project for 2026 and 2027. The company is advancing multiple copper projects in Southern Africa, including expansions and new developments aimed at increasing copper output.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Australian Gold and Copper Unveils High-Grade Drilling Results at Achilles Project</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/stocks/gold/australian-gold-and-copper-unveils-high-grade-drilling-results-at-achilles-project</link><description>Australian Gold and Copper reported high-grade drilling results at its Achilles copper project, indicating promising potential for copper resource expansion. The results support ongoing exploration and development efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Larvotto eyes Blockade copper mine opportunity</title><link>https://industryqld.com.au/larvotto-eyes-blockade-copper-mine-opportunity/</link><description>Larvotto Resources secured an option to acquire the Blockade copper mine, previously mined for high-grade copper in the 1980s. This move reflects Larvotto's strategy to expand its copper production capacity through acquisition and development of existing assets.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Monday Report - 01 December 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/12/01/the-monday-report-01-december-2025/</link><description>Nickel prices showed a slight increase, with the London Metal Exchange nickel price rising by 0.36% to $6.65 per pound. The report highlights a positive trend for base metals including nickel, amid expectations of a Federal Reserve rate cut in December and ongoing commodity market movements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On December 1, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103648236/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 119,750 yuan per metric ton on December 1, up 250 yuan from the previous day, indicating a slight upward movement in refined nickel prices in the Chinese market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM High-Grade NPI] Price Trends Diverge, Outlook Bleak for Next Week</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646634/SMM-High-Grade-NPI:-Price-Trends-Diverge-Outlook-Bleak-for-Next-Week</link><description>High-grade nickel pig iron (NPI) prices are expected to remain weak in the coming week, with refined nickel prices projected to decline again. The report reflects a cautious market sentiment amid ongoing price pressures in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>EcoPro completes Hungary cathode plant, leverages Indonesian nickel</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/ecopro-completes-hungary-cathode-plant-leverages-indonesian-nickel</link><description>South Korea's EcoPro has completed construction of its first European cathode plant in Debrecen, Hungary. The facility will leverage Indonesian nickel supplies for battery material production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Eagle Mine and Allonnia: Nickel Purification Breakthrough 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/eagle-mine-nickel-production-2025-d-solve-technology/</link><description>Eagle Mine and Allonnia have developed the D-Solve technology that reduces nickel impurities by 40% and increases concentrate grade by 18%. This biological innovation enhances nickel recovery from low-grade ores while reducing environmental impact, supporting sustainability and economic goals in nickel mining for clean energy applications.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali obtains ResponsibleSteel™ certification</title><link>https://www.responsiblesteel.org/issued-certificates-and-ongoing-audits</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali S.p.A has received the ResponsibleSteel™ Core Site Certification, reflecting its commitment to sustainability and responsible steel production. This certification aligns with the company's ongoing efforts to reduce environmental impact and promote transparency in its operations.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>