<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 06:09:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aluminum and copper prices take breather after explosive start to 2026</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-and-copper-prices-take-breather-after-explosive-start-to-2026/</link><description>Aluminum prices steadied at $3,197.50 a ton on the LME, the highest in over three years, following a strong start to 2026 amid bullish industrial metals run. Concerns include potential softening Chinese demand and geopolitical risks from US tariffs on countries trading with Iran.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Prysmian signs €2.3 billion contract for UK power link project</title><link>https://au.investing.com/news/company-news/prysmian-signs-23-billion-contract-for-uk-power-link-project-93CH-4235199</link><description>Italian cable maker Prysmian has signed a contract worth over €2.3 billion with SP Energy Networks and National Grid to build a power link between Scotland and England. The project, called Eastern Green Link 4, will connect the electrical grids of Scotland and England as part of a significant infrastructure project for the Italian firm.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>US ALUMINUM: Historically wide spreads in prime scrap market change 2026 contract behavior</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/020226-us-aluminum-historically-wide-spreads-in-prime-scrap-market-change-2026-contract-behavior</link><description>Wide spreads in US aluminum scrap markets, driven by record Midwest premiums, tariff uncertainty, and supply-demand shifts, are disrupting 2026 contracts. UBC scrap prices averaged 111.25 cents/lb in January, at 46% of MWT costs, down from prior norms. Buyers and sellers hesitate on long-term deals amid policy volatility and scrap gluts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Soar to Four-Year High, Creating a Divide in U.S. Industry</title><link>https://nai500.com/blog/2026/02/aluminum-prices-soar-to-four-year-high-creating-a-divide-in-u-s-industry/</link><description>Aluminum prices on the LME have reached four-year highs, with US premiums exceeding $1 per pound, benefiting upstream producers like Alcoa and Century Aluminum while straining downstream manufacturers. Century Aluminum's Mt. Holly facility will add only 50,000 tons of capacity soon, insufficient to ease the supply deficit. Chinese producers profit from exports amid global tightness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Robin Zeng: Unlocking the Sustainable Energy Era with Zero Carbon Technology</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/robin-zeng-unlocking-the-sustainable-energy-era-with-zero-carbon-technology-302679261.html</link><description>Dr. Robin Zeng, Chairman and CEO of CATL, discussed the future of sustainable energy, highlighting renewable energy applications and grid-forming energy storage technology. CATL has achieved industry-leading recovery rates of 99.6% for nickel and cobalt, and 96.5% for lithium, demonstrating commitment to circular economy principles in zero-carbon energy systems.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Pipe producer tightens its grip on giant Black Sea project with double contract win</title><link>https://www.offshore-energy.biz/pipe-producer-tightens-its-grip-on-giant-black-sea-project-with-double-contract-win/</link><description>Tenaris secured a double contract win for the Sakarya Gas Project in the Black Sea. The contracts involve providing advanced tubular and pipeline solutions for Phase 3 development in ultra-deepwater conditions. This strengthens Tenaris's involvement in Turkey's major offshore gas initiative.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel Stocks Rebound In 2026 | Demand, Prices, Margins In Focus</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m_gwQIwtIrM</link><description>Metal stocks are rebounding in early 2026 due to improving demand, stable pricing, easing input costs, and better margins after a subdued 2025. Steel prices rose 3% month-on-month in December, with HRC up 2%, followed by January hikes. Volumes and prices are expected to inch higher amid higher supply outlook.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Futures Decline Across Most Contracts on February 4, 2026</title><link>https://www.indexbox.io/blog/copper-futures-decline-across-most-contracts-on-february-4-2026/</link><description>Copper futures prices fell across most contracts on February 4, 2026, with the high-volume March contract closing at 5.9755 dollars per pound, down 0.1110. The February contract dropped modestly to 5.9855 dollars per pound. Trading volume was lower, and near-term contracts showed a downward trend.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Momentum Technologies advances dual-track US processing for rare earths and battery materials</title><link>https://www.mining.com/momentum-technologies-advances-dual-track-us-processing-for-rare-earths-and-battery-materials/</link><description>Momentum Technologies has commissioned a demonstration plant near Dallas, Texas with proprietary membrane solvent extraction (MSX) technology that compresses traditional solvent extraction into compact membrane reactors. The facility can process both battery materials and rare earth elements, with rare earth commissioning expected in mid-February 2026.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Robin Zeng: Unlocking the Sustainable Energy Era with Zero-Carbon Technology</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/robin-zeng-unlocking-the-sustainable-energy-era-with-zero-carbon-technology-302679261.html</link><description>Dr. Robin Zeng, Chairman and CEO of CATL, discussed the future of sustainable energy, highlighting CATL's achievements in renewable energy deployment and circular economy initiatives. The company has achieved industry-leading recovery rates of 99.6% for nickel and cobalt, and is developing innovative grid-forming energy storage technology to stabilize zero-carbon power systems.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Electric Plans Expanded Copper, Nickel Exploration in Côte d'Ivoire in 2026</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/0502-52620-ivanhoe-electric-plans-expanded-copper-nickel-exploration-in-cote-d-ivoire-in-2026</link><description>Ivanhoe Electric plans to accelerate copper and nickel exploration at the Samapleu-Grata project in Côte d'Ivoire, launching a 4,500-meter diamond drilling campaign across 20 strategic targets starting in February. A 2024 study estimates the project could produce 887,414 tonnes of nickel concentrate over a mine life of 16.1 years.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Aluminum Casting Market to Reach US$ 129.42 Billion by 2033 Driven by Automotive Lightweighting and EV Adoption</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2026/02/04/3231863/0/en/Global-Aluminum-Casting-Market-to-Reach-US-129-42-Billion-by-2033-Driven-by-Automotive-Lightweighting-and-EV-Adoption-Astute-Analytica.html</link><description>The aluminum casting market is growing due to real-time sensor technology enabling precise monitoring, reducing defects in casting for automotive and EV applications. Sustainability drives adoption of recycled aluminum through advanced techniques like high-integrity and vacuum die castings, meeting high-performance needs in aerospace and defense. This supports circular economy principles and environmental responsibility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Early February 2026 Steel Pipe Market: Navigating the Peak of the Annual Holiday Hiatus</title><link>https://www.sanonpipe.com/news/early-february-2026-steel-pipe-market-navigating-the-peak-of-the-annual-holiday-hiatus/</link><description>Asian steel pipe markets, including seamless and welded pipes, face a complete production halt due to Lunar New Year shutdowns, with logistics at minimal capacity and no spot availability. Production is expected to ramp up progressively post-holiday to fulfill backlogged orders for oil, gas, power, and infrastructure projects. This pause allows strategic preparation amid stable price foundations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Goldman, Macquarie raise average nickel price forecasts for 2026 on tighter Indonesian supplies</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/02/04/goldman-macquarie-raises-average-nickel-price-forecasts-for-2026-on-tighter-indonesian-supplies</link><description>Goldman Sachs raised its 2026 nickel price forecast to $17,200 per ton from $14,800, citing Indonesia's reduced ore supply to 260 million wet tons. Prices could peak at $18,700 per ton in Q2 2026 before falling to $15,500 by year-end due to later supply increases. Macquarie lifted its LME nickel forecast to $17,750 per ton, projecting a smaller global surplus of 90,000 tonnes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Can-ification: Aluminium's Role in Circular Packaging</title><link>https://whattheythink.com/news/129149-can-ification-aluminiums-role-circular-packaging/</link><description>This article discusses aluminum cans as trusted solutions for sustainable beverage packaging, emphasizing their role in circular economy initiatives and sustainable packaging practices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 971.06 USD/T on February 5, 2026, down 0.51% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 4.08%. Forecasts indicate trading at 986.72 USD/T by quarter-end and 1065.02 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 05.02.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>Daily updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar terms and regional futures for Turkey, China, Europe, and North America as of February 3-4, 2026. Provides indices, analyses, and market comments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Pull Back Sharply, Downstream Users Replenish Stocks Moderately, Spot Premiums Rise Significantly [SMM Southern China Spot Copper]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103756613-Copper-Prices-Pull-Back-Sharply-Downstream-Users-Replenish-Stocks-Moderately-Spot-Premiums-Rise-Significantly-SMM-Southe</link><description>Spot copper prices in Guangdong fell sharply, with #1 copper cathode averaging 101,565 yuan/mt, down 3,075 yuan/mt from the previous day. Downstream users moderately replenished stocks amid the pullback, while traders actively purchased for arbitrage, leading to improved trading and significantly higher spot premiums. Guangdong inventory increased slightly due to higher arrivals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Retreat Amid Demand Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/02/05/copper-prices-retreat-amid-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices reversed earlier gains amid signs of softening demand, with LME inventories rising in Asian warehouses and extra spot cargoes moving from Africa to China. China's Nonferrous Metals Industry Association forecasts a 5% increase in refined copper output this year, dampening investor enthusiasm despite calls for strategic reserves. This bearish sentiment overshadows initial positive reactions to reserve-boosting suggestions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Feb. 5</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20260205/160dd22086d442a9bd90369d375f7a63/c.html</link><description>London Stock Exchange Group reported copper prices at 5.83 USD at 0200 GMT on Feb. 5. This update includes prices for other metals like gold at 4,988.00 USD and iron ore at 102.17 USD. The data reflects the latest worldwide metals pricing snapshot.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Refined copper output growth to slow in 2026: ICSG</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/refined-copper-output-growth-to-slow-in-2026-icsg/</link><description>Copper output growth is expected to slow to 0.9% in 2026, down from 3.4% in 2025, according to Paul White at the World Copper Conference. World copper mine production is forecast to rise by 2.3%, while refined copper usage grows by 2.1%, leading to a 150,000-metric ton market deficit.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Retreat Amid Demand Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/02/05/copper-prices-retreat-amid-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices reversed gains due to softening demand signals, rising LME inventories in Asia, and extra supply from Africa to China. China's Nonferrous Metals Industry Association forecasts a 5% increase in refined copper output this year. This offsets earlier positivity from calls to boost strategic reserves.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Drop Slightly on February 5 as US January ADP Employment Data Falls Short of Expectations</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103757330-SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-Prices-Drop-Slightly-on-February-5-as-US-January-ADP-Employment-Data-Falls-Short-of-Expe</link><description>On February 5, SMM #1 refined nickel prices averaged 139,850 yuan/mt, down 1,750 yuan/mt from the previous day, amid weak US ADP employment data. The SHFE nickel futures contract (2603) closed at 133,510 yuan/mt, down 1.79%. Despite macro pressures, expectations for reduced nickel ore quotas in Indonesia suggest potential future rebounds.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices surge on Feb 5 amid concerns over trade war ease</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/nickel-prices-surge-on-feb-5-amid-concerns-over-trade-war-ease/152734</link><description>LME nickel futures rose by US$265/ton to close at US$15,535/ton on February 5. The nickel spot price also increased amid easing concerns over trade wars. This surge reflects positive market sentiment in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Analysis] Nickel Sulphate Prices Edge Down as Chinese New Year Approaches Amid Weak Market Sentiment</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103757592-SMM-Analysis-Nickel-Sulphate-Prices-Edge-Down-as-Chinese-New-Year-Approaches-Amid-Weak-Market-Sentiment</link><description>The SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index stood at 31,939 yuan/mt as of Thursday, with prices edging down ahead of Chinese New Year. Weak market sentiment contributed to the decline in nickel sulphate quotations. This reflects broader softening in nickel-related products.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel sees 2026 nickel output broadly in line with previous year</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-sees-2026-nickel-output-broadly-in-line-with-previous-year/</link><description>Russia's Nornickel, the world's largest palladium producer and major nickel producer, expects 2026 nickel output of 193,000–203,000 metric tons, broadly in line with 2025 production of 198,521 tons. The company attributes recent production declines to ore reserve depletion and Western sanctions restricting equipment access, but expects recovery by 2028 through development of the Oktyabrskoye deposit.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 3,047.10 USD/T on February 5, 2026, down 0.17% from the previous day and 2.77% over the past month, though still 16.17% higher year-over-year. The price recently hit a 4-week low of 3031.00 USD/T. It retreated from a three-year high amid base metals pullback.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SHFE Cast Aluminum Alloy Warrants Drop to 66,546 mt on Feb 5</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103758022-SHFE-Cast-Aluminum-Alloy-Warrants-Drop-to-66546-mt-on-Feb-5</link><description>SHFE data indicates that on February 5, the total registered volume of cast aluminum alloy warrants decreased to 66,546 mt, down 245 mt from prior levels. This reflects ongoing adjustments in aluminum alloy inventory and market dynamics on the Shanghai Futures Exchange.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vietnam-Backed Aluminum Project in Sekong Advances Toward 2028 Launch</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2026/02/05/vietnam-backed-aluminum-project-in-sekong-advances-toward-2028-launch/</link><description>A Vietnam-Phuong Group aluminum smelting project in Laos' Sekong Province aims for 1 million tonnes annual capacity by 2028, focusing on bauxite mining in a USD 1 billion complex. Construction began in late 2022, with ministerial oversight on February 3 emphasizing sustainable development.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>World Copper Prices Today, Thursday, February 5, 2026: Sideways around $5.80 per Pound</title><link>https://pintu.co.id/en/news/253839-world-copper-prices-today-thursday-february-5-2026</link><description>World copper prices moved sideways around USD 5.80 per pound on February 5, 2026, following selling pressure and entering a consolidation phase. Market participants await macroeconomic sentiment and global industrial demand cues. Despite short-term bearish sentiment, long-term trends remain positive with a 30.29% yearly gain.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 0.46% Lower at $5.7990 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2026020511206/comex-copper-settles-046-lower-at-57990-data-talk</link><description>Front-month Comex copper for February delivery settled at $5.7990 on February 5, 2026, down 0.46% or 2.70 cents per pound. It marked the seventh lowest settlement this year and continued a downward trend over recent sessions. Year-to-date, prices are up 3.00%, off 6.10% from the 2026 high.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anglo American Cuts 2027 Copper View, Warns of Continued Weak Diamond Market - Commodity Comment</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202602055086/anglo-american-cuts-2027-copper-view-warns-of-continued-weak-diamond-market-commodity-comment</link><description>Anglo American revised its 2026 copper production guidance downward to 700,000-760,000 tonnes from 760,000-820,000 tonnes. The adjustment accounts for lower production levels at Collahuasi mine due to lower grade ore and refractory stockpiles through 2026. This reflects challenges in maintaining copper output.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Group Data Breach in 2026 - Breachsense</title><link>https://www.breachsense.com/breaches/prysmian-group-data-breach/</link><description>Prysmian Group, an Italy-based multinational cable manufacturing company, suffered a data breach on February 05, 2026. The threat actor 0APT claimed responsibility, with a leak size of 14TB affecting prysmian.com. The company produces underground, submarine, industrial energy cables, optical fibers, and telecom systems worldwide.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Pillumina Honored with 2026 SEAL Sustainable Business Product Award for Advancing Sustainable Healthcare Packaging</title><link>https://natlawreview.com/press-releases/pillumina-honored-2026-seal-sustainable-business-product-award-advancing</link><description>Pillumina received the 2026 SEAL Sustainable Product Award for its infinitely recyclable aluminum prescription bottles, replacing single-use plastic ones used in over 7 billion U.S. prescriptions yearly. Aluminum's closed-loop lifecycle reduces plastic waste, microplastics, and landfill contributions compared to plastic's 3% recycle rate. The innovation supports pharmacies and healthcare in achieving sustainability goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Anglo lowers 2026 copper production guidance following lower 2025 output</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/anglo-lowers-2026-copper-production-guidance-following-lower-2025-output-2026-02-05</link><description>Diversified miner Anglo American reported a 14% quarter-on-quarter decrease in copper production to 170,000 tons in the fourth quarter and has lowered its 2026 copper production guidance. The company expects production to rise to between 700,000 and 760,000 tonnes in 2026, following weaker 2025 output.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>ArcelorMittal pins 2026 upturn on EU import curbs; North America to ship more at higher prices in Q1</title><link>https://eurometal.net/arcelormittal-pins-2026-upturn-on-eu-import-curbs-north-america-to-ship-more-at-higher-prices-in-q1/</link><description>ArcelorMittal expects improved steel shipments and prices in North America in Q1 2026 following resolution of Mexico-related disruptions and recent price increases. In Europe, the EU's new import regime and Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) are projected to reduce steel imports by 10 million tonnes versus 2024, boosting domestic utilization and margins. The company reactivated its blast furnace in Mexico in late January after maintenance.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ArcelorMittal expects tariffs, CBAM to restore production levels and profit in 2026</title><link>https://eurometal.net/arcelormittal-expects-tariffs-cbam-to-restore-production-levels-and-profit-in-2026/</link><description>ArcelorMittal anticipates world ex-China apparent steel demand to grow 2% in 2026, with production and shipments rising across regions due to operational improvements and trade protections like tariffs and CBAM. In Europe, these measures are expected to reduce imports by 10 million metric tons, resetting capacity utilization higher and restoring profitability. New capacity, including EAF expansions, is set for commissioning in 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Pressured by Supply Concerns</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper held below $5.85 per pound on Thursday after losing nearly 4% in the previous session, weighed down by rising supplies in top consumer China. An industry group forecasted that China’s refined copper output will likely rise by about 5% this year following a 10% increase last year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Slips on Rising Inventories</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper fell about 1% to $6 per pound on Wednesday, trimming gains amid rising inventories at major trading hubs in Shanghai, London, and New York. The red metal decoupled from gold and silver, which climbed on safe-haven demand, as investors assessed soft price data.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Can a ‘sustainable’ fungicide save France’s vineyards from climate-driven disease?</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/green/2026/02/05/carbon-sucking-fungi-and-forever-chemical-crackdowns-positive-environmental-stories-from-2</link><description>France has banned traditional fungicides, prompting the adoption of a sustainable alternative to copper-pesticides developed by UK-based Eden Research to combat mildew and mould in vineyards exacerbated by climate change. This innovation offers winemakers a viable, eco-friendly option to protect harvests. It represents a positive step in sustainable agriculture amid environmental pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Positive environmental stories from February 2026</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/green/2026/02/05/carbon-sucking-fungi-and-forever-chemical-crackdowns-positive-environmental-stories-from-2</link><description>This article covers multiple environmental innovations from February 2026, including Finland's use of sand for industrial heat decarbonization, a sustainable fungicide alternative to copper-pesticides for French vineyards, and wind and solar overtaking fossil fuels in EU electricity generation for the first time in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>February 6, 2026 Jinshi Futures Morning Report: SHFE adjusts the</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/68518280/february-6-2026-jinshi-futures-morning-report-shfe-adjusts-the</link><description>Mysteel reports China's primary aluminum production in January 2026 reached 3.8385 million tons, up 3.24% year-on-year and 0.26% month-on-month, with average daily output at 123,800 tons. This preliminary data highlights steady growth in primary aluminum output amid market surveys.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>February 6, 2026 Steel Market Summary – International Australia´s Bisalloy Steels Advances Further Onto World Stage</title><link>https://australiansteel.com/2026/02/</link><description>Bisalloy Steels has secured CE certification for its structural grades, consolidating its global presence in Europe. The summary also covers New Zealand Steel's Glenbrook EAF project on track for a resurgent 2026, vital for the nation's economy. BlueScope Steel's new chief outlines the 2026 agenda amid economic pressures like RBA rate hikes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Anglo American Lowers Production Target, Overnight SHFE and LME Copper Prices Fall Together [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103758294-Anglo-American-Lowers-Production-Target-Overnight-SHFE-and-LME-Copper-Prices-Fall-Together-SMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Mi</link><description>LME copper closed at $12,855/mt overnight on February 6, 2026, down 1.42% after a volatile session. SHFE copper fell then slightly rebounded, closing at 101,100 yuan/mt on February 5. Prices face pressure from rising US dollar index, inventory buildup, stable supply, and weak demand; further declines expected.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trading was sluggish for spot copper during the day, with overall transactions limited [SMM Yangshan spot copper]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103760052-Trading-was-sluggish-for-spot-copper-during-the-day-with-overall-transactions-limited-SMM-Yangshan-spot-copper</link><description>Spot copper trading was sluggish on February 6, 2026, with limited transactions and warrant prices at $28-46/mt for February QP, flat from prior day. Overall market activity remained subdued amid ongoing price pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Vale's copper ambition is to produce 1Mt/y</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/vales-copper-ambition-is-to-produce-1mty-2026-02-06</link><description>Vale's base metals unit aims to produce one million tons of copper per year by developing existing assets. This target exceeds previous output goals for the company. The ambition highlights efforts to expand copper production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ero Copper's Record Output: Assessing the Commodity Balance &amp; Liquidity Impact</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/ero-copper-record-output-assessing-commodity-balance-liquidity-impact-2602/</link><description>Ero Copper provided 2026 production guidance of 67,500–77,500 tonnes, indicating cautious growth after strong 2025 performance. This follows record output in Q4 2025, though gold production is expected to decline. The guidance assesses impacts on commodity balance and liquidity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>AWS to Source Low Carbon Nuton Copper from Rio Tinto for U.S. Data Center Infrastructure</title><link>https://esgnews.com/aws-to-source-low-carbon-nuton-copper-from-rio-tinto-for-u-s-data-center-infrastructure/</link><description>Rio Tinto and AWS have partnered under a two-year agreement for AWS to use Nuton copper in U.S. data center components. Nuton's technology uses naturally occurring microorganisms to extract copper from primary sulphide ores, eliminating traditional concentrators and smelters while reducing water use and emissions intensity compared to conventional methods.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price spikes more than 10% as Chinese buying fuels metals surge</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-spikes-more-than-10-as-chinese-buying-fuels-metals-surge/</link><description>Nickel prices spiked over 10% in London, hitting $18,785/ton, driven by Chinese investor buying and production risks in Indonesia despite oversupply. This extends a 30% rally since mid-December, reviving the LME nickel contract after past challenges. Broader base metals like copper and tin also surged amid high-volume Asian trading.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia cuts 2026 nickel quota, global prices jump immediately</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/60514/indonesia-cuts-2026-nickel-quota-global-prices-jump-immediately</link><description>Indonesia's reduction in its 2026 nickel production quota has sparked supply concerns, causing an immediate jump in global nickel prices. This policy shift counters ongoing oversupply issues in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Electric Plans Expanded Copper, Nickel Exploration in Côte d'Ivoire in 2026</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/0502-52620-ivanhoe-electric-plans-expanded-copper-nickel-exploration-in-cote-d-ivoire-in-2026</link><description>Ivanhoe Electric and partner Sama Resources plan to accelerate copper and nickel exploration at the Samapleu-Grata project in Côte d'Ivoire starting in February 2026 with a 4,500-meter diamond drilling campaign across 20 targets. A 2024 study estimates potential production of over 887,000 tonnes of nickel concentrate and 621,000 tonnes of copper concentrate over a 16-year mine life. The initiative aims to demonstrate the project's district-scale potential amid global demand for critical minerals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>High Aluminum Prices Suppress Stockpiling Demand for the Chinese New Year, Extended Holiday Periods for Alloys and Downstream Die-Casting</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103758465-High-Aluminum-Prices-Suppress-Stockpiling-Demand-for-the-Chinese-New-Year-Extended-Holiday-Periods-for-Alloys-and-Downst</link><description>High aluminum prices are suppressing stockpiling demand ahead of Chinese New Year, with A00 aluminum dropping 420 yuan/mt to 23,340 yuan/mt and ADC12 to 23,600 yuan/mt on February 5. Aluminum alloy futures closed up 1.07% at 22,150 yuan/mt, showing potential for a technical rebound after oversold conditions. Secondary aluminum plants plan production suspensions from February 5-13, with resumptions post-holiday.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century's Hawesville smelter sale in the context of US primary aluminum</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/02/06/centurys-hawesville-smelter-sale-in-the-context-of-us-primary-aluminum/</link><description>Century Aluminum's sale of its idled Hawesville smelter highlights challenges in US primary aluminum production, with prior plans to restart capacity to over 220,000 metric tons per year adding about 10% to national output. Even at full capacity across US smelters, the country would remain reliant on imports for most primary aluminum needs. Related expansions include Arconic’s Davenport plant doubling high-purity aluminum to over 40,000 metric tons annually.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Danantara Begins $5.8B Aluminum Smelter Project in West Kalimantan</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103760769-Danantara-Begins-58B-Aluminum-Smelter-Project-in-West-Kalimantan</link><description>Danantara has officially started a $5.8 billion aluminum smelter project in West Kalimantan, marking a significant new development in regional production capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The growing role of critical minerals in global innovation</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2026/01/critical-minerals-innovation-earth-surface/</link><description>Demand for critical minerals like nickel for clean energy technologies is projected to rise over 3.4 times by 2040, creating challenges for sustainable mining amid the net-zero push. The article emphasizes the need for collaboration among mining, governments, and tech leaders to mine responsibly, focusing on environmental stewardship and community benefits. Leaders at the World Economic Forum Annual Meeting 2026 will discuss balancing growth and protection.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World Economic Forum Insights; Global Cathode Active Material ...</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/en/research-insights/market-insights/daily-update-feb-06-2026</link><description>S&amp;P Global forecasts strong growth in cathode active materials demand to 5 million metric tons by 2030, with nickel-based chemistries facing pressure from rising LFP batteries. Capacity expansions in North America and Europe aim to reduce China's dominance, amid ongoing oversupply. This impacts nickel innovation in sustainable battery technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Macro and Fundamentals Present a Mix of Positive and Negative Factors, Aluminum Prices Expected to Consolidate with Mainly Downside Risks</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103758335-Macro-and-Fundamentals-Present-a-Mix-of-Positive-and-Negative-Factors-Aluminum-Prices-Expected-to-Consolidate-with-Mainl</link><description>LME aluminum closed at $3,026/mt on February 5, down 1.08%, while SHFE aluminum rose 0.79% to 23,570 yuan/mt. Spot A00 aluminum fell to 23,340 yuan/mt amid weakening futures and holiday production suspensions extending 8-20 days. Downstream demand contracts, with secondary alloy prices expected to hover at highs but face slight downward pressure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries showcases sustainability in quarterly update</title><link>https://en.antaranews.com/news/402222/nickel-industries-showcases-sustainability-in-quarterly-update</link><description>Nickel Industries Limited reported achieving a zero Lost Time Injury Frequency Rate (LTIFR) with 17.7 million safe man-hours over 12 months as of December 2025. The company completed a strategic acquisition of a 10 percent stake in Excelsior Nickel Cobalt and received national recognition through the Indonesia Leadership Award 2025 and CNBC Indonesia's Excellence in Sustainability Leadership Award.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Simar Bedi Leads Canada's Recycling Revolution With Record-Breaking Innovation at Sol Recycling</title><link>https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/stocks/simar-bedi-leads-canada-s-recycling-revolution-with-record-breaking-innovation-at-sol-recycling-1035798058</link><description>Sol Recycling founder Simar Bedi is advancing sustainability through record-breaking innovations in aluminum and metal recycling in Canada. The efforts position the company as a leader in environmental innovation and circular economy practices for aluminum materials.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,055 CNY/T on February 6, 2026, down 0.81% from the previous day. Steel rebar futures dropped to around CNY 3,070 a ton, a one-month low, due to Chinese steel mills trimming production ahead of Lunar New Year. Blast furnace utilization stayed above 86%, with daily hot metal output rising week-on-week.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price dips below $13,000 with stockpiles, China demand in focus</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-dips-below-13000-with-stockpiles-china-demand-in-focus/</link><description>Copper prices fell below $13,000 per ton as investors focused on rising inventories and weakening demand from Chinese buyers. Daily refined copper spot trading volumes in China declined to 25,300 tons, though State Grid Corporation of China announced a 35% increase in fixed-asset investment for power infrastructure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Futures Hit Record High of $13,000/Ton in 2026 Metals Rally</title><link>https://www.indexbox.io/blog/copper-futures-hit-record-high-of-13000-ton-in-2026-metals-rally/</link><description>Copper futures surged to a record high of $13,000 per ton, driven by strong demand from AI infrastructure and supply disruptions. Global demand is projected to surge from 28 million tons in 2025 to 42 million tons by 2040, though analysts warn the current rally may be unsustainable.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Can copper hit $15,000 in 2026?</title><link>https://theoregongroup.substack.com/p/can-copper-hit-15000-in-2026</link><description>LME cash copper prices reached an all-time high of $13,300 per metric ton on January 6, 2026, marking a 50% year-on-year increase. Major producers including Chile, Peru, and the Democratic Republic of Congo face significant supply constraints, with production disruptions from labor strikes, accidents, and declining ore grades affecting global output.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium prices record cash offer rising to $3,045/t while inventories slide downwards</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-prices-record-cash-offer-rising-to-3-045-t-while-inventories-slide-downwards-117208</link><description>Aluminum prices on the London Metal Exchange rose sharply on February 6, with both cash and forward contracts reporting gains. The LME aluminum opening stocks declined to 490,975 tonnes on February 6 from 492,975 tonnes on February 5, marking a 0.4% decrease, while cancelled warrants dropped sharply by 3.82%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Electricity fees 'too high' in UK steel production</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/electricity-fees-too-high-in-uk-steel-production-2026-2-9/98426</link><description>UK steel firms will continue to pay 25% more for electricity than European rivals despite government intervention. Trade body UK Steel states this disparity will add £26m to members' bills compared to France. Ministers maintain a bright future for UK steel-making.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Bearings of Change: SKF's roadmap for efficient motion</title><link>https://renewablewatch.in/2026/02/09/bearings-of-change-skfs-roadmap-for-efficient-motion/</link><description>SKF Industrial’s bearing innovations emphasize sustainability through advanced materials like corrosion-resistant coatings, lightweight composites, and hybrid ceramic bearings, extending service life and reducing raw material needs. These solutions have driven up to 25% lower carbon emissions, significant grease savings, and longer maintenance intervals in sectors like mining, cement, and power generation. Future developments include smart, sensor-integrated bearings and additive manufacturing to support a low-carbon economy and circularity.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Precious Metals Forecast (Feb 9, 2026): Gold Holds ...</title><link>https://techbytes.app/posts/gold-silver-price-forecast-february-9-2026/</link><description>Copper has hit an all-time high of $14,527/ton, driven by cabling needs for AI data centers. The median forecast for 2026 is $11,975/ton, positioning it as a top-performing base metal. Nickel is stabilizing around $17,235/ton with support from Indonesian supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Market Watch: Monday 9th February, 2026</title><link>https://www.miningnews.net/newsletter-introduction/news-articles/4526819/market-watch-monday-9th-february-2026</link><description>Explorer Cobre is reportedly closing in on a deal to buy a 25,000t-per-annum copper cathode operation in Chile. An associated $50 million raising at 15c per new share is also said to be in progress. This acquisition would expand Cobre's copper production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Stuart Kimball Shares Insights on How Technology Is Transforming Arizona's Mining Industry</title><link>https://gknet.com/news/news/stuart-kimball-shares-insights-on-how-technology-is-transforming-arizonas-mining-industry/</link><description>The article explores how advanced technologies are reshaping Arizona's mining industry with a focus on safety, efficiency, and environmental stewardship. It highlights innovations like Florence Copper's in-situ copper recovery (ISCR), which produces 75% fewer carbon emissions and uses 65% less energy compared to traditional open-pit mining, and Resolution Copper's block cave mining technique that reduces environmental impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>It All Comes Back to Supply Chains</title><link>https://cleantech.com/it-all-comes-back-to-supply-chains/</link><description>This article discusses how supply chain challenges for critical minerals are reshaping the technology industry, with AWS's early 2026 agreement with Rio Tinto to secure copper from Arizona representing the first new U.S.-mined copper supply in over a decade. The piece emphasizes that while this deal is strategically important, the projected 30,000 metric tons over several years represents only a fraction of copper needed for AI and electrification growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel prices rebounded slightly on February 9 as the central bank increased its gold holdings</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103762034-SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-prices-rebounded-slightly-on-February-9-as-the-central-bank-increased-its-gold-holdings-</link><description>On February 9, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 133,900-145,000 yuan/mt, averaging 139,450 yuan/mt, up 3,650 yuan/mt from the previous day. The SHFE nickel contract (2603) closed the morning at 134,630 yuan/mt, up 1.53%, amid sluggish pre-holiday trading and a technical rebound. Spot demand remains weak, with focus post-holiday on Indonesia's nickel ore quota policy.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>DMCI Mining eyes record 3-million WMT nickel output for 2026</title><link>https://mb.com.ph/2026/02/09/dmci-mining-eyes-record-3-million-wmt-nickel-output-for-2026</link><description>DMCI Mining targets 3 million WMT of nickel ore production in 2026 from mines in Zambales and Palawan, driven by higher prices enabling sales of lower-grade ore at $26 per WMT. The company saw 33% production growth to 2 million WMT in 2025, with shipments up 31% to 1.9 million WMT. Rising global nickel prices, boosted by Indonesia's capacity limits, support expansion plans.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Sulphate Daily Review: Pre-Holiday Trading Remained Weak, Nickel Salt Prices Held Steady</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103762479-SMM-Nickel-Sulphate-Daily-Review-February-9th-Pre-Holiday-Trading-Remained-Weak-Nickel-Salt-Prices-Held-Steady</link><description>On February 9, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index was 31,646 yuan/mt, with quotes ranging 31,400-32,000 yuan/mt amid weak pre-holiday trading. Nickel salt prices remained steady despite sluggish market activity. This reflects ongoing trends in the nickel derivatives market tied to refined nickel movements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>DMCI Mining hits record nickel output as Zambales, Long Point ramp-up</title><link>https://insiderph.com/dmci-mining-hits-record-nickel-output-as-zambales-long-point-ramp-up</link><description>DMCI Mining achieved record 2 million WMT nickel ore production in 2025, up 33% year-on-year, with shipments at 1.9 million WMT, fueled by Zambales output and Long Point mine ramp-up. Philippine FOB laterite nickel ore prices for 1.5% grade rose 26% to $45.70, improving fundamentals. The company eyes further growth amid recovering nickel market and new capacity.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>DMCI Mining eyes record 3-million WMT nickel output for 2026</title><link>https://mb.com.ph/2026/02/09/dmci-mining-eyes-record-3-million-wmt-nickel-output-for-2026</link><description>DMCI Mining Corp. plans to achieve a record-high 3 million wet metric tons (WMT) of nickel ore production in 2026 by operating three mine sites, including the pending Long Point mine in Palawan. The company reported a 33% increase in 2025 production to 2 million WMT, driven by Zambales operations. Favorable nickel prices, boosted by Indonesia's capacity limits, enable sales of lower-grade ore at attractive rates.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>DMCI Mining says nickel output up 33% in 2025; Long Point mine set to start operations</title><link>https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2026/02/09/729139/dmci-mining-says-nickel-output-up-33-in-2025-long-point-mine-set-to-start-operations/</link><description>DMCI Mining Corp. achieved 33% higher nickel ore production at 2 million WMT in 2025, with shipments up 31% to 1.9 million WMT, fueled by Zambales mines and initial Long Point project in Palawan. The Long Point mine awaits final permits and could start within weeks, supporting a target of 3 million WMT shipments in 2026 amid strong prices. The company has rehabilitated areas at its Quezon mine ahead of schedule.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Announces US$32 Million Bridge Loan Facility with Auramet International Inc.</title><link>https://www.newswire.ca/news-releases/canada-nickel-announces-us-32-million-bridge-loan-facility-with-auramet-international-inc--806231615.html</link><description>Canada Nickel secured a US$32 million bridge loan from Auramet, closing by February 9, 2026, to fund its Crawford Nickel Sulphide Project, due May 2026 with 1% monthly interest. The project features robust economics from a prior PEA, including a 120,000 tonnes/day plant for nickel and magnetite concentrates. This supports advancement amid strong nickel demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Signs €2.3 Billion Contract for UK Power Link Project</title><link>https://ca.investing.com/news/company-news/prysmian-signs-23-billion-contract-for-uk-power-link-project-93CH-4432135</link><description>Italian cable maker Prysmian signed a contract worth over €2.3 billion with SP Energy Networks and National Grid to build the Eastern Green Link 4 power transmission link connecting the electrical grids of Scotland and England.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>World's Top Cable Maker Sees US Copper Tariff as Opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Prysmian, which acquired Texas-based Encore Wire for $4 billion, expressed support for President Trump's planned 50% copper tariff, stating it will bolster the American supply chain. The company believes its vertical integration and domestic copper sourcing position it favorably relative to competitors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian, Versalis Launch Chemical Recycling Chain for Plastic Cable Waste in Italy</title><link>https://esgnews.com/prysmian-versalis-launch-chemical-recycling-chain-for-plastic-cable-waste-in-italy/</link><description>Prysmian and Versalis established a strategic partnership for chemical recycling of end-of-life and production cable plastics in Italy. Using Versalis's Hoop® technology, the initiative will recover up to 60% of difficult-to-recycle XLPE insulation, with pilot operations scheduled to begin in the second half of 2026.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminium price rallies sharply as LME cash offer spikes to 3,083.5 per tonne</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminium-price-rallies-sharply-as-lme-cash-offer-spikes-to-3-083-5-per-tonne-117222</link><description>On February 9, 2026, LME aluminium prices surged with the cash bid and offer rising by USD 38.5 per tonne or 1.3%, reaching USD 3,083 to 3,083.5 per tonne. Three-month forward contracts also increased by USD 44.5 per tonne or 1.5%. This reflects declining inventory amid market rally.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Seasonal weakness pressure dominates aluminium prices in the doldrums</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/seasonal-weakness-pressure-dominates-aluminium-prices-in-the-doldrums-117221</link><description>SHFE aluminium closed at RMB 23,525 per tonne, down 0.06%, while LME aluminium settled at USD 3,109 per tonne, down 0.67%. Spot A00 aluminium rose to RMB 23,400 per tonne amid slowing transactions before Chinese New Year. Secondary aluminium enterprises are suspending operations, leading to weaker demand and fluctuating prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bechtel to lead preparatory engineering work on Oklahoma aluminum project</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2026/02/09/3234698/0/en/Bechtel-to-lead-preparatory-engineering-work-on-Oklahoma-aluminum-project.html</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium (EGA) and Century Aluminum have selected Bechtel to conduct preparatory engineering for a new primary aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, the first in the US since 1980. The project aims to double US primary aluminum production using EGA's advanced EX technology, creating 1,000 permanent jobs and 4,000 construction jobs. Bechtel's work focuses on value improvement, modularization, and preparing for a final investment decision and construction start by end-2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bechtel to lead preparatory engineering work on Oklahoma aluminum project</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/bechtel-to-lead-preparatory-engineering-work-on-oklahoma-aluminum-project-117223</link><description>EGA and Century Aluminum announced Bechtel will handle preparatory engineering for their planned aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, targeting doubled US primary production. The facility will employ EGA's efficient EX reduction technology and generate significant jobs during construction and operation. Bechtel is also addressing infrastructure, logistics, and modular construction to support local growth.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum taps Bechtel for Oklahoma smelter plan</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CENX/bechtel-to-lead-preparatory-engineering-work-on-oklahoma-aluminum-yzf9wbxb7teo.html</link><description>Century Aluminum and EGA (60%/40% ownership) have engaged Bechtel for engineering on a new Oklahoma smelter using EX technology, set to double US primary aluminum output. The project includes 1,000 permanent and 4,000 construction jobs, with preparatory work targeting construction by end-2026. It builds on prior announcements for a 750,000-tonne-per-year facility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bechtel to Lead Engineering for New US Primary Aluminum Smelter in Oklahoma</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103763081-Bechtel-to-Lead-Engineering-for-New-US-Primary-Aluminum-Smelter-in-Oklahoma</link><description>Bechtel has been selected to lead engineering for a new primary aluminum smelter in Oklahoma by EGA and Century Aluminum, potentially doubling US production capacity. The project incorporates advanced technology and sustainability efforts. It marks a significant expansion in American aluminum manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AISI: Raw steel production increases to 5-month high</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/02/09/aisi-raw-steel-production-increases-to-5-month-high/</link><description>US mills produced an estimated 1,783,000 short tons of raw steel in the week ending Feb. 7, up 1.4% from the previous week and marking a five-month high. Year-to-date production totals 9,557,000 short tons, up 3.7% from last year, with mill capability utilization at 77.1%. Production increased in four of five AISI regions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures rose to around $17,200-$17,400 per tonne, supported by concerns over Indonesian supply constraints as smelters fail to submit reports, potentially disrupting exports. Indonesia confirmed cutting mining permits to 260 million wet tons in 2026 from 379 million last year. Philippine DMCI Mining targets 3 million WMT output in 2026 after record 2025 production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market Eyes $20,000 as Supply Discipline Meets Surging ...</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gb7bxSSP58c</link><description>The nickel market shows a constructive outlook in early 2026, backed by Indonesia's 250-260 million ton ore production targets and strong demand. Prices trade in $16,500-$18,500 range after hitting $19,000. Canada Nickel advances Crawford project with engineering and financing milestones for 2026 construction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>NMDC Price Hike Amidst Soaring Costs Sparks Investor Scrutiny</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/Commodities/NMDC-Price-Hike-Amidst-Soaring-Costs-Sparks-Investor-Scrutiny/698ab3d9757d40c78184d329</link><description>NMDC raised iron ore prices by ₹100 per tonne for lumps and fines effective February 10, 2026, to ₹4,700 and ₹4,000 per tonne respectively, responding to higher steel prices and rupee depreciation. EBITDA margins contracted from 36.1% to 28.2%, amid India's steel demand growth projection of 8% in FY2025/2026. Analyst views are mixed, with upgrades to 'Strong Buy' alongside 'Sell' ratings.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Ltd Hits Intraday High with 3.56% Surge on 10 Feb 2026</title><link>https://www.marketsmojo.com/news/stocks-in-action/tata-steel-ltd-hits-intraday-high-with-356-surge-on-10-feb-2026-3830506</link><description>Tata Steel's share price hit a 52-week high of Rs 208.15, up 3.56% intraday and 2.99% from previous close, outperforming the Ferrous Metals sector. The stock stayed above key moving averages, showing bullish momentum amid a positive market with Sensex up 0.3%. This follows two days of gains totaling 5.56%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel consolidated steel production declines 2% to 24.75 lakh tonne in January</title><link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/jsw-steel-share-price-january-business-update-consolidated-production-india-operations-ohio-us-19846305.htm</link><description>JSW Steel's consolidated crude steel production for January 2026 fell 2% to 24.75 lakh tonnes year-over-year. US Ohio operations saw a 74% decline to 0.17 lakh tonnes due to a scheduled outage for caster upgrades from December 15, 2025, to January 11, 2026. Capacity utilization for Indian operations was 85%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vietnam's 2025 crude steel output hits 5-year high</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/vietnams-2025-crude-steel-output-hits-5-year-high-2026-2-10/98437</link><description>Vietnam’s crude steel output in 2025 reached 24.7 million tons, a 12% year-on-year increase and a five-year high. The Vietnam Steel Association forecasts 8-10% growth in 2026, with finished steel output at 33-34.5 million tons and domestic consumption at 26 million tons. Challenges include green standards and anti-dumping cases.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Ministry signs MOUs for 85 projects under PLI</title><link>https://industrialeconomist.com/steel-ministry-signs-mous-for-85-projects-under-pli/</link><description>The Union Ministry of Steel signed Memorandums of Understanding for 85 projects under the Production Linked Incentive scheme. These initiatives aim to boost steel production capacity in India.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price forecast for 2026: Goldman Sachs</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/02/10/copper-price-forecast-for-2026-goldman-sachs/</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts copper prices to stay around $13,000 per tonne in the first half of 2026 before declining to $11,200 by year-end, assuming a US 15% tariff on refined copper by mid-2026. The price recently rebounded to $13,117 per tonne after a sell-off triggered by US dollar strength. ASX copper shares and ETFs rose today amid ongoing recovery and uncertainty supporting current levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price forecast for 2026: Goldman Sachs</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/02/10/copper-price-forecast-for-2026-goldman-sachs/</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts copper prices to remain around $13,000 per tonne in early 2026 before declining to $11,200 by year-end, citing a short-term 600 kilotonne surplus in 2025 but long-term supply constraints due to lengthy mine development times and declining ore grades in Chile. Demand is driven by grid infrastructure, EVs, renewables, China's building sector, and data centers. The article notes restricted supply amid rising demand from energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices fell to 5.91 USD/Lbs on February 10, 2026, amid supply challenges from power outages at major mines and conservative production guidance. The China Nonferrous Metals Industry Association projects refined copper output to rise about 5% in 2026, half the 2025 growth rate. Global demand remains robust from energy transition and data-center expansion despite short-term pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel prices edged lower on February 10 with market trading turning sluggish</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103764127-SMM-Nickel-Midday-Review-Nickel-prices-edged-lower-on-February-10-with-market-trading-turning-sluggish</link><description>On February 10, SMM #1 refined nickel prices ranged from 133,400-144,500 yuan/mt, averaging 138,950 yuan/mt, down 500 yuan/mt from the previous day. Market trading turned sluggish ahead of the Chinese New Year holiday, with futures prices fluctuating lower and spot prices weakening due to stagnant demand. Post-holiday focus will be on Indonesia's nickel ore quota policy implementation.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel News</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103763647-SMM-Nickel-News</link><description>SMM reports #1 refined nickel prices on February 10 at 133,400–144,500 yuan/mt, averaging 138,950 yuan/mt, a decline of 500 yuan/mt from the prior session. The update highlights ongoing spot market assessments amid broader nickel market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>