<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:30:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aluminium's unifying approach to net-zero transformation</title><link>https://www.worldclimatefoundation.org/post/climate-nature-and-people-aluminium-s-unifying-approach-to-net-zero-transformation</link><description>The aluminum industry is advancing decarbonization through multiple innovations including ELYSIS zero-carbon smelting technology and CelestiAL solar-powered aluminum production by Emirates Global Aluminium. The sector is implementing a multi-faceted strategy combining clean energy investments with recycling revolution to achieve net-zero goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 937.08 USD/T on January 19, 2026, down 0.20% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 3.20% and are up 34.83% year-over-year. Data was last updated on January 20, 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel prices hiked again amid rising exports</title><link>https://tv.rediff.com/business/steel-prices-hiked-again-amid-rising-exports/367686</link><description>Steel prices in India were hiked again on Friday due to safeguard duties, rising exports, and higher input costs. Some mills increased hot-rolled coil (HRC) prices by 500-750 per tonne. HRC serves as a benchmark for flat steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Jan. 20</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20260120/40d7caee401e486c8f030ef3476e9c36/c.html</link><description>At 0200 GMT on Jan. 20, 2026, COMEX copper price stood at 5.82 USD, amid latest global metals updates including gold, iron ore, palladium, and platinum. Reflects current spot pricing in ongoing volatile market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP Boosts Copper Production Outlook for FY26</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/20/bhp-boosts-copper-production-outlook-for-fy26/</link><description>BHP has increased its fiscal year 2026 copper production guidance to between 1.9 and 2.0 million tonnes, driven by record throughput at the Escondida mine and strong asset performance. The company also reported gains in iron ore and coal production amid rising commodity prices. CEO Mike Henry highlighted strong operating momentum and a pathway to 2 million tonnes of copper production in the 2030s.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP lifts copper guidance after record half-year output</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/20/bhp-lifts-copper-guidance-after-record-half-year-output/</link><description>BHP upgraded its FY26 copper production guidance to 1,900–2,000 kt following record half-year output and strong performance at Escondida. Iron ore and coal production also rose, supported by higher prices including copper up 32%. Management emphasized a significant copper growth pipeline targeting around 2 Mt in the 2030s.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP Upgrades Copper Output Guidance; Raises Cost of Potash Project (Again) (2nd Update)</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601194210/bhp-upgrades-copper-output-guidance-raises-cost-of-potash-project-again-2nd-update</link><description>BHP Group raised its FY26 copper production guidance to 1.9-2.0 million metric tons, fueled by strong Escondida performance amid record-high copper prices. Second-quarter copper output was 490,500 tons, with first-half production flat year-over-year. Iron ore production increased, though prices face pressure from China negotiations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chile delays copper output peak, cuts short-term forecasts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/chile-delays-copper-output-peak-cuts-short-term-forecasts/</link><description>Chile, the world's largest copper producer, delayed its peak annual output goal above 6 million tons by several years and cut forecasts for 2026-2031 due to falling ore grades and mining plan adjustments. Production is expected to stabilize at current levels with gradual recovery toward the period's end. The revision was outlined in a Cochilco report.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On January 20, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103728813/</link><description>On January 20, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 140,900-151,800 yuan/mt, averaging 146,350 yuan/mt, up 450 yuan/mt from the previous day. This indicates a slight upward movement in Chinese refined nickel pricing amid ongoing market fluctuations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tariff Noise, Limited Signal</title><link>https://www.sucdenfinancial.com/en/market-insights/metals-outlook/daily-base-metals-analysis/2026-01-20/</link><description>Base metals, including nickel, recovered some of Friday's weakness on January 20, with expectations of transitioning into a rangebound phase in the near term. Dip-buying persisted, reflecting cautious market sentiment amid tariff discussions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>TECH Project high-grade nickel is primed to fuel the global green transition</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/tech-project-high-grade-nickel-is-primed-to-fuel-the-global-green-transition/32893/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals' TECH Project aims to become a leading source of high-grade, ethically derived nickel for EV batteries and green energy. The project features the DNi Process, an environmentally-friendly extraction method with 98% nitric acid recycling and no tailings dam requirements, positioning it as a carbon-negative production facility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel rose to 940 USD/T on January 20, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel increased to 940.09 USD/T, up 0.22% from the previous day. Over the past month, HRC Steel's price has risen 3.53%, and is up 36.05% compared to the same time last year. Trading Economics forecasts HRC Steel to trade at 956.97 USD/T by the end of Q1 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Final Thoughts - Steel Market Update</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/20/final-thoughts-1907/</link><description>Sheet steel prices climbed to new multi-month highs this week, with demand driven by data centers, energy transmission projects, and border fence construction. Extreme cold weather has reduced scrap flows, and the market has experienced a relatively calm start to 2026 without major price shocks.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AISI: Raw steel production rises 0.2%</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/20/aisi-raw-steel-production-rises-0-2/</link><description>US domestic mill production reached 1,756,000 short tons of raw steel in the week ending January 17, 2026, up 0.2% from the previous week and 3.3% higher than the same week last year. The mill capability utilization rate was 75.9%, with year-to-date production up 2.9% compared to the same period in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises on Weaker Dollar</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures climbed above $5.9 per pound on Monday as the dollar weakened amid concerns over US President Donald Trump's tariff threats against European nations over Greenland. The market also assessed mixed economic signals from top consumer China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices rise amid mergers and strong demand forecasts</title><link>https://iol.co.za/business-report/economy/2026-01-20-copper-prices-rise-amid-mergers-and-strong-demand-forecasts/</link><description>Copper prices have rebounded as analysts predict strong demand, spurring merger activity in the mining sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Digital integration boosts safety, productivity, sustainability at Anglo American Barro Alto mine</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2026/01/20/digital-integration-boosts-safety-productivity-sustainability-at-anglo-american-barro-alto-mine/</link><description>Digital integration at Anglo American's Barro Alto mine, a nickel producer, enhances safety, productivity, and sustainability through advanced technologies. The project demonstrates how digitization supports responsible mining operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris resumes production lines at Koppel steel plant, plans to hire 80 workers</title><link>https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/tenaris-resumes-production-lines-koppel-steel-plant-plans-hire-80-workers/NO3STGZCOJG7ZENGDUBVAZ6PXM/</link><description>Tenaris is restarting heat treatment and finishing lines at its Koppel, Pennsylvania steel plant to increase production of steel pipe for the oil and gas industry, planning to hire 80 workers. The plant, acquired in 2020, had been idled during the Covid-19 pandemic but has seen $150 million in investments. Recent investments include $2 million for resuming these operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Produced More Copper, Slightly Less Iron Ore Last Year</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2026012010401/rio-tinto-produced-more-copper-slightly-less-iron-ore-last-year-update</link><description>Rio Tinto reported an 11% increase in copper output for 2025, producing 883,000 metric tons and surpassing its guidance forecast of 860,000-875,000 tons, with Q4 copper output at 240,000 tons, up 5% year-over-year. Growth was driven by rising production from the Oyu Tolgoi mine in Mongolia following its underground expansion.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SSAB to supply decarbonised steel to Rheinmetall</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2779234-ssab-to-supply-decarbonised-steel-to-rheinmetall</link><description>Swedish steelmaker SSAB has signed a preliminary agreement with German defence manufacturer Rheinmetall to supply decarbonised steel. The article also discusses rising trade tensions between the US and Europe over Greenland that could impact raw material costs for US electric arc furnace steelmakers importing prime scrap.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Innovation and Sustainability Define Top Stainless Steel Manufacturer</title><link>https://southeast.newschannelnebraska.com/story/53394150/innovation-and-sustainability-define-top-stainless-steel-manufacturer</link><description>A leading stainless steel manufacturer in Tianjin, China is prioritizing innovation and sustainability in its operations. The article highlights how the company is integrating advanced technologies and sustainable practices into its production processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Teck Announces 2025 Production and Sales Update and Reaffirms Outlook</title><link>https://www.teck.com/news/news-releases/2026/teck-announces-2025-production-and-sales-update-and-reaffirms-outlook</link><description>Teck reported 2025 copper production of 453,500 tonnes, meeting guidance, with strong Q4 output from Quebrada Blanca at 55,400 tonnes. The company reaffirmed 2026 copper production guidance for Antamina at 95,000–105,000 tonnes, while adjusting zinc guidance downward due to an updated mine plan. Q4 sales were slightly below production due to weather-related shipment delays into early 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tariff Talk, Safe-Haven Walk - Daily Base Metals Analysis</title><link>https://www.sucdenfinancial.com/en/market-insights/metals-outlook/daily-base-metals-analysis/2026-01-21/</link><description>Aluminium spreads eased back into contango, while the metal slipped below support at $3,110/t to settle near $3,099/t. This reflects ongoing market adjustments amid tariff discussions and safe-haven flows. Lead also breached key levels in the session.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>January 21, 2026, Jinshi Futures Morning Report: SHFE adjusts the ...</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/67659552/january-21-2026-jinshi-futures-morning-report-shfe-adjusts-the</link><description>China's primary aluminum production in December 2025 was estimated at 3.767 million tons, up from 3.646 million tons previously. Global primary aluminum output reached 6.296 million tons in December 2025. Rio Tinto reported 2025 aluminum production of 3.38 million tons, exceeding guidance.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Reviving Venezuela's Idle Aluminium Industry Challenges</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/venezuela-aluminum-resource-market-dynamics-2026/</link><description>The article discusses strategies and investment requirements to revive Venezuela's idle aluminum industry. It highlights challenges in restarting production capacity that has been dormant.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto copper output climbs as Oyu Tolgoi mine ramps up</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/node/789996</link><description>Rio Tinto Group's copper production climbed 5% in the fourth quarter driven by the expansion of underground operations at the Oyu Tolgoi mine. The company achieved copper equivalent production growth of 8% year-over-year in 2025, with shipments up 5%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto reports record iron ore quarter and soaring copper production</title><link>https://www.marketindex.com.au/news/rio-tinto-reports-record-iron-ore-quarter-and-soaring-copper-production</link><description>Rio Tinto exceeded Q4 production estimates with record copper output up 11%, while the Pilbara iron ore operation hit a quarterly record. The company demonstrated operational excellence across multiple commodity segments despite market pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Pulled Back on January 21, Fiscal Expenditure in 2026 to Increase Overall</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103731053/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-pulled-back-on-january-21-fiscal-expenditure-in-2026-to-increase-overall</link><description>On January 21, SMM #1 refined nickel prices ranged from 139,800-150,000 yuan/mt, averaging 144,900 yuan/mt, down 1,450 yuan/mt from the previous day. The SHFE nickel contract (2602) closed the morning session at 140,850 yuan/mt, down 1.16%, amid battles between Indonesian policy expectations and high inventory realities. Nickel prices may hover at highs if supply cut expectations persist.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Pulled Back on January 21</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103731053/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-pulled-back-on-january-21-fiscal-expenditure-in-2026-to-increase-overall</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices averaged 144,900 yuan/mt on January 21, down 1,450 yuan/mt amid high inventory and weak demand. The market balances expectations for Indonesian production cuts against current realities. SHFE nickel futures closed the morning session at 140,850 yuan/mt, down 1.16%.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Retreat From Recent Highs</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/517935</link><description>Nickel futures fell toward $18,000 per tonne after hitting $18,700, with Indonesia cutting 2026 nickel ore quotas by 34% to align with processing capacity. Chinese spot prices dropped amid profit-taking and soft demand, while SHFE futures declined 1.6%. Nickel Industries reported lower ore sales but resumed shipments in early January.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>MacroAsia unit's Palawan nickel project gets MGB clearance</title><link>https://business.inquirer.net/569726/macroasia-units-palawan-nickel-project-gets-mgb-clearance</link><description>MacroAsia Mining Corp. received approval for its Infanta nickel project in Palawan, planning to invest 12 million for extraction across 1,113 hectares. The project falls under Production Sharing No.220-5-IVB in Brooke's Point. The company anticipates nickel market recovery to enable full commercial production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Three Main Factors Drove the Strong Performance of Aluminum Prices in January</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29923.html</link><description>Aluminum prices rose 6.3% in January 2026, driven by rigid supply constraints, structural demand growth, and macroeconomic factors combined with low inventory levels. The market has experienced a slight recent decline after reaching highs on January 14th, but medium-to-long term outlook remains supported by supply and demand fundamentals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SunSirs: Three Main Factors Drove the Strong Performance of Aluminum Prices in January</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29923.html</link><description>Aluminum prices in East China rose 6.3% in January 2026 to 23,890 RMB/ton as of January 19, driven by supply constraints. China's 45 million ton capacity limit and rising molten aluminum proportion limit ingot supply, while overseas disruptions like Mozal's shutdown and Century Aluminium reductions create a global supply gap of 290,000 to 840,000 tons.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME copper prices rose ~0.4% as tight inventories</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103733527</link><description>LME copper prices rose about 0.4% due to tight inventories. Shanghai transaction prices averaged 99,830 yuan/mt, down slightly by 20 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper demand rockets in the Age of AI</title><link>https://www.metaltechnews.com/story/2026/01/21/tech-metals/copper-demand-rockets-in-the-age-of-ai/2617.html</link><description>A surge in artificial intelligence, electric vehicles, renewable energy, and defense modernization is driving unprecedented growth in global copper demand. The article discusses how copper has become critical infrastructure for the digital economy and energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel and cobalt out, CO2 in at Turnagain</title><link>https://www.metaltechnews.com/story/2026/01/21/tech-bytes/nickel-and-cobalt-out-co2-in-at-turnagain/2613.html</link><description>A future mine at the Turnagain project could produce nickel and cobalt while permanently locking away over 200 million tons of atmospheric CO2, enhancing sustainability in nickel production. This innovative approach integrates carbon sequestration with metal extraction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Raw Steel Production Up 3.3% Year-on-Year in Mid-January</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/u.s.-raw-steel-production-up-3.3-year-on-year-in-mid-january-2026-1-21/98290</link><description>US raw steel production totaled 1,756,000 net tons for the week ending January 17, 2026, with a capability utilization rate of 75.9%. The Southern region led production with 773,000 net tons, followed by the Great Lakes at 504,000 net tons, representing a 3.3% year-over-year increase.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Live Aluminum Prices Today</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-today/</link><description>Aluminum edged higher as intensifying supply risks offset a pause in downstream buying, with physical tightness continuing to support prices. The article provides current pricing analysis and explains aluminum's role as a critical energy metal classified by the U.S. Government in 2022.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>2026 Global Outlook for New Alumina Supply</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103732427/2026-global-outlook-for-new-alumina-supply</link><description>China's alumina capacity is expected to reach 118.92 million mt in 2026 with 8.6 million mt of new capacity, intensifying oversupply. Much of the new capacity in Guangxi will shift local supply from tight to surplus, pressuring prices. Overseas, Indonesia and India will add 1 million mt and 500,000 mt respectively, heightening global competition.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Unilever, Ball and Alcoa unveil “first” carbon-free aluminum aerosol can</title><link>https://www.packaginginsights.com/news/carbon-free-aluminum-aerosol-can.html</link><description>Ball Corporation, Unilever, and Alcoa have debuted the first aerosol can made with Elysis carbon-free smelting technology, combining 50% Elysis aluminum and 50% recycled content to eliminate direct GHG emissions from smelting. The innovation targets personal care products like deodorants and cleaning items, supporting decarbonization in aluminum packaging. Elysis, a partnership of Alcoa and Rio Tinto backed by Apple and governments, produces oxygen instead of CO2 during smelting.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 22.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, indices, and news. It covers Shanghai Futures for rebar across multiple terms and future contracts for regions including Turkey, China, Europe, and North America, with recent data from January 19-20, 2026. The platform includes sections for latest news on rebar, scrap, and iron-steel markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Loses Momentum After 62% Rally: Flat 2026 Performance Raises Questions</title><link>https://scanx.trade/stock-market-news/commodities/copper-loses-momentum-after-62-rally-flat-2026-performance-raises-questions/30449309</link><description>Domestic copper prices in India fell nearly 1% to ₹1,288.90/kg on Tuesday amid mixed global trends, with MCX January contracts at ₹1,292.10, down ₹10. After a 62% rally in 2025, copper shows flat performance in 2026 due to profit booking, though fundamentals remain supportive with support levels at ₹1,230-₹1,250.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 22, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 22, 2026, up 0.43% from the previous day, with a 5.23% monthly gain. On January 21, prices fell to 5.80 USD/Lbs amid demand concerns in China, where the Yangshan import premium halved.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Q4 Production Increases, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103732269/rio-tinto-q4-production-increases-lme-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-lower-overnight-smm-copper-morning-meeting-minutes</link><description>Rio Tinto reported Q4 2025 attributable copper production of 240,000 mt, up 5% year-over-year and 18% quarter-over-quarter, with full-year 2025 production reaching 883,000 mt, an 11% cumulative increase. LME copper futures opened at $12,915.5/mt and closed at $12,761.5/mt, down 0.27%, with trading volume at 89,000 lots.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>More PV Manufacturers Expected to Adopt Copper Metallization in 2026</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-india.com/2026/01/22/more-pv-manufacturers-expected-to-adopt-copper-metallization-in-2026/</link><description>2026 is expected to mark the first year of large-scale mass production for high-copper paste solutions in photovoltaic manufacturing, driven by surging silver prices and sustainability concerns. Gigawatt-scale TOPCon customers and Tier-1 cell manufacturers are accelerating adoption of copper metallization to reduce silver consumption while maintaining conversion efficiency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining Announces 2025 Production Results and 2026 Guidance</title><link>https://www.inderes.fi/releases/lundin-mining-corporation-lundin-mining-announces-2025-production-results-and-2026-guidance</link><description>Lundin Mining forecasts copper production to remain stable at approximately 310,000 to 335,000 tonnes annually in 2026, consistent with 2025 production levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Strike Zone Mining Podcast for January 22 2026</title><link>https://www.netnewsledger.com/2026/01/21/strike-zone-mining-podcast-for-january-22-2026/</link><description>Ontario fast-tracks Canada Nickel's Crawford Nickel Project under the 'One Project, One Process' framework. The project near Timmins is positioned for batteries and green steel with plans for mining, processing, and downstream facilities. This accelerates development amid growing demand for electrification metals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>inaugurazione dell'opera "Per aspera ad astra" di Donato Savin</title><link>https://www.grand-paradis.it/en/news/2026/22-gennaio-2026-inaugurazione-dell%E2%80%99opera-aspera-ad-astra-di-donato-savin</link><description>An artwork titled "Per aspera ad astra" by Donato Savin will be inaugurated on January 22, 2026 at Cogne Acciai Speciali's headquarters in Aosta (Via Paravera 16). This event marks a cultural initiative at the company's main facility.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Tenaris posts 2% rise in quarterly net sales</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/italy-s-tenaris-posts-2-rise-in-quarterly-net-sales-ce7d5dd2de8cf321</link><description>Italian steel pipe maker Tenaris reported a 2% increase in net sales for the third quarter, driven by higher sales across its operations. As the world's leading producer of steel pipes for oil and gas industries, Tenaris generates 95.4% of revenue from pipe production with geographic distribution across North America (45.6%), Asia/Pacific/Middle East/Africa (25.5%), Europe (9.6%), and South America (19.3%).</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired isOplus's oil and gas division for $10 million, gaining pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coating capabilities rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy. The acquisition strengthens Tenaris's offshore market offerings and enables anti-corrosion coating application across facilities in Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rose to 3,140.90 USD/T on January 22, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices reached 3,140.90 USD/T on January 22, 2026, up 0.68% from the previous day and up 19.38% year-over-year. Over the past month, aluminum prices have risen 6.56%, reflecting ongoing market tightness and supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Extends Decline from Record High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures in the US fell to $5.75 per pound, continuing pullback from record high of $6.1 on January 14 as softening demand outweighed tight supply concerns. The Yangshan import premium fell more than 50%, indicating drop in buying amid record high base metal prices pressuring corporate margins.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US copper faces uncertain 2026 outlook</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2771940-viewpoint-us-copper-faces-uncertain-2026-outlook</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts copper prices averaging $5.17/lb in 2026, up from $4.82/lb in 2025, amid narrowing surpluses. Citigroup predicts prices above $5.90/lb by Q2 2026, while Bank of America and TD Cowen also raised forecasts. The copper market saw a 94,000t surplus in the first three quarters of 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Japanese Copper Smelters Still in Talks for 2026 Charges with Miners</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2026-01-22/japanese-copper-smelters-still-talks-2026-charges-miners</link><description>Japanese copper smelters are negotiating 2026 treatment and refining charges with global miners, seeking terms different from those set by China. The negotiations are challenging as smelting capacity expands faster than mined supply, with some miners and smelters agreeing to $0 per metric ton charges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Alcoa Corporation Reports Fourth Quarter and Full Year 2025 Results</title><link>https://news.alcoa.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2026/Alcoa-Corporation-Reports-Fourth-Quarter-and-Full-Year-2025-Results/default.aspx</link><description>Alcoa reported its FY25 financial results with aluminium production increasing 5% primarily due to restarts of smelters in Brazil, Spain, and Norway. The company expects 2026 alumina segment production to range between 9.7 and 9.9 million metric tons, an increase from 2025 driven by productivity improvements.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa shares dip despite 25% earnings boost in FY25</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/23/alcoa-shares-dip-despite-25-earnings-boost-in-fy25/</link><description>Alcoa achieved a 25% earnings boost in FY25 with alumina production dipping 4% due to the full curtailment of the Kwinana refinery, while aluminium production rose 5%. The company also announced a US$200 million joint venture with Japan's Sojitz Corporation to build a gallium extraction plant at its Wagerup refinery in Western Australia.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Overseas alumina transaction</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103734707</link><description>A transaction of 30,000 metric tons of alumina was traded overseas at $305/mt FOB East Australia on January 23, 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>South32 continues stable aluminium performance</title><link>https://aluminiumtoday.com/news/south32-continues-stable-performance-despite-headwinds</link><description>Australian aluminium company South32 reported a 3% increase in alumina production in the December 2025 half year, maintaining stable performance despite industry headwinds.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 23.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides daily updates on global iron and steel prices, including futures for rebar in Shanghai and various regional markets as of January 20-21, 2026. The platform tracks indices, news, and analyses for the iron and steel industry. It features sections on rebar, scrap, and market trends with real-time data.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking in 2026: Cleaner Routes, Tougher Trade Rules and Smarter Supply Chains</title><link>https://www.metallic-group.com/articles/steelmaking-in-2026-cleaner-routes-tougher-trade-rules-and-smarter-supply-chains/</link><description>The steel industry in 2026 is being reshaped by decarbonization technology, tighter trade rules including the EU CBAM effective January 1, 2026, and growing demand for emissions data. The industry is adopting modular technology approaches including EAF modernization, DRI-EAF hydrogen-ready systems, and CCUS upgrades.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global steel industry battles surplus supply, protectionism</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/global-steel-industry-battles-surplus-supply-protectionism/</link><description>India is expected to produce an additional 11.4 million metric tons of crude steel in 2026, increasing from an estimated 154 million metric tons in 2025. The global steel industry continues to face challenges from surplus supply and protectionist trade measures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Nederland unveils packaging steel line with TCCT technology</title><link>https://www.packaginginsights.com/news/tata-steel-nederland-packaging-steel-tcct.html</link><description>Tata Steel Nederland commissioned a new production line using Trivalent Chromium Coating Technology (TCCT) for sustainable packaging steel production that complies with future EU chemical legislation. The technology, combined with Protact polymer-coated packaging steel, reduces chemicals, costs, and supply chain complexity while maintaining food safety standards.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper falls to near two-week low</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40403555</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange dropped 1% to USD12,686 per metric ton in official open outcry activity. This marks a near two-week low amid ongoing market pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Storm Copper Resource Upgraded Ahead of PFS</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/23/northern-neighbors/storm-copper-resource-upgraded-ahead-of-pfs/9500.html</link><description>American West Metals upgraded the Storm Copper resource, which is now 20% larger with 65% of the copper in the higher confidence indicated category. The upgrade reflects improved geological understanding ahead of the prefeasibility study.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Which Copper Developer's Shares Are Flying After a Positive Economic Study for Their Proposed Mine?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/23/which-copper-developers-shares-are-flying-after-a-positive-economic-study-for-their-proposed-mine/</link><description>Celsius Resources completed a definitive feasibility study for a 35-year copper-gold mine project with a maiden ore reserve of 130.2 million tonnes, expecting US$230 million in annual EBITDA during the first 10 years. The company's shares rose 15% following the announcement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper, Gold Set to Be 'Big Winners' in 2026</title><link>https://mining.com.au/copper-gold-set-to-be-big-winners-in-2026/</link><description>White &amp; Case's Mining &amp; Metals 2026 report identifies copper and gold as expected 'big winners' following strong price growth in 2025. Copper reached US$12,000 per tonne in December 2025 due to output reductions from major mines including Escondido, Collahuasi, and Grasberg.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>AWS to Source Low Carbon Nuton Copper from Rio Tinto for U.S. Data Center Infrastructure</title><link>https://esgnews.com/aws-to-source-low-carbon-nuton-copper-from-rio-tinto-for-u-s-data-center-infrastructure/</link><description>AWS and Rio Tinto have partnered to source low-carbon copper produced through Nuton's innovative biohydrometallurgical process, which uses naturally occurring microorganisms to extract copper from primary sulphide ores. The technology eliminates traditional concentrators and smelters, reducing water use and emissions while producing 99.99% pure copper cathode at the mine gate. AWS will provide data and analytics expertise to optimize the process and accelerate commercial deployment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: ESDM estimates Indonesia's nickel production to fall by up to 15% in 2026</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5111197-flash-esdm-estimates-indonesias-nickel-production-to-fall-by-up-to-15-in-2026</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources plans to lower nickel ore production targets for 2026 to 250-260 million tonnes, down from the original 379 million tonnes, representing a 10-15% decrease from 2025 levels. The government aims to maintain supply-demand balance in the global nickel market and support nickel prices, while remaining open to importing nickel ore from the Philippines at current levels of 10-15 million tonnes annually.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia targets nickel prices at $19,000–$20,000 in 2026 after output cuts</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-targets-nickel-prices-at-19-000-20-000-in-2026-after-output-cuts</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources expects global nickel prices to stabilize following the country's announced output cuts for 2026. The production reductions are part of a strategic shift from maximizing supply to maximizing value in the global nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Parabellum Resources Confirms High-Grade Nickel-Cobalt Mineralisation at Miandetta</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/23/parabellum-resources-confirms-high-grade-nickel-cobalt-mineralisation-at-miandetta/</link><description>Parabellum Resources completed Phase 3 drilling at the Miandetta prospect in New South Wales, confirming shallow, high-grade nickel-cobalt mineralisation within the top 50 metres. The company identified notable results including 7 metres at 0.92% nickel and 0.05% cobalt, with mineralization in saprolite material suitable for atmospheric acid leach processing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices showed mixed movements on January 23, 2026, rising to 3175.35 USD/T (up 1.10%) in one report and falling to 3,132 USD/T (down 0.28%) in another. Over the past month, prices have risen between 5.92% and 7.39%, with yearly gains of 18.77% to 20.42%. The commodity remains supported near multi-year highs amid ongoing market volatility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AMU: For LME high grade aluminum, how high is high in a post China cost curve?</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/23/amu-for-lme-high-grade-aluminum-how-high-is-high-in-a-post-china-cost-curve/</link><description>LME aluminum cash prices reached $3,220/t recently, with forecasts predicting up to $4,000/t and 2026 averages in the $3,000s amid a structural shift away from cheap Chinese capacity. The rise is fueled by bullish sentiment, cost-push inflation, and the need for new non-Chinese primary capacity investments. High energy and power risks are limiting supply flexibility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CRU: Fewer imports tighten US steel supply, supporting domestic prices</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/23/cru-fewer-imports-tighten-us-steel-supply-supporting-domestic-prices/</link><description>Lower finished steel imports have supported US domestic prices, with HR coil prices up more than $40 per metric ton month-on-month due to higher seasonal demand and tighter supply. US long products prices also rose amid tight supply and higher scrap costs. Brazilian slab export prices increased by $10/mt to $480/mt fob Brazil.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global steel output falls to 2-year low in December</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/23/global-steel-output-falls-to-2-year-low-in-december/</link><description>Global raw steel production declined 0.4% from November to 139.6 million metric tons in December, marking the lowest monthly production in two years. China accounted for 48.9% of global production at 68.2 million metric tons, its lowest since December 2023, while rest-of-world production rose 1.7% to 71.4 million metric tons.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 2.12% Higher at $5.9110 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601235457/comex-copper-ends-the-week-212-higher-at-59110-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for January delivery rose 12.25 cents per pound, or 2.12%, to $5.9110 over the week, up six of the past nine weeks. On the day, it gained 16.85 cents or 2.93%, marking the largest one-day increase since January 5, 2026. The settlement is the seventh highest this year, off 1.66% from its 52-week high of $6.0105.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to 5.94 USD/Lbs on January 23, 2026, up 2.84% daily, supported by supply risks from a Chilean mine strike offsetting restarts elsewhere and strong demand from renewables and US shipments. Chinese smelters increased exports amid high global prices and domestic property strains. Prices extended a decline from a January record high of 6.11 USD/Lbs due to softening demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel market plays the Indonesia's numbers game – by Andy Home (Reuters) January 23, 2026</title><link>https://republicofmining.com/2026/01/23/nickel-market-plays-the-indonesias-numbers-game-by-andy-home-reuters-january-23-2026/</link><description>Indonesia will cut annual mining permits for nickel ore to 250-260 million wet tons in 2026 from 379 million tons in 2025, according to an energy ministry official. This reduction is part of efforts to manage supply and support market prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian to Acquire Submarine Cable Survey &amp; Installation Solutions Leader ACSM</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/agcm-inspection</link><description>Prysmian announced the acquisition of ACSM, a Spain-based submarine cable installation company, for EUR169 million. The deal strengthens Prysmian's global leadership in submarine cables and expands its service offerings for energy and telecommunications sectors, with closing expected in February 2026.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel Industry Newsletter 1/23/26</title><link>https://steelindustrynews.substack.com/p/steel-industry-newsletter-12326</link><description>The newsletter covers recent steel industry developments including Nucor's pricing strategies, Louisiana securing a site for Hyundai Steel's new mill, and Worthington Steel's $2.4 billion acquisition of Kloeckner &amp; Co. Global steel output has hit near two-year lows amid ongoing trade and tariff pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Dynamics, Inc. (NASDAQ: STLD) Quarterly Earnings Preview</title><link>https://site.financialmodelingprep.com/market-news/steel-dynamics-quarterly-earnings-preview</link><description>Steel Dynamics is preparing to release quarterly earnings on January 26, 2026, with analysts expecting EPS of $1.72 (a 26.5% increase from $1.36 last year) and revenue of approximately $4.54 billion (a 17.2% increase). The company maintains a strong financial position with a debt-to-equity ratio of 0.42 and current ratio of 3.11.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose to 3,129 CNY/T on January 23, 2026, up 0.68% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 1.10%, though still 5.68% lower than a year ago. Recent news highlights steel rebar futures steadying near five-month highs due to China's record December exports.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel prices today, January 24th: World iron ore prices recover to $114/ton, domestic steel prices remain stable</title><link>https://baonghean.vn/en/gia-thep-hom-nay-241-quang-sat-the-gioi-phuc-hoi-len-114-usdtan-thep-noi-dia-duy-tri-on-dinh-10321275.html</link><description>World iron ore prices recovered to $114 USD per ton on January 24, 2026. Domestic steel prices in Vietnam remained stable amid global recovery trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 24.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>Daily update on global iron and steel prices, news, analyses, and comments for January 24, 2026, covering industry trends and market developments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel rose to 18,710 USD/T on January 23, 2026, up 3.37% from the previous day, after reaching 18,564.13 USD/T earlier that day with a 2.56% increase. Nickel futures fell to around $17,800 per tonne, reversing from a nineteen-month high of $18,700, due to profit-taking and softening Chinese demand. Over the past month, prices have risen 18.54%, and are up 19.15% year-over-year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 24 Jan 2026</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2026/01/24/the-market-in-numbers-24-jan-2026/</link><description>Nickel prices stood at 8.1034 USD/lb on January 24, 2026, down 0.76% daily but up 8.23% monthly.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper price rallies back above $13,000 on supply worries</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-rallies-back-above-13000-on-supply-worries/</link><description>Copper surged over 3% to $13,173.50/t on the LME, a one-week high, driven by long-term supply concerns amid exploding AI demand and investor shifts to hard assets. US critical minerals status and potential tariffs under Trump add upward pressure. Year-to-date in 2026, prices have risen more than 6%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price spikes more than 10% as Chinese buying fuels metals surge</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-spikes-more-than-10-as-chinese-buying-fuels-metals-surge/</link><description>Nickel prices spiked over 10% in London to a high of $18,785 a ton on the LME, the biggest gain in over three years, driven by surging Chinese investor interest and mounting risks to Indonesian production. This extends a 30% rise since mid-December despite oversupply, marking a reversal from excess output and weak EV battery demand. Trading dynamics show Chinese influence with high-volume rallies during Asian hours.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] Refined high-grade NPI prices set to rise further next week</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103736898/smm-nickel-flash-refined-high-grade-npi-prices-set-to-rise-further-next-week</link><description>Refined nickel prices continued rising, with the most-traded SHFE nickel contract (2602) closing at 148,010 yuan/mt on Friday, up 2.52% week-on-week, hitting a weekly high of 150,000 yuan/mt. The LME nickel 3M contract also advanced amid the rally.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia cuts 2026 nickel quota, global prices jump immediately</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/60514/indonesia-cuts-2026-nickel-quota-global-prices-jump-immediately</link><description>Indonesia cut its 2026 nickel quota, leading to immediate strengthening of nickel prices on the LME and Asian exchanges due to growing concerns over tighter supply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Zijin officially puts Julong Copper Mine Phase 2 into production</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2026/01/25/zijin-officially-puts-julong-copper-mine-phase-2-into-production/</link><description>Zijin Mining announced that Phase 2 of the Julong Copper Mine project was officially completed and put into production on January 23, 2026. This expansion enhances the mine's production capacity, supporting global copper supply amid rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Jan '26 Futures Price</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/futures/quotes/ALF26</link><description>Aluminum Jan '26 futures traded at 3,097.50, up 1.20% with a +36.75 gain. Over the past month, prices rose 7.29% from lows, and 52-week performance shows a 16.56% increase. The dollar index decline supported the rally amid stock market gains.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Record high prices pressure Chinese aluminium demand</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2774952-record-high-prices-pressure-chinese-aluminium-demand</link><description>Chinese aluminum prices hit a record 25,075 yuan/t ($3,592/t) due to tight supply and strong sentiment, pressuring demand as some producers consider early Lunar New Year holidays. Social inventories rose to 714,000t by January 8, signaling ample supply amid weak spot demand. Traders anticipate further stock builds in January-February due to high prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Analysis: Processing Fees for Aluminum Billets Remain ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103725189</link><description>On January 5, 2026, SMM A00 aluminum prices surged 850 yuan/mt post-New Year's, causing billet processing fees to drop 0–160 yuan/mt but stay positive initially. By January 6, another 600 yuan/mt rise pushed fees negative despite production costs of 200–300 yuan/mt. The analysis examines producer and trader dynamics behind this trend.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Why Is Alcoa Corporation Stock Gaining Friday?</title><link>https://www.benzinga.com/markets/earnings/26/01/50090888/alcoa-cashes-in-on-higher-aluminum-prices-eyes-more-output-in-2026</link><description>Alcoa reported strong Q4 2025 results with increased alumina and aluminum production, projecting 2026 alumina output at 9.7–9.9 million metric tons and aluminum at 2.4–2.6 million metric tons due to productivity gains and smelter restarts. The Aluminum segment saw a 21% quarter-over-quarter revenue increase from higher pricing and shipments. Cash balance stood at $1.6 billion with $537 million from operations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Gain Support from Macro Tailwinds, Consolidating at High Levels in the Short Term - SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103737147/aluminum-prices-gain-support-from-macro-tailwinds-consolidating-at-high-levels-in-the-short-term-smm-aluminum-morning-me</link><description>SHFE aluminum futures showed slight gains amid supply disturbances including tax policy expectations, compliance checks, transportation issues, and environmental production restrictions in China. Domestic and Indonesian aluminum projects are ramping up steadily, but industry's operating rate is expected to trend downward short-term. Market selling improved slightly, though downstream buying remains weak.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Industry Newsletter 1/23/26</title><link>https://steelindustrynews.substack.com/p/steel-industry-newsletter-12326</link><description>Nucor continues to hold CSP steel price for the 4th week amid January 2026 market analysis. Highlights include Nucor raising HRC to $960/ton, US steel mills hiking coating extras, and global trade imbalances. Other news covers tariffs, production, and corporate developments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 19-month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/519806</link><description>Nickel increased to $18,908/T, the highest level since June 2024. Over the past 4 weeks, nickel has gained significantly as market sentiment remains bullish due to supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price Update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103738363</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price was 149,800-157,800 yuan/mt with an average price of 153,800 yuan/mt, up 5,250 yuan/mt from the previous trading day, reflecting continued strength in Asian markets.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Delayed publication of NPI FOB Indonesia price: pricing notice</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/delayed-publication-of-npi-fob-indonesia-price-pricing-notice/</link><description>Fastmarkets delayed the publication of its Nickel pig iron (10-14% Ni content, fob Indonesia) price assessment originally due on January 20, 2026, due to a technical error, with the database now updated. This price is part of the Steel Raw Materials package and relates to Indonesian nickel production capacities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>