<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 05:16:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>LME Explores Sustainable Metal Premia as Aluminum Demand Grows</title><link>https://www.lme.com/en/metals/non-ferrous/lme-aluminium</link><description>The LME is considering the introduction of price premia for sustainable metals, including aluminum, as part of efforts to meet rising demand for low-carbon materials. Aluminum remains a key metal for global industries due to its recyclability and strength-to-weight ratio, with the LME Official Price serving as the global benchmark.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Golden Triangle builds on Steel Dynamics growth with new Kloeckner aluminum plant</title><link>https://www.newsfromthestates.com/article/golden-triangle-builds-steel-dynamics-growth-new-kloeckner-aluminum-plant</link><description>The Golden Triangle is expanding its industrial capacity with a new Kloeckner aluminum plant, building on the growth of Steel Dynamics. This development aims to enhance regional economic and industrial activities.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LIXIL Standardizes Low-Carbon PremiAL Across Its Product Line</title><link>https://newsroom.lixil.com/2025091701</link><description>LIXIL Corporation is standardizing the use of PremiAL, its recycled low-carbon aluminum that reduces CO₂ emissions by approximately 50%, across its product line at no extra cost starting October 2025. This initiative leverages nearly 30 years of aluminum recycling expertise to significantly lower embodied carbon in building materials, supporting the decarbonization of the construction industry in Japan.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Update and Forecast</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices decreased to $789/tonne, the lowest since February 2025, down 0.48% from the previous day. Prices have fallen 2.40% over the past month but remain 15.05% higher than a year ago. Analysts expect prices to rise to $831/tonne by the end of the quarter and $894/tonne within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMU Survey: Current Sentiment Sinks to Lowest Level Since May 2020</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/17/smu-survey-current-sentiment-sinks-to-lowest-level-since-may-2020/</link><description>Steel buyers report steady to slightly higher prices but weak demand and slow inventories. U.S. domestic sheet prices remain rangebound amid supply tightness and weak demand, with scrap prices falling in October. Tariffs continue to cloud market outlook as the industry heads into the final quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMU flat-rolled market survey results now available</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/17/smu-flat-rolled-market-survey-results-now-available-18/</link><description>Steel mill lead times have decreased across most sheet and plate products in the US, according to the latest SMU survey. Current steel buyer sentiment has dropped to its lowest level since May 2020, reflecting weak demand and rangebound domestic prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to $4.96 per pound on October 17, 2025, up 0.33% from the previous day, with a 9.32% increase over the past month and a 13.92% rise year-over-year. Trading Economics forecasts copper to trade at $4.93 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.40 in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 1.71% Higher at $4.9315 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510176093/comex-copper-ends-the-week-171-higher-at-49315-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for October delivery gained 1.71% this week to $4.9315 per pound, despite a recent four-session losing streak and a 3.31% drop over the last four sessions. Copper remains up 23.72% from its 52-week low but is down 14.9% from its 2025 high.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Pulled Back This Week Due to Fundamental Pressure</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575414/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-pulled-back-this-week-due-to-fundamental-pressure-and-inventory-levels-increased-further</link><description>Nickel prices have retreated due to fundamental pressures and increased inventory levels. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 121,160 yuan/mt, down 1.89% week-over-week. LME nickel prices also fell to $15,140/mt, showing synchronized weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alaska Energy Metals Provides Corporate Update On Nikolai Nickel Project, Alaska And Announces Amendment To Restricted Share Plan And Grants Of Stock Options And Restricted Share Units</title><link>https://www.webdisclosure.com/press-release/alaska-energy-metals-provides-corporate-update-on-nikolai-nickel-project-alaska-and-announces-amendment-to-restricted-share-plan-and-grants-of-stock-options-and-restricted-share-units-0QbQl3fiVKg</link><description>Alaska Energy Metals reports that first-pass metallurgical testing at the Eureka deposit of the Nikolai nickel project is nearing completion, with results expected in November 2025. The company is also advancing an internal options study and pursuing US government grant funding, with a Preliminary Economic Assessment planned for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,774.55 USD/T on October 17, 2025, down 0.88% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped slightly to $2,774.55 per tonne on October 17, 2025, down 0.88% from the previous day. Despite this dip, prices have risen 2.89% over the past month and are up 6.06% compared to the same time last year. Aluminum futures recently hit a three-year high amid tight supply and bullish demand expectations, with forecasts suggesting prices could reach $2,805.80 per tonne by the end of the quarter.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price heads for longest winning streak in a year</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-heads-for-longest-winning-streak-in-a-year-before-fed/</link><description>Aluminum prices climbed for a seventh consecutive session ahead of the Federal Reserve's anticipated interest rate decision, reaching the highest levels since March 2025. The metal's gains are supported by expectations of monetary easing, which tends to weaken the dollar and boost industrial metals. Additionally, increased withdrawals from inventories have raised concerns about supply tightness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CRU: Soft Demand Weighs on Sheet Imports into the US</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/17/cru-soft-demand-weighs-on-sheet-imports-into-the-us/</link><description>Brazilian slab export prices remained stable in October amid competition from low-priced Asian offers, with export volumes slightly down month-over-month but up year-over-year. An incident at ArcelorMittal Mexico impacted slab production, potentially increasing reliance on imported slabs to offset shortfalls.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash bid hits $2,789/t; stocks down to 491,225t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-bid-hits-2-789-t-stocks-down-to-491-225t-115885</link><description>LME aluminium prices edged higher on October 17, with the cash bid at $2,789 per tonne and warehouse stocks declining slightly by 0.83% to 491,225 tonnes. The three-month and forward contract prices also increased, reflecting modest gains across the market despite a small drop in inventories. The LME alumina Platts price remained steady at $318.91 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices and Market Trends - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China rose slightly to 3,044 CNY per ton on October 17, 2025, marking a 0.03% increase from the previous day. However, steel prices have fallen 1.07% over the past month and are down 6.34% compared to the same period last year, with forecasts suggesting a slight increase by the end of the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>First Africa-Europe Power Bridge Moves Ahead As Contract Awarded For Submarine Cable</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news/0110-49154-first-africa-europe-power-bridge-moves-ahead-as-contract-awarded-for-submarine-cable</link><description>Prysmian has won a €460 million contract to build a 220-km high-voltage submarine power cable connecting Sicily, Italy, to Tunisia. The cable will carry 600 MW and is part of the Tunisia-Italy interconnection project (ELMED), supporting cleaner energy and energy security between Europe and Africa.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian wins 460 million euros power cable deal connecting Italy to Tunisia</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/prysmian-wins-460-mln-euros-power-cable-deal-connecting-italy-to-tunisia-ce7d58d3d08af02d</link><description>Prysmian secured a contract worth around €460 million to build a submarine power cable from the Partanna substation in Sicily to the Mlaabi substation in Tunisia. The project is part of the Elmed Project and aims to enhance energy interconnection and support the transition to cleaner energy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME WEEK: US aluminum price rise spurs deliveries from Canada</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/lme-week-us-aluminum-price-rise-spurs-deliveries-from-canada/</link><description>The rise in US aluminum prices has led to an increase in deliveries from Canada, though not yet at full pace. The Midwest premium has hit a record high, effectively pricing in the 50% tariff. This has also influenced European duty-paid aluminum premiums, which have jumped significantly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump's tariffs spur US aluminum industry to boost recycling</title><link>https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/clean-aluminum/trump-tariffs-spur-metal-recycling</link><description>President Trump's tariffs have prompted the US aluminum industry to increase recycling efforts. This shift is part of broader trends in the US aluminum market, which has seen changes in inventories and production strategies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Chart and Historical Data</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose slightly to 3,044 CNY/tonne on October 17, 2025, up 0.03% from the previous day. However, steel prices have fallen 1.07% over the past month and are down 6.34% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect steel to trade around 3,047 CNY/tonne by the end of the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China rose slightly to 3,044 CNY/T on October 17, 2025, up 0.03% from the previous day, but are down 1.07% over the past month and 6.34% year-over-year. Trading Economics forecasts steel to trade at 3047.39 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter, with a further decline expected over the next 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP's Copper Boom: Sustainable Mining to Meet Soaring Global Demand</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/bhps-copper-boom-sustainable-mining-to-meet-soaring-global-demand/</link><description>BHP is investing in sustainable mining practices to meet the growing demand for copper, driven by electric vehicles, renewable energy, and data centers. The company aims to support a lower-carbon future with strong operations and clean energy goals. Recycled copper will also play a significant role in meeting rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anaconda Copper Mine 2025: Innovations &amp; Sustainability</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/anaconda-copper-mine-2025-innovations-sustainability</link><description>The Anaconda Copper Mine is embracing innovations like AI, digital monitoring, and eco-rehabilitation to meet sustainability and economic goals. The mine serves as a model for responsible resource extraction, balancing environmental stewardship with community resilience. Advances in technology are crucial for the future of mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, Silver &amp; Copper: Tech and Sustainability Trends</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_ca/insights/mining-metals/gold-silver-and-copper-tech-and-sustainability-trends</link><description>Copper companies are leveraging digital innovations and sustainability practices to address supply gaps. Technologies like AI and satellite imaging are being used to enhance exploration and production. Recycling and circular economy principles are also key strategies to ensure long-term value and reduce environmental impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Glut Persists but African Mining Ambitions Remain Strong</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/1410-49523-nickel-glut-persists-but-african-mining-ambitions-remain-strong</link><description>The global nickel market is expected to remain oversupplied in 2026, with a projected surplus of 261,000 tons. Despite weak prices, African mining projects continue to advance. Nickel prices have fallen significantly since 2022.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper slips on US credit fears</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40388118</link><description>Copper slid to a one-week low, tracking a fall in global financial stocks as signs of credit stress at US regional banks weighed on market sentiment. The decline reflected broader concerns about credit quality in the US financial sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price back on track for weekly gain as Trump calms trade angst</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-back-on-track-for-weekly-gain-as-trump-calms-trade-angst/</link><description>Copper pared declines after US President Donald Trump eased fears of a trade war with China, boosting demand prospects for the metal. The wiring metal is on pace for a 0.5% weekly gain, having touched $11,000 a ton the previous week—the highest intraday level since May 2024—on supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 15,110 USD/T on October 17, 2025, down 0.79% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices decreased to $15,110 per tonne on October 17, 2025, marking a 0.79% drop from the previous day and a 1.47% decline over the past month. The price is down 11.02% compared to the same time last year, with expectations for further decline over the next 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>RMI Introduces New Sustainable Aluminum Finance Framework to Propel Industry Decarbonization</title><link>https://esgnews.com/rmi-introduces-new-sustainable-aluminum-finance-framework-to-propel-industry-decarbonization/</link><description>RMI has introduced a Sustainable Aluminum Finance Framework to help banks align financing with decarbonization goals. Aluminum is crucial for electric vehicles and renewable energy infrastructure, and decarbonizing the sector requires switching to clean power sources and increasing recycling rates.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Chart and Market Trends</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose slightly to 3,044 CNY/ton on October 17, 2025, up 0.03% from the previous day. However, steel prices have fallen 1.07% over the past month and are down 6.34% compared to last year. Forecasts expect prices to trade around 3,008.71 CNY/ton by the end of the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Copper Demand Projected to Outpace Supply by Over 500,000 Tonnes In 2025</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-copper-demand-projected-to-outpace-supply-by-over-500-000-tonnes-in-2025--driving-upward-price-pressure-302563846.html</link><description>Copper demand is expected to exceed supply by over 500,000 tonnes in 2025, leading to upward price pressure. The metal is crucial for infrastructure development, renewable energy initiatives, and agricultural modernization. Persistent supply constraints and geopolitical challenges are contributing factors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price maintains upward trend on Oct 19</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-price-maintains-upward-trend-on-oct-19/121795</link><description>The three-month futures price of nickel on the London Metal Exchange (LME) rose by US$32/ton on October 19, closing at US$15,684/ton, indicating a short-term upward trend in nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On October 19th, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulfate index price was 32113/ton</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/102425401/</link><description>The battery-grade nickel sulfate index price dropped by 121 yuan/ton on October 19 compared to the previous working day, reflecting a slight decrease in prices for battery-grade nickel products.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Enhances Energy Performance and Reduces Environmental Impact</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA to enhance energy performance and reduce environmental impact. This agreement supports the company's decarbonization efforts and aligns with regional sustainability goals. It also benefits CVA by stabilizing energy sale prices and providing economic incentives.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italian Steelmaker Cogne Acciai Speciali Sourcing All Energy from Renewables</title><link>https://eurometal.net/italian-steelmaker-cogne-acciai-speciali-sourcing-all-energy-from-renewables/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali now sources all its energy from renewable sources in Europe. The company plans to build a hydroelectric plant and an electrolyzer at its Aosta site to produce green hydrogen. This project is part of Italy's National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Launches Green Hydrogen Pilot Plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has launched a pilot plant in Aosta, Italy, to produce green hydrogen. This initiative is part of the company's efforts to transition towards cleaner energy sources. The project is supported by the European Union through NextGenerationEU.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian has been awarded a contract for the construction of a submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia under the Elmed Project. The project aims to create an energy bridge between Europe and Africa, enhancing energy security. The contract could reach a value of around €460 million.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Secures €460m Contract For Italy–Tunisia Subsea Power Link</title><link>https://www.wireworld.com/wirenews/prysmian-secures-460m-contract-for-italytunisia-subsea-power-link.html</link><description>Prysmian has secured a contract to build a submarine power cable connecting Italy and Tunisia. The project is valued at approximately €460 million. It will enhance energy connectivity between Europe and Africa.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Green Steel &amp; Renewable Energy: Revolutionizing the Industry</title><link>https://www.allthingssupplychain.com/green-steel-renewable-energy-revolutionizing-the-industry/</link><description>Green steel production powered by renewable energy, especially green hydrogen, is transforming the steel industry by significantly reducing CO2 emissions. This innovation replaces coal in steelmaking with green hydrogen produced via electrolysis using renewable sources like wind and solar, offering a sustainable pathway for the global steel supply chain.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Global Steel Industry 2025: At a Pivotal Crossroads</title><link>https://www.steel-technology.com/articles/the-global-steel-industry-2025-at-a-pivotal-crossroads</link><description>The steel industry is undergoing major changes with AI integration, automation, and sustainability driving new production methods. Green steel production is gaining momentum as demand for low-carbon materials rises, with companies adopting sustainable steelmaking to meet zero-emission goals and attract investors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises Toward 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/490733</link><description>Aluminum futures rose toward $2,730 per tonne in October, reaching the highest level in three years amid expectations of lower supply. Chinese authorities have cut their annual output growth target for base metals to 1.5% for 2025 and 2026, down from 5%, and Alcoa announced the shutdown of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia due to deteriorating bauxite grades. Physical aluminum demand increased, causing primary aluminum stocks to drop by 55,000 tonnes in September before rebounding slightly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Drops on Oct 20</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575945/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Drops-on-Oct-20</link><description>Social inventory of aluminum ingots in major domestic consumption areas dropped to 625,000 metric tons as of October 20, indicating tightening supply conditions in the domestic market. This decline in inventory aligns with broader trends of reduced aluminum availability amid strong demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weekly Recap: Aluminium's low-carbon revolution in action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminum industry is rapidly transforming with a focus on sustainability, including the adoption of renewable energy, advanced recycling technologies, and innovative production methods. Highlights include RUSAL’s new electrochemical technology for high-purity recycling, Taural India’s emission-reducing initiatives, and Egypt’s Dandara Solar Energy project to cut Egyptalum’s emissions by 30%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Stainless Mills Hold Prices Pre-Contracting</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/10/20/nickel-prices-flat-mills-hold-prices/</link><description>U.S. stainless steel prices remained flat with mills maintaining base price increases from summer, showing no further hikes or price erosion despite weak demand. Market survey indicates stable demand for 60% of respondents, with no significant oversupply or undersupply evidenced by steady mill lead times.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Coal and Steel Production Shrink Again as Demand Slumps</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-20/china-s-coal-and-steel-production-shrink-again-as-demand-slumps</link><description>China's steel production fell for the fifth consecutive month in September to its lowest level since December 2023, driven by weaker demand and government efforts to curb excessive output. Coal production also declined year-on-year due to inspections and flooding, while steel output dropped 4.6% in September amid rising feedstock costs and subdued demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Q2: Strong volumes boost profit, brokers maintain cautious stance</title><link>https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/jsw-steel-q2-strong-volumes-boost-profit-brokers-maintain-cautious-stance-125102000132_1.html</link><description>JSW Steel reported a 269.7% year-on-year jump in consolidated net profit to ₹1,623 crore in Q2FY26, driven by higher sales volumes despite lower realisations. The company achieved record crude steel production of 7.90 million tonnes, with domestic sales up 14% year-on-year and exports surging 89%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Coal and Steel Production Shrink Again as Demand Slumps</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-20/china-s-coal-and-steel-production-shrink-again-as-demand-slumps</link><description>China's coal and steel output declined in September due to weak demand and government efforts to curb excessive production. Steelmaking output dropped for the fifth consecutive month to its lowest since December 2023.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Climbs on Easing Trade Tensions, China's Economic Outlook</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-20/copper-climbs-on-easing-trade-tensions-china-s-economic-outlook</link><description>Copper prices rose more than 1% as US President Donald Trump sought to ease trade tensions with China and Beijing signaled confidence in meeting its economic growth targets. The improved sentiment around risk assets, including commodities, followed signs of reduced US-China confrontation ahead of expected trade talks later this month.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco Plans to Raise Copper Premiums in Europe, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575818/Codelco-Plans-to-Raise-Copper-Premiums-in-Europe-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Chile's Codelco plans to increase copper premiums for European customers to a record $345/mt in 2026, reflecting tight global supply and rising energy costs. Meanwhile, LME copper futures saw significant intraday volatility but closed slightly lower, while SHFE copper edged up modestly amid active trading.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Commodity Radar: Copper prices cool off after Monday's sharp rally – time to buy on dips for 16% potential gains, says Religare expert</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/commodity-radar-copper-prices-cool-off-after-mondays-sharp-rally-time-to-buy-on-dips-for-16-potential-gains-says-religare-expert/articleshow/124548572.cms</link><description>Copper prices fell sharply on Tuesday following a strong rally the previous day, as investors took profits. Despite the pullback, analysts highlight ongoing supply disruptions, falling exchange inventories, and strong demand from green energy and EVs as factors supporting a bullish long-term outlook for copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>This ASX All Ords copper stock has almost tripled investors' money in 2025. Here's why it could keep charging higher</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/10/20/this-asx-all-ords-copper-stock-has-almost-tripled-investors-money-in-2025-heres-why-it-could-keep-charging-higher/</link><description>Aeris Resources Ltd shares have significantly increased in value due to rising copper prices and strategic positioning in the defence sector. Copper is crucial for both green energy transitions and defence applications, contributing to its demand growth. The company's operational performance and market trends suggest potential for further growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>TRADE REVIEW: Copper concentrate TC/RCs to be pressured in Q4 by restocking demand from smelters</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/trade-review-copper-concentrate-tc-rcs-to-be-pressured-in-q4-by-restocking-demand-from-smelters/</link><description>Copper concentrate treatment and refining charges are expected to face pressure in Q4 due to restocking demand from smelters preparing for 2026 production. This demand could impact the pricing dynamics of copper concentrates in the Asian market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ero Copper (TSX:ERO) Boost Operations Growth Listed TSX Smallcap Index</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/ca/stocks/metal-and-mining/ero-copper-tsxero-boost-operations-growth-listed-tsx-smallcap-index</link><description>Ero Copper has exceeded quarterly earnings expectations, reflecting operational efficiency. The company's Tucumã Operation has begun commercial production, contributing to increased operational capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia releases October (Period I) benchmark prices for nickel ore</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5100101-flash-indonesia-releases-october-period-i-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore</link><description>The Indonesia Nickel Miners Association announced domestic benchmark prices for nickel ore for the first half of October 2025, with prices increasing slightly from September. Prices for nickel ore grades from 1.6% to 2.0% Ni content rose by $0.18 to $0.28 per wet metric ton compared to the previous period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices edged down slightly on October 20 as China and the US agreed to hold a new round of trade consultations</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103576549/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-down-slightly-on-October-20-as-China-and-the-US-agreed-to-hold-a-new-round-of-trade-consultations-as-soon-as-possible</link><description>On October 20, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,100 yuan/mt, down 250 yuan/mt from the previous day. The slight price decline coincided with news of upcoming trade talks between China and the US, which may influence market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices pulled back this week due to fundamental pressure and inventory levels increased further</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575414/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-pulled-back-this-week-due-to-fundamental-pressure-and-inventory-levels-increased-further</link><description>Nickel prices declined under pressure from fundamentals with the SHFE nickel contract closing down 1.89% week-on-week at 121,160 yuan/mt. Inventory levels increased, creating a stalemate between cost support and inventory pressure. LME nickel prices also showed weakness, settling at $15,140/mt, down 0.53% week-on-week.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Stainless Mills Hold Prices Pre-Contracting</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/10/20/nickel-prices-flat-mills-hold-prices/</link><description>Nickel prices have remained range-bound through September and October with some upward drift from summer lows. Despite this, downside risks persist due to funds shifting to net short positions and global economic headwinds. Stainless steel buyers may benefit from potential nickel price declines affecting surcharges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Poised to Exit $15K Range as Seasonal Supply Constraints Hit Market</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-prices-poised-to-exit-15k-range-as-seasonal-supply-constraints-hit-market</link><description>Nickel prices have been range-bound between $15,000 and $15,800 per ton since April 2025, but seasonal supply constraints and regulatory crackdowns in Indonesia are creating conditions for potential price increases. Growing electric vehicle demand and government support in Canada add to positive market fundamentals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Stainless Mills Hold Prices Pre-Contracting - MetalMiner</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/10/20/nickel-prices-flat-mills-hold-prices/</link><description>Nickel prices remain flat amid ample supply and a strong U.S. dollar, with little indication of a demand turnaround in the short term. Stainless steel buyers may benefit from potential declines in nickel surcharges, although global economic headwinds persist.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Sumitomo-Mitsubishi partnership underpins Kalgoorlie Nickel Project development</title><link>https://mining.com.au/sumitomo-mitsubishi-partnership-underpins-kalgoorlie-nickel-project-development/</link><description>The partnership between Sumitomo Metal Mining and Mitsubishi Corporation is driving the development of the Kalgoorlie Nickel Project (KNP) with a fully funded $98.5 million Definitive Feasibility Study. The collaboration strengthens the project's path to market and supports long-term nickel-cobalt supply security.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Kalgoorlie Nickel Project Secures Three-Year Major Status Extension</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/kalgoorlie-nickel-project-2025-critical-minerals-renewal/</link><description>The Kalgoorlie Nickel Project benefits from a three-year major status extension, leveraging laterite deposits with improved processing technologies for better recovery and sustainability. The joint venture between Ardea Resources, Sumitomo Metal Mining, and Mitsubishi Corporation combines Australian expertise with Japanese technology and market access to strengthen nickel production capacity.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices edged down slightly on October 20</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103576549/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-down-slightly-on-October-20-as-China-and-the-US-agreed-to-hold-a-new-round-of-trade-consultations-as-soon-as-possible</link><description>Nickel prices in China edged down slightly amid ongoing trade negotiations between China and the U.S. The SHFE nickel contract showed consolidation with prices expected to remain subdued due to weak fundamentals and external uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale scraps plans to build Quebec nickel sulphate facility</title><link>https://www.mining.com/vale-scraps-plans-to-build-quebec-nickel-sulphate-facility/</link><description>Vale has cancelled its C$325 million nickel sulphate plant project in Quebec after General Motors delayed its Ultium Cam battery expansion. The facility would have been North America's first fully domestic nickel sulphate plant, critical for lithium-ion battery production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali and CVA Agreement for Decarbonization</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA to enhance energy performance and reduce environmental impact. The agreement supports CVA's leadership in decarbonization and provides stable revenue flows for CVA through the Energy Release scheme. It aligns with Cogne's strategic goals for sustainability.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Falls Amid Renewed US-China Tensions</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell due to renewed tensions between the US and China, particularly over rare earth export controls. Despite this, aluminum prices remain high, supported by strong market fundamentals. The price dropped to $2,740 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Approaches Record on US-China Trade Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-approaches-record-on-us-china-trade-uncertainty/</link><description>Copper prices neared records due to uncertainty surrounding US-China trade talks and global supply disruptions. Prices reached as high as $10,691.50 per tonne in London and $5.0485 per lb. on the Comex. The market remains bullish amid mine disruptions and supply issues.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Arizona Sonoran soars on new copper ranking</title><link>https://www.mining.com/arizona-sonoran-soars-on-new-copper-ranking/</link><description>Arizona Sonoran Copper's shares hit a historic high after releasing a pre-feasibility study showing its Cactus project could become the third largest cathode copper producer in the U.S. The project is expected to produce about 103,000 tonnes annually over the first 10 years with strong economic metrics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The global copper conundrum</title><link>https://www.africanmining.co.za/2025/10/21/the-global-copper-conundrum/</link><description>This analysis discusses concerns over the long-term sustainability of copper supply, citing an imbalance between merger and acquisition activity and the discovery of new copper deposits. It raises questions about whether current innovation and investment levels can meet future demand amid tightening supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Rises, But Sentiment Bearish on Strong Supply -- Market Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510203761/how-china-took-over-worlds-rare-earths-industry-2</link><description>Nickel prices edged higher with the three-month LME contract rising slightly. Indonesia has increased efforts to address safety and environmental issues in nickel mining by revoking permits and suspending companies, which has eased concerns about overexpansion but market sentiment remains bearish due to expectations of strong Indonesian nickel supply continuing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Bunker Hill Provides October Project Update</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=68f616484300f3e8520eeaef</link><description>Bunker Hill Mining Corp. reported substantial progress toward restarting the Bunker Hill Mine in Idaho, targeting the first half of 2026 for restart. The company highlighted advances in project development including filter press concrete foundations and processing plant installations, supporting efforts to strengthen the US metals supply chain with nickel among key metals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali to construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will build four photovoltaic plants in Sicily with over 20 MW capacity, enhancing energy performance and reducing environmental impact. This initiative aligns with their 2026–2029 Strategic Plan and supports regional decarbonisation efforts, strengthening their partnership with CVA.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, Italy, marking a step towards sustainable steel production. This initiative reflects the company's commitment to innovation and environmental responsibility in the specialty steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Macro Tailwinds and Solid Fundamentals Support Aluminum Prices</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices are expected to hold up well in the short term due to macroeconomic tailwinds and solid market fundamentals. The SHFE aluminum contract showed a consolidating trend, fluctuating around 20,930 yuan/mt. Technical indicators suggest a bullish alignment.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tightening Fundamentals and Inventory Drawdown to Boost Aluminum Prices</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103578139/Tightening-fundamentals-and-inventory-drawdown-to-boost-aluminum-prices-in-the-short-term-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Aluminum prices are likely to be boosted by tightening market fundamentals and inventory drawdowns. The most-traded SHFE aluminum contract closed at 20,920 yuan/mt, showing a fluctuating upward trend. Market sentiment remains cautious due to insufficient trading volume.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>South32 Ltd (S32) Earnings: Alumina &amp; Aluminum Production Increase as FY26 Guidance Holds</title><link>https://www.smartkarma.com/home/newswire/earnings-alerts/south32-ltd-s32-earnings-alumina-aluminum-production-increase-as-fy26-guidance-holds/</link><description>South32 reported a 1.4% increase in alumina production to 1.29 million tons and a 0.6% rise in aluminum production to 311,000 tons in the first quarter. The company maintained its FY26 production guidance despite some fluctuations in other metal outputs. Production increases were supported by operations exceeding capacity and improved supply conditions, while negotiations for long-term electricity supply at Mozal Aluminium remain unresolved.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Dynamics Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/steel-dynamics-reports-third-quarter-2025-results-302589340.html</link><description>Steel Dynamics highlighted strong performance in its aluminum flat rolled products segment, with finished products for industrial, beverage can, and automotive sectors being qualified earlier than expected. The company is ramping up operations and expects stronger demand for aluminum flat rolled products heading into 2026. Additionally, Steel Dynamics produced its first biocarbon to lower carbon emissions in steel production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>South32 Production Guidance Steady Despite Share Slump</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/21/south32-production-guidance-steady-despite-share-slump/</link><description>South32 reaffirmed its FY26 production guidance across all operations, including aluminum, despite a nearly 10% share price decline this year. The company reported a 33% increase in manganese volumes and a 12% rise in payable copper equivalent production. CEO Graham Kerr emphasized the focus on maintaining momentum and capitalizing on strengthening base metals market conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum's Low-Carbon Revolution in Action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminum industry is undergoing a significant transformation with a focus on sustainability, innovation, and circular practices. Companies are adopting low-carbon production methods, renewable energy, and advanced recycling technologies. This shift is driven by changing environmental standards and market needs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit 3-Year High: Is It the Next Key Metal in the Clean Energy Shift?</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-hit-3-year-high-is-it-the-next-key-metal-in-the-clean-energy-shift/</link><description>Aluminum prices have reached a three-year high due to increased demand from electric vehicles, solar, and grid upgrades. The industry is shifting towards low-carbon production, with new projects in Europe, Canada, and the Middle East expected to increase global capacity for low-carbon aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium's Real Paradox – Energy Use vs Carbon Saving</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminiums-real-paradox-energy-use-vs-carbon-saving-uncover-the-role-of-recycling-in-this-from-our-latest-magazine-115858</link><description>The aluminum industry faces a paradox between energy use and carbon savings. Recycling is highlighted as a key solution, saving up to 95% of energy needed for primary aluminum production and reducing greenhouse gas emissions. The global recycling rate was 76% in 2024.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Falls Slightly on October 20, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel price fell to 812 USD/T on October 20, 2025, down 0.25% from the previous day and 2.05% over the past month, though still 15.18% higher than a year ago. Forecasts expect HRC steel prices to rise to 829.86 USD/T by the end of Q4 2025 and 893.93 USD/T within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Jin10 Futures Morning Report, October 21, 2025</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/63534555/jin10-futures-morning-report-october-21-2025-tuesday</link><description>The report highlights global iron ore shipments from October 13 to October 19, 2025, which increased by 1.26 million tonnes from the previous week. China's crude steel production in September 2025 was 73.49 million tons, marking a year-on-year decrease of 4.6%. Additionally, coal mines in the Shanyin County area halted production temporarily.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Pressured by Weak Demand</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel/news/494316</link><description>Steel rebar futures remain low due to sluggish demand and narrowing margins. China's crude steel production in September was 73.49 million metric tons, down 4.6% from a year earlier. Only about 57% of Chinese steel mills were profitable by the end of September.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ASI Honours Sustainability Leaders</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/asi-honours-sustainability-leaders-1554271/</link><description>The Australian Steel Institute's 2025 Steel Sustainability Awards recognized leading sustainability projects in the steel industry. Winners included the St Marys Integrated Project Office and Bradbury Park Playscape for their innovative and sustainable construction methods. These projects highlight the industry's focus on reducing waste and emissions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103578116/MMGs-Copper-Loss-Amounts-to-90000-mt-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, initially dropping to $10,601/mt before rising to a high of $10,714/mt and closing at $10,712.5/mt, up 0.99%. The SHFE copper contract also saw fluctuations, closing at 85,670 yuan/mt, up 0.48%. MMG reported copper losses of about 90,000 mt due to illegal mining at its Las Bambas mine.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Demand to Rise 24% to 43 MTPA, Tightening Supply: Report</title><link>https://www.mercomindia.com/copper-demand-to-rise-24-to-43-mtpa-tightening-supply-report</link><description>A report by Wood Mackenzie forecasts copper demand to increase by 24% to 42.7 million tons per annum, driven by global economic development and electrification. Factors like electric vehicles and industrialization in Asia are expected to significantly boost demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Ticks Higher on Strong China Industrial Data; Plenum in Focus</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-ticks-higher-on-strong-china-industrial-data-plenum-in-focus/</link><description>Copper prices rose following strong industrial data from China. Investors are also focusing on upcoming political events in China, which could impact market trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP starts FY strong as copper and iron-ore output lift in tightening markets</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/bhp-starts-fy-strong-as-copper-and-iron-ore-output-lift-in-tightening-markets-2025-10-21</link><description>BHP reported a 4% increase in group copper production, driven by record concentrator throughput at the Escondida mine. This production boost comes amid tightening markets for copper and iron ore.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Demand to Rise 24% to 43 MTPA, Tightening Supply: Report</title><link>https://www.mercomindia.com/copper-demand-to-rise-24-to-43-mtpa-tightening-supply-report</link><description>A Wood Mackenzie report forecasts copper demand to increase by 24% to 42.7 million tons per annum by 2035, driven by factors such as electric vehicles, renewable energy, AI data centers, and industrialization in India and Southeast Asia. The report highlights supply tightening amid rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Solis Minerals to Acquire Cucho Copper Project in Peru</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/21/solis-minerals-to-acquire-cucho-copper-project-in-peru/</link><description>Solis Minerals announced a binding agreement to acquire up to 75% interest in the Cucho Copper Project in Peru, a large-scale copper-molybdenum-silver porphyry system. The project has significant historical drilling data and potential for a major resource, with plans for exploration drilling in early 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tartana Minerals Returns Strong Copper-Gold Assays from Exploration at Muscleville Project in FNQ</title><link>https://smallcaps.com.au/tartana-minerals-strong-copper-gold-assays-exploration-muscleville-project/</link><description>Tartana Minerals reported strong copper and gold assay results from its Muscleville prospect in Queensland, Australia. The results confirm mineralization in new zones near the existing open pit, supporting future drilling targets and exploration potential.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP Resolution Copper Mine: 7 Innovations For 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/bhp-resolution-copper-mine-7-innovations-for-2025</link><description>The article details seven major technological and sustainability innovations at BHP's Resolution Copper Mine, including automated drilling, advanced ore processing, intelligent mine management, water recycling, sustainable land reclamation, renewable energy integration, and community engagement. These innovations are projected to significantly reduce CO2 emissions, increase efficiency, and boost annual copper output, setting a benchmark for sustainable copper mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Sandvik Mining Equipment Demand Drives Record Industry Growth</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/sandvik-mining-equipment-demand-2025-technological-innovation/</link><description>The article reports on surging global demand for Sandvik mining equipment, driven by the energy transition, infrastructure development, and stricter environmental regulations. It notes that copper and other critical minerals are central to this growth, with mining companies upgrading equipment for greater efficiency and lower emissions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On October 21, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel was 121,100-123,900 yuan/mt, with an average price of 122,500 yuan/mt, up 400 yuan/mt from the previous</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103578980/</link><description>Nickel prices edged up slightly on October 21, with the average price of SMM #1 refined nickel rising by 400 yuan/mt to 122,500 yuan/mt. This reflects a modest increase in the nickel market on that day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices edged up slightly on October 21 while China's GDP in the first three quarters rose 5.2% YoY</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103579044/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-up-slightly-on-October-21-while-Chinas-GDP-in-the-first-three-quarters-rose-52-YoY</link><description>Nickel prices showed a slight increase on October 21, with the average price of SMM #1 refined nickel at 122,500 yuan/mt, up 400 yuan/mt from the previous day. The report also notes China's GDP growth of 5.2% year-over-year for the first three quarters of 2025, which may influence market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Jin10 Futures Morning Report, October 21, 2025 (Tuesday)</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/63534555/jin10-futures-morning-report-october-21-2025-tuesday</link><description>The report covers broader commodity trends including iron ore shipments and steel production in China, with no direct update on nickel prices. However, it provides context on raw material supply and demand which can impact nickel market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On October 21, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel was up</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103578980/</link><description>The price of SMM #1 refined nickel increased by 400 yuan/mt to an average of 122,500 yuan/mt, reflecting a short-term price rise in refined nickel on October 21, 2025.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali transaction closing: Walsin Lihwa Corporation at 70% of capital</title><link>https://www.industrialvalvenews.com/featured/cogne-acciai-speciali-transaction-closing-walsin-lihwa-corporation-at-70-of-capital/</link><description>Walsin Lihwa Corporation has become the majority shareholder of Cogne Acciai Speciali with a 70% stake, while the Marzorati family retains 30%. Yu-Lon Chiao will succeed Eng. Giuseppe Marzorati as President starting December 1st, and Massimiliano Burelli has been appointed CEO to lead integration and growth plans.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris to launch TenarisShawcor White Jacket™ coating at the Hydrogen and CCUS Technology World Expo</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-to-launch-tenarisshawcor-white-jacket-coating-at-the-hydrogen-and-ccus-technology-world-expo</link><description>Tenaris is unveiling its new TenarisShawcor White Jacket™ coating system at the Hydrogen and Carbon Capture Technology World Expo in Hamburg, Germany. The coating is designed for severe onshore and underground pipeline applications, offering enhanced mechanical strength and resistance for hydrogen and carbon capture transportation pipelines.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>