<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 05:21:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aluminum price hits $3,000 for first time since 2022 on supply concern</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-hits-3000-for-first-time-since-2022-on-supply-concern/</link><description>Aluminum climbed above $3,000 per ton for the first time in over three years, driven by a tightening supply outlook and strong long-term demand expectations. A cap on Chinese smelting capacity and European production constraints from high electricity prices have reduced global inventories, while construction and renewable energy sectors maintain robust demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Pioneering Sustainability and Innovation</title><link>https://www.lightmetalage.com/news/event-news/aluminium-2026-pioneering-sustainability-and-innovation/</link><description>The global aluminum industry will converge at ALUMINIUM 2026, held October 6–8 in Düsseldorf, Germany, focusing on sustainability, innovation, and collaboration. The event highlights secondary aluminum's role in decarbonization, advancements in metal processing, recycling, casting, automation, and surface finishing. New features include Hall 7A for semi-finished products, an expanded ALUMINIUM Conference, and a Sustainability &amp; Recycling Conference.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aerosol can features Elysis primary aluminum, recycled content</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/alcoa-ball-unilever-partner-on-aerosole-can-made-with-elysis-primary-aluminum/</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever have partnered to create an aerosol can using 50% Elysis carbon-free primary aluminum and 50% postconsumer recycled content, marking the first use of this technology in consumer packaging. Elysis, a joint venture between Alcoa and Rio Tinto, employs inert anode technology to eliminate direct greenhouse gas emissions from smelting by producing oxygen instead of CO₂. This collaboration demonstrates low-carbon innovation across the aluminum value chain to meet decarbonization goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium's unifying approach to net-zero transformation</title><link>https://www.worldclimatefoundation.org/post/climate-nature-and-people-aluminium-s-unifying-approach-to-net-zero-transformation</link><description>Alcoa and Rio Tinto are demonstrating Elysis zero-carbon smelting technology industrially, while Alcoa pioneers mechanical vapour recompression to reduce alumina refining emissions. Emirates Global Aluminium's CelestiAL uses solar power to lower production carbon intensity, and the industry is advancing recycling and clean energy investments. These efforts position aluminum as a key sustainable metal for net-zero across applications like EVs and renewable infrastructure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The more sustainability and transparency, the better the decisions</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/the-more-transparency-the-better-the-decisions/59167/</link><description>Speira utilizes advanced technologies and AI in recycling to champion transparency and sustainability, focusing on carbon footprint reduction. Their RIVOS products combine external scrap and low-carbon primary metal, tailored to regional sustainable energy, maximizing efficiency and minimizing emissions. This third-party certified approach helps customers select sustainable aluminum closer to net zero.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>EU's carbon border tax on heavy industry goods goes into effect ...</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2026/01/01/eus-carbon-border-tax-on-heavy-industry-goods-goes-into-effect-risking-trade-escalation</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) takes effect on January 1, 2026, requiring steel and aluminium exporters to pay for CO2 emissions linked to their production. This aims to protect EU manufacturers from less stringent foreign regulations but risks trade escalation and higher costs for importers. Revenues from CBAM, projected at €1.5 billion by 2028, will fund support for affected industries.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Overcapacity, China focuses on controlling steel production</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/59971/overcapacity-china-focuses-on-controlling-steel-production</link><description>China plans to maintain strict control over crude steel production during 2026-2030 to address overcapacity issues. This policy reaffirms government efforts to manage supply amid global concerns about excess steel output.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Blastr Green Steel's Strategic Water Innovation with Ecolab - AInvest</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/blastr-green-steel-strategic-water-innovation-ecolab-model-sustainable-industrial-growth-2508/</link><description>Blastr Green Steel partners with Ecolab to redefine water management in ultra-low CO₂ steel production, offering a blueprint for decarbonizing heavy industries. The collaboration reduces water and energy use, aligns with EU climate goals like CBAM, and enhances ESG credentials. It demonstrates how sustainability can drive profitability in the green steel race.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Advancing Electric Smelting for Sustainable Iron Production: Pilot-Scale Validation of Controlled Open-Arc DC Technology by Metix Pty Ltd</title><link>https://www.aist.org/advertise/advertise-exhibit/iron-steel-technology/feature-articles</link><description>A feature article discusses advancing electric smelting technology for sustainable iron production. It covers pilot-scale validation of controlled open-arc DC technology by Metix Pty Ltd. This innovation aims to enhance sustainability in iron and steelmaking processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chile's Mantoverde Copper Mine Strike, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday - SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701527/chiles-mantoverde-copper-mine-strike-lme-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-lower-last-friday-smm-copper-morning-meeting-minut</link><description>Union #2 at Capstone Copper's Mantoverde copper mine in Chile commenced strike action on January 2, affecting 22% of the workforce and reducing operations to about 30% of normal production. The company remains open to negotiations. LME copper futures fluctuated and closed lower at $12,460.5/mt, down 0.29%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Southern Copper Corporation's Decade-Long Copper Production Growth Strategy: Strategic Capital Deployment and Long-Term Scalability</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/southern-copper-corporation-decade-long-copper-production-growth-strategy-strategic-capital-deployment-long-term-scalability-2601/</link><description>Southern Copper is advancing projects like Tia Maria despite delays from protests, mobilizing 1,900 workers to bolster Peru's copper production. The $2.6 billion Los Chancas project faces illegal mining challenges but is set to start in 2030-2031, adding significant output. These efforts support long-term capacity expansion.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price extends rebound after Indonesia signals mine output cut</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-extends-rebound-after-indonesia-signals-mine-output-cut/</link><description>Nickel prices on the LME rose 0.7% to $14,750 a ton, extending gains over 3% from an eight-month low following Indonesia's proposal to cut nickel ore production to 250 million tons in 2026 from 379 million tons this year. The reduction addresses a slump in prices amid oversupply from Indonesia and China outpacing demand. Analysts predict nickel will outperform other base metals in 2026 if the cut proceeds.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia Paused Nickel Mining While Waiting On 2026 Permits</title><link>https://finimize.com/content/vale-indonesia-paused-nickel-mining-while-waiting-on-2026-permits</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia has paused nickel mining operations while awaiting Indonesian government approval for its 2026 production plan. The smelter organization FINI anticipates nickel demand to reach 340-350 million metric tons by 2026, up 50 million from the previous year. Regulatory approvals are significantly influencing nickel market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Woes: Innovations Steering a Sustainable EV Future</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-supply-woes-innovations-steering-a-sustainable-ev-future-aemc/</link><description>The article discusses challenges in nickel supply for high-nickel NMC batteries amid surging demand from China, the US, and EU. It highlights innovations like LFP batteries, sodium-ion batteries, battery recycling, and smaller batteries to reduce nickel dependency and promote sustainability. Alaska Energy Metals Corporation is advancing sustainable nickel sourcing through its Nikolai project in Alaska.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel's role in the future of safer electric vehicle batteries</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/nickels-role-in-the-future-of-safer-electric-vehicle-batteries/56357/</link><description>Researchers from The University of Texas at Austin and Argonne National Laboratory analyzed high-nickel cathodes, which offer higher energy density for longer EV ranges but face stability issues. The study identifies critical states of charge based on metal-oxygen bonds and surface reactivity to enhance thermal stability and safety. These findings provide a roadmap for safer, efficient EV batteries.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mining with integrity to advance sustainable nickel downstreaming</title><link>https://en.antaranews.com/news/392137/mining-with-integrity-to-advance-sustainable-nickel-downstreaming</link><description>The article covers a company's commitment to sustainable nickel production through emission reductions. It aims to cut emissions by 33% by 2030 and reduce carbon intensity of nickel products by up to 50%. This supports ethical mining and downstream processing for sustainability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal, Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris has acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems for district heating and anti-corrosion coatings in Europe. The acquired business unit has been rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy, focusing on anti-corrosion coatings for oil and gas pipelines applied at Tenaris facilities in Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil. This strategic move aims to reduce delivery times, ensure quality standards, lower logistical costs, and minimize environmental impact, as stated by Andrea Previtali, Vice President Line Pipe and Process at Tenaris.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Driving Innovation for a Sustainable Future</title><link>https://www.aluminium-exhibition.com/germany/en-gb/blog/pressemitteilungen/alude2026-showpreparations.html</link><description>The ALUMINIUM 2026 trade fair will focus on sustainability as its central theme, with particular emphasis on secondary aluminum for decarbonization. The event will feature themed pavilions covering metal processing, recycling, automation, and cross-sectoral applications in mobility, construction, and manufacturing, positioning itself as the world's leading platform for innovation and networking in the aluminum industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[CES Innovation Awards® 2026 Honoree] Portable SSD T7 Resurrected</title><link>https://semiconductor.samsung.com/news-events/tech-blog/ces-innovation-awards-2026-honoree-portable-ssd-t7-resurrected/</link><description>Samsung's T7 Resurrected portable SSD won a CES 2026 Innovation Award for its 100% recycled aluminum enclosure and recycled paper packaging. The product represents Samsung's circular-design strategy, utilizing aluminum waste from smartphone production and demonstrating a commitment to expanding a circular ecosystem across multiple product categories.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China's Baosteel hikes January 2026 prices due to rising raw material costs, market optimism</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/chinas-baosteel-hikes-january-2026-prices-due-to-rising-raw-material-costs-market-optimism/158231</link><description>China's Baosteel raised its prices for January 2026, ending three consecutive months of flat pricing. The price increase reflects rising raw material costs and market optimism, though steel demand in China remains weak overall.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Shares in nation's biggest steel maker hit 17-year high</title><link>https://michaelwest.com.au/shares-in-nations-biggest-steel-maker-hit-17-year-high/</link><description>BlueScope Steel shares surged to a 17-year high following a $13.2 billion takeover offer from SGH and US-based Steel Dynamics. The non-binding offer proposes splitting BlueScope, with SGH retaining Australian and Asia operations and selling North American assets to Steel Dynamics. BlueScope had previously rejected similar bids as undervaluing its prospects and is leading a consortium to acquire Whyalla Steelworks.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. judge sends Algoma Steel-U.S. Steel iron ore contract dispute to arbitration</title><link>https://www.northernontariobusiness.com/industry-news/manufacturing/us-judge-sends-algoma-steel-us-steel-iron-ore-contract-dispute-to-arbitration-11697401</link><description>A U.S. judge in Pittsburgh denied Algoma Steel's bid to void its iron ore contract with U.S. Steel and ordered the dispute to arbitration. The ruling addresses a contract disagreement relevant to Algoma's steel production inputs. No further details on production capacity impacts were provided.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ArcelorMittal Announces Three Green Energy Projects in India</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>ArcelorMittal announced three new renewable energy projects in India, expected to cost about US$900 million in total. These projects will provide 1 GW of solar and wind energy capacity upon completion. The initiative supports sustainability in steel production through green energy integration.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Danieli to Deliver Rolling Mill, 4-Strand Caster to Hoa Phat</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>Danieli announced that Hoa Phat Group has selected it to supply a new long product rolling mill and a 4-strand continuous casting machine. The equipment is for Hoa Phat's facility in Tay Ninh Province, Vietnam. This represents technological innovation in steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Sidersa Orders MIDA QLP-DUE Mini-Mill From Danieli</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>Danieli announced that Argentinian steelmaker Sidersa has ordered a MIDA QLP-DUE mini-mill. The mini-mill will be installed in San Nicolás de los Arroyos. This order highlights advancements in efficient steel production technology.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper climbs to record high above $13,000 after strike at Chilean mine</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/copper-climbs-to-record-high-above-13000-after-strike-at-chilean-mine/articleshow/126364832.cms</link><description>Copper prices surged past $13,000 a ton, reaching a new record high driven by worries over supply shortages following a strike at a Chilean mine. The rally highlights ongoing supply constraints in major producing regions. Traders are closely monitoring the impact on global availability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME Copper Prices Surge Past $13,000 to Hit Record High, Supply Crisis or Speculative Frenzy?</title><link>https://nai500.com/blog/2026/01/lme-copper-prices-surge-past-13000-to-hit-record-high-supply-crisis-or-speculative-frenzy/</link><description>LME copper prices have surged past $13,000 per ton, marking a record high amid debates over whether it's due to a genuine supply crisis or speculative trading frenzy. The sharp rise reflects intense market volatility and concerns about future availability. Investors are watching for signs of sustained upward momentum.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Record copper price signals accelerating race for supplies</title><link>https://infra.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/construction/record-copper-price-signals-accelerating-race-for-supplies/126364639</link><description>Copper prices surged above $13,000 per metric ton due to supply shortages from mine disruptions like the Grasberg accident in Indonesia and a strike at Capstone Copper's Mantoverde mine in Chile. Citi analysts estimate refined copper production at 26.9 million tons this year, creating a 308,000-ton deficit. New copper mine development requires breakeven prices over $13,000 per ton amid strong demand from AI, EVs, and potential US tariffs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>MEMR allows limited mining output amid 2026 RKAB delays</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/memr-allows-limited-mining-output-amid-2026-rkab-delays-2</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources has permitted mining companies, including nickel producers, to operate at up to 25% of their 2026 planned output amid delays in RKAB approvals. This temporary measure, via a circular issued December 31, 2025, aims to provide operational certainty until March 31, 2026, while signaling intentions to curb nickel output to support prices. PT Vale Indonesia has suspended operations due to lacking 2026 RKAB approval.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Fini boss forecasts huge increase in nickel demand</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2026/01/01/fini-boss-forecasts-huge-increase-in-nickel-demand</link><description>The Indonesian Nickel Smelter Association (Fini) forecasts nickel ore demand from domestic smelters in 2026 to reach 340-350 million tonnes, up 40-50 million tonnes annually due to new production capacity. Indonesia plans to slash mineral production quotas to support prices, potentially causing ore shortages and increased imports from places like the Philippines. Some smelters may reduce refining capacity by 15-18% amid logistical challenges.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts nickel mining on delayed work plan approval</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/vale-indonesia-halts-nickel-mining-delayed-work-plan-approval</link><description>Vale Indonesia suspended nickel mining operations due to delayed approval of its 2026 work plan by regulators. The company is investing in high-pressure acid leach (HPAL) plants amid Indonesia's planned output cuts. HPAL capacity in the country is set to expand significantly this year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>New method replaces nickel and cobalt in battery for cleaner, cheaper lithium-ion batteries</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-07-method-nickel-cobalt-battery-cleaner.html</link><description>Researchers developed a synthesis method for uniformly sized, highly crystalline disordered rock-salt (DRX) cathode particles, eliminating nickel and cobalt for more sustainable lithium-ion batteries. This breakthrough enables mass production without grinding, improving scalability for EVs and renewable storage. Published in Nature Communications, it promises cost-effective, energy-efficient manufacturing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel ...</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy's Antitrust Authority has launched an investigation into major low-voltage copper cable manufacturers, including Prysmian Cavi e Sistemi Italia Srl and others, for alleged price-fixing since 2005. Inspections were conducted yesterday at company offices, distributors, and the Italian Association of Electrical Cable and Conductor Industries. Prysmian shares fell 1.26% and Nexans dropped 1.9% following the news, though analysts view the impact as negligible given the small market share.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Off-Season, coupled with high aluminium prices, the proportion of liquid aluminium declined in December</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/off-season-coupled-with-high-aluminium-prices-the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminium-declined-in-december-116778</link><description>High aluminum prices combined with the off-season led to a decline in the proportion of liquid aluminum in December. This reflects broader market trends affecting aluminum usage and supply dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,096 Yuan/MT on January 2, 2026, down 0.32% daily amid soft Chinese demand, with rebar futures maintaining pullbacks from recent highs. Forecasts predict trading at 3014.96 Yuan/MT by quarter-end and 2868.13 in 12 months. Recent news highlights steel rises on improving profitability and pressures from regulatory export concerns.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 931.97 USD/T on January 2, 2026, down 0.32% daily, though up 2.87% monthly and 31.63% yearly. Forecasts expect 949.49 USD/T by quarter-end and 1042.73 in 12 months. Recent updates note rises to 940 USD/T on December 31 amid improving trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM: Copper Wire &amp; Cable Industry's Jan Operating Rate to Edge Up MoM, Still Below Normal</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701113/SMM:-Copper-Wire-Cable-Industrys-Jan-Operating-Rate-to-Edge-Up-MoM-Still-Below-Normal</link><description>SMM reports that China's copper wire and cable industry's operating rate for January 2026 is expected to edge up month-over-month but remain below normal levels. Domestic prices are suspended during the New Year holiday, with overseas prices resuming on January 2. This reflects ongoing market adjustments amid high prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM: Copper Wire &amp; Cable Operating Rate Drops Further Amid High Prices, Holidays</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103700497/SMM:-Copper-Wire-Cable-Operating-Rate-Drops-Further-Amid-High-Prices-Holidays</link><description>SMM indicates that the operating rate in China's copper wire and cable sector has dropped further due to high copper prices and holiday effects. This trend highlights supply chain pressures in the industry. Contact details provided for further research reports.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Austral Resources Defies Weather, Exceeds Copper Output Targets</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/02/austral-resources-defies-weather-exceeds-copper-output-targets/</link><description>Austral Resources (ASX:AR1) exceeded its Q4 copper production targets with 2,643 tonnes despite extreme weather in Northwest Queensland. December production hit a record 910 tonnes since the 2023 restructure, with no environmental issues and stable processing operations. Access to the Rocklands site is restricted due to flooding, but recovery is expected soon.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Austral Resources Beats Q4 Copper Output Guidance Despite Record Weather</title><link>https://smallcaps.com.au/article/austral-resources-beats-q4-copper-output-guidance-despite-record-weather</link><description>Austral Resources surpassed Q4 copper production guidance of 2,610 tonnes, achieving 2,643 tonnes amid severe wet season weather. December output exceeded 910 tonnes, the highest post-2023 restructure, with Lady Annie and Mt Kelly sites maintaining full capacity. The company advances exploration with a 2026 drill program targeting oxide resources near processing facilities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries partners with Sphere Corp in landmark ENC deal</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/02/nickel-industries-partners-with-sphere-corp-in-landmark-enc-deal/</link><description>Nickel Industries announced a strategic partnership with Sphere Corp, valuing its ENC HPAL project at US$2.4 billion, with Sphere acquiring a 10% stake and entering an offtake agreement for nickel cathode. The ENC project targets annual production of 72,000 tonnes of nickel metal upon commissioning, expected in early Q1 2026. This deal marks the first offtake for ENC material into Western markets, targeting aerospace and EV sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Rockets 8% as SpaceX Supplier Buys Into US$2.4B ENC HPAL Project</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/nickel-industries/</link><description>Nickel Industries' shares rose 8% following Sphere Corp's investment in the US$2.4 billion ENC HPAL project. Sphere, a SpaceX supplier, is acquiring a stake, supporting the project's development for nickel production. The deal highlights growing interest in Nickel Industries' capacity expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/513911</link><description>Aluminum increased to 2999.00 USD/T, the highest since April 2022. Over the past 4 weeks, Aluminum gained 3.64%, and in the last 12 months, it increased 18.54%. The price rise reflects tightening supply conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel development minister sets agenda for growth in 2026</title><link>https://authorityngr.com/2026/01/02/steel-development-minister-sets-agenda-for-growth-in-2026/</link><description>Nigeria's Steel Development Minister outlines 2026 plans to revitalize Ajaokuta Steel Complex via MoUs with Chinese investors and original manufacturers, alongside $500 million in mini-LNG plants for power supply. Investments include a $400 million steel plant by Inner Galaxy Group in Ewekoro and Orbit Galvanised Steel Plant commissioning, boosting local production, jobs, and capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel fell to 16,760 USD/T on January 2, 2026, down 0.48% from the previous day, though it has risen 12.97% over the past month and 10.27% year-over-year. UK nickel futures surged to $15,600 per tonne, the highest since May, after hitting four-year lows, as markets reconsider oversupply views. Indonesia proposed a 34% reduction in nickel output for 2026 to address oversupply and deteriorating ore grades.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel reaches 14-month high following Vale Indonesia's halt to mining</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/01/02/nickel-reaches-14month-high-following-vale-indonesias-halt-to-mining</link><description>Nickel prices hit a 14-month high after Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to a delay in annual production plan approval. The LME three-month nickel rose 1.4% to $16,875 per metric ton. Indonesia's planned cut in ore production by a third by 2026 further supported prices amid previous oversupply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries says South Korea's Sphere to buy 10% stake in Indonesian project</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-industries-says-south-koreas-sphere-to-buy-10-stake-in-indonesian-project/</link><description>South Korea's Sphere Corp will acquire a 10% stake in Nickel Industries' Excelsior Nickel Cobalt HPAL project in Indonesia's Central Sulawesi, capable of producing MHP, nickel sulphate, and cathode. The deal values the project at $2.4 billion and includes offtake agreements, amid soaring nickel prices from Indonesia's output cut plans. Funding is expected early Q1 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>South Korea's Sphere to invest in Indonesian Ni project</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2771207-south-korea-s-sphere-to-invest-in-indonesian-ni-project</link><description>South Korea's Sphere will invest in a 10% stake of Nickel Industries' Excelsior nickel project in Indonesia, with production starting April-June 2026 and offtake of 10% nickel cathode. Indonesian MHP capacity is expanding significantly, with prices recently assessed at $132.50/mtu. The investment aligns with rising nickel prices from planned output cuts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel reaches 14-month high following Vale Indonesia's halt to mining</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/01/02/nickel-reaches-14month-high-following-vale-indonesias-halt-to-mining</link><description>Nickel prices surged to a 14-month high of $16,945 per metric ton after Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to a delay in production plan approval. This follows Indonesia's announcement to cut ore production by a third by 2026 to support prices amid oversupply. The event highlights sustainability efforts through regulated supply in nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to 3,023.10 USD/T on January 2, 2026, up 0.91% daily amid concerns of insufficient supply. China, the top producer, prioritizes preventing overcapacity after breaching its 45 million ton cap, forcing smelters to limit 2026 output. UK futures exceeded $3,000 for the first time since 2022 due to supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 36-week High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel increased to 941.00 USD/T, marking the highest level since April 2025. Over the past 4 weeks, Hot-Rolled Coil Steel gained 2.87%, and in the last 12 months, it rose 31.63%. This reflects upward momentum in steel prices amid recent market trends.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Winter weather a factor as scrap market debates January pricing</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/02/winter-weather-a-factor-as-scrap-market-debates-january-pricing/</link><description>US steelmakers are optimistic for 2026 with Section 232 tariffs supporting price hikes for long and flat products, but scrap price increases may be limited to $20-40/gt in January due to weather-reduced flows and historical trends. Mills like Oregon Steel Mills raised plate prices by $40/ton. Disagreement persists on scrap pricing amid barge issues and shifts in sourcing.[3]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines begins copper anode production at new Congo smelter</title><link>https://www.mining.com/ivanhoe-mines-begins-copper-anode-production-at-new-congo-smelter/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines started copper anode production on December 29, 2025, at its Kamoa-Kakula direct-to-blister smelter in the DRC, five weeks after heat-up and one week after first concentrate feed. The smelter has a 500,000 tonnes per annum capacity, the largest in Africa upon full ramp-up by year-end. 2026 production guidance is 380,000-420,000 tonnes, with sales boosted by 20,000 tonnes from destocking amid high copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Greenland grants 30-year permit to EU-backed Molybdenum mine</title><link>https://www.mining.com/greenland-grants-30-year-permit-to-eu-backed-molybdenum-mine/</link><description>Greenland Resources has received a 30-year permit for its Malmbjerg molybdenum mine, supported by the European Raw Materials Alliance. The project has off-take agreements with Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali and Finland's Outokumpu. Greenland’s Minister highlighted it as a step toward economic autonomy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash climbs to $2,985.5/t as opening stocks ease 0.49% to 509,250t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-climbs-to-2-985-5-t-as-opening-stocks-ease-0-49-to-509-250t-116796</link><description>LME aluminum cash prices reached $2,985.5 per tonne as warehouse inventory declined to 509,250 tonnes. The 3-month contract strengthened to $3,010 per tonne, with December 2026 futures also showing gains of approximately 1.10 percent.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>L&amp;T wins Orders (Major*) for Minerals &amp; Metals Business</title><link>https://www.larsentoubro.com/pressreleases/2026-01-02-lt-wins-orders-major-for-minerals-metals-business</link><description>Larsen &amp; Toubro's Minerals &amp; Metals business secures major orders from Steel Authority of India (SAIL) for expanding IISCO Steel Plant capacity from 2.5 MTPA to 6.5 MTPA. The package includes engineering, procurement, and installation for Coke Oven Battery, By-Product Plant, Basic Oxygen Furnace, and material handling. This supports India's steel manufacturing through innovation, capacity augmentation, and sustainable development.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (December 29, 2025 – January 2, 2026) on the Share Buyback Program</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-december-29-2025-a-january-2-2026-on-the-s-ce7e59d9d089f225</link><description>Under its Second Tranche of the USD1.2 billion Share Buyback Program, Tenaris repurchased 3,320,025 ordinary shares from December 29, 2025, to January 2, 2026, for approximately USD64.2 million. As of January 2, 2026, the company holds 62,328,172 treasury shares, equating to 5.81% of total issued share capital, with plans to cancel them in due course. Details of the transactions are available on Tenaris's investor relations website.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel Rebar Set to Drop 7% in 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Chinese steel rebar futures were trading at CNY 3,085 per tonne, maintaining pullback from December highs and set to close the year around 7% lower amid soft demand for ferrous metals. Falling input costs including coal and coke are expected to support profitability among steelmakers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Details Late-December Share Buybacks Under $1.2 Billion Program</title><link>https://www.tipranks.com/news/company-announcements/tenaris-details-late-december-share-buybacks-under-1-2-billion-program</link><description>Tenaris repurchased 3.32 million shares between December 29, 2025 and January 2, 2026 for €54.6 million under its $1.2 billion buyback program. Treasury holdings reached 5.81% of total issued capital, with the company planning to cancel these shares in due course.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices top $3000 for the first time since 2022 as supply risks grow</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/news/aluminum-prices-top-3000-for-the-first-time-since-2022-as-supply-risks-grow/articleshow/126303415.cms</link><description>Global aluminium prices surged to $3,000 per tonne, the highest in over three years. The increase is driven by China's production cap and rising demand in key sectors. Supply risks continue to support the upward trend.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Year-End Aluminum Ingot Inventory Alert Sounded! Domestic Inventory Buildup in Q1 2026 a Foregone Conclusion</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701077/year-end-aluminum-ingot-inventory-alert-sounded-domestic-inventory-buildup-in-q1-2026-a-foregone-conclusion-smm-analysis</link><description>Domestic aluminum production increased 1.9% year-over-year and 4.0% month-over-month in December, driven by ongoing commissioning of new electrolytic aluminum projects in Inner Mongolia and Xinjiang. Casting volumes are expected to continue increasing before Chinese New Year, with domestic aluminum ingot inventory projected to reach around 730,000 tonnes by end-January 2026, creating inventory buildup pressure in Q1.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Macro policies remain positive, aluminium prices hit new highs during the week</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/macro-policies-remain-positive-aluminium-prices-hit-new-highs-during-the-week-fundamental-negative-feedback-suppresses-post-holiday-upside-momentum-116785</link><description>New aluminum projects in China and Indonesia continued ramping up production, with a new Inner Mongolia facility successfully powering on December 20. However, high prices suppressed downstream demand, with the operating rate of leading domestic aluminum processing enterprises falling to 59.9%, while inventory is forecast to rise to 730,000 tonnes by end-January 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/513911</link><description>Aluminum prices reached $2,999 per tonne, the highest level since April 2022, as China faces pressure to restrain output growth in 2026 due to approaching its 45 million ton annual production cap. The commodity gained 3.64% over the past four weeks and 18.54% over the past 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises Past $3,000</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/te_news:514029:0-aluminum-rises-past-3-000/</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK surpassed $3,000 per tonne for the first time since 2022 at the turn of the year, driven by growing concerns about insufficient global supply amid structural constraints in production capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Move over gold and silver: Copper, aluminium head for monster rally in 2026</title><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/commodities/move-over-gold-and-silver-copper-aluminium-head-for-monster-rally-in-2026-household-goods-to-get-costlier-13755091.html</link><description>Aluminum prices climbed past $3,000 per tonne for the first time in over three years, lifted by structural supply constraints including China's smelting capacity caps and reduced European output due to high power costs. Strong long-term demand from construction, renewable energy, and infrastructure projects continues to support prices, with futures rising 17% in 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Higher on Mine Suspension</title><link>https://www.admis.com/nickel-higher-on-mine-suspension/</link><description>Nickel rose 1.6% to $16,910, breaking 14-month highs following the suspension of Vale's Indonesia mine. Recent support comes from Indonesia's announcement to cut nickel ore output by a third in 2026 to support prices. This occurs amid broader base metal movements, with demand in China remaining resilient.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts mining activities on delayed approval for 2026 output plan</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/vale-indonesia-halts-mining-activities-on-delayed-approval-for-2026-output-plan/</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to delays in obtaining government approval for its 2026 production plan. Indonesia's nickel smelter association FINI forecasts domestic demand will reach 340-350 million metric tons in 2026, representing an annual increase of up to 50 million tons.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel notches 14-month high after Vale Indonesia halts mining</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40400503</link><description>Nickel reached its highest price in more than 14 months following Vale Indonesia's suspension of mining activities. The price increase reflects market response to Indonesia's announced production cuts designed to support commodity prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel's New Era: Rising Prices, Growing EV Demand, and Major Projects Moving Forward</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickels-new-era-rising-prices-growing-ev-demand-and-major-projects-moving-forward-8868</link><description>The nickel market is shifting due to Indonesia's supply management, driving prices from $14,200 to $16,500 per ton since mid-December 2025, with projections up to $18,500-$20,000. Policies include shorter mining licenses, mine closures, and bans on new processing plants, countering prior surpluses. North American projects and EV demand signal stronger conditions for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>COMMODITIES 2026: Mexican Aluminum Prices Poised to Rise After Atypical Year</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/122425-commodities-2026-mexican-aluminum-prices-poised-to-rise-after-atypical-year-sources-say</link><description>Mexican aluminum industry sources expect 2026 to bring price increases and a more dynamic market despite ongoing Trump tariffs. Prices climbed back to $330/mt by year-end 2025, with some sources predicting premiums could surpass $400/mt.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 04.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides daily updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar 3-month term and various 1-month futures for Turkey, China, Europe, and North America, all showing no change as of 02.01.2026. The platform offers analyses and comments on industry trends. This reflects stable futures pricing at the start of 2026.[6]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fertiliser, steel prices fall; cement remains stable</title><link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1964990/fertiliser-steel-prices-fall-cement-remains-stable</link><description>Steel bar prices in Pakistan have fallen to a range of Rs220,000 to Rs230,000 per tonne from Rs240,000 to Rs250,000 per tonne as of early January 2026, due to weak demand. The Secretary General of the Pakistan Association of Large Steel Producers noted leading brands at Rs226,000 per tonne, with some as low as Rs215,000. This decline aligns with broader price reductions in fertilizers while cement prices remain stable amid rising construction demand.[4]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts mining amid delayed 2026 output approval</title><link>https://www.thejakartapost.com/business/2026/01/04/vale-indonesia-halts-mining-amid-delayed-2026-output-approval.html</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia suspended mining activities due to delays in government approval of its 2026 annual production plan (RKAB). The halt comes as Indonesia's government plans to cut nickel output quotas to support prices, with Deputy Mining Minister Yuliot Tanjung stating the approval is "currently being consolidated."</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris to invest in hydrogen steelmaking in Italy</title><link>https://eurometal.net/tenaris-to-invest-in-hydrogen-steelmaking-in-italy/</link><description>Tubemaker Tenaris has signed an agreement with Italian energy suppliers Edison and Snam for a project aimed at using hydrogen in steelmaking operations at the Tenaris Dalmine seamless tube plant in Italy. The project will study hydrogen supply and adapt the mill to use the gas in the steelmaking process, which could further lower CO2 emissions from the electric arc furnace-based steelmaker.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coatings. The business unit was rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy and will apply anti-corrosion coatings to line pipes at Tenaris facilities across Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Rise Slightly on January 5, South Korean President Lee Jae-myung Makes First Visit to China</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701928/</link><description>Nickel prices rose slightly on January 5 according to the SMM midday review. The update coincides with South Korean President Lee Jae-myung's first visit to China. This reflects ongoing market movements in nickel amid regional developments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum starts the year on a bullish note</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/aluminum-price-january-2026-china-europe-warehouse-inventory-reduced-recycling/</link><description>Aluminum prices have surpassed $3,000 per ton on U.S. and European exchanges, with the Comex exchange listing aluminum at $3,050.75 per metric ton. Supply-side factors driving the price increase include declining output in China due to government-imposed smelting capacity caps and production constraints in Europe from high electricity prices, while demand from construction and renewable sectors remains robust.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>PRICE INCREASE ANNOUNCEMENT - January 5, 2026</title><link>https://cemcosteel.com/news/price-increase-announcement-january-5-2026/</link><description>Domestic steel mills announced sharp price increases for all January 2026 orders across all markets. The hikes are driven by various market factors pressuring steel pricing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Korea steel industry faces triple hit from structural slump, tariffs, and ...</title><link>https://biz.chosun.com/en/en-industry/2026/01/05/3DZRG5TYKVB57LQZMJRZMGCGMA/</link><description>Korea's steel industry anticipates ongoing challenges in 2026 due to structural downturns, tariff burdens, and weak demand in real estate and construction. Cumulative crude steel production from January to November 2025 was 56.1 million tons, down 3.7% year-over-year, potentially reaching the lowest in 15 years. Experts highlight a mismatch between production capacity and demand in both domestic and export markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Shanghai copper kicks off 2026 strong on supply jitters</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/shanghai-copper-kicks-off-2026-strong-on-supply-jitters-ce7e59d9d08df321</link><description>Shanghai copper opened the year strongly due to intensified supply concerns from a strike at a Chilean mine. The most-active copper contract rose amid these jitters. This reflects broader market sensitivity to production disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Capstone Copper (ASX:CSC) Drops on Chile Strike</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/capstone-copper-drops-on-chile-strike/</link><description>Capstone Copper's shares fell 4% to A$14.51 following a strike by workers at its Mantoverde mine in Chile starting January 2, 2026. The strike impacts operations at this key copper facility. This event highlights vulnerabilities in copper supply chains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On January 5, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701837/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on January 5 stood at 133700-142600 yuan/mt, with an average price of 138150 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 600 yuan/mt from the previous day. The report highlights the latest spot pricing trends in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Sphere joins Nickel Industries ENC move in Indonesia</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/news/market-updates/sphere-joins-nickel-industries-enc-move-in-indonesia</link><description>Sphere has joined Nickel Industries' ENC move in Indonesia, signaling new developments in nickel operations or investments. This activity occurs amid rising nickel prices and production adjustments in the region. Details on the specific collaboration or capacity implications remain limited in the report.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Why Alcoa (AA) Is Up 5.2% After Aluminum Tops $3,000 Amid Supply Strains And ESG Demand</title><link>https://simplywall.st/stocks/us/materials/nyse-aa/alcoa/news/why-alcoa-aa-is-up-52-after-aluminum-tops-3000-amid-supply-s</link><description>Alcoa's stock rose 5.2% as LME aluminum prices exceeded $3,000 per ton due to supply constraints in China and Europe tightening inventories, alongside strong demand from construction and renewables. The company benefits from its lower-carbon aluminum production aligning with ESG trends. Upcoming Q4 2025 earnings on January 22 will reveal impacts on sales and margins.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium surges as cash offer hits USD 3,022.5 per tonne</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-surges-as-cash-offer-hits-usd-3-022-5-per-tonne-116808</link><description>LME aluminum cash offer reached USD 3,022.5 per tonne on January 5, extending gains supported by lower inventories and stronger demand factors. Global supply constraints continue to bolster prices amid robust sector outlooks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nucor holds HR spot price at $950/ton</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/05/nucor-holds-hr-spot-price-at-950-ton/</link><description>Nucor maintained its consumer spot price for hot-rolled coil unchanged at $950 per short ton for a third consecutive week. The steelmaker's West Coast joint venture, California Steel Industries, also kept prices steady at $1,000/st, with lead times continuing at 3 to 5 weeks.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metal Market Update: Steel &amp; Aluminum Prices Heading Into 2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9wBLv3trcMA</link><description>Sheffield Metals announced steel price increases going into Q1 2026, driven by mill maintenance downtime, the Nippon/US Steel situation, and coating extras. The video discusses how tariffs and inventory restocking are stretching lead times, with price increases expected to take effect in mid to late January.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SGH and Steel Dynamics confirm the submission of a NBIO to acquire BlueScope Steel Ltd.</title><link>https://ir.steeldynamics.com/sgh-and-steel-dynamics-confirm-the-submission-of-a-nbio-to-acquire-bluescope-steel-ltd/</link><description>SGH and Steel Dynamics submitted a Non-Binding Indicative Offer for SGH to acquire 100% of BlueScope Steel via scheme of arrangement, followed by on-selling North American operations like the North Star mill to Steel Dynamics. The firms argue BlueScope's Australia/ROW and North American businesses are not strategically compatible and would thrive separately. The proposal aligns with SGH's industrial focus and complements SDI's steel operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel extracted from Mati City supplies global EV battery market</title><link>https://mb.com.ph/2026/01/05/nickel-extracted-from-mati-city-supplies-global-ev-battery-market</link><description>Hallmark Mining Corp in Mati City, Davao Oriental, Philippines, extracts nickel laterite ore shipped to China and Indonesia for EV batteries, supporting global clean energy transition. The Philippines, second-largest nickel producer, complies with environmental standards and plans mine rehabilitation. Demand for battery-grade nickel is expected to grow through 2040 amid decarbonization efforts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Night Session SHFE Aluminum Rises Over 2%, Breaking Through 24100 yuan/mt, Multiple Positive Factors Support Aluminum Prices</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103702543/night-session-shfe-aluminum-rises-over-2-breaking-through-24100-yuanmt-multiple-positive-factors-support-aluminum-prices</link><description>SHFE aluminum 2602 contract surged 2.20% to close at 24,165 yuan/mt during the January 5 night session, driven by positive supply factors amid year-end trading. Spot prices in major Chinese regions rose 100-300 yuan/mt, though high prices suppressed downstream demand, with operating rates declining. Medium-term demand from policy support is expected, but environmental restrictions impact production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>New Heat-Resistant Alloys: In Japan, 3D Printing Pushes the Limits of Aluminum</title><link>https://www.3dnatives.com/en/heat-resistant-alloys-in-japan-06012026/</link><description>Researchers at Nagoya University developed new aluminum alloys using metal 3D printing technology that achieve greater mechanical strength and heat tolerance, with one variant maintaining both strength and flexibility at temperatures up to 300°C. The breakthrough uses laser powder bed fusion to trap iron and other elements in metastable forms, creating alloys with copper, manganese, and titanium that are lightweight, durable, and recyclable, with promising applications in automotive and aerospace components.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Australia's BlueScope Steel mulls US$8.8 bn takeover bid | Business</title><link>https://www.bssnews.net/business/348350</link><description>Australia's BlueScope Steel is evaluating a Aus$13.2 billion (US$8.8 billion) joint takeover bid from US-based Steel Dynamics and Australian firm SGH. Under the proposal, SGH would acquire all shares and sell BlueScope's North American operations to Steel Dynamics while retaining the rest. BlueScope stated it is considering the indicative proposal against its own forecasts for improvements in costs, productivity, cashflow, and earnings.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Australia's BlueScope Steel mulls US$8.8 billion takeover bid</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/international-business/australias-bluescope-steel-mulls-us8-8-billion-takeover-bid/articleshow/126363796.cms</link><description>Australia's BlueScope Steel is assessing a joint Aus$13.2 billion takeover bid from Steel Dynamics and SGH, marking the fourth attempt by the US firm to acquire its American operations. The plan involves SGH buying all shares and on-selling North American assets to Steel Dynamics. BlueScope is weighing the offer against its internal value projections, having rejected prior bids as undervaluing the company.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BlueScope Steel Rejects US Steel Dynamics' Bids</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/06/bluescope-steel-rejects-us-steel-dynamics-bids/</link><description>BlueScope Steel has rejected multiple takeover bids from US-based Steel Dynamics, including all-cash, partial, and mixed proposals aimed at its US assets. The board cited concerns over valuation, execution risks, funding, and regulatory approvals despite premiums offered. The rejections underscore BlueScope's confidence in its independent strategy as Australia's leading steel manufacturer.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to 6.02 USD/Lbs on January 6, 2026, up 1.82% from the previous day, with futures climbing above $5.8 per pound amid tightening global supply and concerns over potential US tariffs redirecting shipments. Over the past month, prices have risen 12.46% and are up 45.08% year-over-year. This continues a strong upward trend into the new year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>With the copper price hitting a new record, how can you get exposure?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/06/with-the-copper-price-hitting-a-new-record-how-can-you-get-exposure/</link><description>Copper prices hit a record high amid supply disruptions at major mines like Grasberg in Indonesia, Kamoa-Kakula in Congo, and El Teniente in Chile, straining the supply chain with falling ore grades and high US stockpiles. Refined copper is forecasted to face a 600,000-tonne deficit in 2026 after a 200,000-tonne deficit in 2025. Companies like BHP boosted production to over two million tonnes in FY25, while Rio Tinto upgraded its 2025 guidance to 860,000-875,000 tonnes.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Soar to Record High</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/06/copper-prices-soar-to-record-high/</link><description>Copper prices reached a record $13,000 per tonne driven by mine outages, including a strike at Mantoverde in Chile, and accidents in Indonesia and Congo, alongside rising demand for energy transition applications. In 2025, prices surged 42%, the best annual gain since 2009. Potential US import tariffs have spurred shipments to the US, reducing supplies elsewhere and impacting global inventory flows.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Already up 15% in 2026, how high can this penny stock rise?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/06/already-up-15-in-2026-how-high-can-this-penny-stock-rise/</link><description>Nickel Industries Ltd (ASX: NIC), a nickel pig iron producer, has surged nearly 15% in early 2026 trading to $0.95, driven by rising nickel prices, an increased ore sales permit, and a strategic partnership. Broker Bell Potter maintains a buy rating with a $1.30 price target, citing LME nickel's recent surge from an 8-month low to a 14-month high as a key catalyst amid market volatility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Forecast: Top Trends for Nickel in 2026</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/nickel-price-forecast-top-trends-nickel-2026</link><description>Analyst Manthey forecasts nickel prices to remain under pressure throughout 2026, struggling to hold above US$16,000 per ton due to ongoing market dynamics. This outlook highlights persistent challenges in the nickel market despite recent volatility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>MEMR allows limited mining output amid 2026 RKAB delays</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/memr-allows-limited-mining-output-amid-2026-rkab-delays-2</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources permits mining companies to operate at up to 25% of 2026 planned output until March 31 due to delays in RKAB approvals, amid plans to curb nickel output for price support. PT Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations without approval. The circular addresses transition issues during quota adjustments.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>