<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:24:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy's Antitrust Authority has initiated an investigation into major low-voltage copper cable manufacturers, including Prysmian Cavi e Sistemi Italia Srl, for alleged price-fixing since 2005. Inspections were conducted yesterday at company offices, distributors, and the Italian Association of Electrical Cable Industries. Prysmian shares dropped 1.26% following the news, though analysts view the impact as negligible given the small market share.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Closes in on $12,000-a-Ton Mark</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-heads-toward-12000-a-ton-as-banks-predict-further-gains/copper-closes-in-on-12000-a-ton-mark-prices-have-surged-by-more-than-a-third-on-trade-dislocations-and-mine-outages/</link><description>Coverage of the price surge toward $12,000/ton, emphasizing analyst warnings that structural deficits may begin in 2026 as demand from energy transition and technology accelerates while supply faces outages and trade disruptions.[6]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to 3½-Year Highs</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/511743</link><description>Aluminum futures climbed toward $2,970 per tonne, the highest since May 2022, following South32's announcement to place its Mozal smelter under care and maintenance by March 2026 due to power issues. Supply tightens with disruptions at Iceland’s Grundartangi smelter and declining Japanese inventories. Prices have risen nearly 17% this year, supported by China's output cap.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Inventory Update: Decrease in Ingots, Increase in Billets as of December 23</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103100302/Aluminum-Inventory-Update:-Decrease-in-Ingots-Increase-in-Billets-as-of-December-23</link><description>SMM reports aluminum inventory changes as of December 23, with decreases in ingots and increases in billets. Macro boosts failed to outweigh fundamental pressures, leading to expectations of slight price pullbacks from recent highs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is down 1.6 percent - week 52, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-down-16-percent-week-52-2025-1425864.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending December 20, 2025, was 1.725 million net tons at 76.3% capacity utilization, down 1.6% from the prior week. This represents a 3.6% increase from the same week in 2024. Year-to-date production through December 20 is up 3.4% at 87.606 million net tons.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is down 1.6 percent - week 52, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-down-16-percent-week-52-2025-1425864.htm</link><description>According to the American Iron and Steel Institute (AISI), US domestic raw steel production for the week ending December 20, 2025, was 1.725 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.3 percent. Production decreased 1.6 percent from the previous week but increased 3.6 percent compared to the same week in 2024. Year-to-date production through December 20, 2025, reached 87.606 million net tons, up 3.4 percent from the prior year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SDI predicts Q4 earnings greater than in 2024</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/sdi-steel-aluminum-production-recycling-profits-q4-2025-usa-mexico/</link><description>Steel Dynamics Inc. (SDI) reports that fourth quarter 2025 steel operations profitability is expected to be meaningfully lower than Q3 2025, impacted by planned maintenance outages that reduced flat-rolled steel production by 140,000-150,000 tons and a $70+ per ton decline in hot-rolled steel prices from July to October. However, the company notes recent improvements in flat-rolled steel prices due to declining import volumes and steady underlying demand, with order backlogs extending into Q2 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper scales new peak as zero-fee smelter processing highlights shortages</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/copper-scales-new-peak-as-zero-fee-smelter-processing-highlights-shortages/articleshow/126123369.cms</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.4% to $11,930 per metric ton in official trading, reaching a new peak supported by speculative buying and news of zero-fee smelter processing agreements that underscore global supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP eyes Canadian copper after Anglo bid</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/23/bhp-eyes-canadian-copper-after-anglo-bid/</link><description>BHP is redirecting focus to copper growth in Canada following the withdrawal of its bid for Anglo American. CEO Mike Henry highlighted copper exploration partnerships across Canada and plans for further investments in high-quality copper assets amid rising demand from electrification. BHP is already investing over $10 billion in its Jansen potash project in Saskatchewan.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Solis Minerals Strengthens Copper Path With Project Milestones</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/stocks/metal-and-mining/solis-minerals-strengthens-copper-path-with-project-milestones</link><description>Solis Minerals announced project milestones advancing its copper exploration efforts. The updates strengthen the company's position in copper development. Specific details on milestones were highlighted in the announcement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 23, SMM #1 refined nickel prices were 121,500-129,000 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103685427/</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices on December 23 ranged from 121,500-129,000 yuan/mt, with an average of 125,250 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 3,450 yuan/mt from the previous day. The price rise indicates a short-term bullish shift amid recent market volatility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] Indonesian High-Grade NPI Traded at 920 Yuan/Nickel Unit for Jan 2025 Delivery</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103685675/Indonesian-High-Grade-NPI-Traded-at-920-YuanNickel-Unit-for-Jan-2025-Delivery:-SMM</link><description>High inventory and market pessimism pushed nickel prices to new lows before a strong rebound started on Wednesday. Indonesian high-grade NPI traded at 920 yuan per nickel unit for January 2025 delivery. This reflects ongoing supply pressures balanced by recent recovery signals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel on Dec 22 hits near 2-month high on Indonesia production cut &amp; Fed expected rate drop</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-on-dec-22-hits-near-2-month-high-on-indonesia-production-cut-fed-expected-rate-drop/158448</link><description>LME nickel prices reached near 2-month highs on December 22, driven by Indonesia's announced production cuts and expectations of Federal Reserve rate drops. The price movement reflects market response to supply-side interventions aimed at supporting commodity prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer rises to $2,916/t as opening stocks hold steady at 519,600t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-rises-to-2-916-t-as-opening-stocks-hold-steady-at-519-600t-116693</link><description>LME aluminium cash and forward prices firmed on December 23, with the cash offer rising to USD 2,916/t while LME opening stocks remained unchanged at 519,600 tonnes; 3-month forward bids also increased modestly amid firming physical bids and steady warehouse inventories. The report notes parallel gains for near-dated contracts and provides regional reference prices and an assessment of alumina (Platts) as supportive context for near-term market strength.[2]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price falls to one-month low in wider commodity slump</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-falls-to-one-month-low-in-wider-commodity-slump/</link><description>Aluminum led base metals lower amid a broader commodity selloff, dropping as much as 1.6% to $2,526/t on the LME—the lowest since Nov. 14—as traders reacted to macro data and Fed-rate expectations; the piece highlights rising Chinese output and strong exports as contributors to near-term weakness while some banks remain bullish on longer-term price upside.[3]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Holds Near 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/512215</link><description>A Trading Economics news item notes aluminum futures in the UK near USD 2,950/t in December—close to the highest in over three years—driven by worries over low supply and China’s emphasis on preventing overcapacity, which is supporting prices and an 18% year-to-date gain.[4]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices remain elevated near three-year highs amid global supply tightness</title><link>https://ecopulse24.com/news/aluminum-prices-remain-elevated-near-three-year-highs-amid-global-supply-tightness</link><description>This article reports that aluminum prices are holding near three-year highs, attributing the strength to global supply tightness, tighter Chinese output controls, decreased exports, and broader production challenges that are limiting available metal and supporting prices.[7]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nucor Plate Group adds $40/ton to plate prices</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com</link><description>Nucor Plate Group has increased plate prices by $40/ton. This update appears amid latest news on steel market trends, including global steel production falling to a near two-year low in November and weekly raw steel mill output ticking lower.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China steel group urges domestic pricing in iron ore contracts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/china-steel-group-urges-domestic-pricing-in-iron-ore-contracts/</link><description>China's top steel industry group, the China Iron and Steel Association, urged the state-backed China Mineral Resources Group to use domestic price benchmarks in iron ore supply talks with major miners like BHP and Rio Tinto. A new port-side spot price index should serve as a core reference for long-term contracts to shift pricing power toward China. This reflects ongoing efforts to counter USD-dominated benchmarks amid negotiations for next year's supply deals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Clarification of holiday pricing schedule for Turkey flat steel, slab assessments</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/clarification-of-holiday-pricing-schedule-for-turkey-flat-steel-slab-assessments/</link><description>Fastmarkets clarified its holiday pricing calendar for Turkey flat steel and slab assessments, noting no publications on December 26 due to a UK public holiday, with updates resuming December 29. This affects prices like hot-rolled coil import CFR main port Turkey and related assessments. The updated calendar is available on their site.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits $12,000 a Ton. Time to Mine Freeport-McMoRan for More Profits</title><link>https://247wallst.com/investing/2025/12/23/copper-hits-12000-a-ton-time-to-mine-freeport-mcmoran-for-more-profits/</link><description>Copper prices hit an all-time high of around $12,000 per ton on the LME, fueled by Trump's tariff threats, supply constraints, and demand from EVs, renewables, and AI. Freeport-McMoRan, up 34% YTD, benefits from higher prices and strong operations at mines like Morenci and Cerro Verde. Analysts rate it a Buy with a $49.11 target.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits $12,000 a Ton. Time to Mine Freeport-McMoRan for More Profits</title><link>https://247wallst.com/investing/2025/12/23/copper-hits-12000-a-ton-time-to-mine-freeport-mcmoran-for-more-profits/</link><description>Investment-focused article highlights that copper's rally to $12,000/ton is boosting margins for major producers like Freeport-McMoRan, while noting production disruptions at Grasberg have constrained output; the piece discusses company-level production guidance and where earnings may benefit from higher prices.[4]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia may slash nickel output to steady prices</title><link>https://www.mining.com/indonesia-may-slash-nickel-output-to-steady-prices/</link><description>Indonesia, the world’s top nickel producer, is proposing a 34% reduction in nickel production to 250 million tonnes in 2026 from this year's roughly 379 million tonnes to curb oversupply and support prices. The plan, outlined in the government's 2026 Work Plan and Budget, aims to address a global surplus projected at 209 million tonnes in 2025, potentially widening to 261 million tonnes next year with Indonesia contributing 65%. Analysts note this could help nickel prices recover toward $18,000-$20,000 per tonne amid declining ore grades and imports.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>CVA and Cogne Acciai Speciali sign Energy Release contract; CVA to build four photovoltaic plants in Sicily</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>CVA Group and Cogne Acciai Speciali signed an Energy Release contract under which CVA will construct four photovoltaic plants in Sicily (total capacity &gt;20 MW) and advance electricity to CAS under Italy’s Energy Release scheme; the arrangement supports CAS’s decarbonisation and aligns with regional and EU energy goals.[1]</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Effective Tariff Rates and Revenues (Updated December 23, 2025)</title><link>https://budgetmodel.wharton.upenn.edu/issues/2025/12/23/effective-tariff-rates-and-revenues-updated-december-23-2025</link><description>Steel and aluminum products face the highest effective US tariff rates at 40%, due to Section 232 tariffs and recent increases. Average effective tariff rate rose to 10.65% in September 2025. China faces the highest partner tariffs at 37.1%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Company uses solar ovens for 100% recycled steel production</title><link>https://inspenet.com/en/noticias/100-recycled-steel-solar-oven-production/</link><description>PANATERE inaugurated two solar furnaces in La Chaux-de-Fonds, Switzerland, capable of melting 100% recycled steel using concentrated solar energy without fossil fuels. This innovation produces fully recycled stainless steel and copper with a near-zero carbon footprint, reducing emissions by a factor of 165 compared to conventional processes. The project promotes circular economy and industrial sovereignty, with potential for replication in other countries.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price nears $12,000 as base metals stage broad rally</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-nears-12000-a-ton-as-base-metals-stage-broad-rally/</link><description>Copper prices rallied to $11,928 a ton, nearing $12,000, driven by mine disruptions, US imports surge, and bullish AI-linked demand despite weak Chinese demand. Prices have climbed over a third this year, with nickel also advancing on Indonesia's planned production cuts. The rally reflects tightening supply across base metals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Dec. 24</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20251224/7655d55ac2ad4f4bbbe0ea44e8eaa12b/c.html</link><description>London Stock Exchange Group reports copper at 5.48 USD at 0200 GMT on December 24. Other metals include iron ore at 106.95 USD, palladium at 2,004.50 USD, and platinum at 2,359.20 USD. This update provides snapshot pricing for global commodities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On December 24, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103687575/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price reached 126,400–134,000 yuan/mt on December 24, with an average of 130,200 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 4,950 yuan/mt from the previous day. The rise reflects recent market momentum in nickel pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel hits near two-month high on supply Curbs, fed rate-cut hopes</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/lme-nickel-hits-near-two-month-high-on-supply-curbs-fed-rate-cut-hopes</link><description>LME nickel futures rose by US$473 per tonne to US$15,276 per tonne, while the spot price gained US$472 to US$15,087 per tonne. The rally, marking the fourth consecutive gain, is driven by supply curbs and hopes for Fed rate cuts. Prices jumped sharply on December 24.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel hits near two-month high on supply curbs, Fed rate-cut hopes</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/lme-nickel-hits-near-two-month-high-on-supply-curbs-fed-rate-cut-hopes</link><description>LME nickel futures rose sharply by US$473 per tonne to US$15,276 per tonne, with the spot price gaining US$472 to US$15,087 per tonne, marking a near two-month high. The rally is attributed to supply curbs and hopes for Fed rate cuts. Prices climbed on December 24 amid these factors influencing the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>This nickel stock leaves oversold area, reaches a new resistance</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/59860/this-nickel-stock-leaves-oversold-area-reaches-a-new-resistance</link><description>Analysts highlight positive sentiment for a nickel stock due to the Indonesian government's decision to cut the 2026 nickel production target to 250 million tonnes. The stock has exited an oversold area and is heading toward a new resistance level. This reflects market reactions to production restraint measures aimed at stabilizing prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>This nickel stock exits the oversold zone, heading toward a new resistance</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/videos/watch/2180/nickel-stock-exits-oversold-zone-heading-resistance</link><description>Ina Sekuritas analysts recommend a nickel mining and processing company, PT Merdeka Battery Materials Tbk (MBMA), following its exit from an oversold zone toward new resistance. The positive outlook stems from Indonesia's plan to reduce 2026 nickel production to 250 million tonnes. This move is expected to bolster market sentiment amid oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminium cash offer hits USD 2,932/t as LME momentum builds</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminium-cash-offer-hits-usd-2-932-t-as-lme-momentum-builds-116710</link><description>LME aluminium cash offers strengthened to USD 2,932 per tonne on December 24, up 0.54% from the prior session. The 3-month contract bid rose to USD 2,957 per tonne, with forward contracts also gaining. Alumina Platts prices edged down slightly to USD 310.22 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to 3½-Year Highs as Mozal Smelter to Be Placed Under Care and Maintenance</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Trading Economics reports aluminium futures climbed toward multi-year highs after South32 announced its Mozal smelter in Mozambique will be placed under care and maintenance by March 2026, tightening global primary aluminium supply; the report also cites a potline suspension at Iceland’s Grundartangi and falling Japanese port inventories as market-supportive. The item notes China is expected to approach its 45 million tonne annual output cap, contributing to supply concerns and higher prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 906 USD/T on December 24, 2025, down 0.22% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices rose 0.44% and are up 27.60% year-over-year. Recent news highlights HRC Steel hitting multi-week highs and lows earlier in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US steel tariffs cause scrap supply glut</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2769786-viewpoint-us-steel-tariffs-cause-scrap-supply-glut</link><description>US flat and long steel prices continued climbing in December amid tariffs causing a scrap supply glut, while Turkish rebar prices fell to $559/t ex-works. Production changes will take time, with China dampening global steel and scrap prices into 2026. US exporters may prefer domestic sales in Q1 due to price divergence.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper's Red Metal Revolution: Prices Target $12,000 Milestone Amid Supply Shocks and AI Demand</title><link>http://business.times-online.com/times-online/article/marketminute-2025-12-24-coppers-red-metal-revolution-prices-target-12000-milestone-amid-supply-shocks-and-ai-demand</link><description>Copper prices are surging toward $12,000 per metric ton due to supply shocks and surging demand from AI data centers, which require about 27 tons per megawatt. This rally is driven by the green transition and digital revolutions, with limited substitution options for high-performance uses. Mining firms are investing in recycling technologies, though secondary supply remains insufficient for projected demand growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Great Metal Super-Surge of 2025: Gold, Silver, and Copper Hit Historic Peaks as Economic Clouds Gather</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-12-24-the-great-metal-super-surge-of-2025-gold-silver-and-copper-hit-historic-peaks-as-economic-clouds-gather</link><description>Copper reached a historic $12,200 per metric ton in December 2025 amid supply disruptions at major mines and booming demand from AI data centers and grid upgrades. Mining giants like BHP and Rio Tinto are capitalizing with record production and strategic acquisitions to secure energy transition supply. The surge underscores copper's critical role in AI infrastructure and global electrification efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Xiarihamu Nickel-Cobalt Mine officially included in Provincial Green Mining List</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5108121-flash-xiarihamu-nickel-cobalt-mine-officially-included-in-provincial-green-mining-list</link><description>Qinghai Province added the Xiarihamu Nickel-Cobalt Mine to its 2025 Provincial Green Mining List, recognizing Qinghai Jinchuan Mining's efforts in ecological protection despite challenges like high altitude and arid conditions. The company has implemented vegetation restoration, windbreak measures, and technological innovations for efficient resource use and emission reductions. This supports both mining operations and environmental goals in the region.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China launches first million-tonne near-zero-carbon steel line</title><link>https://news.cgtn.com/news/2025-12-24/China-launches-first-million-tonne-near-zero-carbon-steel-line-1JmEgY4p1WU/p.html</link><description>China has completed its first million-tonne near-zero-carbon steel production line in Zhanjiang City, Guangdong Province, using a hydrogen-based metallurgical electric smelting process that replaces traditional coke with hydrogen. This technology reduces carbon emissions by 50 to 80 percent compared to conventional methods and can cut over 3.14 million tonnes of emissions annually. The project marks a major breakthrough in the steel industry's green transformation during the 14th Five-Year Plan period.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Reach Record $12,000 a Metric Ton as Market Navigates Supply Constraints and Growing Demand Outlook</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-prices-reach-record-12-000-metric-ton-market-navigates-supply-constraints-growing-demand-outlook-2512/</link><description>Copper prices hit a record $12,000 per metric ton amid global supply tightness driven by U.S.-bound copper redirection, mine outages, and zero-fee smelter processing agreements that have forced some smelters to cut operations. Citigroup and Goldman Sachs project bullish copper markets for 2026, citing strong demand from energy transition and AI infrastructure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Structural Supercycle: Why $12,000 Is Just the Beginning</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-structural-supercycle-12-000-beginning-2512/</link><description>Opinion/analysis piece arguing geopolitical shocks, tariffs and accelerating demand tied to electrification and AI are creating a long-term 'supercycle' for copper, citing forecasts of a 2026 refined-copper deficit and multi-year price appreciation scenarios from major banks.[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Domestic and international liquidity easing supports aluminum prices hovering at highs [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103688975/Domestic-and-international-liquidity-easing-supports-aluminum-prices-hovering-at-highs-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME aluminum closed at $2,956.5/mt on December 24 after hitting a high of $2,969.5/mt, supported by liquidity easing. SHFE aluminum futures fell 0.83% to 22,145 yuan/mt, while spot A00 aluminum surged to 22,030 yuan/mt. Secondary aluminum prices like ADC12 rose, with import windows reopening due to stronger domestic prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 25.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel exchanges, including Shanghai Futures Rebar prices as of December 24, 2025. Various futures terms for rebar and other steel products show flat performance at 0.00 change. Coverage includes indices, prices, and news for major markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's 304 stainless steel export offers rise sharply on Tsingshan price hike</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5108057-indonesias-304-stainless-steel-export-offers-rise-sharply-on-tsingshan-price-hike</link><description>Indonesia's 304 stainless steel export prices rose sharply for the third week in December due to Tsingshan's price hike. Related updates include stainless HRC and round bar prices in China on December 25. Nickel and chrome ore markets also show activity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper hits record high as robust US GDP data boosts demand prospects</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-record-high-as-robust-us-gdp-data-boosts-demand-prospects/</link><description>Copper prices extended gains to hit all-time highs, supported by robust U.S. GDP data enhancing demand prospects. The rally reflects ongoing market strength amid broader commodity trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Weekly Market Recap (December 25) –Copper 2025</title><link>https://nai500.com/blog/2025/12/weekly-market-recap-december-25-copper-2025-shocks-mergers-and-megatrends/</link><description>Copper prices surged to unprecedented highs this week, concluding a year of supply shocks and trade realignments. The recap highlights key market shocks, mergers, and megatrends impacting copper in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690218/</link><description>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 123,400–131,400 yuan/mt, with an average price of 127,400 yuan/mt. This represents a decline of 2,800 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices experienced a significant correction on December 25...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690257/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-correction-on-December-25-while-the-central-bank-conducted-a-400-billion-yuan-MLF-operation</link><description>Nickel prices underwent a significant correction on December 25 amid a 400-billion-yuan MLF operation by the central bank. The SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 127,400 yuan/mt, down 2,800 yuan/mt from the prior session.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On December 25, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690218/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on December 25 averaged 127,400 yuan/mt, ranging from 123,400–131,400 yuan/mt, down 2,800 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects ongoing price pressures in the refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Why copper is set to play a big role in BHP's future</title><link>https://aheadoftheherd.com/why-copper-is-set-to-play-a-big-role-in-bhps-future/</link><description>BHP is positioning copper centrally in its strategy amid global critical minerals discussions, including meetings with US leadership on AI supply chains. The company's history of innovation supports its leadership in copper production for electrification and digital technologies. This focus highlights copper's growing importance in sustainable mining and technology advancements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel traded flat at 15,660 USD/T on December 25, 2025. Over the past month, nickel's price has risen 5.49%, and it is up 1.26% compared to the same time last year. This reflects trading on a contract for difference tracking the benchmark market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Talon buys nation's only nickel mine to create Midwest 'powerhouse'</title><link>https://www.eenews.net/articles/talon-buys-nations-only-nickel-mine-to-create-midwest-powerhouse/</link><description>Talon Metals announced the purchase of the Eagle nickel mine in Michigan's Upper Peninsula from Lundin Mining, along with a nearby mill, to expand production of nickel and copper for stainless steel and EV batteries. The deal positions Talon to develop a critical minerals hub in the Midwest amid rising demand. Lundin will hold nearly 20% stake in Talon as part of the agreement.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper's Record-Breaking Rally: A Strategic Buy Opportunity Amid Tariffs, Supply Constraints, and the Energy Transition</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-record-breaking-rally-strategic-buy-opportunity-tariffs-supply-constraints-energy-transition-2512/</link><description>Copper prices reached an all-time high of $11,700 per metric ton in December 2025, fueled by supply shocks from mine outages, tariff uncertainties, and surging demand from the energy transition. Mine disruptions at key sites like Grasberg and Quebrada Blanca have created a 330kmt deficit projected for 2026. J.P. Morgan forecasts prices peaking at $12,500/mt in Q2 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium opens the week with a fall of $13.5/t; December 26 bid price adds $5/t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-opens-the-week-with-a-fall-of-13-5-t-december-26-bid-price-adds-5-t-115507</link><description>LME aluminium cash bid and official settlement prices fell by USD 13-13.5 per tonne to around USD 2,693 per tonne. The December 26 bid and offer prices rose by USD 5 per tonne to USD 2,728-2,733 per tonne, while the 3-month Asian Reference Price increased by USD 11 to USD 2,700.5 per tonne. Alumina Platts price declined by USD 5.45 per tonne to USD 333.35 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SINBON Brings Enhanced EV Connection Solutions to Automotive World Tokyo 2026</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/26/sinbon-brings-enhanced-ev-connection-solutions-to-automotive-world-tokyo-2026/</link><description>SINBON Electronics is showcasing an expanded portfolio of EV connection technologies, including charging cables and inlets with aluminum busbars and rods, at Automotive World Tokyo 2026. The solutions support diverse standards and emphasize sustainable innovation in mobility. SINBON's commitment to ESG drives carbon management and green solutions across global manufacturing sites.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SINBON Brings Enhanced EV Connection Solutions to Automotive World Tokyo 2026</title><link>https://macaubusiness.com/sinbon-brings-enhanced-ev-connection-solutions-to-automotive-world-tokyo-2026/</link><description>SINBON Electronics announces its return to Automotive World Tokyo 2026 with enhanced EV connection solutions featuring aluminum designs for charging inlets and cables. The portfolio addresses regional standards and supports sustainable automotive advancements. The company focuses on full-process engineering and global support for cleaner mobility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3066 CNY/T on December 26, 2025, marking a 0.07% decline from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have dropped 0.87%, and are down 6.21% from the same period last year. On December 25, prices were at 3,084 CNY/T, down 0.03%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Surtaxes, Tariff Rate Quotas and Steel Derivatives – Is this for real??</title><link>https://sourcealliance.net/surtaxes-tariff-rate-quotas-and-steel-derivatives-is-this-for-real/</link><description>Effective December 26, 2025, Canada imposes 25% tariffs on steel derivative products from all countries. These measures target US, Chinese, and non-US imports containing Chinese steel or aluminum. This escalates protectionism in response to international trade tensions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China pledges to control steel output during 2026-2030 period</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/commodities-news/china-pledges-to-control-steel-output-during-20262030-period-4422922</link><description>China announced it will regulate crude steel output and prohibit illegal new capacity from 2026 to 2030 to address overcapacity and support supply-side reforms. In the first 11 months of 2025, crude steel output fell 4% year-on-year, on track to drop below 1 billion tons for the first time in six years amid a property downturn. The plan coincides with robust steel exports facing global protectionism, prompting a new export licensing system for 300 steel-related items.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel demand seen buoyed by autos, appliances in '26</title><link>https://www.chinadaily.com.cn/a/202512/26/WS694deb74a310d6866eb30963.html</link><description>China's steel consumption is projected at 808 million tons in 2025 and 800 million tons in 2026, with growth in automotive, shipbuilding, and appliance sectors despite overall decline. The report emphasizes steel enterprises advancing intelligent, green, and integrated development through industrial ecosystems. ESG ratings for 108 companies show improving disclosure and performance, calling for stronger industry-wide coordination.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Dec. 26</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20251226/14571663689a47869f9d42b3a7a3be3b/c.html</link><description>London Stock Exchange Group reported copper prices at 5.65 USD at 0200 GMT on December 26. This update provides the latest snapshot of global metals prices, including gold, iron ore, palladium, and platinum. The data reflects ongoing market movements in commodities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Oil Prices Dip, LME Copper Extends Record Rally, Gold Slightly Lower</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/m/page/commodity-news-detail/commodity-news-detail-29163.html</link><description>LME copper futures gained 0.9% to settle at $12,162.50 per tonne, extending its record rally. LME aluminum futures also rose 0.7% to $2,960.50 per tonne. The gains occur amid broader commodity market movements, with oil prices dipping and gold slightly lower.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>On December 26, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel was</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103692395/</link><description>On December 26, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel ranged from 125,700–133,700 yuan/mt, with an average of 129,700 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 2,300 yuan/mt from the previous day. The update highlights short-term price gains in the refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Environmental protection-driven production restrictions intensified, coupled with high aluminum prices suppressing demand, the operating rate of downstream aluminum processors weakened to 60.8% - SMM Aluminum Processing Weekly Survey</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103693363/environmental-protection-driven-production-restrictions-intensified-coupled-with-high-aluminum-prices-suppressing-demand-the-operating-rate-of-downstream-aluminum-processors-weakened-to-608-smm-aluminum-processing-weekly-survey</link><description>The weekly operating rate of domestic aluminum downstream processing enterprises fell to 60.8% as of December 26, 2025, down 0.6 percentage points week-over-week. High aluminum prices suppressed demand, leading to cautious buying, while intensified environmental production restrictions in central China constrained operations. Export orders faced pressure from holiday slowdowns, with weak year-end stockpiling expected to persist.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Environmental protection-driven production restrictions intensified, coupled with high aluminum prices suppressing demand; the operating rate of downstream aluminum processors weakened to 60.8% - SMM Aluminum Processing Weekly Survey</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103693363/environmental-protection-driven-production-restrictions-intensified-coupled-with-high-aluminum-prices-suppressing-demand-the-operating-rate-of-downstream-aluminum-processors-weakened-to-608-smm-aluminum-processing-weekly-survey</link><description>The weekly operating rate of leading domestic aluminum downstream processing enterprises fell 0.6 percentage points week-over-week to 60.8% due to weak orders, environmental protection controls, and high aluminum prices. Environmental protection-driven production restrictions escalated in central China, with a red alert for air pollution in Gongyi lasting until December 28, constraining production and transportation. Downstream sectors like aluminum alloy, wire, cable, and foil face ongoing pressure from slow orders and delayed stockpiling, with operating rates expected to remain weak.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China to rein in copper, alumina capacity expansion under next five-year plan</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2025-12-26/china-rein-copper-alumina-capacity-expansion-under-next-five-year-plan</link><description>China will tighten oversight of new copper and alumina projects from 2026 to 2030 to curb irrational investment and overcapacity, as it is the world’s largest producer of both. From January to November 2025, China produced 13.3 million metric tons of refined copper (up 9.8% year-over-year) and 84.7 million tons of alumina, both on track for records. This policy aims to address risks of unchecked expansion amid rising output.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Russia expects 5pc drop steel output 2025</title><link>https://www.nation.com.pk/26-Dec-2025/russia-expects-5pc-drop-steel-output-2025</link><description>Russia anticipates a 5 percent decline in steel output for 2025, reaching 67 million tonnes. This forecast comes from First Deputy Prime Minister Denis Manturov amid ongoing industry challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Beijing tightens reins on copper and alumina projects to stop disorderly expansion</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/beijing-tightens-reins-on-copper-and-alumina-projects-to-stop-disorderly-expansion-116733</link><description>China's National Development and Reform Commission is tightening controls on new copper and alumina projects to prevent irrational investment and disorderly expansion from 2026 to 2030. From January to November 2025, China produced 13.3 million tonnes of refined copper, up 9.8% year-over-year, on track for a record. The policy emphasizes regional differences, mergers among large firms, and continued overseas mining investments.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China to rein in copper, alumina capacity expansion under next five-year plan</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2025-12-26/china-rein-copper-alumina-capacity-expansion-under-next-five-year-plan</link><description>China's NDRC announced tighter oversight on copper and alumina projects to curb overcapacity, requiring feasibility studies aligned with national policy. China produced 13.3 million metric tons of refined copper from January to November 2025, up 9.8%, with plans for 2 million tons of smelting capacity already suspended. The measures support industry consolidation and overseas investments amid strong production and rising prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Hindustan Copper Surges as Global Copper Prices Hit 16-Year High</title><link>https://news.legalparivar.com/hindustan-copper-surges-as-global-copper-prices-hit-16-year-high/</link><description>Hindustan Copper's stock surged as global copper prices reached a 16-year high, reflecting strong market momentum. The price rally underscores tightening supply conditions in copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Daily Nickel price, LME SHFE Price of Nickel live</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Nickel</link><description>SMM reports #1 Jinchuan Nickel at 16,790.92 USD/mt on Dec 26, with high-grade NPI averaging 904 yuan/mtu, up 5 yuan MoM, showing bottom support and short-term upside potential. Various nickel premiums and prices listed, including import nickel at 15,946.96 USD/mt. Includes review of nickel ore for 2025 and outlook for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Environmental protection-driven production restrictions intensified, coupled with high aluminum prices suppressing demand, the operating rate of downstream aluminum processors weakened to 60.8% [SMM Aluminum Processing Weekly Survey]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103693363/Environmental-protection-driven-production-restrictions-intensified-coupled-with-high-aluminum-prices-suppressing-demand-the-operating-rate-of-downstream-aluminum-processors-weakened-to-608-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Processing-Weekly-Survey%5D</link><description>The weekly operating rate of leading domestic aluminum downstream processing enterprises fell 0.6 percentage points week-on-week to 60.8% due to weak orders, environmental protection controls, and high aluminum prices. Environmental restrictions escalated in central China, with a red alert for air pollution in Gongyi lasting until December 28, constraining production and transportation. Looking ahead, ongoing restrictions and weak year-end stockpiling are expected to keep operating rates under pressure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Environmental protection-driven production restrictions intensified, coupled with high aluminium prices suppressing demand, the operating rate of downstream aluminium processors weakened</title><link>http://www.alcircle.com/press-release/environmental-protection-driven-production-restrictions-intensified-coupled-with-high-aluminium-prices-suppressing-demand-the-operating-rate-of-downst-116731</link><description>The weekly operating rate of leading domestic aluminium downstream processing enterprises fell 0.6 percentage points week-on-week to 60.8%. This decline is attributed to intensified environmental protection-driven production restrictions and high aluminium prices suppressing demand. The report highlights challenges in the aluminium processing sector amid off-season dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Five-Month Peak</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures climbed to $5.7 per pound, a five-month high, driven by global energy transition demand and supply constraints. The metal has gained 42% annually in New York. Prices partially pared gains but remain supported by robust fundamentals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Holds Near 5-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures hovered around $5.7 per pound near a five-month high, bolstered by tight supply and strong US economic growth. The US economy expanded at its fastest pace in two years in Q3, aiding prices. Robust industrial activity continues to underpin the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price 26 dec 2025</title><link>https://www.mining.com/new-york-copper-price-surges-again-shanghai-sets-record/copper-price-26-dec-2025/</link><description>Copper prices surpassed $12,000 per tonne for the first time on record, propelled by mine disruptions and tariff concerns despite weak Chinese demand. Shanghai copper also set a record. The rally reflects persistent supply tightness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>New IIT (ISM) Dhanbad Centre to Drive Critical Minerals Innovation for Clean-Tech</title><link>https://solarquarter.com/2025/12/26/new-iit-ism-dhanbad-centre-to-drive-critical-minerals-innovation-for-clean-tech/</link><description>IIT (ISM) Dhanbad launched a Critical Minerals Centre under India's National Critical Mineral Mission to boost innovation in minerals like nickel for clean energy technologies. The centre focuses on applied research and industry collaboration to secure supply chains for EVs, renewables, and battery storage. This addresses India's growing demand and reduces import dependence amid global competition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper surges to record near $13,000 in London after a 7% jump</title><link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/commodities/copper-surges-to-record-near-13000-in-london-after-a-7-jump-19805731.htm</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange surged nearly 7% to an all-time high near $13,000 per tonne after reopening following a two-day hiatus. The metal hit as high as $12,960 per tonne, driven by expectations of massive flows to the US leaving global shortages. Aluminium and zinc also rose by 0.6% and 0.9% respectively.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Five-Month Peak; Prices Rise on Tight Supply and Strong Demand</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures hit five-month highs (around $5.7 per pound) as tight supply, robust US economic activity and structural demand from EVs, renewables and AI infrastructure underpinned prices; the page also reports recent national production figures for Chile and Peru. The report highlights inventory pressures and continued price appreciation through late December.[4]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 27.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures rebar contracts showing no change on December 26, 2025. Coverage includes indices, news, and analyses for various markets like Turkey, China, Europe, and North America. Users can track commodities via watch lists for the latest price changes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Beyond Gold: Copper's Explosive Rise as AI and EVs Fuel Demand!</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/commodities/Beyond-Gold-Coppers-Explosive-Rise-as-AI-and-EVs-Fuel-Demand/694f469c4342f77179d8a3fe</link><description>Copper prices have surged 36% due to demand from AI data centers, electric vehicles, and supply disruptions, with analysts bullish citing Chinese buying and recommending mining stocks like Freeport McMoRan. Industrial metals rally reflects technology and energy transition trends. Uranium and cobalt also saw significant gains amid broader market strength.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits $12K: Supply Crisis Drives Historic Rally</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-historic-rally-2025-supply-demand-tech-geopolitics/</link><description>Copper prices have exceeded $12,000 per tonne amid a supply crisis sparking a historic market rally. The surge is driven by ongoing supply-demand imbalances in production and capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel fell 1.8% to $15,235 a ton on the LME amid stronger dollar and higher financing costs from fewer expected Fed rate cuts in 2025. Indonesia considers deep cuts to nickel mining quotas to boost slumping prices, offsetting market gloom. Prices are down 8% year-to-date due to new Indonesian supply and slowing EV sales.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Talon Metals to Acquire Lundin Mining's Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill Operations, Creating a Multi-Asset U.S. Nickel-Copper Company</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=6944a95118e86fe8dc044412</link><description>Talon Metals is acquiring the cash-flow-positive Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill from Lundin Mining to form a unified US nickel-copper platform with exploration and expansion opportunities. The move advances priorities like extending Eagle's mine life, exploring in Michigan and Minnesota, and permitting the Tamarack Nickel-Copper Project. It addresses US dependence on foreign critical minerals for defense and energy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CISA mills' daily crude steel output down 1.3% in mid-December, stocks up</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cisa-mills-daily-crude-steel-output-down-13-in-mid-december-stocks-up-1426220.htm</link><description>The China Iron and Steel Association reported average daily crude steel output of large and medium Chinese steel enterprises fell to 1.845 million tonnes during December 11–20, down 1.3% from early December, while finished steel inventories rose to 16.01 million tonnes as of December 20. The story also notes recent week-by-week movements in US raw steel production and broader inventory trends for Chinese mills.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China pledges to control steel output during 2026–2030 period</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/china-pledges-to-control-steel-output-during-2026-2030-period/</link><description>China said it will continue to regulate crude steel output and prohibit the addition of illegal new capacity from 2026–2030 as part of supply-side reforms and carbon-emission controls, noting crude steel output fell about 4% in the first 11 months of 2025 versus a year earlier. The announcement also referenced a planned export licensing system for roughly 300 steel-related items starting in 2026.[2]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China pledges to control steel output during 2026–2030 period</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40399452/china-pledges-to-control-steel-output-during-2026-2030-period</link><description>A re-reporting of the Chinese state planner's pledge to regulate crude steel output through 2026–2030, noting the 4% drop in crude steel production in the first 11 months of 2025 and the planned licensing system for steel-related exports; the piece summarizes official comments on supply-side reform and overcapacity.[6]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper hits all-time high today: Will Trump's tariffs and mine disruptions keep prices soaring despite slowing China demand?</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/copper-hits-all-time-high-today-will-trumps-tariffs-and-mine-disruptions-keep-prices-soaring-despite-slowing-china-demand/articleshow/126144292.cms</link><description>Copper prices hit a record high above $12,000 per ton, driven by Trump tariff concerns and mine disruptions. The rally persists even amid weaker demand from China. Supply constraints are expected to maintain upward pressure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nornickel believes 2026 will bring dividends, CEO says</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-believes-2026-will-bring-dividends-ceo-says/</link><description>Nornickel’s CEO Vladimir Potanin stated that the company expects positive cash flow in 2026, enabling resumption of dividend payments after skipping them in 2022-2024. The world’s largest nickel producer faces challenges from Western sanctions but is redirecting sales to Asia. Potanin anticipates dividends, though smaller than before, amid improving financial conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Why Metal Prices Keep Climbing</title><link>https://www.businesstoday.com.my/2025/12/28/why-metal-prices-keep-climbing/</link><description>Precious and industrial metals, including aluminum, are surging to record highs as 2025 ends, driven by economic and geopolitical uncertainty. The article highlights ongoing climbs in metal prices amid broader market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel industry urges FBR to seek advance tax guarantees on duty-free Chinese imports via Sost</title><link>https://profit.pakistantoday.com.pk/2025/12/29/steel-industry-urges-fbr-to-seek-advance-tax-guarantees-on-duty-free-chinese-imports-via-sost/</link><description>Pakistan's steel producers have urged the Federal Board of Revenue to require advance tax guarantees from importers of duty-free Chinese steel products via the Sost Dry Port to prevent diversion to taxable areas. The industry highlights Pakistan's surplus steel production capacity and opposes tax exemptions on finished steel goods. They suggest limiting exemptions to raw materials or scrap to protect local production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Business sentiment for January pessimistic over slump in construction, steel sectors: Poll</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-12-29/business/economy/Business-sentiment-for-January-pessimistic-over-slump-in-construction-steel-sectors-Poll/2488134</link><description>South Korea's business sentiment index for January signals pessimism, particularly in the steel and construction sectors, with the steel sector reading at 85.2 below the 100 benchmark. The Federation of Korean Industries attributes the slump to weak performance dragging down related industries like metal processing. Experts call for government support in restructuring steel and reducing financial burdens on raw materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices, Charts, Analysis &amp; Forecast | SMM Metals Market</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper prices have surged strongly since mid-September 2025, repeatedly hitting record highs, with SHFE.CU2602 at CNY/mt 101,380. High-grade copper traded around USD 12,316.7 per mt as of Dec 26. Rising prices are driving up motor costs and supply chain pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices hit record as investors bet on tighter times coming ...</title><link>https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/biz/archives/2025/12/29/2003849659</link><description>Copper prices hit records in Shanghai and rallied in New York, with Shanghai futures nearing 100,000 yuan per tonne and Comex up 5.6% to $5.8075 a pound. Investors anticipate tighter global supplies next year amid a weaker US dollar and energy transition demand. The rally caps a 42% yearly gain for copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices hit record as investors bet on tighter times coming</title><link>https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/biz/archives/2025/12/29/2003849659</link><description>Shanghai and New York copper prices surged to record or near-record levels as investors priced in tighter global supplies next year, aided by a weaker US dollar and large annual gains; the piece links price strength to trade dislocations and the energy transition boosting long-term demand. The article reports SHFE copper trading near 100,000 yuan/tonne and Comex copper reaching intraday highs above $5.80/lb.[5]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Can the sizzling rally in ASX 200 copper stocks boost BHP shares in 2026?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/12/29/can-the-sizzling-rally-in-asx-200-copper-stocks-boost-bhp-shares-in-2026/</link><description>The article examines how the rally in copper is benefiting ASX-listed miners and notes BHP's record FY25 copper production of 2,017 kt, driven by stronger performances across operated assets and projects that could deliver ~2 Mtpa of attributable copper production during the 2030s. It contextualizes producer-level capacity increases amid the broader market rally.[7]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 29, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103694778/</link><description>Shanghai Metals Market reported the SMM #1 refined nickel price range and an average price for December 29, 2025, showing an intraday rise (average price 131,700 yuan/mt, up 2,000 yuan/mt from the prior period), reflecting local refined-nickel market moves amid supply tightness in Indonesia and year-end dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Flash — December 29: Indonesia’s ore market remains tight as 2025 closes</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103694014</link><description>A rapid market note summarised December 29 developments, stating Indonesia's nickel ore market remains structurally tight and describing downward price pressure from weak demand in some segments while noting policy and supply shifts that could alter near-term balances.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>