<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 05:35:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SMM Analysis: Processing Fees for Aluminum Billets Remain ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103725189</link><description>On January 5, 2026, SMM A00 aluminum prices surged 850 yuan/mt post-New Year's, causing billet processing fees to drop 0–160 yuan/mt but stay positive initially. By January 6, another 600 yuan/mt rise pushed fees negative despite production costs of 200–300 yuan/mt. The analysis examines producer and trader dynamics behind this trend.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Why Is Alcoa Corporation Stock Gaining Friday?</title><link>https://www.benzinga.com/markets/earnings/26/01/50090888/alcoa-cashes-in-on-higher-aluminum-prices-eyes-more-output-in-2026</link><description>Alcoa reported strong Q4 2025 results with increased alumina and aluminum production, projecting 2026 alumina output at 9.7–9.9 million metric tons and aluminum at 2.4–2.6 million metric tons due to productivity gains and smelter restarts. The Aluminum segment saw a 21% quarter-over-quarter revenue increase from higher pricing and shipments. Cash balance stood at $1.6 billion with $537 million from operations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Gain Support from Macro Tailwinds, Consolidating at High Levels in the Short Term - SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103737147/aluminum-prices-gain-support-from-macro-tailwinds-consolidating-at-high-levels-in-the-short-term-smm-aluminum-morning-me</link><description>SHFE aluminum futures showed slight gains amid supply disturbances including tax policy expectations, compliance checks, transportation issues, and environmental production restrictions in China. Domestic and Indonesian aluminum projects are ramping up steadily, but industry's operating rate is expected to trend downward short-term. Market selling improved slightly, though downstream buying remains weak.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Industry Newsletter 1/23/26</title><link>https://steelindustrynews.substack.com/p/steel-industry-newsletter-12326</link><description>Nucor continues to hold CSP steel price for the 4th week amid January 2026 market analysis. Highlights include Nucor raising HRC to $960/ton, US steel mills hiking coating extras, and global trade imbalances. Other news covers tariffs, production, and corporate developments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 19-month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/519806</link><description>Nickel increased to $18,908/T, the highest level since June 2024. Over the past 4 weeks, nickel has gained significantly as market sentiment remains bullish due to supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price Update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103738363</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price was 149,800-157,800 yuan/mt with an average price of 153,800 yuan/mt, up 5,250 yuan/mt from the previous trading day, reflecting continued strength in Asian markets.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Delayed publication of NPI FOB Indonesia price: pricing notice</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/delayed-publication-of-npi-fob-indonesia-price-pricing-notice/</link><description>Fastmarkets delayed the publication of its Nickel pig iron (10-14% Ni content, fob Indonesia) price assessment originally due on January 20, 2026, due to a technical error, with the database now updated. This price is part of the Steel Raw Materials package and relates to Indonesian nickel production capacities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EGA signs deal to build first US aluminium plant in almost five decades</title><link>https://www.thenationalnews.com/business/2026/01/26/ega-signs-deal-to-build-first-us-aluminium-plant-in-almost-five-decades/</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium (EGA) and Century Aluminum announced a joint venture to build a new primary aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, with a $4 billion investment. The facility will produce 750,000 tonnes of aluminum annually, more than doubling current U.S. production, and create 1,000 permanent jobs plus 4,000 construction positions. Construction is expected to begin by the end of 2026, with production starting before the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum joins EGA project to build first U.S. smelter in almost 50 years</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CENX/century-aluminum-joins-ega-project-to-build-first-u-s-smelter-in-oq49xwngoo58.html</link><description>Century Aluminum (NASDAQ: CENX) and Emirates Global Aluminium announced a joint development agreement for a 750,000-tonne-per-year primary aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, with EGA holding 60% and Century 40% ownership. This marks the first new U.S. primary smelter since 1980 and will address the current situation where 85% of domestic aluminum needs are met by imports. Construction is targeted for the end of 2026 with production expected by the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Joins EGA Project to Build First U.S. Smelter in Almost 50 Years</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/281637/Century-Aluminum-Joins-EGA-Project-to-Build-First-U.S.-Smelter-in-Almost-50-Years</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Century Aluminum entered into a joint development agreement to construct the first new primary aluminum production plant in the United States since 1980 in Inola, Oklahoma. The facility will produce 750,000 tonnes annually using EGA's advanced technology, creating 1,000 permanent jobs and 4,000 construction jobs while more than doubling current U.S. production capacity. Detailed engineering is underway with construction expected to start by the end of 2026 and production by the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Major Aluminum Project in Oklahoma Promises Thousands of Jobs</title><link>https://ktul.com/news/local/major-aluminum-project-in-oklahoma-promises-thousands-of-jobs</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Century Aluminum announced a partnership to develop the first new primary aluminum smelter in the U.S. in nearly five decades in Inola, Oklahoma, with planned annual production of 750,000 metric tons. The project will use EGA's most advanced smelting technology and is expected to create approximately 1,000 permanent jobs and 4,000 construction jobs while significantly strengthening domestic aluminum supply. The facility will be located at the Tulsa Port of Inola, providing access to national shipping routes through the Mississippi River system.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Joins EGA Project to Build First U.S. Smelter in Almost 50 Years</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/press-release/century-aluminum-joins-ega-project-build-first-us-smelter-almost-50-years-2026-01-0</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium (EGA) and Century Aluminum have agreed to build a new primary aluminum smelter in Oklahoma, the first in the U.S. since 1980, using advanced EGA technology to double domestic production. The facility will address import dependency for this critical mineral, benefiting industries like automotive, aerospace, and defense while creating manufacturing jobs. Construction is slated to start by late 2026, with production by the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Falls as China Output Declines</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures fell toward CNY 3,100 per ton, hitting a two-week low after official data showed China’s steel production sank to a seven-year low in 2025 despite strong exports. Annual output dropped 4.4% to 961 million tons, falling below the 1 billion threshold and highlighting weak domestic demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nucor increases HRC spot price by $5/ton</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/26/nucor-increases-hrc-spot-price-by-5-ton/</link><description>Nucor's consumer spot price for hot-rolled coil increased to $965 per short ton, up $5 per short ton from the prior week. The West Coast joint venture price also rose $5 to $1,015 per short ton, with lead times of 3 to 5 weeks continuing.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel Falls as China Output Declines</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>China’s steel production fell to a seven-year low of 961 million tons in 2025, down 4.4% year-over-year, due to weak domestic demand despite strong exports. December output hit a two-year low of 68.2 million tons amid property sector strains and government curbs on new capacity. Member mills slightly increased early January output but remained 3.3% below last year's pace.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Steel Production Drops 2% in 2025 Amid Market Pressures – Worldsteel</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/global-steel-production-drops-2-in-2025-amid-market-pressures-worldsteel-2026-1-26/98324</link><description>Global crude steel production by World Steel Association members fell 3.7% year-over-year to 139.6 million tonnes in December 2025, with full-year 2025 output at 1,803.8 million tonnes, down 2.0% from 2024. Asia and Oceania saw the steepest decline at 6.3%, while the Middle East surged 13.9%. EU-27, Other Europe, and South America showed positive growth.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Daily Report on 26 January 2026</title><link>https://www.ferroalloynet.com/report/nickel_daily_report_on_26_january_2026.html</link><description>Daily report on nickel market trends and prices for January 26, 2026, providing updates relevant to recent developments in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Week-in-Review and Thoughts for the Upcoming Week of 01/26/2026</title><link>https://www.aluminummarketupdate.crugroup.com/global-trade/week-in-review-and-thoughts-for-the-upcoming-week-of-01-26-2026/</link><description>The US Midwest aluminum premium hit a record above $1 per pound, comprising nearly 70% of the LME cash price. LME aluminum rose 1.1% weekly amid strong base metals performance. Upcoming data includes US jobless claims, trade deficit, and factory orders.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>EGA and Century Aluminium set to build first new US smelter in nearly 50 years</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/ega-and-century-aluminium-set-to-build-first-new-us-smelter-in-nearly-50-years-117055</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Century Aluminum have partnered to build the first new primary aluminum smelter in the U.S. since 1980 in Inola, Oklahoma, with a capacity of 750,000 tonnes per year. The project will create over 1,000 permanent jobs and 4,000 construction jobs, with construction expected to begin by late 2026 and production targeted for the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum joins Oklahoma smelter</title><link>https://www.metaltechnews.com/story/2026/01/28/tech-metals/century-aluminum-joins-oklahoma-smelter/2625.html</link><description>Century Aluminum has joined the Oklahoma smelter project partnership, with construction expected to begin by the end of 2026 and initial production targeted thereafter.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AISI: Raw steel production jumps to 20-week high</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/26/aisi-raw-steel-production-jumps-to-20-week-high/</link><description>US raw steel production reached 1,778,000 short tons in the week ending January 24, 2026, marking the highest rate in over four months with a 1.3% week-over-week increase. The mill capability utilization rate stood at 76.9%, up from 75.9% the previous week and 76.3% year-over-year. Year-to-date production through January 24 totaled 6,016,000 short tons, up 3.4% compared to the same period last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Stainless Steel Prices, Inventory &amp; Insights in China from Jan 12th to Jan 25th</title><link>https://www.jinlingmetals.com/article/stainless-steel-prices-inventory-insights-in-china-from-jan-12th-to-jan-25th-2026.html</link><description>The main stainless steel contract rose by US$65/MT to US$2245/MT, up 3.15% from last week. On January 26th, futures rose 0.51% to close at US$2245/MT, with Tsingshan Indonesia raising 304 export quotes by $30/MT for the fourth time in January. Spot prices for cold and hot-rolled 304 strengthened, supported by rising raw material costs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Can Copper Extend Its Gains in 2026? | Presented by CME Group</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LElmDTGl7tU</link><description>After 41% gains in 2025, copper rallied above $6/lb on January 6, 2026; key factors include declining ore grades, Trump's tariff policies inflating US premiums, and volatility influenced by Fed policy and China stimulus. Consensus price targets range $5–$6.35/lb amid high volatility over 31%. The video analyzes sustainability of the rally.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Supply-Demand Marginal Changes Limited, Aluminum Prices ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103739462</link><description>LME aluminum closed at $3,195.5/mt, up 0.69%, while SHFE aluminum 2603 closed at 24,380 yuan/mt, up 0.68%. Spot primary aluminum prices edged down, with mainstream transactions at a discount, and aluminum scrap prices showed divergence amid weak downstream demand. The market is expected to hover at highs this week but faces downside pressures ahead of Chinese New Year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Press Metal to gain from higher aluminium prices</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2026/01/27/press-metal-to-gain-from-higher-aluminium-prices</link><description>Press Metal is expected to benefit from higher aluminum prices and favorable alumina costs, with revised LME assumptions at US$2,950 per tonne for 2026. Alumina prices fell 54% year-on-year to US$310 per tonne, improving cost ratios. Forecasts for the company lifted by 5-18% for 2025-2027.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Oklahoma Smelter: $4B Investment Plan</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/americas-aluminum-supply-chain-vulnerability-2026/</link><description>Century Aluminum announces a $4 billion joint venture for an Oklahoma smelter project, reinforcing efforts to bolster America's aluminum supply chain. This initiative highlights vulnerabilities in domestic production and aims to enhance sustainability and security through expanded capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Digitalization: The Key to Steel Decarbonization</title><link>https://www.metalconstructionnews.com/articles/digitalization-the-key-to-steel-decarbonization/</link><description>Digital tools are essential for verifying emission reduction claims and improving manufacturing efficiency in steel production. Digitalization enables supply chain transparency and traceability, helping build trust in low-emissions steel by monitoring sustainability credentials throughout production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Daily Topic of China Commodity Data (January 27, 2026)</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-30081.html</link><description>On January 26, 2026, SunSirs monitored 96 commodities with year-on-year price increases, including 15 in the non-ferrous sector. Recent updates highlight LME copper rises alongside oil price falls and gold breaking $5,000. The commodity price index BPI reached 952 points, up 9 points from the previous day.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Immediate transition to copper is technically and economically feasible</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/2026/01/27/immediate-transition-to-copper-is-technically-and-economically-feasible/</link><description>Rising silver prices are prompting large solar manufacturers to switch to copper for cell metallization, with Chinese firms like Longi adopting copper-based technology. Experts from ISC Konstanz and UNSW indicate that copper-metallized solar modules perform comparably to silver ones with acceptable efficiency trade-offs. This shift could mark 2026 as a milestone in reducing PV industry reliance on costly silver.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>DRC plans to export 100,000 metric tons of copper to the US</title><link>https://news.mongabay.com/2026/01/drc-plans-to-export-100000-metric-tons-of-copper-to-the-us/</link><description>The Democratic Republic of Congo plans to ship 100,000 metric tons of copper from the Tenke Fungurume Mine to the U.S. by end of January, amid U.S. investment in critical minerals. The mine, operated by CMOC Group and Gécamines, supports growing demand from renewables and AI applications. Gécamines aims for long-term sales of up to 500,000 tons of copper from its stakes.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Freeport-McMoRan Boosts 2026, 2027 Capex, Advancing Copper Projects</title><link>https://www.industrialinfo.com/news/article/freeport-mcmoran-boosts-2026-2027-capex-advancing-copper-projects--352397</link><description>Freeport-McMoRan plans $4.3-$4.5 billion in capex for 2026-2027 to expand U.S. copper production by over 50% in the next 4-5 years, focusing on innovation and facilities. The company supplies 70% of U.S. refined copper and anticipates strong global demand from power grids, renewables, and tech. Q4 2025 results were solid despite Grasberg disruptions, with operations resuming in Q2 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Record Copper Prices Highlight the Urgency of New U.S. Supply</title><link>https://www.mining.com/sponsored-content/record-copper-prices-highlight-the-urgency-of-new-u-s-supply/</link><description>Copper prices hit records above $6/lb on COMEX and $13,387/ton on LME due to supply disruptions at mines like Grasberg and Mantoverde, plus trade concerns. Forecasts predict deficits and 24% demand growth by 2035 from electrification. Gunnison Copper restarted production at Johnson Camp Mine in Arizona, advancing sulfide-leaching tech and planning a PEA update.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices experienced a significant correction on January 27 as Trump announced an increase</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103740650/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-correction-on-january-27-as-trump-announced-an-increase</link><description>On January 27, SMM #1 refined nickel prices dropped significantly to an average of 148,100 yuan/mt, down 5,700 yuan/mt from the previous day, amid Trump's announcement of higher tariffs on South Korean goods. SHFE nickel futures also declined 2.48% to 145,200 yuan/mt in the morning session. Despite the correction, nickel prices are likely to rise due to Indonesia's nickel ore quota cuts and supply disruptions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Jump After Top Producer Indonesia Signals 2026 Output Cut</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news/3112-51714-nickel-prices-jump-after-top-producer-indonesia-signals-2026-output-cut</link><description>Indonesia plans to cut nickel production quotas in 2026 to balance supply and demand, causing spot nickel prices to rise to $16,500/tonne from $15,800/tonne and LME three-month contract up 6.4%. The move aims to curb surplus and support prices, similar to DRC's cobalt strategy. Indonesia's market share has grown to 60.2% by 2024.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Challenges and opportunities of the EU battery and raw materials industries</title><link>https://www.pubaffairsbruxelles.eu/event/challenges-and-opportunities-of-the-eu-battery-and-raw-materials-industries-january-27/</link><description>An event on January 27 discusses EU strategies for a domestic EV battery value chain, emphasizing nickel and other raw materials for sustainability and reducing China dependency. Speakers from the Nickel Institute highlight opportunities in battery recycling and secure supply chains via initiatives like RESourceEU. The focus is on metals' role in green mobility and the twin transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian, Versalis Launch Chemical Recycling Chain for Plastic Cable Waste in Italy</title><link>https://esgnews.com/prysmian-versalis-launch-chemical-recycling-chain-for-plastic-cable-waste-in-italy/</link><description>Prysmian and Versalis have established a strategic partnership for chemical recycling of plastic cable insulation. The pilot project will begin in Italy in the second half of 2026, using Versalis's Hoop® technology to recover up to 60% of difficult-to-recycle XLPE insulation.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>AGCM Inspection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/agcm-inspection</link><description>The Italian Competition Authority (AGCM) conducted an inspection at Prysmian's Italian subsidiary regarding a possible anti-competitive arrangement involving price coordination and commercial sales conditions in the Italian low-voltage copper cable market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>AISI: US Steel Production Up 4.6% Year-on-Year in Late January</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/aisi-us-steel-production-up-4.6-year-on-year-in-late-january-2026-1-27/98335</link><description>US raw steel production rose to 1,778,000 net tons in the week ending January 24, 2026, representing a 4.6% year-over-year increase from 1,700,000 net tons in the same week of 2025. The capability utilization rate reached 76.9%, up from 76.3% a year prior, with regional production showing broad-based strength across all major US steelmaking hubs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steeled for Transition: A Deep-Dive Analysis of Steel Dynamics (STLD)</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/finterra-2026-1-27-steeled-for-transition-a-deep-dive-analysis-of-steel-dynamics-stld</link><description>Steel Dynamics (STLD) is diversifying into higher-margin products like painted steels and recycled aluminum to reduce sensitivity to steel price cycles and meet demand for sustainable materials. The company leads in 'Green Steel' with EAF technology achieving 75% lower carbon intensity than blast furnaces, certified by the Global Steel Climate Council in July 2025. Innovations include the energy-optimized Sinton mill and a $2.5 billion aluminum rolling mill applying scrap-based expertise for lower-emission production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Holds Gains on Dollar Weakness</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures held around $5.94 per pound after rallying nearly 3% in the previous session, supported by a weaker US dollar that boosts demand for commodities priced in greenbacks. This makes copper more affordable for buyers using other currencies. The market shows ongoing strength amid broader metal demand trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Highland Copper Recaps 2025 Execution and Announces 2026 Work Plan to Advance Copperwood Toward Construction Decision</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2026/01/27/3227121/0/en/Highland-Copper-Recaps-2025-Execution-and-Announces-2026-Work-Plan-to-Advance-Copperwood-Toward-Construction-Decision.html</link><description>Highland Copper announced its 2026 work plan to advance the Copperwood project toward a construction decision, including completion of FEED engineering and improved copper recoveries to 87.6% via ultrafine flotation technology. Contracts for tailings disposal and water balance engineering were awarded in 2025. The plan anticipates project financing, including $250 million from the US in 2027, and updates to mine design for potential cost reductions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Turkey copper mine owners are said to hire Goldman for sale</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/turkey-copper-mine-owners-are-said-to-hire-goldman-for-sale/</link><description>Owners of Turkey's largest open-pit copper mine, Gokirmak, hired Goldman Sachs to sell the business, seeking up to $1 billion for part or all of Acacia Mining Enterprises. The mine has 24 million tons of copper-ore reserves and produces 120,000 tons of concentrate annually. The sale follows record copper prices amid mine disruptions and strong demand from electrification.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>MIGA Continues to Support Renewable Energy in Chile</title><link>https://www.miga.org/press-release/miga-continues-support-renewable-energy-chile</link><description>MIGA issued a second guarantee backing renewable energy purchases to support clean copper production by Corporación Nacional del Cobre de Chile (CODELCO), critical for the global energy transition. Chile's leadership in copper production is highlighted as vital beyond its borders. This aids financial inclusion and climate finance through BancoEstado.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Revolutionises Zero-Carbon Production Through Advanced Mineralisation Technology</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/canada-nickel-zero-carbon-production-2026/</link><description>Canada Nickel has achieved a breakthrough in zero-carbon nickel production using advanced mineralisation technology. This innovation aims to revolutionize sustainable nickel processing for battery applications. The development supports cleaner energy supply chains amid growing demand for low-emission metals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Arca and Giga Metals sign exclusive agreement to explore carbon removal at B.C. nickel project</title><link>https://environmentjournal.ca/arca-and-giga-metals-sign-exclusive-agreement-to-explore-carbon-removal-at-b-c-nickel-project/</link><description>Arca Climate Technologies and Giga Metals have signed an exclusive agreement to explore carbon removal integration at a British Columbia nickel project. This partnership focuses on enhancing sustainability through carbon sequestration in nickel mining operations. It represents a step toward net-zero emissions in critical mineral production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Goldman Sachs raises its first-half 2026 Aluminum Price Forecast and adjusts surplus Outlook</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/01/27/goldman-sachs-raises-its-firsthalf-2026-aluminum-price-forecast-and-adjusts-surplus-outlook</link><description>Goldman Sachs raised its London Metal Exchange aluminum price forecast for the first half of 2026 to $3,150 per tonne from $2,575, citing low global inventories, doubts on Indonesian smelter power, and strong demand from EVs and grid expansion. The bank revised its 2026 surplus forecast down to 0.8 million tonnes from 1.1 million but expects prices not to stay above $3,000 long-term due to accelerating supply growth. LME aluminum traded at $3,180 per tonne after hitting a nearly three-year high.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tariffs, demand boost US steel outlook: Nucor</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/commodities/steel</link><description>US steelmaker Nucor expressed a moderately upbeat outlook for 2026 based on demand improvements and continued US tariff protections against steel imports. Nucor entered 2026 with historic order backlogs, up nearly 40% annually in the steel mill segment and up 15% in its steel products segment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper's momentum: Key catalysts to watch in 2026</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/opinion/2026-01-27/coppers-momentum-key-catalysts-watch-2026</link><description>Copper reached all-time highs due to supply disruptions and structural deficits driving repricing. The article from Sprott highlights key catalysts to monitor in 2026 for continued momentum. It emphasizes the metal's strong performance amid ongoing market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>January 28, 2026, SHFE Aluminum Prices Experienced a Sudden Surge [SMM Analysis]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103743247/january-28-2026-shfe-aluminum-prices-experienced-a-sudden-surge-smm-analysis</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices surged suddenly on January 28, 2026, according to SMM analysis. This movement reflects volatility in the Chinese futures market amid broader aluminum trends. The surge comes after recent fluctuations in spot and futures pricing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>January 28 SMM Cast Aluminum Alloy Morning Comment: Futures Stabilize, Spot Premiums Widen</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103741749</link><description>Overnight aluminum alloy futures surged to 23,230 yuan/mt before stabilizing around 23,060 yuan/mt, up slightly. Spot premiums for ADC12 widened to 1,100 yuan/mt, while aluminum scrap prices followed primary aluminum declines. Downstream demand remains sluggish due to high prices and pre-holiday factors, with supply disruptions from weather and regulations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Goldman Sachs lifts first-half 2026 aluminum price forecast, adjusts surplus outlook</title><link>https://au.marketscreener.com/news/goldman-sachs-lifts-first-half-2026-aluminum-price-forecast-adjusts-surplus-outlook-ce7e5bd8dc80fe20</link><description>Goldman Sachs raised its first-half 2026 LME aluminum price forecast to $3,150 per tonne from $2,575. The adjustment reflects revised expectations for market surplus. This bullish outlook signals anticipated tighter supply-demand balance.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US aluminium prices break away as tariffs collide with global supply strain</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/us-aluminium-prices-break-away-as-tariffs-collide-with-global-supply-strain-117048</link><description>US aluminum prices exceeded $5,000 per tonne due to escalating tariffs up to 50%, falling imports, and low stocks. Premiums over LME prices reached 68%, driven by factors like EU sanctions on Russian aluminum and China's production cap. Europe's CBAM adds further cost pressures on high-carbon imports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 962.05 USD/T on January 28, 2026, down 0.31% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 2.56%, and year-over-year they are up significantly. Forecasts indicate trading at 958.30 USD/T by quarter-end and 1034.13 in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SSAB and Rheinmetall Sign Letter of Intent for Fossil-Free Steel Supply</title><link>https://www.ssab.com/en</link><description>SSAB and German defense firm Rheinmetall have signed a letter of intent for supplying fossil-free steel, marking a key milestone in sustainable production. SSAB's new electric steel mill in Luleå has been designated a strategic net-zero project under the EU’s Net-Zero Industry Act. The company specializes in high-strength, sustainable steels like Strenx® and Hardox® aimed at creating a stronger, lighter, and fossil-free world.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Both bids and offers were scarce during the day, with weak supply and demand leading to a slight decline in the Yangshan premium</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103742925/both-bids-and-offers-were-scarce-during-the-day-with-weak-supply-and-demand-leading-to-a-slight-decline-in-the-yangshan-</link><description>Warrant prices for copper dropped slightly, with averages down $2/mt for QP February, amid scarce bids and offers. The LME contango widened as suppliers held back and downstream demand remained absent, leading to declining premiums for physical cargo. Transactions were limited, with small deals around $15-20/mt for early February delivery.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper, Gold, and Silver Take a Step Back</title><link>https://www.admis.com/copper-gold-and-silver-take-a-step-back/</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the LME fell 0.68% to $13,109 due to profit-taking and higher SHFE margin requirements effective January 28, which curbed demand. Supply disruption concerns provide underlying support, alongside long-term demand from AI data centers and China's $574 billion power grid investment through 2030. SHFE also adjusted trading limits and curbed some client activities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Decline Amid Demand Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/28/copper-prices-decline-amid-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices declined in Asian sessions due to a firmer US dollar and signs of weakening demand, particularly in China ahead of Lunar New Year with reduced consumer purchasing. SHFE raised margin requirements for copper from 10% to 11% to curb speculation, adding downward pressure. ANZ analysts noted decelerating Chinese economic activity and inventory buildup caution.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Jan. 28</title><link>http://www.china.org.cn/world/Off_the_Wire/2026-01/28/content_118304047.shtml</link><description>London Stock Exchange Group reported copper at 5.83 USD at 0200 GMT on January 28. This update includes prices for other metals like gold at 5,079.90 USD, iron ore at 106.03 USD, palladium at 1,967.50 USD, and platinum at 2,675.10 USD. The data reflects early morning global metals market snapshot.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metals Market Shaken as Aluminum Hits Fresh Peak Amid Four-Year Low for US Dollar</title><link>http://markets.chroniclejournal.com/chroniclejournal/article/marketminute-2026-1-28-metals-market-shaken-as-aluminum-hits-fresh-peak-amid-four-year-low-for-us-dollar</link><description>Aluminum prices surged to $3,289.55 per tonne on the LME on January 28, 2026, a multi-year peak driven by tightening global supply and a weak US dollar, up 11% in January. Volatility is expected as the market balances demand, with potential to test $3,500 if the dollar weakens further. Producers like Alcoa and Rio Tinto may invest in capacity amid supply deficits.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Aluminum Premium Tops $1 Per Pound For First Time</title><link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/world/us-aluminum-premium-tops-1-per-pound-for-first-time-10903807</link><description>The US Midwest aluminum premium reached $1.005 per pound on Wednesday, a record high due to President Trump's 50% tariffs on imports. This marks successive peaks since June, with US prices rising faster than global benchmarks amid tariff impacts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits Near 4-Year High</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/aluminum-hits-near-4-year-high/</link><description>UK aluminum futures exceeded $3,280 per tonne, reaching the highest since April 2022, fueled by tightening global supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Stainless Steel Daily Review: SHFE Nickel Weakness + Pre-Holiday Demand Slump</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Finished-Steel</link><description>Stainless steel futures declined due to SHFE nickel weakness and pre-holiday demand slump, with intraday low at 14,260 yuan/mt. Spot market showed sluggish trading. Social inventory remains low amid bullish sentiment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>CHAMPION IRON REPORTS ITS FY2026 THIRD QUARTER RESULTS AND ADVANCES THE DRPF PROJECT AS PLANNED</title><link>https://newsroom.championiron.com/2026-01-28-CHAMPION-IRON-REPORTS-ITS-FY2026-THIRD-QUARTER-RESULTS-AND-ADVANCES-THE-DRPF-PROJECT-AS-PLANNED</link><description>Champion Iron reported improved iron ore concentrate production in Q3 FY2026, with Fe recovery rates reaching 79.7% compared to 79.1% in the prior year period. The company's DRPF project to upgrade Bloom Lake's capacity to DR quality pellet feed iron ore is progressing as planned, with initial commercial shipments anticipated by the end of the first half of 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Aluminum Alloy Daily Report] Aluminum prices surged</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103743863/aluminum-prices-soar-secondary-alloy-firms-hike-rates-amid-thin-trading</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices surged suddenly on January 28, 2026, with the most-traded continuous contract reaching new levels by 11:30, prompting secondary alloy firms to hike rates amid thin trading conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>January 28, 2026, SHFE aluminum prices experienced a sudden surge - SMM analysis</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103743247/january-28-2026-shfe-aluminum-prices-experienced-a-sudden-surge-smm-analysis</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices surged 4.54% to 25,345 yuan/mt on January 28, 2026, driven by US-Iran geopolitical tensions disrupting aluminum trade and raw material transport, funds shifting from precious to base metals, and expectations of domestic alumina refinery production cuts. Open interest rose by about 68,000 lots, boosting market activity. The report warns of potential price corrections as sentiment cools.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 36-week High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel increased to 941.00 USD/T, marking its highest level since April 2025. Over the past 4 weeks, Hot-Rolled Coil Steel gained 2.87%, and over the last 12 months, it increased 31.63%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Daily Aluminum price, LME SHFE Price of Aluminum live | SMM</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices surged suddenly on January 28, 2026, with the most-traded contract reaching 25,345 yuan/mt, up 4.54% from the previous settlement. Open interest increased by about 68,000 contracts, showing heightened trading activity. Prices are consolidating at high levels due to macro factors despite limited supply-demand changes and high inventories.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Futures Rise: Fresh Bets Fuel Price Surge</title><link>https://money.rediff.com/news/market/aluminium-futures-rise-fresh-bets-fuel-price-surge/40977220260129</link><description>Aluminum futures on the Multi Commodity Exchange rose 5.75% to Rs 350.50 per kg on January 29, 2026, driven by speculators building positions amid positive spot trends and industry demand. The February contract saw significant volume in trading.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>High-purity alumina HPA First Project bags $175 million</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/2026/01/29/high-purity-alumina-hpa-first-project-bags-175-million/</link><description>Alpha HPA secured a $75 million investment from Australia's National Reconstruction Fund for its HPA First Project in Gladstone, producing ultra-high purity alumina for semiconductors, lithium-ion batteries, and pharmaceuticals. The project uses 100% renewable energy via Smart SX Technology, recycling nearly 100% of reagents to yield 5N+ purity materials. It positions Australia as a key supplier in global supply chains for AI and critical manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Steel Production Up 4.6% Year-on-Year in Late January 2026</title><link>https://www.indexbox.io/blog/us-steel-production-up-46-year-on-year-in-late-january-2026/</link><description>U.S. raw steel production increased 4.6% year-on-year for the week ending January 24, 2026, reaching 1.78 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.9%. Year-to-date production through January 24 totaled 6.016 million net tons, up 3.4% compared to the same period last year, with broad-based production strength across all major U.S. steelmaking regions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 1.3 percent - week 4, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-13-percent-week-3-2026-1431863.htm</link><description>According to AISI data, U.S. domestic raw steel production for the week ending January 24, 2026, was 1.778 million net tons with a 76.9% capacity utilization rate, representing a 1.3% increase from the previous week. The production level marks a 4.6% increase compared to the same week in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Record Highs: Geopolitical Tensions and Dollar Impact</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/copper-sets-record-amid-geopolitical-risks-weak-dollar/</link><description>Copper prices hit record highs amid geopolitical risks and a weak dollar, with the Shanghai Futures Exchange contract surging 6.35% to 108,740 yuan per metric ton and the London Metal Exchange benchmark climbing 6.63% to $13,953.50 a ton. The rally follows significant yearly gains fueled by supply concerns from mine disruptions and U.S. tariff threats. Other metals like zinc, lead, nickel, and tin also advanced.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Collaborates with SQM to Explore for Copper in Chile; LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103744065/ivanhoe-collaborates-with-sqm-to-explore-for-copper-in-chile-lme-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-higher-overnight-smm-coppe</link><description>LME copper opened at $13,111/mt overnight, fluctuated significantly, and closed at $13,120/mt, up 0.74%. Shanghai SHFE copper showed a 'V' shape, closing at 103,170 yuan/mt after probing a low. Imported and secondary copper prices saw slight declines in premiums.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Rallies to All-Time High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/520956</link><description>Copper futures surged nearly 7% to above $6.3 per pound, hitting record highs driven by demand for real assets amid geopolitical and trade uncertainties, including U.S. President Trump's threats against Iran, and a sudden dollar drop. The price reached an all-time high of 6.11 USD/Lbs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold and Copper Lead Metals Rally, Dollar Weakens: Markets Wrap</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/gold-and-copper-lead-metals-rally-dollar-weakens-markets-wrap/</link><description>Copper jumped 5% on the London Metal Exchange as part of a broader metals rally led by gold and silver, benefiting from a weakening dollar that makes dollar-denominated assets more attractive. Brent crude also climbed to its highest since September amid the market movements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Collaborates with SQM to Explore for Copper in Chile</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103744065/ivanhoe-collaborates-with-sqm-to-explore-for-copper-in-chile-lme-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-higher-overnight-smm-coppe</link><description>Ivanhoe has partnered with SQM to explore for copper resources in Chile. LME copper futures opened at $13,111/mt and closed at $13,120/mt with a 0.74% gain, while spot prices across Shanghai, imported copper, and secondary copper markets showed mixed movements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Rally: Mining Stocks Rise on AI Demand</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-price-rally-2026-technological-demand-energy/</link><description>Copper prices have rallied to around $13,000 per metric ton, driving gains in mining stocks as technological demand, particularly from AI applications, supports the commodity. The price surge reflects broader market momentum in the metals sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold and Copper Lead Metals Rally, Dollar Weakens: Markets Wrap</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/gold-and-copper-lead-metals-rally-dollar-weakens-markets-wrap/</link><description>Copper jumped 5% on the London Metal Exchange as part of a broader commodities rally, hitting all-time highs alongside gold and silver amid a weaker dollar and rising geopolitical tensions. The rally was supported by currency weakness, as these dollar-priced assets benefited from greenback decline.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mantoverde makes workers new offer as strike continues</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/mantoverde-makes-workers-new-offer-as-strike-continues-2026-01-29</link><description>Mantoverde copper mine in Chile has made a new offer to workers amid ongoing strike action. In 2025, the operation produced 62,308 tons of copper sulfide concentrate and 32,807 tons of copper cathodes, representing approximately 0.4% of global copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>NIC: Record EBITDA margins, strategic asset sale, and strong nickel prices drive positive outlook</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/urn:summary_document_transcript:quartr.com:2684283:0-nic-record-ebitda-margins-strategic-asset-sale-and-strong-nickel-prices-drive-positive-outlook/</link><description>Analysis of nickel market dynamics highlighting record EBITDA margins and strategic asset sales benefiting from strong nickel prices and positive market outlook.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries December 2025 quarter: Strong HPAL margins, mining rebounds</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/29/nickel-industries-december-2025-quarter-strong-hpal-margins-mining-rebounds/</link><description>Nickel Industries reported US$37.3 million adjusted EBITDA for Q4 2025, with strong HPAL margins despite mining delays from late government approval. Operations rebounded, targeting over 1.4 million wet metric tonnes of ore sales in January. The company anticipates a higher 2026 mining quota of 19 million wmt and progress on the ENC HPAL project.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Mines Q4 2025 slides: HPAL strength offsets mining challenges</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/company-news/nickel-mines-q4-2025-slides-hpal-strength-offsets-mining-challenges-93CH-4471728</link><description>Nickel Mines' HPAL operations produced 2,144 tonnes of nickel at 43% above nameplate capacity, with attributable EBITDA up 32% to US$17.2 million. RKEF production rose 1% to 31,561 tonnes despite EBITDA decline. The ENC project advances toward commissioning, supported by a major solar project for low-carbon production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Limited, Q4 2025 Earnings Call, Jan 29, 2026</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/transcript-nickel-industries-limited-q4-2025-earnings-call-jan-29-2026-ce7e5bdedb8ef520</link><description>Nickel Industries held its Q4 2025 earnings call on January 29, 2026, discussing quarterly activities. The webcast covered operational updates and operator instructions. It provides insights into recent production and financial performance.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Limited, Q4 2025 Earnings Call</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/transcript-nickel-industries-limited-q4-2025-earnings-call-jan-29-2026-ce7e5bdedb8ef520</link><description>Nickel Industries Limited held its Q4 2025 earnings call on January 29, 2026, discussing financial performance and operational updates. The transcript covers nickel production advancements and potential sustainability innovations in their operations. This reflects ongoing developments in the nickel sector relevant to technology and market sustainability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fluctuated on January 29, 2026, falling to $3,230.50 USD/T (down 1.12%) before rising to $3,306.20 USD/T (up 1.20%), with monthly gains of 8-10% and yearly increases over 26%. On January 28, prices hit 3,296 USD/T, a near 4-year high, up 8.78% in four weeks and 24.6% over 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fluctuated on January 29, 2026, reaching 3,306.20 USD/T amid China's capacity limits at 45 million tons, production disruptions in Iceland, Mozambique, and Australia, and rising demand from the energy transition. Traders worry about global producers' ability to ramp up supply quickly. A weaker US dollar and geopolitical tensions further supported prices, with recent rises hitting over three-year highs due to Chinese supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking raw material prices increase through January</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/29/steelmaking-raw-material-prices-increase-through-january/</link><description>All but one of the tracked steelmaking raw materials, including coking coal, pig iron, shredded scrap, busheling scrap, zinc, and aluminum, increased in price over the last month, with collective prices up 8% month-on-month. Shredded scrap rose to $420 per gross ton and busheling to $423/gt, 8-14% higher than three months ago. Iron ore fines eased to $106/dmt, down 1% month-on-month, while buyers expect further scrap price increases in February due to weather disruptions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto strengthens its global low-carbon aluminium footprint through joint acquisition with Chalco of Votorantim's interest in CBA</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2026/rio-tinto-strengthens-its-global-low-carbon-aluminium-footprint-through-joint-acquisition-with-chalco-of-votorantims-interest-in-cba</link><description>Rio Tinto and Chalco have jointly acquired Votorantim's interest in CBA to expand low-carbon aluminum production. This move enhances Rio Tinto's global sustainable aluminum capabilities. The acquisition aligns with efforts to reduce carbon emissions in aluminum manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Metal Stocks Plunge on Profit-Taking, Fed Fears</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/Commodities/Metal-Stocks-Plunge-on-Profit-Taking-Fed-Fears/697c40a85fc43f26c545dd8f</link><description>The Nifty Metal index plummeted nearly 5% on January 30, 2026, reversing recent gains as investors booked profits amid Federal Reserve concerns.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Today, January 30: Why Are Copper Rates Hitting Record Highs</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/business/copper-price-today-january-30-why-are-copper-rates-hitting-record-highs-167203/</link><description>Copper prices reached record highs above $14,000 per ton on January 30, 2026, driven by speculative buying from Chinese funds, weak US dollar, and demand from renewables and electrification. Physical demand remains low with high exchange stocks, potentially leading to corrections. Supply constraints from slow mine development exacerbate price volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Shining! Metal's record rally has boosted the fortunes of this ...</title><link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/copper-price-rally-hindustan-copper-boost-govt-stake-lic-value-unlocking-share-returns-ws-e-19836582.htm</link><description>Hindustan Copper plans to expand mine capacity from 4 MT to over 12 MT with ₹2,000 crore investment over five to six years, targeting 20% volume growth in FY2026 at over 40% margins. The expansion supports rising copper demand from EVs, renewables, AI data centers, and grid expansion amid a weak US dollar. Production costs are around $5,500 per tonne.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Final Cowley assays expand copper system</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/30/northern-neighbors/final-cowley-assays-expand-copper-system/9517.html</link><description>Final assays from Cowley expand the copper system, as reported in recent exploration updates. The findings indicate potential growth in copper resources at the site.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Autonomous Copper Refining at Olympic Dam: Tech Guide - Olympic Dam's Revolutionary Autonomous Copper Refining Technology Breakthrough</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-processing-technology-metallurgy-2026/</link><description>Olympic Dam has introduced a revolutionary autonomous copper refining technology featuring robotic arms for advanced processing. This innovation represents a breakthrough in copper metallurgy and processing technology. The article provides a tech guide on this development published today.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FNI unit ships first nickel ore cargo for 2026</title><link>https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2026/01/30/727443/fni-unit-ships-first-nickel-ore-cargo-for-2026/</link><description>Ipilan Nickel Corp., a subsidiary of Global Ferronickel Holdings, Inc., shipped its first nickel ore cargo of 2026, consisting of 53,912 wet metric tons of low-grade nickel ore to China. The company targets production of at least 1.5 million WMT for the year, with a sales mix of 52.6% low-grade and 47.4% medium-grade ore. Mine development includes expanding areas, building haul roads, and installing environmental protections to meet targets while complying with regulations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Solway to restart Guatemala nickel plant after price surge</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/solway-to-restart-guatemala-nickel-plant-after-price-surge/</link><description>Swiss-based Solway Investment Group plans to restart its PRONICO nickel plant and CGN mine in Guatemala within months, following a nickel price surge to $19,160 per ton and the lifting of U.S. sanctions. The facility has an annual capacity of 25,000 metric tons of ferronickel, with the mine capable of extracting up to 2.2 million tons of nickel ore. Restart is anticipated around April to May 2026, indicating high prices are enabling resumption of previously curtailed production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Global Ferronickel unit sets 2026 output target</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2026/01/30/business/top-business/global-ferronickel-unit-sets-2026-output-target/2268361</link><description>Global Ferronickel announced that its Ipilan unit has commenced 2026 mining operations with the first nickel ore shipment. The company has set specific output targets for the year amid ongoing operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries cements leadership in ENC, welcomes Sphere as strategic partner</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/30/nickel-industries-cements-leadership-in-enc-welcomes-sphere-as-strategic-partner/</link><description>Nickel Industries increased its stake in the ENC project to 46%, becoming the largest shareholder, while Sphere acquired a 10% interest at a US$2.4 billion valuation, reducing cash outflows by US$207 million. The company secured a 15-year MOU for 14 million WMT/year limonite ore supply for the Sampala Project. This strengthens financial flexibility and positions Nickel Industries for battery-grade nickel production as ENC nears commissioning.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries completes strategic partner’s entry into ENC project, revises acquisition terms</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-completes-strategic-partner-s-entry-into-enc-project-revises-acquisition-terms</link><description>ASX-listed Nickel Industries completed Sphere's entry into the ENC project and revised acquisition terms. The update enhances project ownership and financial terms for the nickel processor.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries cements leadership in ENC, welcomes Sphere as strategic partner</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/30/nickel-industries-cements-leadership-in-enc-welcomes-sphere-as-strategic-partner/</link><description>Nickel Industries increases its stake in the ENC project to 46%, becoming the largest shareholder, while welcoming Sphere as a 10% strategic partner at a US$2.4 billion valuation. This deal reduces future cash outflows by US$207 million and secures a 15-year exclusive limonite ore supply MOU for the Sampala Project. The partnership supports transition to battery-grade nickel and cobalt for electric vehicles, enhancing supply chain reliability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>