<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:16:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>China proposes more stringent steel capacity swap plan to curb overcapacity</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/china-proposes-more-stringent-steel-capacity-swap-plan-to-curb-overcapacity/</link><description>China has proposed a more stringent steel capacity swap plan to address overcapacity issues in the industry. This plan follows the pause of a previous program that failed to achieve its goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hebei Songting Steel to Start Blast Furnace Shutdown on Oct 27</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103588781/Hebei-Songting-Steel-to-Start-Blast-Furnace-Shutdown-on-Oct-27</link><description>Hebei Songting Steel is set to begin a blast furnace shutdown for maintenance starting October 27. This shutdown is part of routine maintenance to ensure operational efficiency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Experts urge factories to produce 100% refined steel to cut carbon emissions</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/economy/industry/experts-urge-factories-produce-100-refined-steel-cut-carbon-emissions-1270086</link><description>Industry experts are calling for factories to adopt 100% refined steel production as a key measure to reduce carbon emissions. This push aligns with broader efforts to decarbonize the steel sector and promote sustainability in manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Greece's New Copper-Gold Mine Nears Completion, LME Copper Rose Sharply on Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103587605/Greeces-New-Copper-Gold-Mine-Nears-Completion-LME-Copper-Rose-Sharply-on-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices rose 1.2% to close at $10,947/mt on Friday, with trading volume and open interest increasing. Canadian company Eldorado Gold announced its Skouries copper-gold project in Greece is about 70% complete, with first production expected in early 2026 and commercial production by mid-2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Remain Near Record Highs</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/27/copper-prices-remain-near-record-highs/</link><description>Copper prices are holding near record highs just below $11,000 a tonne, driven by concerns over supply disruptions such as the suspension of Freeport-McMoRan’s Grasberg mine in Indonesia after a fatal mudslide. The metal has rallied about 25% this year, reflecting strong demand and supply-side challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Metals on fire: What's driving the unstoppable rally in copper, aluminium and zinc</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/metals-on-fire-whats-driving-the-unstoppable-rally-in-copper-aluminium-and-zinc/articleshow/124824209.cms</link><description>Copper prices have surged past $10,000 on the LME and are near record highs on India's MCX platform, driven by supply disruptions at major mines, strong demand from infrastructure and green energy sectors, and geopolitical tensions. The rally is supported by factors including accidents at Chile's El Teniente mine, protests in Peru, and a mudslide at Indonesia's Grasberg mine.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper jumps to 16-month high on trade deal optimism</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/metals-copper-jumps-to-16-month-high-on-trade-deal-optimism-158328/</link><description>Copper prices climbed to a 16-month high driven by optimism over a potential U.S.-China trade agreement, reflecting positive market sentiment on easing trade tensions between the two largest economies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to $5.16 USD/Lbs on October 27, 2025, up 1.42% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices increased to $5.16 per pound, up 1.42% from the previous day, with a 6.23% rise over the past month and an 18.92% increase year-over-year. Analysts expect copper to trade at $5.20 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.74 in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Remain Near Record Highs</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/27/copper-prices-remain-near-record-highs/</link><description>Copper prices are holding near record highs, just below $11,000 per tonne, driven by concerns over supply disruptions. A key factor is the suspension of operations at Freeport-McMoRan’s Grasberg mine in Indonesia after a fatal mudslide, impacting the world's second-largest copper mine. The metal's strong rally this year reflects rising global demand and supply-side challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Diablo Resources (ASX:DBO) Confirms Copper Mineralisation Open in All Directions at Phoenix Project</title><link>https://www.marketopen.com.au/diablo-resources-asxdbo-confirms-copper-mineralisation-open-in-all-directions-at-phoenix-project/</link><description>Diablo Resources reported early drilling success at its Phoenix Copper Project in Utah, USA, with significant copper mineralisation confirmed open in all directions and at depth. Maiden drilling returned 10.5 metres at 1.02% copper, including a high-grade interval of 1.5 metres at 3.99% copper. Follow-up drilling is planned for mid-November, targeting further exploration in this recognized copper district.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Copper Smelter Emissions Rule Reversal Explained</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/biden-copper-rule-air-quality-standards-2025/</link><description>The Trump administration reversed Biden-era copper smelter emissions rules, granting a two-year exemption to protect domestic processing. The US processes less than 5% of global copper despite significant mining, relying heavily on foreign smelters, especially in China, which controls about 50% of global copper smelting capacity. This reversal highlights strategic concerns about supply chain security amid rising copper demand driven by clean energy and electric vehicle growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FireFly Announces Major High-Grade Copper and Gold Exploration Breakthrough at Green Bay</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/26/3174278/0/en/FireFly-announces-major-high-grade-copper-and-gold-exploration-breakthrough-at-Green-Bay.html</link><description>FireFly Metals reported exceptional drilling results at its Green Bay Copper-Gold Project in Canada, revealing a high-grade mineralised core over at least 800 meters strike length. Recent assays include 43 meters at 7.6% copper equivalent and 15 meters at 16% copper equivalent, indicating significant potential to expand the mineral resource. Ongoing drilling aims to define the full extent of this core for upcoming resource updates.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Miner Sandfire Tracks Ahead of Plan in Strong First Quarter</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/copper-miner-sandfire-tracks-ahead-of-plan-in-strong-first-quarter-2025-10-27</link><description>Sandfire Resources produced 21,800 tonnes of copper-equivalent in the first quarter, representing 23% of its 2026 financial year guidance. This performance reflects planned mining activities and positions the company well for the remainder of the year. The strong start indicates robust operational execution in copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Corruption Probe Underway at Rio Tinto's Mongolian Copper Mine</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2025102752/corruption-probe-underway-at-rio-tintos-mongolian-copper-mine-update</link><description>An internal investigation into allegations of corruption and unethical conduct is underway at Rio Tinto's Oyu Tolgoi copper mine in Mongolia. The probe involves procurement-related activities and has sought law enforcement cooperation. Oyu Tolgoi is a major copper and gold deposit expected to become the world's fourth-largest copper mine by 2030, critical to Rio Tinto's strategic shift toward copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Reverses Biden-Era Rules on Copper Smelters</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/trump-reverses-biden-era-rules-on-copper-smelters-2025-10-27</link><description>US President Donald Trump reversed a Biden-era air pollution rule that imposed stricter emissions limits on copper smelters. This regulatory change aims to ease restrictions on domestic copper processing, addressing concerns about supply chain resilience and domestic capacity limitations. The move reflects ongoing tensions between environmental regulations and industrial policy in the copper sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Hellenic Copper Mines Ltd: 2026 Outlook For Large Copper Mines</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/hellenic-copper-mines-ltd-2026-outlook-for-large-copper-mines</link><description>Hellenic Copper Mines Ltd is advancing innovation and sustainability in copper mining through automation, AI-powered resource management, advanced recycling, and digital traceability. The company focuses on energy-efficient operations, enhanced waste management, and compliance with stringent EU environmental standards to boost productivity and minimize environmental impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, Silver &amp; Copper: tech and sustainability trends</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_ca/insights/mining-metals/gold-silver-and-copper-tech-and-sustainability-trends</link><description>Copper companies are addressing supply challenges by adopting digital innovations, AI, satellite technology, and advanced mineral processing to optimize recovery and productivity. Recycling plays a key role, with recycled copper accounting for 32% of global supply in 2023, and companies increasingly collaborating with cleantech firms to enhance sustainable copper supplies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Rise Slightly on October 27 as China-US Economic and Trade Consultations Make Positive Progress</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103588834/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Rise-Slightly-on-October-27-as-China-US-Economic-and-Trade-Consultations-Make-Positive-Progress</link><description>On October 27, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,900 yuan/mt, up 750 yuan/mt from the previous day. Positive progress in China-US economic and trade talks and lower-than-expected US CPI data boosted market sentiment, supporting a slightly higher nickel price with expected sideways movement in the near term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel price rose slightly to $15,334.13 per ton on October 27, 2025, up 0.06% from the previous day. Despite a modest monthly increase, prices remain about 4-5% lower than a year ago. Forecasts suggest nickel may trade around $15,152 by the end of the quarter but could decline to about $14,420 in 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>METALS-Copper jumps to 16-month high on trade deal optimism; nickel rose 0.25%</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/gold-silver-prices-extend-fall-yellow-metal-below-rs-1-23-lakh-what-should-investors-do/articleshow/124839539.cms</link><description>On October 27, nickel prices rose by 0.25% amid broader positive market sentiment driven by optimism over trade deals. This modest increase aligns with gains in other base metals like copper and tin.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SPC's polymetallic Muskox treads the path of giants</title><link>https://mining.com.au/spcs-polymetallic-muskox-treads-the-path-of-giants/</link><description>SPC Nickel has completed a comprehensive field program at the Muskox Project in Nunavut, Canada, including the most thorough modern geophysical survey ever flown over the intrusion. The project shows promising high-grade silver and significant nickel-copper resources, with a 1km trend of high conductivity EM targets identified for potential drilling.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China, ASEAN to upgrade free trade, bring more certainties to world</title><link>https://english.www.gov.cn/news/202510/27/content_WS68fec32dc6d00ca5f9a070ee.html</link><description>A new project covering the full supply chain from nickel mining and processing to battery materials production, manufacturing, and recycling is underway, aiming to strengthen trade and industrial cooperation between China and ASEAN countries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Trump Strikes Strategic Critical Minerals Trade Deals in Southeast Asia</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-2025-strategic-partnerships-southeast-asia/</link><description>Former President Trump secured critical minerals trade deals in Southeast Asia, focusing on strategic partnerships that include nickel among other critical minerals, to support supply chains for commercial and defense industries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,876.15 per tonne on October 27, 2025, marking a 0.57% daily increase and a 7.35% gain over the past month. The surge is attributed to tightening supply, especially due to China's aluminum output cap, with prices reaching their highest level in three years.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash price rises to $2,878.5/t on October 27 as stocks dip to 469,275t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-price-rises-to-2-878-5-t-on-october-27-as-stocks-dip-to-469-275t-115973</link><description>LME aluminum prices climbed to $2,878.5 per tonne on October 27, driven by firm demand and a 3,850-tonne drop in exchange stocks to 469,275 tonnes. The price increase reflects ongoing tightness in the physical aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Key takeaways from AICE 2025 SMM (14th) aluminium industry annual conference</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/key-takeaways-from-aice-2025-smm-14th-aluminium-industry-annual-conference-115965</link><description>The conference discussed China's 'dual carbon' goals impacting the aluminum industry with stricter energy and emission limits. Innovations like anode surface coating technology reduce carbon electrode consumption and emissions, while new roasting technologies for red mud were analyzed for energy efficiency and environmental impact.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum-air long-duration generation technology selected by Net Zero Innovation Hub for Data Centers</title><link>https://www.netzerodatacenters.com/aluminum-air-long-duration-generation-technology-selected-by-net-zero-innovation-hub-for-data-centers-for-groundbreaking-clean-backup-energy-initiative-in-data-centers</link><description>Phinergy's aluminum-air backup energy solution was selected by the Net Zero Innovation Hub from over 70 proposals to scale to megawatt levels for data centers. This technology aims to replace diesel backup generators, supporting the transition to net-zero operations in digital infrastructure.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcast Company Advances the Future of Precision Aluminum Casting</title><link>https://www.digitaljournal.com/pr/news/prodigy-press-wire/alcast-company-advances-future-precision-153390634.html</link><description>Alcast Company integrates environmentally conscious practices in precision aluminum casting to minimize waste and maximize material efficiency. The company offers comprehensive services including machining and finishing, supporting sustainable production aligned with modern standards.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper price nears record on trade deal boost, supply woes</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-nears-record-on-trade-deal-boost-supply-woes/</link><description>Copper prices surged toward a record as optimism grows over an imminent US-China trade deal, boosting demand outlook amid supply disruptions at major mines in Congo, Chile, and Indonesia. The International Copper Study Group cut its 2025 mine supply forecast due to these disruptions, while demand is expected to rise significantly by 2050 driven by energy transition needs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises as Risk Appetite Improves</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/494267</link><description>Copper futures climbed above $5 per pound, reaching the highest level since July 2025, supported by easing US-China trade tensions and expectations of US Federal Reserve rate cuts. Supply disruptions at major mines and increased Chinese smelter shipments also influenced the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price nears record on trade deal boost, supply woes</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-nears-record-on-trade-deal-boost-supply-woes/</link><description>Copper prices surged toward a record as optimism over a potential US-China trade deal and ongoing supply disruptions at major mines drove the rally. The International Copper Study Group has cut its 2025 mine supply growth forecast to 1.4% due to recent incidents at key mines in Congo, Chile, and Indonesia, raising concerns about meeting future demand amid the global energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper to hold gains in 2026 as mine disruptions fuel deficit</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/metals-base-poll-two/</link><description>Analysts have raised their 2026 copper price forecasts due to ongoing mine disruptions, with the LME cash copper contract expected to average $10,500 per metric ton. Recent incidents, including the suspension of operations at Indonesia's Grasberg mine, have shifted market expectations from a surplus to a deficit in 2025, though new mine ramps could eventually ease supply pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper to hold gains in 2026 as mine disruptions fuel deficit</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/metals-base-poll-two/</link><description>Analysts raised copper price forecasts for 2026 due to mine disruptions in Indonesia, Congo, and Chile causing supply concerns and market deficits. The article notes copper's price gains in 2025 and anticipates a tightening refined copper market, while also discussing new mine developments that may moderate prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The world's first electric car without metals or minerals is launched</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/10/27/the-worlds-first-electric-car-without-metals-or-minerals-is-launched-and-it-doesnt-work/</link><description>This article presents eNimon, the first electric car made without metals or minerals, highlighting the critical role of sustainable mining in meeting the material demands of green technologies. It underscores the challenges of mineral shortages for climate goals and features Sandvik's efforts to innovate sustainable mining practices.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Nornickel, Russia’s largest nickel producer, has maintained its 2025 nickel production forecast at 196,000–204,000 metric tons despite a 4% year-to-date decline. The company reported an 18% quarterly increase in nickel output to 54,000 metric tons in Q3, attributed to higher processing of raw materials accumulated during Q2, but cited ongoing challenges from equipment replacement and seasonal disruptions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME Aluminium Cash Price Rises Amid Firm Demand and Tightening Inventories</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-price-rises-to-2-878-5-t-on-october-27-as-stocks-dip-to-469-275t-115973</link><description>The LME aluminium cash price increased to $2,878.5 per tonne on October 27, supported by steady demand and a drop in exchange stocks. The 3-month bid price rose to $2,876.50 per tonne. Inventories fell by 3,850 tonnes to 469,275 tonnes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-Year High Amid Supply Tightness</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices have reached a three-year high due to increasingly tight supply conditions. Major consumers are concerned about near-term tightness in physical markets, partly due to China's aluminum output cap. Aluminum futures rose to $2,815 per tonne in October.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Dips on Oct 28</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103590099/SMM-Flash:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-on-Oct-28</link><description>Secondary aluminum alloy ingot inventories have declined, with prices expected to remain firm in the short term due to strong cost support and a tight supply-demand balance. The market outlook suggests continued price resilience for ADC12 aluminum alloy ingots.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Australia's largest aluminum smelter could close, says Rio Tinto</title><link>https://english.news.cn/asiapacific/20251028/8bce499c1acf41f3ab35ec946d82483d/c.html</link><description>Rio Tinto announced that Australia's largest aluminum smelter, Tomago, may shut down in 2028 due to rising electricity costs, with power making up over 40% of operating expenses. The company has begun consultations with employees, as both coal and renewable energy options are expected to become unaffordable after the current power contract expires.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto flags uncertain future at Australia’s largest aluminum smelter</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/rio-tinto-contemplates-ceasing-tomago-aluminum-operations/</link><description>Rio Tinto warned that the Tomago smelter, Australia's largest, faces closure after 2028 as it struggles to secure commercially viable power contracts. The smelter, a major power user in New South Wales, is emblematic of challenges facing energy-intensive industries amid Australia's transition to renewables.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tomago Aluminium Faces Closure Due to Rising Energy Costs</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/tomago-aluminium-closure-energy-2025-opportunities/</link><description>Tomago Aluminium in Australia is facing potential closure from rising energy costs. The article details technological innovations such as prebaked anode technology, advanced process controls, and inert anode research that could reduce energy consumption by up to 20%, though significant investment is required to implement these solutions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Extends Gains on Proposal to Constrain China's Steel Supply</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/iron-ore-extends-gains-on-new-proposal-aiming-to-constrain-chinas-steel-supply-158471/</link><description>Iron ore prices have increased due to a new proposal aimed at limiting China's steel supply. This development could impact global steel production and prices. The proposal's effects on the steel market are being closely monitored.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nigeria's Steel Development Transformation</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/nigeria-steel-development-transformation-2025/</link><description>Nigeria aims to transform its steel sector with ambitious production targets, including achieving 10 million tonnes of annual liquid steel production by 2030. This involves significant investment in infrastructure and utilizing local iron ore reserves to reduce import dependency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metso to Supply Advanced Iron Ore Sintering Plant to India</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/iron-ore-sintering-technology-2025-steel-production/</link><description>Metso is delivering an advanced iron ore sintering plant to India, integrating emission-optimized sintering technology to enhance sustainability and production efficiency. This technology reduces CO2 emissions by over 54,000 tonnes annually and optimizes fuel consumption. The plant will contribute to regional economic growth and diversification.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Omani Green Iron to Revive British Steel Industry</title><link>https://omanet.om/en/news/economy/omani-green-iron-revives-british-steel/</link><description>Meranti Green Steel plans to produce low-carbon Hot Briquetted Iron (HBI) in Oman using green hydrogen and natural gas. This will help the UK transition away from outdated blast furnaces and secure a reliable supply chain for clean iron, aligning with global trends towards low-carbon steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Utility and Seongnam City Sign H2Gen Hydrogen Demonstration and Certification Project</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/10/28/utility-and-seongnam-city-sign-h2gen-hydrogen-demonstration-and-certification-project/</link><description>Utility and Seongnam City have partnered on a hydrogen demonstration project using H2Gen technology, which produces low-carbon hydrogen from industrial off-gases. This project aims to decarbonize industrial sectors in Korea, starting with heavy mobility.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Argentina's Mining Sector Receives US Investment, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103590021/Argentinas-Mining-Sector-Receives-US-Investment-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, closing slightly higher at $11,000.5/mt amid trading volume of 25,000 lots. Argentina received about $20 billion in US support to promote mining projects including copper, aiming to boost foreign investment and infrastructure, though political and economic stability remain critical for sustained recovery.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Nears Record High on Trade Deal Hopes</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/28/copper-nears-record-high-on-trade-deal-hopes/</link><description>Copper prices surged close to record highs driven by optimism over a US-China trade agreement and supply disruptions at major mines worldwide. The metal has gained 25% this year, recovering from previous trade tension impacts, with demand expected to rise sharply due to electrification and energy transition needs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Oil Prices Stabilize, Copper Prices Rise, Gold Falls Below $4,000</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/63879177/commodities-overview-oil-prices-stabilize-copper-prices-rise-gold-falls</link><description>LME copper futures rose 0.61% to settle at $11,029 per ton, nearing historical highs due to ongoing supply disruptions at major mines. The rally is supported by supply constraints and strong demand outlook amid global energy transition efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper hits 17-month peak on US-China trade deal optimism</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-17-month-peak-on-us-china-trade-deal-optimism/</link><description>Copper prices reached a 17-month peak driven by optimism about a US-China trade deal, reflecting improved market sentiment and supply concerns. The metal's price strength is linked to expectations of increased demand and constrained supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices edge higher as US-China trade optimism lingers</title><link>https://www.klsescreener.com/v2/news/view/1610571/copper-prices-edge-higher-as-us-china-trade-optimism-lingers</link><description>Copper prices on the Shanghai Futures Exchange rose slightly by 0.18% to 88,100 yuan per metric ton, supported by ongoing optimism about a US-China trade agreement and supply disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Reach 16-Month High: Effects of the Trade Agreement</title><link>https://www.yatirimmasasi.com/en/haberler/bakir-fiyatlari-16-ayin-zirvesine-ulasti-ticaret-anlasmasinin-etkileri</link><description>Copper prices hit a 16-month high fueled by optimism surrounding the US-China trade agreement, which also positively impacted other metals. The trade deal outlook is a key driver behind the recent price surge.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Argentina's Mining Sector Receives US Investment, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103590021/Argentinas-Mining-Sector-Receives-US-Investment-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Argentina received about $20 billion in US support to promote mining projects in lithium, copper, and energy, aiming to boost foreign exchange reserves and attract more investment. Meanwhile, LME copper prices opened higher, fluctuated, and closed up 0.49%, reflecting ongoing market volatility and investor interest in copper amid global supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Nears Record High on Trade Deal Hopes</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/28/copper-nears-record-high-on-trade-deal-hopes/</link><description>Copper prices are approaching record highs, buoyed by optimism over a potential US-China trade deal and persistent supply disruptions at major mines in Chile, Congo, and Indonesia. The metal has gained 25% this year, with investors focused on the delicate balance between rising demand for electrification and constrained production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Harmony Gold Acquires MAC Copper for $1.01 Billion Deal</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/gold-miners-pivot-copper-2025/</link><description>Harmony Gold has acquired MAC Copper for $1.01 billion, reflecting a strategic shift by gold miners to expand into copper production amid surging demand for electrification metals. The move highlights the industry's response to projections that copper demand will rise 70% by 2040, driven by renewable energy and electric vehicle adoption.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>A Copper Mine In The Desert Could Recast Pakistan's Future – OpEd</title><link>https://www.eurasiareview.com/28102025-a-copper-mine-in-the-desert-could-recast-pakistans-future-oped/</link><description>The Reko Diq copper and gold project in Pakistan, one of the world's largest untapped mineral deposits, is moving forward again this month. The development could significantly impact Pakistan's economy and global copper supply, though the article focuses more on geopolitical and economic implications than current production or capacity details.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices experienced a significant decline on October 28 while nickel inventory reached a new record high</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103591204/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-decline-on-October-28-while-nickel-inventory-reached-a-new-record-high</link><description>Spot nickel prices in China fell sharply on October 28, with SMM #1 refined nickel trading at 120,700–123,600 yuan/mt, down 900 yuan/mt from the previous day, as inventories hit a record high, signaling continued weak demand and ample supply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Antam 9-month profit surges 197% on strong gold and nickel sales</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/antam-9-month-profit-surges-197-on-strong-gold-and-nickel-sales</link><description>Indonesian miner Antam reported a 197% jump in net profit for the first nine months of 2025, driven by robust sales of gold, nickel, and bauxite, alongside cost management and downstreaming efforts, despite broader nickel market weakness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Reports Strong September Quarter with Increased EBITDA</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/28/nickel-industries-reports-strong-september-quarter-with-increased-ebitda/</link><description>Nickel Industries announced a strong September quarter, with adjusted EBITDA up significantly due to lower cash costs and higher sales, though mine sales were impacted by quota delays; the company also highlighted progress on new projects and ESG achievements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Reports Strong September Quarter with Increased EBITDA</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/28/nickel-industries-reports-strong-september-quarter-with-increased-ebitda/</link><description>Nickel Industries announced robust Q3 2025 results, with adjusted EBITDA rising to US$87 million, driven by strong performance in both RKEF and HPAL operations. The company highlighted cost reductions, increased sales, and progress on new projects, though mine sales were impacted by quota delays. Nickel Industries also emphasized its safety record and recent debt refinancing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Q3 EBITDA rises on strong RKEF, HPAL performance</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-q3-ebitda-rises-on-strong-rkef-hpal-performance</link><description>Australia-listed Nickel Industries Ltd reported another solid quarterly performance, with EBITDA growth supported by strong RKEF and HPAL operations. Details are behind a paywall, but the headline confirms continued operational strength in Indonesian nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne, located in Aosta, has entered a new period in steel production with a green hydrogen facility</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/haber/cogne-located-in-aosta-has-entered-a-new-period-in-steel-production-with-a-green-hydrogen-facility/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started using green hydrogen produced via electrolysis to replace fossil natural gas in its heat treatment processes, marking a significant step toward climate-neutral steel production. The company also supplies high-performance stainless steels for hydrogen infrastructure, supporting the broader energy transition.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris signs agreement with Axpo for green energy supply to Dalmine plant</title><link>https://news.mesteel.com/tenaris-signs-agreement-with-axpo-for-green-energy-supply-to-dalmine-plant/</link><description>Tenaris signed a Power Purchase Agreement with Axpo Italia to supply green energy to its Dalmine seamless steel tube factory. This agreement supports Tenaris's commitment to renewable energy sources.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World's top cable maker sees US copper tariff as opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Prysmian, the world's largest cable maker, views the proposed US copper tariff as an opportunity. The company believes it can benefit from the tariff due to its vertically integrated copper operation in the U.S. This includes sourcing raw copper from a mine in Arizona and operating a copper rod mill in Texas.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium giant urged to back Hunter workers before shutdown</title><link>https://newcastleweekly.com.au/aluminium-giant-urged-to-back-hunter-workers-before-shutdown/</link><description>Australia's largest aluminium smelter is facing a potential closure, prompting calls for the company to support its workforce, which has had a 40-year history with the facility. The shutdown reflects challenges in the aluminum production sector, including operational and market pressures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Anglo American lifts copper output amid portfolio shake-up</title><link>https://iol.co.za/business-report/companies/2025-10-28-anglo-american-lifts-copper-output-amid-portfolio-shake-up/</link><description>Anglo American reported steady copper production and improved operational performance despite a temporary dip at its Collahuasi mine. The company is managing operational challenges while maintaining output levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anglo American Faces 9% Copper Production Decline in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/anglo-american-copper-production-challenges-2025/</link><description>Anglo American experienced a 9% decline in copper production during the first nine months of 2025, with output falling to 526,000 tonnes. Operational challenges earlier in the year have been addressed, but sustained improvement remains uncertain. The company faces risks including equipment failures, geopolitical factors, and integration complexities following the Teck Resources merger.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali will benefit from enhanced energy performance and reduced environmental impact</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali signed a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA in December 2024 to enhance energy performance and reduce environmental impact in its production. The agreement supports regional decarbonisation targets and stabilizes energy sale prices, contributing to the competitiveness of the local steel sector and broader green industry conversion.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of producing green hydrogen at its plant in Aosta, Italy, using a 1.008 MW Anion Exchange Membrane electrolyzer. The project aims to reduce carbon emissions by powering one of its 70 furnaces entirely with green hydrogen, supported by €7.9 million funding from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has commenced operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, northern Italy, marking a significant step in its efforts to decarbonize steel production through renewable energy technologies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory Drops in Two Regions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103592374/Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Drops-by-2000-mt-on-Oct-29-2025:-SMM</link><description>The inventory of aluminum billet in two domestic regions decreased by 2,000 mt on October 29, 2025. This drop reflects ongoing trends in aluminum prices and inventory levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa Corporation Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://news.alcoa.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/Alcoa-Corporation-Reports-Third-Quarter-2025-Results/default.aspx</link><description>Alcoa reported a 4 percent sequential increase in alumina production to 2.5 million metric tons in Q3 2025, driven primarily by higher output. The company also announced plans to shut its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia due to deteriorating bauxite ore grades, impacting future production capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>RUSAL Deploys AI-Powered Machine Hearing and Vision Technologies to Enhance Aluminium Production Efficiency</title><link>https://thecsruniverse.com/articles/rusal-deploys-ai-powered-machine-hearing-and-vision-technologies-to-enhance-aluminium-production-efficiency</link><description>RUSAL has implemented AI-powered machine hearing and vision technologies to improve aluminum production efficiency. This technological advancement is part of the company's efforts to optimize operations and reduce costs in a competitive market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>From Refinery Waste to Useful Materials and Green Fuel: New Research Could Revolutionize the Global Aluminum Industry</title><link>https://educationnewscanada.com/article/education/level/university/1/1167056/from-refinery-waste-to-useful-materials-and-green-fuel-new-research-could-revolutionize-the-global-aluminum-industry.html</link><description>New research from the University of New Brunswick could transform the aluminum industry by making smelting more efficient and sustainable. It involves turning refinery waste into green fuel and useful materials, reducing landfill waste and supporting a sustainable future. The research aims to create a closed-loop, low-energy aluminum digestion process.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>RUSAL Deploys AI-Powered Machine Hearing and Vision Technologies to Enhance Aluminium Production Efficiency</title><link>https://thecsruniverse.com/articles/rusal-deploys-ai-powered-machine-hearing-and-vision-technologies-to-enhance-aluminium-production-efficiency</link><description>RUSAL, a major aluminum producer, has implemented AI-powered machine hearing and vision technologies to improve production efficiency. This innovation aims to enhance operational performance and sustainability in aluminum production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Mill Price Adjustment</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103012401/Anhui-Changjiang-Steel-Raises-Guided-Prices-for-Building-Materials-on-October-29th</link><description>Anhui Changjiang Steel has raised its guided prices for building materials, including rebar, coiled rebar, and high-speed wire, by 20 units. This adjustment reflects recent market dynamics and pricing strategies in the steel sector. The move could influence broader steel market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hot Rolled Coil Futures See Steady Rise</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/m/page/commodity-news-detail/commodity-news-detail-27489.html</link><description>Hot rolled coil futures experienced a steady rise last week, which provided some boost to the spot market sentiment. This trend could indicate improving market conditions for steel products. However, broader market trends remain mixed.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Algoma Steel Group Inc. to Announce 2025 Third Quarter Results</title><link>https://m.fastbull.com/news-detail/press-release-algoma-steel-group-inc-to-announce-news_7200_0_2025_4_34523_3</link><description>Algoma Steel Group Inc. is set to announce its third-quarter results for 2025. This announcement could provide insights into the company's performance and the overall steel market conditions. The results may influence investor sentiment and market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Price Forecast Revised Upward</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/29/iron-ore-price-forecast-revised-upward/</link><description>Goldman Sachs has revised its iron ore price forecast upward for 2026 due to a tighter market and supportive macroeconomic factors. However, the firm maintains a bearish outlook for the long term, expecting prices to decline by Q4 2026. China's steel sector is facing oversupply challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rare-Earth Steel Production Trends and Applications</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/rare-earth-steel-production-2025-trends-applications/</link><description>The article discusses advancements in rare-earth steel production, focusing on sustainable production methods and expanding applications in sectors like aerospace and automotive. These advancements are expected to support decarbonization efforts and infrastructure modernization.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>304 Stainless Steel Bolt Market Size Report 2025</title><link>https://www.openpr.com/news/4243694/304-stainless-steel-bolt-market-size-report-2025</link><description>The global 304 Stainless Steel Bolt market is projected to grow significantly, driven by industrial development and equipment modernization. The market size is expected to increase from $448 million in 2024 to $739 million by 2031. The report analyzes market trends and competitive structures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rare-Earth Steel Production: Guide to REE-Enhanced Alloys</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/rare-earth-steel-production-2025-trends-applications/</link><description>This article discusses advanced rare-earth steel production methods emphasizing sustainability through resource efficiency, reduced waste, and recycling programs. It highlights technological advancements such as AI-driven quality control and hydrogen materials research supporting decarbonisation in transport and industrial sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rare-Earth Steel Revolution: Advanced Alloys Transform</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/rare-earth-steel-technology-2025/</link><description>The article covers environmental sustainability in rare-earth steel production, focusing on green chemistry, biotechnology, hydrogen-based metallurgy, and circular economy approaches like recycling and urban mining. It details efforts to reduce carbon emissions and improve resource utilization in steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Steady Amid Trade Deal Anticipation</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/29/copper-prices-steady-amid-trade-deal-anticipation/</link><description>Copper prices have stabilized near record highs as markets await confirmation of a U.S.-China trade agreement. The metal is supported by tightening supply conditions and a more optimistic demand forecast. However, details of the trade deal remain vague, contributing to trader caution.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Struggles for Clear Direction as Fed Decision, Trump-Xi Meeting Loom</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3WA08X:0-copper-struggles-for-clear-direction-as-fed-decision-trump-xi-meeting-loom/</link><description>Copper prices were little changed as investors awaited the Federal Reserve's rate decision and a potential meeting between U.S. President Donald Trump and Chinese leader Xi Jinping. The metal has been supported by supply-side issues and a brighter demand outlook in Europe.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>U.S. Government Shutdown Continues, Overnight Copper Prices First Fell Then Rose</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper prices initially fell but then rose overnight, closing higher on both the London Metal Exchange and the Shanghai Futures Exchange. The market saw improved procurement sentiment despite ongoing price pressure from buyers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Quantum Minerals Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.first-quantum.com/news/first-quantum-minerals-reports-third-quarter-2025-results/</link><description>Kansanshi mine reported copper production of 46,881 tonnes in Q3 2025, up by 6,778 tonnes from the previous quarter due to increased mill throughput from the Kansanshi S3 Expansion project. Sentinel mine produced 51,336 tonnes, an increase of 8,228 tonnes quarter-over-quarter, driven by improved ore fragmentation and crusher performance. Copper production guidance for 2025 is narrowed to 175,000 – 185,000 tonnes with expectations of higher production in Q4 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Steady Amid Trade Deal Anticipation</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/29/copper-prices-steady-amid-trade-deal-anticipation/</link><description>Copper prices remain stable near record highs as markets await a US-China trade agreement. Anglo American announced that production at its Collahuasi copper mine in Chile is expected to fall below previous forecasts for 2026, revising output from 470,000 tonnes to between 380,000 and 410,000 tonnes. This downgrade adds to already tight supply conditions, supporting elevated copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Copper Demand Projected to Outpace Supply by Over 500,000 Tonnes In 2025, Driving Upward Price Pressure</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-copper-demand-projected-to-outpace-supply-by-over-500-000-tonnes-in-2025--driving-upward-price-pressure-302563846.html</link><description>Copper demand continues to rise due to its critical role in infrastructure, agriculture, renewable energy, and electrification. Supply constraints, geopolitical challenges, and the need for resource resilience are driving copper prices higher. The metal is essential for smart farming, energy transmission, and electric vehicles, underscoring the importance of sustainable and innovative copper technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>A Fireside Conversation with BHP Americas President Brandon Craig</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/whats-behind-copper-hype-fireside-conversation-bhp-americas-president-brandon-craig</link><description>This event discusses copper's critical role in the modern economy and the challenges of tightening supply, declining ore grades, and geopolitical risks. It highlights the importance of innovation and investment to secure copper supply chains and maintain technological and economic leadership, especially in the U.S. and allied countries.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fluctuated at lows on October 29 as the US government shutdown is expected to continue</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103593505/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fluctuated-at-lows-on-October-29-as-the-US-government-shutdown-is-expected-to-continue</link><description>On October 29, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 120,400 and 123,400 yuan/mt, averaging 121,900 yuan/mt, which was down 250 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. The price fluctuation occurred amid expectations that the US government shutdown would continue, impacting market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel stabilizes amid US-China trade uncertainty</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-stabilizes-amid-us-china-trade-uncertainty-47588</link><description>Nickel prices remained largely unchanged amid ongoing uncertainty in US-China trade relations. Goldman Sachs forecasted a 6% decline in nickel prices to $14,500 per metric ton by December 2026, citing the need for Indonesian producer margins to shrink to curb supply growth and address the market surplus.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On October 29, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103592974/</link><description>The LME nickel price settled at $15,320 per metric ton on Friday, marking a 1.39% week-over-week increase. Meanwhile, the most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 122,150 yuan/mt, also showing gains, reflecting a positive short-term trend in nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Quantum Minerals Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.first-quantum.com/news/first-quantum-minerals-reports-third-quarter-2025-results/</link><description>First Quantum Minerals reported a 44% increase in nickel production in Q3 2025, reaching 5,767 tonnes due to higher throughput and improved recoveries. The company also lowered nickel unit cost guidance reflecting operational performance, indicating improved efficiency in nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Intermediate Product Market Outlook for 2026</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103589711/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-Intermediate-Product-Market-Outlook-for-2026</link><description>Indonesia's nickel production is expected to reach about 680 kt in metal content in 2026, up over 45% year-over-year, driven by new project ramp-ups and capacity expansions. The Indonesian government’s control of ore prices and quota releases will increase costs, while demand growth is limited due to shifts in electric vehicle policies and battery material market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel mining threatens Raja Ampat ecosystems, communities</title><link>https://news.mongabay.com/2025/10/nickel-mining-threatens-raja-ampat-ecosystems-communities-conservation-report/</link><description>An environmental report highlights the threat expanding nickel mining poses to Raja Ampat's coral reefs, forests, and Indigenous communities. Despite environmental concerns, the government maintained Gag Nikel’s mining permit due to compliance with environmental standards. Global automakers like Tesla and Volkswagen are linked to this supply chain through nickel supply agreements with Indonesian processors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada G7 Critical Minerals Supply Deals Secure Chains</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-partnerships-g72025/</link><description>Canada is a key player in G7 critical minerals strategy, ranking 5th globally in nickel production with 170,000-180,000 tonnes annually, mainly from the Sudbury basin. While Canada has strong nickel production, it faces processing gaps, exporting most cobalt concentrates for refining abroad. Government initiatives aim to boost domestic processing capacity for battery-grade materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low Amid Oversupply</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to $15,226 per tonne on October 29, 2025, pressured by oversupply from Indonesia's expanded nickel sector. Indonesia's nickel mining quotas were reduced by 120 million tons this year, cutting global supply by 35%, but markets remain oversupplied with LME nickel stockpiles rising to over 250,000 tonnes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada G7 Critical Minerals Supply Deals Secure Chains</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-partnerships-g72025/</link><description>Canada is enhancing its critical minerals supply chains through strategic partnerships with G7 countries. These partnerships focus on integrated manufacturing networks and advanced processing technologies to optimize material yields and reduce environmental impact. The initiative aims to secure premium products and competitive advantages in the critical minerals market.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>