<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:15:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Steel Meets Innovation: Emerging Technologies Reshaping the Sector</title><link>https://www.steel-technology.com/articles/steel-meets-innovation-emerging-technologies-reshaping-the-sector</link><description>This article discusses how advances in AI and green steel technologies are transforming the steel industry. It highlights the adoption of smart manufacturing and sustainable production methods to meet growing demand while reducing environmental impact.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Harmony Copper Mine Project Investment Approved, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103639429/Harmony-Copper-Mine-Project-Investment-Approved-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, closing up 0.47% at $10,832.5/mt amid tight supply of high-quality copper and easing geopolitical risks such as potential Russia-Ukraine peace talks. US retail sales data falling short of expectations strengthened market hopes for a Fed interest rate cut, supporting copper prices despite some easing in downstream demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.03 USD/Lbs on November 26, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures climbed above $5 per pound, reaching a near two-week high as investors positioned ahead of a key industry gathering in Shanghai. The global copper-processing sector has faced record low annual treatment and refining charges as metal-processing capacity in China outpaced mined production. Prices were supported by signs of tightening supply, with Chile's Codelco proposing record premiums for 2026 metal sales.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Barrick committed to Pakistan's Reko Diq copper project, says interim CEO</title><link>https://tribune.com.pk/story/2579095/barrick-committed-to-pakistans-reko-diq-copper-project-says-interim-ceo</link><description>Barrick Mining Corp reaffirmed its commitment to the Reko Diq copper mine in Pakistan, one of the world's largest undeveloped deposits. The $7 billion project is expected to produce up to 400,000 tons of copper yearly and is scheduled to start production by the end of 2028.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Doubleview Gold Corp. Achieves a Major Breakthrough in Scandium Recovery from Copper Porphyry Tailings</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/11/26/doubleview-gold-corp-achieves-a-major-breakthrough-in-scandium-recovery-from-copper-porphyry-tailings/</link><description>Doubleview Gold Corp achieved a global first in successfully recovering scandium from copper porphyry flotation tailings with 88% overall recovery to high-purity scandium oxide product. The breakthrough could enable scandium to become a high-margin bonus product alongside a potential world-class copper-gold-cobalt operation at the HAT project.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On November 26, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103640502/</link><description>On November 26, the SMM #1 refined nickel price rose further to an average of 119,850 yuan/mt, up 1,300 yuan/mt from the previous day, indicating continued short-term price recovery amid market fluctuations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price drops 3.7% on Nov 26</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-price-drops-37-on-nov-26/130389</link><description>The London Metal Exchange (LME) nickel price fell by 3.7% on November 26, closing at US$19,897 per ton. This decline reflects ongoing volatility in the nickel market despite recent rebounds in some regions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's Nickel Supply &amp; The Global Price Slump: What the Market Sell-Off Signals for Investors</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/indonesias-nickel-supply-the-global-price-slump-what-the-market-sell-off-signals-for-investors</link><description>Nickel prices have fallen to $14,550 per tonne, near a four-year low, due to Indonesia's refinery expansion flooding the market and causing oversupply. Despite Indonesia's planned quota cuts, market skepticism remains about their impact on tightening supply. LME inventories surged by 90,000 tonnes in 2025, with stainless steel demand weak but EV battery growth providing some long-term support.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Falls to 7-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures in the UK dropped to $14,550 per tonne in November 2025, the lowest since a four-year low in April, due to mounting oversupply largely driven by Indonesia's over-expansion of its nickel sector. Prices have fallen 2.99% over the past month and 6.56% year-over-year, reflecting ample output despite export restrictions implemented since 2020.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Waste constraints hit output at major Indonesia nickel plant</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/waste-constraints-hit-output-at-major-indonesia-nickel-plant</link><description>A major Chinese-owned nickel processing plant in Indonesia's key production hub has reduced output due to waste management constraints. This development adds complexity to the already oversupplied nickel market dominated by Indonesia's refinery expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FPX Nickel secures ECOLOGO certification for sustainable practices</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/fpx-nickel-secures-ecologo-certification-for-sustainable-practices/</link><description>FPX Nickel has achieved UL Solutions ECOLOGO certification, marking a significant milestone in sustainable mineral exploration. This certification reflects the company's commitment to transparency, accountability, and minimizing environmental impacts, making it the first Canadian company outside Quebec to earn this recognition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,871.65 per tonne on November 26, 2025, up 2.12% from the previous day, rebounding from a recent four-week low. Despite a slight monthly decline, prices remain nearly 10% higher than a year ago, supported by macroeconomic tailwinds and stimulus signals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME Aluminium Cash Offer Jumps 1.27% to $2,822.50/t as Opening Stocks Fall</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-jumps-1-27-to-2-822-50-t-as-opening-stocks-fall-0-37-116348</link><description>LME aluminium prices rose to $2,822.50 per tonne on November 26, 2025, as exchange stocks declined by 0.37%. The increase reflects tightening supply conditions and sustained market demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Premium for Aluminum in the US Spot Market Has Hit a Record High</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103615477/</link><description>The US spot market aluminum premium reached a record high, with buyers paying $4,792 per tonne when the base price is $2,850. The surge is attributed to import tariffs and global supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Carney to announce new supports today for steel industry hammered by U.S. tariffs</title><link>https://ottawa.citynews.ca/2025/11/26/carney-to-announce-new-supports-today-for-steel-industry-hammered-by-u-s-tariffs/</link><description>Prime Minister Mark Carney announced new measures to support Canada's steel sector, including limiting foreign steel imports and cutting interprovincial rail freight rates by 50%. The government plans to reduce steel imports from non-free-trade agreement countries to 20% of 2024 levels and subsidize rail freight rate reductions to help the industry affected by U.S. tariffs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Canada unveils more measures to protect tariff-hit steel, lumber industries</title><link>https://infra.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/construction/canada-strengthens-measures-to-protect-steel-and-lumber-industries-amid-us-tariffs/125603230</link><description>Canada announced enhanced protections for its steel and lumber industries facing U.S. tariffs, including reducing steel import quotas from non-FTA countries to 20% of 2024 levels and imposing a 25% tariff on steel derivative products. The government will also work with railways to cut freight rates by 50% for interprovincial steel shipments and support local steel use in construction.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>'Fire away copper, build the bank': Revolver Resources</title><link>https://mining.com.au/fire-away-copper-build-the-bank-revolver-resources/</link><description>Revolver Resources is preparing for a final investment decision to develop copper production, expecting first copper cathode output in H2 2026. The company highlights strong copper demand growth and increased copper grades in its resource, positioning it well for production and cash flow generation next year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>All resolutions passed as the company advances copper expansion and strategic partnerships</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/urn:summary_document_transcript:quartr.com:2343472:0-hch-all-resolutions-passed-as-the-company-advances-copper-expansion-and-strategic-partnerships/</link><description>HCH announced the passing of all resolutions related to advancing its copper expansion projects and forming strategic partnerships, signaling progress in increasing copper production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>AI boom pushes copper toward a supply crunch, BNEF warns</title><link>https://www.mining.com/video/ai-boom-pushes-copper-toward-a-supply-crunch-bnef-warns/</link><description>The expansion of artificial intelligence data centres is increasing copper demand by an estimated 400,000 tonnes annually, with prices potentially reaching $13,500 per tonne by 2028. Energy transition projects and fragile mine supply are adding additional pressure to the copper market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SPC Nickel highlights Muskox's geological potential</title><link>https://mining.com.au/spc-nickel-highlights-muskoxs-geological-potential/</link><description>SPC Nickel has released assay results from its 2025 exploration program at the Muskox Project in Nunavut, Canada, revealing high-grade copper-nickel-platinum group mineralization and significant exploration potential. The results reinforce Muskox as a leading exploration opportunity with the potential for multiple deposits.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>6K Additive Secures Approval for $27.4 Million EXIM Loan to assist with Critical Minerals Expansion in Pennsylvania</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/11/26/6k-additive-secures-approval-for-27-4-million-exim-loan-to-assist-with-critical-minerals-expansion-in-pennsylvania-with-the-department-of-war/</link><description>6K Additive has secured a $27.4 million EXIM loan to expand its powder capacity in Pennsylvania, including nickel powders for additive manufacturing. The expansion will increase production capacity and support growing demand for critical minerals in defense and advanced manufacturing sectors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, northern Italy. This initiative aligns with the company's commitment to sustainability and reducing carbon emissions in steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EC approves Mannesmann Stainless Pipes' acquisition by Cogne</title><link>https://www.stainless.club/industry-news/read/ec-approves-cognes-acquisition-of-mannesmann-stainless-pipes.html</link><description>The European Commission has approved Cogne Acciai Speciali's acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Pipes, enabling Cogne to gain control over MST and its subsidiaries across Europe and the U.S. The deal, valued at EUR 135 million, strengthens Cogne's position in the stainless steel tube market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hydro to idle European extrusions facilities</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/hydro-aluminum-production-recycling-extrusions-europe-plant-closings-2026/</link><description>Norway-based Norsk Hydro announced the closure of five European extrusion plants in the United Kingdom, Germany, Italy, and the Netherlands to optimize its extrusion footprint in Europe. The closures will affect 730 employees and are scheduled for 2026, with the company citing the need for decisive action to strengthen long-term competitiveness in the European market.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>CISA mills' daily crude steel output up 0.9 percent in mid-November 2025, stocks also up</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cisa-mills-daily-crude-steel-output-up-09-percent-in-mid-november-2025-stocks-also-up-1421501.htm</link><description>China Iron and Steel Association reported a 0.9% increase in average daily crude steel output of large and medium-sized steel enterprises in mid-November compared to early November. Finished steel inventories also rose by 0.8% as of November 20, reflecting a moderate build-up in stock levels.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>CISA Mills' Daily Crude Steel Output Up 0.9 Percent in Mid-November 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cisa-mills-daily-crude-steel-output-up-09-percent-in-mid-november-2025-stocks-also-up-1421501.htm</link><description>The China Iron and Steel Association reported that average daily crude steel output of large and medium-sized steel enterprises totaled 1.943 million mt in mid-November, up 0.9% compared to early November. Inventory levels also increased, with finished steel inventories reaching 15.61 million mt as of November 20.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>According to SMM statistics, the weekly aluminum ingot outflow was 143200 tons last week</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/102493865/</link><description>Weekly aluminum ingot outflow reached 143,200 tons, representing an increase of 18,500 tons compared to the previous week. This data reflects current market activity in aluminum production and distribution.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Canada to add new tariffs to US steel, curb foreign imports</title><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/canada-to-add-new-tariffs-to-us-steel-curb-foreign-imports-13698384.html</link><description>Canada introduced a new 25% tariff on steel derivative products imported from the U.S. as part of a broader strategy to protect its steel industry. This marks the first time new import taxes on U.S. products have been added since most retaliatory tariffs were dropped in September, aiming to curb foreign imports and support domestic producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Govt Urged to Act on Surge in Cheap Imported Steel</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/govt-urged-to-act-on-surge-in-cheap-imported-1578786/</link><description>The Australian steel industry has requested emergency trade relief measures to counter a surge in low-priced imported fabricated steelwork threatening local manufacturers. The Australian Steel Institute highlighted significant business closures and reduced capacity utilization due to competition from cheap imports, urging government intervention to preserve domestic steel production capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Prices Forecast to Ease</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/27/iron-ore-prices-forecast-to-ease/</link><description>Iron ore prices are expected to decline in 2026 due to increased supply from new projects and ongoing demand pressure from China. Despite low inventories supporting prices currently, factors such as steel production curbs and weak Chinese demand are forecasted to weigh on prices, with a long-term decline projected through 2034.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper breaks above $11,000 on increased likelihood of US rate cut</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-breaks-above-11000-on-increased-likelihood-of-us-rate-cut/</link><description>Copper prices rose to their highest level in almost a month, reaching $11,025 per metric ton on Wednesday. The rally was driven by increased expectations for a US Federal Reserve rate cut, with CME's FedWatch Tool showing over 84% probability of a 25 basis point cut in December.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Highland Copper Partial Project Equity Transfer Overnight LME Copper Surged Significantly</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103641780/Highland-Copper-Partial-Project-Equity-Transfer-Overnight-LME-Copper-Surged-Significantly-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper opened at $10,992.5/mt and touched a high of $11,009.5/mt in early trading on Thursday, November 27, 2025. The contract closed at $10,953/mt, up 1.11%, with trading volume at 22,000 lots.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mercuria's copper bull forecasts more price records next year</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/mercurias-copper-bull-forecasts-more-price-records-next-year/</link><description>A squeeze in global copper markets is expected to tighten again next year, pushing prices of concentrate and refined metal to new records. Market analysts forecast continued upward pressure on copper prices due to supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex copper premium here to stay, LME executive says</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/comex-copper-premium-here-to-stay-lme-executive-says-2025-11-27</link><description>An LME executive stated that the copper price premium on the US Comex exchange over the London Metal Exchange is likely to persist over the next 18 months. This premium reflects structural differences in the two markets.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>UBS raises copper outlook as mine disruptions deepen supply deficits</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/ubs-raises-copper-outlook-as-mine-disruptions-deepen-supply-deficits/</link><description>UBS lowered its refined copper production growth estimates to 1.2% for 2025 and 2.2% for 2026 due to declining ore grades and operational challenges at mines, signaling deeper supply deficits in the copper market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mitsubishi Materials to cut primary copper smelting volume by 30% to 40% by 2035</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/mitsubishi-materials-to-cut-primary-copper-smelting-volume-by-30-to-40-by-2035/</link><description>Japan's Mitsubishi Materials announced plans to reduce its primary copper smelting volume by 30% to 40% by 2035, reflecting strategic adjustments in copper production capacity over the next decade.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME nickel prices rise to 2-week high</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-prices-rise-to-2-week-high/156449</link><description>Despite recent losses and a market closure, LME nickel futures rebounded, closing at $15,285 per ton, up $185 from the previous session. The recovery comes amid ongoing volatility and oversupply concerns in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/nickel-price-update-q3-2025-review</link><description>Nickel prices remained volatile in the first half of 2025 but stabilized in Q3, with ongoing oversupply concerns continuing to weigh on the market. The article reviews recent trends and factors influencing nickel prices over the past quarter.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Unleashing sustainable nickel production for a net zero future</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/unleashing-sustainable-nickel-production-for-a-net-zero-future/34671/</link><description>This article explores how optimizing nickel production, particularly through High Pressure Acid Leaching (HPAL), can create a more sustainable battery industry with a lower carbon footprint. It highlights efforts in pollution prevention, biodiversity conservation, waste management, and stakeholder engagement to advance sustainable nickel production aligned with global net-zero goals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Genomines raises $45M to grow nickel from plants, not mines</title><link>https://www.agtechnavigator.com/Article/2025/10/07/genomines-raises-45m-to-grow-nickel-from-plants-not-mines/</link><description>French start-up Genomines secured $45 million in Series A funding to scale its innovative method of extracting nickel from plants instead of traditional mining. This approach promises faster, cheaper, and cleaner nickel production with higher purity and productivity, and the company is piloting projects with major automakers and battery manufacturers.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,833.25 USD/T on November 27, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices declined 1.34% to $2,833.25 per tonne on November 27, 2025, continuing a downward trend over the past month with a 2.29% decline. Despite recent weakness, aluminum remains 9.50% higher than a year ago, with prices rebounding from a near-one-month low of $2,790 reached on November 18th as macroeconomic tailwinds from Fed rate cut signals and Beijing stimulus measures lifted base metals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Three-Region Aluminum Ingot Inventory Falls to 441000 mt as of Nov 28</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103644074/SMM:-Three-Region-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Falls-to-441000-mt-as-of-Nov-28</link><description>Aluminum ingot inventory across three regions has declined to 441,000 mt. Secondary aluminum alloy prices are expected to fluctuate within a range in the short term, with price resilience remaining stable.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Top news on China steel and other commodity markets</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/top-news/all/</link><description>Retail inventories of major carbon steel items in China have declined recently but at a slower pace. The report also highlights steady iron ore prices and procurement trends, suggesting cautious market activity amid fluctuating demand and supply conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper prices rise after Nvidia's results, but the dollar is still strong</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/11/20/copper-prices-rise-after-nvidias-results-but-the-dollar-is-still-strong</link><description>Copper prices edged up following strong earnings from Nvidia, with the LME three-month copper price rising 0.3% to $10,784 per metric ton. However, a strong US dollar and weak demand from China, including a 22.1% annual drop in copper cathode imports, continue to weigh on the market. Analysts expect ongoing consolidation after recent price setbacks.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices dropped slightly on November 27, US extends some tariff exemptions for China</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103642823</link><description>Nickel prices slightly declined on November 27, with the SMM #1 refined nickel average price dropping to 119,000 yuan/mt, down 850 yuan/mt from the previous day. Futures on SHFE also fell by 0.35%-0.61%. Market sentiment was influenced by dovish signals from US Fed officials and positive China-US diplomatic communications, though long-term price pressure remains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Nickel 28 reports 34.33% rise in Q3 2025 nickel production</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103923-flash-nickel-28-reports-3433-rise-in-q3-2025-nickel-production</link><description>Nickel 28 announced a 34.33% year-on-year increase in nickel production at the Ramu nickel-cobalt project in Papua New Guinea for Q3 2025, producing 9,242 tonnes of nickel contained in mixed hydroxide precipitate (MHP). Cobalt production also rose to 887 tonnes. The project benefited from no unplanned outages or scheduled maintenance, with net cash costs at $3.07 per pound of nickel produced.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel 28 Releases Ramu Q3 2025 Operating Performance</title><link>https://www.nickel28.com/investors/news-releases/nickel-28-releases-ramu-q3-2025-operating-performance</link><description>Nickel 28 reported strong Q3 2025 results with 9,242 tonnes of contained nickel and 887 tonnes of cobalt produced in MHP, surpassing last year's figures. Nickel sales reached 9,880 tonnes, exceeding production and reducing inventory. CEO Craig Lennon highlighted uninterrupted production and expects continued strong sales into Q4 2025 despite a slight decrease in average nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Lifezone Metals Advances Kabanga Nickel Project Toward 2026 Final Investment Decision</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/lifezone-metals-advances-kabanga-nickel-project-toward-2026-final-investment-decision</link><description>Lifezone Metals is progressing the Kabanga Nickel Project with a targeted final investment decision (FID) in late 2026. The project holds about 50 million tons of reserves at 1.9-2% nickel grades and offers robust economics with a $1.6 billion NPV and 23.3% IRR. The project uses a hydrometallurgical process with renewable energy, aiming for sustainable nickel production aligned with tightening environmental regulations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Fastmarkets launches European aluminium scrap shredded old sheet taint tabor price assessment</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/fastmarkets-launches-european-aluminium-scrap-shredded-old-sheet-taint-tabor-price-assessment/</link><description>Fastmarkets launched a new price assessment for European aluminium scrap shredded old sheet on Friday, November 28, 2025, following a consultation period that began on October 29 and concluded on November 26. This development reflects ongoing efforts to establish standardized pricing mechanisms in the aluminum scrap market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Researchers make incredible breakthrough using material from old cars</title><link>https://www.thecooldown.com/green-tech/ridgealloy-recycled-aluminum-alloy-carbon-energy/</link><description>A new recycled aluminum alloy called RidgeAlloy has been developed to address the challenge of recycling aluminum from old cars. This alloy is tough and can be produced rapidly, reducing energy use by up to 95% compared to primary aluminum processing, thus significantly lowering environmental impact.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever debut carbon-free aluminium aerosol packaging</title><link>https://worldaerosols.com/news/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-debut-carbon-free-aluminium-aerosol-packaging/</link><description>Ahead of COP30, Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever launched an aerosol can made with 50% ELYSIS aluminium and 50% recycled content, eliminating direct greenhouse gas emissions through the ELYSIS process. This breakthrough could transform sustainable packaging in personal and home care sectors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>United States clean energy spending reaches a new high on EV surge, solar boom, and rising aluminium usage</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/united-states-clean-energy-spending-reaches-a-new-high-on-ev-surge-solar-boom-and-rising-aluminium-usage-116361</link><description>The surge in electric vehicle production in the US has increased demand for automotive-grade, low-carbon aluminium, which helps reduce emissions in EV parts. Manufacturers are raising recycled aluminium content to meet stricter emissions standards and consumer demand for sustainability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum-air long-duration generation technology selected by Net Zero Innovation Hub for Data Centers</title><link>https://www.netzerodatacenters.com/aluminum-air-long-duration-generation-technology-selected-by-net-zero-innovation-hub-for-data-centers-for-groundbreaking-clean-backup-energy-initiative-in-data-centers</link><description>Phinergy's aluminum-air backup energy technology was selected by the Net Zero Innovation Hub for Data Centers to accelerate clean backup energy adoption. This technology offers a scalable, clean alternative to diesel generators, supporting net-zero operations in data centers.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Low-Carbon Metal Premiums: Market Trends &amp; Price Evolution</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/low-carbon-metal-price-premiums-trends-2025/</link><description>Sustainability premiums for low-carbon metals like aluminum are rising due to corporate decarbonization commitments and innovations such as renewable energy integration and inert anode technology. These trends are driving demand for low-carbon aluminum in automotive, electronics, and construction sectors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Latest Update in the SMM Steel Billet Market</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Steel-Billet</link><description>Steel billet inventory in major stainless steel markets slightly increased by 0.64% week-on-week, indicating a limited supply-demand imbalance. Despite some recovery in stainless steel transactions, market sentiment remains weak with persistent destocking pressure and sluggish sales expected to limit steel price gains in December.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Daily Topic of China Bulk Commodity Data (November 28, 2025)</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28334.html</link><description>On November 27, 2025, steel commodities showed a month-on-month price decline among eight steel products, contributing to a broader trend of price decreases in the steel sector. The overall commodity price index remained stable but significantly below its cycle peak, indicating ongoing market pressure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fastmarkets amends Europe stainless steel scrap price assessments to domestic from import</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/fastmarkets-amends-europe-stainless-steel-scrap-price-assessments-to-domestic-from-import/</link><description>Fastmarkets changed its Europe stainless steel scrap price assessments from import to domestic delivery terms due to sporadic imports and more consistent domestic market liquidity. This adjustment aims to provide a more relevant pricing tool reflecting current market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Share Price Live Updates: JSW Steel's Final Trading Price</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/stock-liveblog/jsw-steel-stock-price-live-updates-28-nov-2025/liveblog/125627693.cms</link><description>JSW Steel's stock price showed a slight downturn with a -0.8% return for the week, indicating some negative market sentiment or pressure on steel sector equities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel prices in the fourth week of November 2025 - Arab Iron and Steel</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/38265/</link><description>Russian hot-rolled coil prices dropped by $15 to $430–445/ton FOB, while Chinese cold-rolled coil prices remained stable, reflecting regional variations in steel price trends during the fourth week of November.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Minister Sidhu reinforces commitment to Canada's steel industry</title><link>https://www.canada.ca/en/global-affairs/news/2025/11/minister-sidhu-reinforces-commitment-to-canadas-steel-industry.html</link><description>Canada's Minister of International Trade, Maninder Sidhu, will participate in an event highlighting the country's ongoing commitment to the steel industry, signaling government support and engagement with the sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel news and insights about steel market - steel prices - GMK Center</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Recent updates include a 3% year-on-year increase in global stainless steel production for January-September 2025, Spain's 5.4% production increase in the first half of 2025, and ArcelorMittal's temporary blast furnace shutdown in Poland due to import pressures. Other news covers price adjustments, production changes, and trade measures affecting steel markets worldwide.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SunSirs: Copper Prices Skyrocket by 20,000 RMB/Ton</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28328.html</link><description>Copper prices have surged by over 20,000 RMB per ton this year, reaching historic highs above $11,200 per ton on the LME and nearly 90,000 RMB per ton on the Shanghai Futures Exchange. This price boom supports increased processing of lower-grade copper ores. The rise is driven by demand from emerging industries and strong upstream production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Base Metal Prices Face Growth Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/28/base-metal-prices-face-growth-uncertainty/</link><description>TD Securities expects London-traded copper to maintain recent gains into 2026 following a record high in October. Aluminium and zinc prices show mixed outlooks, while nickel faces oversupply concerns. The forecast reflects cautious sentiment amid evolving economic and supply-demand factors in the base metals market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>BHP bets big on Chile's copper boom</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/11/28/bhp-bets-big-on-chiles-copper-boom/</link><description>BHP's Escondida mine increased copper output by 4% to 494,000 tonnes in FY26, driven by record throughput and improved recoveries. Copper demand is forecast to rise 70% between 2021 and 2050, positioning Chile as a key supplier. The ramp-up of new projects like the Full SaL project supports production growth amid strong market demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper breaks above USD11,000 on increased likelihood of US rate cut</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40394482/copper-breaks-above-usd11000-on-increased-likelihood-of-us-rate-cut</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rose 1.3% to $10,963 per metric ton amid growing expectations of a US Federal Reserve rate cut. The price surge reflects optimism about softer monetary policy supporting industrial metals demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Cascabel Copper-Gold Mine Is Expected to Commence Production in 2028</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103644055/The-Cascabel-Copper-Gold-Mine-Is-Expected-to-Commence-Production-in-2028-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>SolGold has accelerated development of its Cascabel copper-gold project in northern Ecuador, with preliminary engineering set to begin in 2026 and first production expected in 2028. The news comes amid fluctuating copper prices and shifting global supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP bets big on Chile's copper boom</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/11/28/bhp-bets-big-on-chiles-copper-boom/</link><description>BHP's Escondida mine in Chile started the 2025–26 financial year with a 4% increase in copper output, reaching 494,000 tonnes. The company is expanding production amid rising global demand and ongoing infrastructure developments.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper smelters idle as China slows</title><link>https://mining.com.au/copper-smelters-idle-as-china-slows/</link><description>Global copper smelting activity declined in October, with inactive capacity rising to 15.1% of world nameplate—the highest this year. China drove most of the decline, with inactivity jumping to 13.8%, while other regions saw modest improvements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's overcapacity crackdown reaches copper, but market impact unlikely</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/chinas-overcapacity-crackdown-reaches-copper-but-market-impact-unlikely-2025-11-28</link><description>China has shelved several planned copper smelters as part of its overcapacity crackdown, but the move is not expected to significantly impact the market. The government's actions are aimed at curbing excess industrial capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On November 28, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 117,000-122,000 yuan/mt, with an average price of 119,500 yuan/mt, up 500 yuan/mt from the previous day</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103644263/</link><description>Nickel prices rebounded slightly on November 28, with the SMM #1 refined nickel average price rising by 500 yuan/mt to 119,500 yuan/mt. This indicates a short-term recovery following the previous day's decline, reflecting ongoing market fluctuations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Base Metal Prices Face Growth Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/28/base-metal-prices-face-growth-uncertainty/</link><description>TD Securities forecasts nickel prices to plateau in 2026 amid global economic growth concerns and potential delays in US interest rate cuts. While Beijing’s stimulus measures may support demand, nickel faces oversupply worries. A modest price rebound is expected in 2027, reflecting cautious market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Base Metal Prices Face Growth Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/28/base-metal-prices-face-growth-uncertainty/</link><description>Financial firm TD Securities forecasts nickel prices to plateau in 2026 with a modest rebound expected in 2027. The outlook reflects concerns about oversupply and cautious market sentiment amid various economic and supply-demand factors affecting base metals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China's Nickel-Free EV Batteries Hit Indonesia's Nickel Plan</title><link>https://chinaglobalsouth.com/2025/11/28/chinas-nickel-free-ev-batteries-hit-indonesias-nickel-plan/</link><description>A new report from Energy Shift Institute highlights how China's development of nickel-free electric vehicle batteries is impacting Indonesia's nickel strategy, potentially affecting demand and market dynamics for nickel producers.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Low-Carbon Metal Premiums: Market Trends &amp; Price Evolution</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/low-carbon-metal-price-premiums-trends-2025/</link><description>The London Metal Exchange (LME) is advancing initiatives to establish low-carbon price premiums for nickel and other metals, incentivizing sustainable production. This market-based mechanism supports decarbonization by financially rewarding environmentally friendly production methods, driven by demand from automotive and battery manufacturing sectors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance after reporting third-quarter revenue and earnings above forecasts, driven by strong growth in Renewable Transmission and Power Grids segments. The company’s performance in North America and Europe, along with a stable high-voltage backlog, supports optimism for future growth, with analysts noting potential benefits from copper tariffs in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rose to 2,873.60 USD/T on November 28, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices increased to $2,873.60 per tonne on November 28, 2025, up 1.42% from the previous day. The rise was driven by macroeconomic tailwinds as key Fed officials signaled support for additional rate cuts and Beijing announced fresh stimulus measures. Over the past month, aluminum prices have fallen 0.38%, but remain 9.51% higher than a year ago.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price hits three-year high as US-China truce buoys outlook</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-hits-three-year-high-as-us-china-truce-buoys-outlook/</link><description>Aluminum futures on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.6% to settle at $2,902 per metric ton, reaching the highest level since May 2022. The rally is supported by tightening supply in China due to state-imposed production caps and an improving demand outlook as trade tensions ease between the US and China.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global alumina production in Oct up 4% on month, says Aluminium Institute</title><link>https://informistmedia.com/CommodityWire/39856/Alumina-Output-Global-alumina-production-in-Oct-up-4-37-on-month-says-Aluminium-Institute</link><description>Global alumina production rose nearly 4% month-on-month to 13.37 million tonnes in October, with China accounting for 62% of global output at 8.21 million tonnes. Production across regions showed growth, with Oceania up over 5%, Africa and Asia (excluding China) up nearly 4%, and global primary aluminium production up nearly 4% to 6.3 million tonnes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rod: Inventory Drawdown, Fees Bottoming Out; Cable Operating Rate Up</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646544/aluminum-rod-inventory-drawdown-fees-bottoming-out-cable-operating-rate-up-demand-weakness-persistent-smm-analysis</link><description>Domestic aluminum rod producers' inventory days decreased to 6.68 days as of November 28, 2025, indicating an inventory drawdown trend with eased supply-side pressure. Aluminum cable operating rate rose to 63%, continuing its moderate recovery trend, though demand weakness persists with year-end approaching and winter temperatures constraining project progress.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Rebounds to Highest in November</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China rose above CNY 3,100 per tonne, reaching the highest level so far in November as lower supply returned to buyers' attention. Crude steel output in China fell 12% annually in October, the lowest for the month since 2021, consistent with China's pledges to cap industries suffering from overcapacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.19 USD/Lbs on November 28, 2025, up 2.15% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices reached 5.19 USD per pound, marking a 2.15% increase from the previous day and a four-week high. The rise is attributed to record-high premiums offered by Chilean producer Codelco to US buyers and expectations of aggressive US Federal Reserve rate cuts, reinforcing a bullish market outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Month 2.37% Higher at $5.1855 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511285171/comex-copper-ends-the-month-237-higher-at-51855-data-talk</link><description>Front-month Comex Copper for December delivery closed at $5.1855 per pound, up 2.37% for the month and marking its fourth consecutive monthly gain. The price remains below its 2025 high but is up nearly 30% from the previous year, reflecting strong market momentum.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco offers US clients copper at record premiums above $500/t</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2025-11-28/codelco-offers-us-clients-copper-record-premiums-above-500t-over-lme</link><description>Chilean copper producer Codelco has offered US customers copper at record premiums exceeding $500 per metric ton, signaling a shift in supply priorities and reinforcing market expectations of a tightening copper market. This move is seen as a response to shifting global trade flows and robust demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Taseko Mines (TGB) Posts Mixed Q3 Performance with Increased Copper Production</title><link>https://stockstotrade.com/news/tasekominesltd-tgb-news-2025_11_28/</link><description>Taseko Mines reported increased copper production and revenue in Q3 2025 despite a slight decrease in adjusted EPS. Operational improvements, reduced costs, and successful equity financing have strengthened the company's financial position, with positive outlooks for production growth and efficiency in 2026 amid strong copper market conditions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's Jiangxi Copper Rejected by SolGold in $1 Billion Takeover Approach</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511284079/chinas-jiangxi-copper-rejected-by-solgold-in-1-billion-takeover-approach</link><description>SolGold's $1 billion takeover bid for China's Jiangxi Copper was rejected, indicating ongoing strategic positioning and consolidation attempts within the copper industry. This development reflects competitive dynamics in copper production and corporate control in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 14,822.63 USD/ton on November 28, down 0.12% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have declined by 3.78%, and are down 7.41% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel inches down ahead of Fed's decision</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-inches-down-ahead-of-feds-decision-47634</link><description>Nickel prices edged lower on November 28 as the US dollar strengthened and Goldman Sachs forecast a further decline to $14,500 per metric ton by December 2026. Market expectations for a Fed rate cut in December remain high.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Samsung's T7 Resurrected SSD Uses 100% Recycled Aluminum</title><link>https://www.techbuzz.ai/articles/samsung-s-t7-resurrected-ssd-uses-100-recycled-aluminum</link><description>Samsung has launched the T7 Resurrected portable SSD, the first in the storage industry to use 100% recycled aluminum sourced from Galaxy smartphone production scraps. The product eliminates the coloring process, showcasing the natural aluminum finish and reducing chemical use, while packaging is made from 100% recycled paper and soy ink. The SSD has already won the 2026 CES Innovation Award in the Sustainability &amp; Energy category.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Samsung Launches New SSD T7 Resurrected</title><link>https://news.samsung.com/global/samsung-launches-new-ssd-t7-resurrected</link><description>Samsung's new T7 Resurrected SSD features a body case made entirely from recycled aluminum generated during Galaxy smartphone production, promoting cross-division resource circulation. The manufacturing process avoids coloring, highlighting the natural luster of aluminum and minimizing chemical use, with packaging made from 100% recycled paper and soy ink. The product received the 2026 CES Innovation Award in the Sustainability &amp; Energy category.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Green Steelmaking Innovation: Tech &amp; Climate Impact 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/green-steel-technology-2025-industrial-decarbonisation/</link><description>Green steelmaking using hydrogen technology is revolutionizing manufacturing by cutting emissions by 85-95%. Innovations include electric arc furnace optimization, molten oxide electrolysis, and advanced material handling systems, supported by government investments such as Australia's $500 million Green Iron Investment Fund. Leading countries like those in Europe are advancing commercial-scale hydrogen-based steel production through initiatives like HYBRIT.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>How decarbonizing steel build a greener future</title><link>https://alj.com/en/spotlight-by-fady-jameel/steel-deal-how-could-decarbonizing-steel-help-build-a-greener-future/</link><description>Steel production is undergoing significant innovation to reduce carbon emissions, including electric arc furnaces using less fossil fuel and green hydrogen-based processes. The UAE's Masdar and EMSTEEL have launched a pilot project producing green steel with up to 95% CO₂ emission reduction. Government support and market education are key to overcoming the higher costs of green steel and driving demand for sustainable steel products.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Building a sustainable metals industry</title><link>https://steeltech.bilbaoexhibitioncentre.com/en/building-a-sustainable-metals-industry/</link><description>The steel industry is advancing sustainability through electrification, automation, and digitalization to reduce environmental impact. Events like STEEL TECH 2025 highlight innovations such as the world's first 100% green hydrogen ladle preheater and new electric arc furnace projects, demonstrating industry commitment to sustainable steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Canada Steel Industry Gets Boost, New Protective Measures</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/canada-steel-industry-gets-boost-new-protective-1580087/</link><description>Canada is investing over $100 million starting in 2025-2026 to support its steel industry through modernization, skills development, and protection against foreign steel dumping. Measures include enhanced border controls, ending tariff remissions on imported steel by January 2026, and initiatives to reduce freight costs for Canadian steel transport. The government also plans to implement a Buy Canadian Policy to prioritize domestic steel in large contracts.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Secretary of State Belanger highlights new measures to protect and transform Canada's steel industry</title><link>https://themalaysianreserve.com/2025/11/29/secretary-of-state-belanger-highlights-new-measures-to-protect-and-transform-canadas-steel-industry/</link><description>Secretary of State Belanger announced new measures aimed at protecting and transforming Canada's steel industry, focusing on strengthening domestic production and competitiveness amid global trade challenges. These efforts align with broader government strategies to build a resilient and sustainable steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>NTT DATA partners with Codelco on AI‑driven copper mining</title><link>https://news.outsourceaccelerator.com/ntt-data-partners-with-codelco-on-ai%E2%80%91driven-copper-mining/</link><description>NTT DATA has partnered with Codelco to implement AI-driven technologies in copper mining, aiming to enhance operational efficiency and sustainability. This collaboration represents a significant step in integrating advanced digital solutions to optimize copper extraction and processing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price rebounds on Nov 29</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/nickel-price-rebounds-on-nov-29/99539</link><description>On November 29, the three-month futures price of nickel on the London Metal Exchange surged by US$250/ton to US$11,055/ton, with the spot price also rising. This rebound comes amid ongoing volatility and fluctuating market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Analysis: Nickel giants under pressure</title><link>https://www.thejakartapost.com/opinion/2025/11/29/analysis-nickel-giants-under-pressure.html</link><description>Nickel futures prices have trended downward, reaching US$14,550 in November, one of the lowest levels since early 2021. Despite government efforts to cut mining quotas, oversupply persists, with LME inventories rising significantly.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>BUMA International posts weaker 9M25, stronger 3Q recovery</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/buma-international-posts-weaker-9m25-stronger-3q-recovery</link><description>BUMA International reported weaker financial results for the first nine months of 2025, but showed a stronger recovery in the third quarter. The article covers the company's performance in mining and coal operations, though specific nickel production details are not highlighted.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>TGEM Targets 3,200 Tons of Class 1 Nickel MHP Production in 2025 with Enhanced STAL Technology Capabilities</title><link>https://tgem.group/category/tgem-press-release/</link><description>Trinitan Green Energy Metals announced a strategic target to produce 3,200 tons of sustainable Class 1 nickel Mixed Hydroxide Precipitate (MHP) in 2025, leveraging enhanced STAL technology. This production ramp-up supports sustainable nickel supply for electric vehicle and high-tech industries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (November 24, 2025 - November 28, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-november-24-2025-a-november-28-2025-on-the-ce7d51dbda8ff122</link><description>Tenaris published its weekly report covering share buyback activities from November 24-28, 2025. As of November 28, 2025, the company held 41,950,073 ordinary shares in treasury equal to 3.91% of total issued share capital. The report details share purchases across multiple trading venues with weighted average prices around EUR 17.17-17.31.</description><category>general</category></item></channel></rss>