<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:17:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HRC Steel Hits Multi‑Month High as 2026 Begins</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>US hot‑rolled coil (HRC) steel prices rose to **around 940 USD/ton** on January 9, 2026, extending a rally that has lifted values more than 30% compared with the same period a year earlier.[2] Trading Economics highlights that HRC recently touched its highest level since April 2025, reflecting tighter supply and firmer demand in flat steel markets.[2]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. crude steel production recorded an increase on an annual basis in the week ending January 3, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/haber/us-crude-steel-production-recorded-an-increase-on-an-annual-basis-in-the-week-ending-january-3/</link><description>According to American Iron and Steel Institute (AISI) data, U.S. crude steel production reached 1,704,000 net tons in the week ending January 3, 2026, up 1.4% from 1,680,000 net tons in the same week a year earlier.[1] Capacity utilization was 74.4%, slightly below 75.6% a year ago, while production rose 0.5% from the previous week’s 1,695,000 net tons and regional output was led by the South with 759,000 net tons.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel falls from 19-month peak as metals rally pauses</title><link>https://news.az/news/nickel-falls-from-19-month-peak-as-metals-rally-pauses</link><description>Nickel prices eased after briefly touching a 19‑month high near $18,800 per ton, as the recent broad rally in base metals paused.[3] The earlier surge was driven by concerns over reduced output from Indonesia and strong investment flows into Chinese metals markets, but three‑month LME nickel was last quoted around $18,370 per ton alongside declines in copper, aluminum, zinc, and lead.[3]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel gluts to zinc deficits: LME shadow stocks tell the story</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/nickel-gluts-to-zinc-deficits-lme-shadow-stocks-tell-the-story/</link><description>LME shadow stock data show a pronounced contrast between nickel oversupply and zinc tightness, highlighting how off‑warrant inventories shape apparent market balance.[9] The article notes that three‑month nickel recently spiked to a 19‑month high of $18,800 per ton before retreating to $17,895, underscoring how supply‑risk headlines can trigger sharp but volatile price moves in an otherwise well‑supplied nickel market.[9]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Pressure for Indonesian quota U-turn is a risk for nickel price rally</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/pressure-for-indonesian-quota-u-turn-is-a-risk-for-nickel-price-rally/</link><description>Indonesia, which accounts for about 70% of global nickel production, has pushed nickel prices to 19‑month highs by planning cuts to mining quotas, but analysts warn there is strong industry pressure for the government to reverse course.[4] Many new Indonesian nickel projects are due to come onstream in the second half of the year, and producers may seek higher quotas later, which could lift output and cap further price gains.[4]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel price tumbles 4.12% as Indonesia's output remains unclear</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/60275/nickel-price-tumbles-4-12-as-indonesias-output-remains-unclear</link><description>Nickel prices on the London Metal Exchange fell more than 4% from their recent peak as uncertainty persisted over Indonesia’s 2026 production plans and output quotas.[8] Market participants are reassessing expectations for Indonesian supply, with ambiguity over approved mining volumes creating volatility in both price direction and capacity outlook.[8]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel – Price, news and Indonesian output cuts</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures recently hit around $18,500 per tonne, the highest in over two years, supported by concerns over supply from Indonesia after Jakarta proposed a 34% reduction in nickel output in its 2026 budget.[1] The piece notes that Indonesia’s move, aimed at addressing oversupply and declining ore grades, could significantly tighten global production capacity even as prices remain volatile.[1]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Talon Metals completes acquisition of Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill, creating a multi‑asset U.S. nickel‑copper company</title><link>https://investingnews.com/talon-metals-completes-previously-announced-acquisition-of-lundin-mining-s-eagle-mine-and-humboldt-mill-operations-creating-a-multi-asset-u-s-nickel-copper-company/</link><description>Talon Metals has closed its acquisition of Lundin Mining’s Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill operations in the U.S., forming a multi‑asset nickel‑copper company with an expanded domestic production base.[6] The company plans to extend mine life at Eagle, accelerate exploration in Michigan and Minnesota, and advance the Tamarack Nickel‑Copper Project and a planned battery minerals processing facility, effectively increasing future U.S. nickel capacity.[6]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>TECH Project high-grade nickel is primed to fuel the global green transition</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/tech-project-high-grade-nickel-is-primed-to-fuel-the-global-green-transition/32893/</link><description>Innovation News Network reports on Queensland Pacific Metals’ TECH Project in Australia, which aims to become a major source of high‑grade, ethically derived nickel for electric vehicle and energy‑storage supply chains.[1] The project uses the DNi Process, an extraction technology designed to recycle more than 98% of nitric acid, avoid tailings dams, minimize waste, and ultimately operate as a carbon‑negative, sustainable facility.[1]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Woes: Innovations Steering a Sustainable EV Future</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-supply-woes-innovations-steering-a-sustainable-ev-future-aemc/</link><description>CarbonCredits.com analyzes how high‑nickel NMC batteries are driving nickel demand and examines technological and supply‑chain innovations to keep EV growth sustainable.[2] The article highlights alternative chemistries like LFP and sodium‑ion, material innovation toward low‑nickel or nickel‑free batteries, and advanced recycling to create a more circular, resilient nickel supply chain.[2]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel's role in the future of safer electric vehicle batteries</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/nickels-role-in-the-future-of-safer-electric-vehicle-batteries/56357/</link><description>Researchers from the University of Texas at Austin and Argonne National Laboratory have conducted an extensive study on high‑nickel cathodes for EV batteries, detailing how nickel’s high energy density can be harnessed while addressing safety and stability challenges.[3] By mapping critical states of charge and understanding metal‑oxygen bond strength and surface reactivity, the work proposes guidelines for safer, more efficient nickel‑rich battery designs that support the clean‑energy transition.[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel – Prysmian and Nexans Down on the Stock Exchange</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy’s antitrust authority (AGCM) has opened an investigation into several major low‑voltage copper cable manufacturers in Italy, including Prysmian Cavi e Sistemi Italia, over alleged price‑fixing conduct dating back to 2005.[2] The probe, still at an early stage, triggered share price declines for Prysmian and Nexans, though analysts currently expect only a negligible impact on Prysmian given that the Italian low‑voltage copper cable market represents less than 3% of its revenues.[2]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium alloy futures fluctuate at highs, and short-term macro tailwinds boost the market</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/aluminium-alloy-futures-fluctuate-at-highs-and-short-term-macro-tailwinds-boost-the-market-116875</link><description>This report notes that aluminium alloy futures in China have been fluctuating at relatively high levels, supported by macroeconomic tailwinds and firm cost support.[3] SHFE data show total registered cast aluminium alloy warrant volumes around 69,922 tonnes as of January 9, 2026, indicating ample exchange stocks even as prices resume an upward trend.[3]</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SHFE aluminium night session breaks through 25,000</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/shfe-aluminium-night-session-breaks-through-25-000-aluminium-prices-maintain-high-levels-116890</link><description>LME aluminum closed at $3,191 per tonne, up 1.33%, with prices reaching a high of $3,200 per tonne during the session. The market continues to experience tightness driven by supply constraints in China and Europe, though demand suppression is intensifying as the Chinese New Year approaches.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 2.21% Higher at $5.9850</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601127865/comex-copper-settles-221-higher-at-59850-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for January delivery gained 12.95 cents per pound to $5.9850, marking the largest one-day gain since January 5, 2026. This represents the second-highest close in history and is up 6.31% month-to-date.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global steel industry battles surplus supply, protectionism</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/011226-global-steel-industry-battles-surplus-supply-protectionism</link><description>Global steelmaking capacity is projected to reach 2.55 billion metric tons by end-2025, with a 2025 surplus of 680 million mt, exacerbated by additions in Asia and the Middle East. India anticipates producing 11.4 million mt more crude steel in 2026, aiming for 300 million mt capacity by 2030 amid weakening prices. Protectionist measures, like US 50% steel tariffs, intensify challenges for Europe and global trade.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper in the Age of AI: Challenges of Electrification</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/en/research-insights/market-insights/daily-update-jan-12-2026</link><description>S&amp;P Global's comprehensive study projects global copper demand will rise 50% to 42 million metric tons by 2040 from 28 million metric tons in 2025, driven by electrification, renewable energy, data centers, and AI infrastructure. The report identifies a potential 10 million metric ton shortfall by 2040 without significant supply expansion and emphasizes that copper has become essential to technological progress and economic growth. The analysis highlights the need for multilateral cooperation, regional diversification, and innovation across the entire copper value chain to ensure a resilient supply system.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME Nickel Prices Surge Toward $17,900 on Weaker US Dollar</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-prices-surge-toward-17900-on-weaker-us-dollar/158742</link><description>London Metal Exchange nickel futures rose by $185 on January 12, nearing the $17,900 level after a two-day increase. This reflects continued strength in nickel prices driven by macroeconomic factors and currency movements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SunSirs: Last Week, Nickel Prices Rose Initially and Then Fell (January 5-9)</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29620.html</link><description>Nickel prices fluctuated last week, rising initially due to Indonesia's planned 34% cut in nickel ore production quotas for 2026, then falling. Refined nickel production in China is expected to decrease month-on-month, narrowing short-term surplus amid abundant overall supply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM January 13 News: Aluminum Ingot and Billet Warehouse Outflows Increase</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103134504/smm-january-13-aluminum-ingot-and-billet-warehouse-outflows-increase</link><description>According to SMM statistics, outflows from warehouses of aluminum ingots reached 149,000 mt last week, an increase compared to prior periods. This indicates rising demand or movement in aluminum inventories. The update highlights shifts in aluminum ingot and billet stocks as of January 13.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Inventory Update: Social Stocks Decline While Billet Stocks Rise</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103134130/aluminum-inventory-update-social-stocks-decline-while-billet-stocks-rise</link><description>SMM reports changes in aluminum inventories as of January 13, with social stocks declining and billet stocks rising. This follows a decline in alumina raw material prices, leading to expected month-on-month decreases in total aluminum costs for January. The update reflects ongoing dynamics in aluminum supply and production costs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>January US ferrous scrap seen $20-30/gt up as mills raise early 2026 offers</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-prices/steel-prices-market-analyses/scrap-and-raw-materials/january-us-ferrous-scrap-seen-20-30gt-up-as-mills-raise-early-2026-offers-1428399.htm</link><description>January US ferrous scrap prices are expected to rise by $20-30/gt as mills increase early 2026 offers. Northeast busheling scrap could settle near $370-390/gt, up $30/gt, while shredded grades are also projected higher. This reflects ongoing market adjustments into the new year.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>North EU HRC futures firming on CME</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/commodities/steel</link><description>CME north EU hot-rolled coil (HRC) futures prices increased, with second-quarter strips trading at €676/t and further appetite noted. March material traded at €663-665/t, driven by supply constraints and firmer sentiment in the EU steel market. Strength may also stem from rallies in Chinese coking coal futures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The TEX Report - January 13, 2026</title><link>https://www.texreport.co.jp/en/daily-reports/3644</link><description>The daily report covers steel market updates, including stainless steel scrap import volumes and LME prices for Ni, Co, and Mo as of early January 2026. It notes prices rose 13-14% from the prior month in some segments. This provides insights into raw material trends affecting steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cleveland-Cliffs Steelton plant to officially close early 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cleveland-cliffs-steelton-plant-to-officially-close-early-2026-1415550.htm</link><description>Cleveland-Cliffs announced the permanent closure of its Steelton plant, following months after the company idled the facility with 500 layoffs. The closure decision was driven by weak demand and insufficient pricing for products produced at the facility.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Domestic Iron and Steel Industry Urges Congress to Maintain Buy America in Upcoming Transportation Bill</title><link>https://www.americanmanufacturing.org/blog/domestic-iron-and-steel-industry-urges-congress-to-maintain-buy-america-in-upcoming-transportation-bill/</link><description>The domestic iron and steel industry is advocating for Congress to maintain Buy America provisions in the upcoming transportation bill.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Codelco expects to lift copper output by 10 000 t this year</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/codelco-expects-to-lift-copper-output-by-10-000-t-this-year-2026-01-13</link><description>Chilean state-run miner Codelco plans to produce 1.344 million metric tons of copper in 2026, an increase of about 10,000 tons from the previous year. This output lift reflects efforts to boost production capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>MAX RESOURCE ENTERS MASTERS SERVICES AGREEMENT</title><link>https://www.maxresource.com/20260112-max-resource-enters-masters-services-agreement</link><description>Max Resource Corp. entered a masters services agreement, highlighting its Serra Azul Copper-Silver Project in Colombia along the Andean copper belt. The project is fully funded by Freeport-McMoRan up to $50 million for an 80% earn-in, validating its geological potential amid global copper supply discussions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why are commodity prices going crazy?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/13/why-are-commodity-prices-going-crazy/</link><description>The nickel price has risen 26% in one month and 13% year over year, signaling a recovery after a three-year slump due to Indonesian oversupply. Improving demand from Chinese stainless steel mills and EV battery producers supports the rebound, amid supply uncertainty from Indonesia's potential 34% output cut in 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[1.14 Nickel Morning Meeting Summary] SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate price stays flat WoW</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103135568/114-nickel-morning-meeting-smm-battery-grade-nickel-sulphate-price-stays-flat-wow</link><description>On January 13, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price held steady at 26423 yuan/mt. The quotation range remained flat week-over-week amid ongoing market monitoring.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel price spikes more than 10% as Chinese buying fuels metals surge</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-spikes-more-than-10-as-chinese-buying-fuels-metals-surge/</link><description>Nickel prices spiked over 10% to $18,785 a ton on the LME, the biggest gain in over three years, driven by Chinese investor buying and risks to Indonesian supply. This extends a 30% rise since mid-December, reversing oversupply issues despite weaker EV battery demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Metals - Nickel: supportive macro-backdrop to further boost LME price</title><link>https://www.indopremier.com/module/newsDetail.php?jdl=Metals___Nickel__supportive_macro_backdrop_to_further_boost_LME_price&amp;news_id=211459&amp;group_news=IPOTNEWS&amp;taging_subtype=NOTESIPS&amp;name=&amp;search=y_general&amp;q=Sector+Update%2C%C2%A0Metals%2C+LME+nickel+price%2C+%28INCO%29%2C+%28ANTM%29%2C+%28MBMA%29%2C&amp;halaman=1</link><description>LME nickel trades at ~US$18k/t, a 19-month high, driven by Indonesia's plan to cut FY26F RKAB quota. Supportive macro factors are expected to further elevate prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia quota talk triggers nickel reality check</title><link>https://www.mining.com/indonesia-quota-talk-triggers-nickel-reality-check/</link><description>Nickel prices surged on speculation of Indonesia slashing 2026 ore quotas by a third to 250 million tonnes, potentially removing 700,000 tonnes of supply and flipping the market to deficit. However, a massive 20,760-tonne LME warranting on Jan. 7 highlighted ongoing oversupply, pulling prices back from $18,800. Processing capacity constraints outside China limit quick responses from new mines.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Weiming to trial second nickel matte line at Indonesia's Jiaman project</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/weiming-to-trial-second-nickel-matte-line-at-indonesia-s-jiaman-project</link><description>Weiming plans to trial a second nickel matte production line at its Jiaman project in Indonesia. This expansion aims to boost nickel processing capacity at the site.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Strengthening nickel resources, MBMA spends IDR 44.37 billion</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/60352/strengthening-nickel-resources-mbma-spends-idr-44-37-billion</link><description>MBMA invested IDR 44.37 billion to complete 1,659 drill holes at the SCM Mine, upgrading the status of its nickel resources. This effort strengthens the company's nickel asset base.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The 2026 Aluminum Squeeze: Why This Industrial Metal is Outperforming the S&amp;P 500</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2026-1-13-the-2026-aluminum-squeeze-why-this-industrial-metal-is-outperforming-the-s-and-p-500</link><description>A structural price squeeze grips the global aluminum market as of mid-January 2026, driven by supply bottlenecks including Guinea's bauxite processing shift and China's 45 million tonne production ceiling. Chinese exports fell 9% in late 2025 amid domestic green economy demand. Future scenarios include potential demand destruction above $3,200/tonne or relief from Russian supply if sanctions ease.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 942 USD/T on January 13, 2026, down 0.11% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 3.86%, and are up 33.24% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts indicate trading at 959.80 USD/T by quarter-end and 1032.31 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Sherritt-Canada's Nickel Mines in Cuba Need Oil to Operate</title><link>https://havanatimes.org/features/sherritt-canadas-nickel-mines-in-cuba-need-oil-to-operate/</link><description>Sherritt's nickel mining operations in Cuba rely on Venezuelan oil supplies. Disruptions to this oil could impact production capacity at these mines.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices surge on Indonesia output-cut news… highest in 15 months</title><link>https://en.bloomingbit.io/feed/news/104016</link><description>Nickel futures on the LME settled at $17,681/t following Indonesia's announcement to cut output this year. While prices have risen 25.3% over the past month, analysts caution that further gains may be limited until concrete implementation details emerge, and supply resumption from the Philippines in March could ease the current price uptrend.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>CBAM starts in January 2026, with limited aluminium impact until Q1</title><link>http://www.alcircle.com/news/cbam-begins-in-january-2026-but-aluminium-supply-disruptions-may-stay-muted-through-q1-what-shifts-from-april-116803</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) begins in January 2026, pricing carbon on imports like aluminum to support EU industries. Aluminum supply disruptions are expected to remain muted through Q1, with potential shifts from April.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Paragon Union-Japan's Asahi Seiren to tap RM648b recycled aluminium market</title><link>https://themalaysianreserve.com/2026/01/14/paragon-union-japans-asahi-seiren-to-tap-rm648b-recycled-aluminium-market/</link><description>Paragon Union and Japan's Asahi Seiren partner to enter the RM648b recycled aluminum market. Recycled aluminum production uses just 5% of the energy required for primary production and cuts greenhouse gas emissions by up to 95%. This addresses key sustainability challenges in the industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 2.8 percent - week 1, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-28-percent-week-1-2026-1429283.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending January 10, 2026, reached 1.752 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 75.7 percent, up 2.8 percent from the prior week. This marks a 3.1 percent increase from the same week in 2025. Year-to-date production through January 10 is up 2.6 percent from last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fujitsu launches demonstration experiment into green steel value flow utilizing blockchain technology to accelerate decarbonization in the steel Industry</title><link>https://global.fujitsu/en-global/pr/news/2026/01/14-02</link><description>Fujitsu has started a demonstration experiment on green steel value flow using blockchain, selected by Japan's METI for its FY2025 project, running from December 2025 to February 2026. The initiative ensures secure distribution of environmental value data, like emissions reduction certificates, across steel supply chains via CO2 reduction expertise and data platforms. It addresses challenges in propagating green steel's benefits downstream to promote decarbonization.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Signal Group Spotlight: Steel Seaborne Trends</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/signal-group-spotlight-steel-seaborne-trends/</link><description>The start of 2026 is expected to feature a seasonal dip in steel production due to Chinese New Year holidays, impacting exports with weaker Q1 volumes. This trend follows historical patterns of reduced activity during the holiday period.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fujitsu launches demonstration experiment into green steel value flow utilizing blockchain technology to accelerate decarbonization in the steel industry</title><link>https://global.fujitsu/en-global/pr/news/2026/01/14-02</link><description>Fujitsu has commenced a demonstration experiment into green steel value flow using blockchain technology, running from December 2025 to February 2026. The project, selected by Japan's Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry (METI), aims to ensure environmental value and transaction confidentiality are secured across steel supply chains while exploring mechanisms for green steel information distribution.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Driving innovation at Escondida</title><link>https://www.bhp.com/news/articles/2026/01/driving-innovation-at-escondida</link><description>BHP's Escondida copper mine in Chile has achieved full autonomy at its Escondida Norte pit, operating 33 autonomous trucks and 11 autonomous drills that move over 350,000 tonnes of material daily. The autonomous zone now accounts for 30% of Escondida's production and has trained over 5,000 workers in new technologies while maintaining 64% female participation in autonomy-related roles. These innovations enhance safety, productivity, and sustainability while positioning the world's largest copper producer to meet growing global demand driven by electrification and renewable energy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review - Nickel Prices Continued to Rise</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103719313</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices averaged 146,450 yuan/mt on January 14, up 1,250 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 143,160 yuan/mt, up 1.47%, amid a tug-of-war between strong expectations for Indonesian policies and weak demand fundamentals. The market is expected to remain volatile within a 128,000-145,000 yuan/mt range.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>From volume to value: 5 strategic pillars to reform Indonesia's nickel downstream processing</title><link>https://observerid.com/from-volume-to-value-5-strategic-pillars-to-reform-indonesias-nickel-downstream-processin/</link><description>Transisi Bersih held a briefing on January 14, 2026, outlining five strategic pillars for reforming Indonesia's nickel downstream processing. The focus shifts from maximizing volume to enhancing value in nickel production. This addresses sustainability and efficiency in capacity utilization.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices soar on Trump tariffs, global shortages, and China ...</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=azAGvW91wss</link><description>Aluminum prices are soaring due to Trump's 50% tariffs and global shortages of 2 million tons per year. Century Aluminum plans to restart its Mt. Holly, SC smelter to full production, increasing U.S. output by 50,000 metric tons and creating over 100 jobs by June 2026. U.S. buyers face record spreads over global benchmarks amid reduced Chinese production and exports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel market set for steady growth as stainless steel and ev demand reshape supply</title><link>https://www.industrysourcing.com/article/473242</link><description>The nickel market anticipates steady growth driven by stainless steel and EV battery demand, with acceleration in battery-grade refinery projects in North America for lower-carbon supply chains. Sustainability pressures are intensifying, as automakers enforce stricter emissions standards, promoting renewable energy, traceability, and cleaner methods in nickel production. Investment momentum persists despite some project delays, shaped by long-term forecasts.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Market Update</title><link>https://www.crugroup.com/en/communities/newsletters-and-magazines/steel-market-update/</link><description>The Steel Market Update provides the latest pricing, trends, and industry news for flat-rolled steel, including assessments on scrap and futures. It features real-time price tracking, sentiment surveys, inventory levels, and demand analysis for sectors like construction and automotive. Businesses use it to anticipate market shifts.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The TEX Report - January 15, 2026</title><link>https://www.texreport.co.jp/en/daily-reports/3653</link><description>Vietnam's FHS raised domestic HRC prices for March shipments by $7–8. China's 2025 steel exports reached a record 119 million tonnes, with a high monthly average. The daily report covers key steel market developments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A North of 60 copper supply solution</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/15/mining-explorers-2025/a-north-of-60-copper-supply-solution/9433.html</link><description>The article discusses upcoming copper mining projects in the Golden Triangle region, including Galore Creek, KSM, and Schaft Creek, which are poised to significantly boost annual copper production capacity in the area north of 60 degrees latitude.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 refined nickel average price update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103720728/</link><description>On January 15, the SMM #1 refined nickel average price stood at 150,050 yuan/mt, up 3,600 yuan/mt from the previous day, reflecting continued strength in nickel prices amid recent market developments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Surged Sharply on January 15</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103721760/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-surged-sharply-on-january-15-central-bank-conducted-900-billion-yuan-in-outright-</link><description>On January 15, 2026, SMM #1 refined nickel prices rose sharply to an average of 150,050 yuan/mt, up 3,600 yuan/mt from the previous day, amid central bank liquidity measures. The SHFE nickel futures contract gained 3.04%, closing at 145,280 yuan/mt in the morning session. Market dynamics reflect ongoing tension between Indonesian policy expectations and high inventory realities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia may approve nickel ore production quota of around 260 mln tons in 2026, local media says</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/indonesia-may-approve-nickel-ore-production-quota-of-around-260-mln-tons-in-2026-local-media-says/</link><description>Indonesia is considering approving a nickel ore production quota of approximately 260 million tons for 2026. This follows discussions on curbing output to support prices amid global market shifts. The quota aims to balance supply with value maximization strategies.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ontario fast-tracks Crawford nickel project</title><link>https://www.engineeringnews.co.za/article/ontario-fast-tracks-crawford-nickel-project-2026-01-15</link><description>Ontario is accelerating the Crawford nickel project, described as the Western world's largest nickel sulphide mine. The initiative includes building a new nickel processing plant and downstream alloy production to create a fully domestic supply chain. This aims to bolster Canada's critical minerals leadership.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ontario fast-tracks Crawford nickel project</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/ontario-fast-tracks-crawford-nickel-project-2026-01-15</link><description>The Ontario government is prioritizing the Crawford nickel project in 2026 to unlock one of the world's largest nickel deposits. This move is intended to boost the economy and support secure nickel supply chains. It emphasizes full domestic production from mining to processing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Growth Shares: Strategic Investment Opportunity in 2026</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/nickel-industries-growth-shares-2026-investment-opportunity/</link><description>Nickel Industries is highlighted as a strategic investment pick for 2026 growth shares. The article positions the company amid rising nickel market opportunities. It focuses on potential expansion in production capacity.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Major steel and raw material futures prices in China - January 15, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-prices/steel-prices-market-analyses/longs-and-billet/major-steel-and-raw-material-futures-prices-in-china-january-15-2026-1429717.htm</link><description>Rebar futures at Shanghai Futures Exchange closed at RMB 3,160/mt ($451/mt) on January 15, 2026. Other steel products like HRC listed with weekly changes; iron ore down 0.73%, scrap up 0.88%. Turkish rebar index up 0.17%, reflecting mixed regional trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Coolbrook Named on the 2026 Global Cleantech 100</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20260115771313/en/Coolbrook-Named-on-the-2026-Global-Cleantech-100</link><description>Coolbrook has been recognized on the 2026 Global Cleantech 100 for its RotoDynamic Technology, which replaces fossil fuel burning in heavy industries like iron and steel with electrification. The technology's RotoDynamic Reactor and Heater achieve temperatures up to 1700°C for carbon-free production, potentially cutting 2.4 billion tons of annual CO2 emissions. It supports rapid decarbonization in steel, cement, and chemicals sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto and Amazon Web Services collaborate to bring low-carbon Nuton copper to U.S. data centres</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2026/rio-tinto-and-amazon-web-services-collaborate-to-bring-low-carbon-nuton-copper-to-u-s--data-centres</link><description>Rio Tinto and Amazon Web Services have partnered to deploy Nuton copper technology at U.S. data centers. The technology is projected to use substantially less water and generate lower carbon emissions than conventional concentrator-based copper production methods.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia secures mining quota approval for 2026</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2026-01-15/vale-indonesia-secures-mining-quota-approval-2026</link><description>Nickel miner PT Vale Indonesia has secured approval for its 2026 mining quota, allowing all operational activities to return to normal. The company did not disclose the specific volume of nickel ore permitted for production this year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Macro factors are mixed, with bullish sentiment slightly cooling in the latter part of the week</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/macro-factors-are-mixed-with-bullish-sentiment-slightly-cooling-in-the-latter-part-of-the-week-aluminium-prices-are-expected-to-fluctuate-at-highs-in-116949</link><description>Mixed macro signals and weak fundamentals persist, but liquidity support keeps aluminum prices elevated. Bullish fund sentiment has cooled slightly after Trump's tariff decision on critical minerals. SHFE aluminum is forecast at RMB 23,800-25,000 per tonne, LME at USD 3,080-3,200 per tonne next week.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Indonesian Mining Restrictions Send Shockwaves Through Global Markets</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hPkZng04cFo</link><description>The nickel market experienced significant volatility in early 2026, with prices climbing $2,200 per ton to $18,650 following Vale's announcement of mining permit delays in Indonesia. Market observers anticipate prices could reach $20,000 per ton during the January-March quarter as Chinese processors face mounting pressure to secure material.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>This week, the macro cycle rebounded, aluminum | SMM - Metal News</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103141883</link><description>This week, macroeconomic cycles rebounded, leading to unexpected destocking in aluminum inventories. Aluminum prices showed a steady rise as a result. The report highlights positive momentum in the aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>January 16, 2026, Jinshi Futures Morning Report: The Trump Administration</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/67476046/january-16-2026-jinshi-futures-morning-report-the-trump-administration?futusource=news_newspage_recommend</link><description>China Iron and Steel Association reports key steel enterprises produced 19.97 million tons of crude steel in early January, up 21.6% from prior period, estimating national daily output at 2.48 million tons. Mysteel data shows rebar production at 1.903 million tons for week ending January 15, down 0.39%, while apparent demand rose 8.79%. LME base metals mostly declined amid ferrous metals updates.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Business Intelligence Group Honors Axalta with Six BIG Innovation Awards</title><link>https://ir.axalta.com/news/press-releases/detail/678/business-intelligence-group-honors-axalta-with-six-big-innovation-awards</link><description>Axalta received awards for coatings innovations enhancing sustainability in automotive and industrial applications, including electrical steel coatings for efficient electric motors. Technologies like Lumeera 3250 low-bake clearcoat reduce CO2 emissions by at least 20% per vehicle by curing at lower temperatures. Other solutions offer energy savings up to 40%, zero VOCs, and high transfer efficiency for cabinet coatings.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Capstone Copper Achieves Production Guidance</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/16/capstone-copper-achieves-production-guidance/</link><description>Capstone Copper reported record 2025 copper production of 224,764 tonnes, exceeding guidance and up 22% from 2024. Growth was driven by the Mantoverde Development Project and Mantos Blancos debottlenecking, with a record quarterly output of 58,273 tonnes in December. Despite a strike, Mantoverde operates at 75% capacity, and shares surged post-announcement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why Capstone Copper, Catalyst Metals, DroneShield, and Wildcat shares are rising today</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/16/why-capstone-copper-catalyst-metals-droneshield-and-wildcat-shares-are-rising-today/</link><description>Capstone Copper achieved its FY 2025 production guidance with record 224,764 tonnes of copper, up 22% year-over-year due to key project executions. CEO Cashel Meagher highlighted transformational growth from catalysts like Mantoverde. Shares rose 7.5% following the announcement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Quantum backs Panama's plan to allow stockpile processing at shut copper mine</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/first-quantum-backs-panamas-plan-to-allow-stockpile-processing-at-shut-copper-mine-2026-01-16</link><description>First Quantum Minerals supports Panama's plan to process stockpiles at the shut Cobre Panama copper mine. The company awaits formal approvals to coordinate activities with the government. This could enable some production resumption from existing materials.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Experienced a Significant Correction on January 16</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103723987/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-correction-on-january-16-central-bank-cuts-relending-an</link><description>On January 16, SMM #1 refined nickel prices ranged from 144,700-154,000 yuan/mt, averaging 149,350 yuan/mt, down 700 yuan/mt from the previous day. Spot premiums for Jinchuan #1 refined nickel averaged 6,500 yuan/mt, down 1,500 yuan/mt. The SHFE nickel contract (2602) closed the morning session at 142,540 yuan/mt, down 3.19%, amid central bank rate cuts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] January 16 — Supply side, upstream offers remained at 1,050-1,100 yuan/mtu</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103724001/smm-nickel-market-price-hike-fails-to-boost-demand-cautious-sentiment-persists</link><description>On January 16, upstream offers for nickel remained stable at 1,050-1,100 yuan/mtu, with some iron plants holding firm. A price hike failed to boost demand, as cautious sentiment persists in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>In Case You Missed It - BC Extra Upgrades &amp; Downgrades - 16-01-26</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2026/01/16/in-case-you-missed-it-bc-extra-upgrades-downgrades-16-01-26/</link><description>Canaccord Genuity upgrades Nickel Industries Limited to Buy, raising the target to $1.05 from $0.80 due to higher nickel price forecasts and base metals strength. The broker expects weaker nickel prices to impact EBITDA but sees upside from revised metal price outlooks, including copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel and cobalt out, CO2 in at Turnagain</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/16/news/nickel-and-cobalt-out-co2-in-at-turnagain/9492.html</link><description>The Turnagain nickel-cobalt project is shifting focus from nickel and cobalt production to CO2 sequestration. Details on the operational changes at the site were reported in the latest update.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Quantum Minerals Announces 2025 Preliminary Production and 2026-2028 Guidance</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2026/01/16/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/first-quantum-minerals-announces-2025-preliminary-production-and-2026-2028-guidance/2260062</link><description>First Quantum Minerals released preliminary 2025 production figures and provided guidance for nickel and other metals through 2028. The announcement details expected output capacities in U.S. dollars.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>GT reassesses Finnish nickel-PGM project</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/16/northern-neighbors/gt-reassesses-finnish-nickel-pgm-project/9490.html</link><description>GT Resources is reassessing its Kaukua nickel-PGM project in Finland by analyzing over 4,600 historic pulps and 500 infill samples to standardize data. The program aims to update resource estimates ahead of potential development.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 3,140.70 USD/T on January 16, 2026, down 0.93% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 8.21%, and are up 17.10% compared to the same time last year. The price reflects trading on a contract for difference tracking the benchmark market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 3,140.70 USD/T on January 16, 2026, amid tightening supply and production disruptions. China is curbing overcapacity, set to breach its 45 million ton output cap, while new smelters in Indonesia face setbacks. Operations at smelters in Iceland, Mozambique, and Australia are suspended due to high energy costs, equipment failures, bauxite sourcing issues, and geopolitical risks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AMU: Labor agreement timelines converge in US aluminum</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/16/labor-contracts-unions-aluminum-2026-trade-prices/</link><description>Multiple collective bargaining agreements at U.S. aluminum producers are expiring or entering negotiations in 2026, potentially impacting operations. This convergence occurs amid trade protections, high aluminum prices, elevated Midwest premiums, and uneven demand. Facilities like Constellium’s Muscle Shoals and Ravenswood are approaching key bargaining phases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel traded flat at around 3,138-3,141 CNY/T on January 16, 2026, marking a slight 0.10% increase from the previous day. Over the past month, prices rose 1.65-1.75%, though they remain 5.68-5.77% lower than a year ago. Steel rebar futures gained on hopes of China stimulus, reaching CNY 3,130 per tonne amid discussions on fiscal measures to boost demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US-based Worthington Steel to acquire Klöckner &amp; Co for $2.4 billion</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Worthington Steel announced plans to acquire Klöckner &amp; Co for $2.4 billion, potentially impacting steel production and distribution capacities. This deal highlights consolidation trends in the global steel sector. Further details on production implications are emerging.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ferrexpo reduced production by 9% y/y in 2025</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Ukrainian producer Ferrexpo reported a 9% year-on-year decline in production for 2025, affecting steel-related output. This reduction comes amid ongoing market challenges. The news was published in the context of recent steel market updates.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Nederland Opens New Production Line for Sustainable Food Packaging</title><link>https://www.tatasteel.com/newsroom/press-releases/india/2026/tata-steel-nederland-opens-new-production-line-for-sustainable-food-packaging/</link><description>Tata Steel Nederland has commissioned a new production line using innovative TCCT (Trivalent Chromium Coating Technology) for more sustainable packaging steel production, complying with future legislation. This patented technology, combined with Protact®, enhances food safety, reduces costs by eliminating extra lacquer layers, and simplifies supply chains. It sets a new European standard for eco-friendly steel packaging.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 1.14% Lower at $5.7885 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601165062/comex-copper-ends-the-week-114-lower-at-57885-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for January delivery fell 6.70 cents per pound, or 1.14%, to $5.7885 over the week, down two of the past three weeks. It declined 15.95 cents or 2.68% on the day, marking the largest one-day drop since January 7, 2026. Year-to-date, it is up 2.82%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper fell to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 16, down 3.40% from the previous day, amid reports of drops due to China curbing high-frequency trading and retreating from record highs. Over the past month, prices rose 7.88%, and year-over-year up 33.95%. Historically, it reached an all-time high of 6.11 USD/Lbs in January 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper theft ticks up as prices surge</title><link>https://www.foxbusiness.com/video/6387831862112</link><description>Copper thefts are increasing as prices surge, highlighting secondary market impacts of rising copper values. The video discusses trends in theft related to high commodity prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 17,825 USD/T on January 16, 2026, down 4.14% from the previous day, though up 24.09% over the past month. A later update shows prices at 17,566.63 USD/T, down 5.53% daily but up 22.29% monthly and 9.25% year-over-year. This reflects ongoing volatility amid broader market trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Extends Drop Amid Lack of Detail on Indonesia Output Cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-extends-drop-amid-lack-of-detail-on-indonesia-output-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices settled 4.1% lower at $17,155 per ton on the LME, extending declines from a 19-month high due to absent details on Indonesia's output cuts. Three-month futures dropped as much as 5.9% after peaking at $18,800 per ton. The pullback follows a rally driven by supply concerns from the top producer.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Arca &amp; Giga Metals To Explore CDR At Nickel Mine In Canada</title><link>https://carbonherald.com/arca-giga-metals-to-explore-cdr-at-nickel-mine-in-canada/</link><description>Arca Climate Technologies has a 10-year exclusive agreement to assess carbon dioxide removal potential at Giga Metals' Turnagain nickel project using ultramafic waste. The technology accelerates CO2 mineralization, targeting 220 million tonnes of removal, and builds on a decade of collaboration for ESG-enhanced nickel production. This aligns with Canada's critical minerals priorities and demonstrates innovative mining with societal benefits.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 17.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel exchanges, showing Shanghai Futures rebar prices flat at 0.00 change on January 16, 2026, for 1-3 month terms. Other futures like Turkey, China, Europe, and North America 1-month terms also held steady as of January 15, 2026. The platform highlights ongoing price monitoring amid global market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper hits one-week low on profit-taking and China demand concerns</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-one-week-low-on-profit-taking-and-china-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices hit a one-week low on Friday due to profit-taking after a rally driven by speculative funds. Physical demand from buyers in China remained muted. This reflects recent market volatility in the commodity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Amazon to be first user of copper made by Rio Tinto venture</title><link>https://www.mining.com/amazon-to-be-first-user-of-copper-made-by-rio-tinto-venture/</link><description>Amazon Web Services will be the first to use copper produced at an Arizona mine using Nuton's bioleaching technology, which uses microorganisms to extract copper from sulfide ores. The technology reduces water usage by up to 80% and carbon emissions by as much as 60% compared to traditional copper production, while achieving recovery rates of up to 85%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Battery-Grade Nickel Sulphate Prices Rise on January 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103143543/smm-battery-grade-nickel-sulphate-prices-rise-on-january-17</link><description>On January 17, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price reached 26,516 yuan/mt. Quotations for battery-grade nickel sulphate showed an upward trend. This indicates rising prices in nickel derivatives amid recent market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Live Nickel Prices Today</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-prices-today/</link><description>Nickel prices retreated on January 17, 2026, as markets reassessed Indonesia's proposed output cuts. This follows recent volatility in the nickel market. The analysis highlights ongoing price adjustments amid supply uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Squeeze Intensifies as Indonesia Restricts Exports and Canada Accelerates Projects</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-supply-squeeze-intensifies-as-indonesia-restricts-exports-and-canada-accelerates-projects</link><description>Nickel prices surged to $18,650 following Indonesian supply restrictions confirmed by Vale's mining halt. Canada Nickel's Crawford project received Ontario's fast-track approval as a strategic alternative, while the Reid deposit resource increased 46% to 5 million tonnes of contained nickel with superior economics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia's ESDM confirms plan to reduce nickel production to 250-260 million tonnes for 2026</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5110162-flash-indonesias-esdm-confirms-plan-to-reduce-nickel-production-to-250-260-million-tonnes-for-2026</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources confirmed a nickel production target of 250-260 million tonnes for 2026, down from 379 million tonnes in 2025. The quota reduction aims to align with domestic processing capacity and support nickel prices, with global prices surging to $18,000/tonne following the announcement.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Can nickel prices hit $25,000 in 2026?</title><link>https://theoregongroup.substack.com/p/can-nickel-prices-hit-25000-in-2026</link><description>Nickel prices jumped to $16,500–$18,500 per ton in early January 2026, with Indonesia shifting from maximizing supply to maximizing value through production cuts. Only 55% of Indonesia's approved nickel ore production capacity was actually utilized in 2025, suggesting much of the supposed surplus was statistical illusion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Highlights Relevance of Pipestone XL Awaruite Nickel-Cobalt Alloy Discovery to Address U.S. Critical Mineral Supply Chain Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/280485/First-Atlantic-Nickel-Highlights-Relevance-of-Pipestone-XL-Awaruite-NickelCobalt-Alloy-Discovery-to-Address-U.S.-Critical-Mineral-Supply-Chain-Vulnerabilities-Identified-in-January-14-2026-White-House-Proclamation</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel announced preliminary metallurgical testing results for its Pipestone XL project, with magnetic concentrate averaging 1.3% nickel that can be upgraded to approximately 60% through flotation. The project also identified chromium as a potential recoverable mineral, addressing North America's lack of sufficient mined chromium concentrates.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>