<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 05:23:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nickel Futures Retreat From Recent Highs</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/517935</link><description>Nickel futures fell toward $18,000 per tonne after hitting $18,700, with Indonesia cutting 2026 nickel ore quotas by 34% to align with processing capacity. Chinese spot prices dropped amid profit-taking and soft demand, while SHFE futures declined 1.6%. Nickel Industries reported lower ore sales but resumed shipments in early January.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>MacroAsia unit's Palawan nickel project gets MGB clearance</title><link>https://business.inquirer.net/569726/macroasia-units-palawan-nickel-project-gets-mgb-clearance</link><description>MacroAsia Mining Corp. received approval for its Infanta nickel project in Palawan, planning to invest 12 million for extraction across 1,113 hectares. The project falls under Production Sharing No.220-5-IVB in Brooke's Point. The company anticipates nickel market recovery to enable full commercial production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Three Main Factors Drove the Strong Performance of Aluminum Prices in January</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29923.html</link><description>Aluminum prices rose 6.3% in January 2026, driven by rigid supply constraints, structural demand growth, and macroeconomic factors combined with low inventory levels. The market has experienced a slight recent decline after reaching highs on January 14th, but medium-to-long term outlook remains supported by supply and demand fundamentals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SunSirs: Three Main Factors Drove the Strong Performance of Aluminum Prices in January</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29923.html</link><description>Aluminum prices in East China rose 6.3% in January 2026 to 23,890 RMB/ton as of January 19, driven by supply constraints. China's 45 million ton capacity limit and rising molten aluminum proportion limit ingot supply, while overseas disruptions like Mozal's shutdown and Century Aluminium reductions create a global supply gap of 290,000 to 840,000 tons.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME copper prices rose ~0.4% as tight inventories</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103733527</link><description>LME copper prices rose about 0.4% due to tight inventories. Shanghai transaction prices averaged 99,830 yuan/mt, down slightly by 20 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper demand rockets in the Age of AI</title><link>https://www.metaltechnews.com/story/2026/01/21/tech-metals/copper-demand-rockets-in-the-age-of-ai/2617.html</link><description>A surge in artificial intelligence, electric vehicles, renewable energy, and defense modernization is driving unprecedented growth in global copper demand. The article discusses how copper has become critical infrastructure for the digital economy and energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel and cobalt out, CO2 in at Turnagain</title><link>https://www.metaltechnews.com/story/2026/01/21/tech-bytes/nickel-and-cobalt-out-co2-in-at-turnagain/2613.html</link><description>A future mine at the Turnagain project could produce nickel and cobalt while permanently locking away over 200 million tons of atmospheric CO2, enhancing sustainability in nickel production. This innovative approach integrates carbon sequestration with metal extraction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Raw Steel Production Up 3.3% Year-on-Year in Mid-January</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/u.s.-raw-steel-production-up-3.3-year-on-year-in-mid-january-2026-1-21/98290</link><description>US raw steel production totaled 1,756,000 net tons for the week ending January 17, 2026, with a capability utilization rate of 75.9%. The Southern region led production with 773,000 net tons, followed by the Great Lakes at 504,000 net tons, representing a 3.3% year-over-year increase.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Live Aluminum Prices Today</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-today/</link><description>Aluminum edged higher as intensifying supply risks offset a pause in downstream buying, with physical tightness continuing to support prices. The article provides current pricing analysis and explains aluminum's role as a critical energy metal classified by the U.S. Government in 2022.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>2026 Global Outlook for New Alumina Supply</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103732427/2026-global-outlook-for-new-alumina-supply</link><description>China's alumina capacity is expected to reach 118.92 million mt in 2026 with 8.6 million mt of new capacity, intensifying oversupply. Much of the new capacity in Guangxi will shift local supply from tight to surplus, pressuring prices. Overseas, Indonesia and India will add 1 million mt and 500,000 mt respectively, heightening global competition.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Unilever, Ball and Alcoa unveil “first” carbon-free aluminum aerosol can</title><link>https://www.packaginginsights.com/news/carbon-free-aluminum-aerosol-can.html</link><description>Ball Corporation, Unilever, and Alcoa have debuted the first aerosol can made with Elysis carbon-free smelting technology, combining 50% Elysis aluminum and 50% recycled content to eliminate direct GHG emissions from smelting. The innovation targets personal care products like deodorants and cleaning items, supporting decarbonization in aluminum packaging. Elysis, a partnership of Alcoa and Rio Tinto backed by Apple and governments, produces oxygen instead of CO2 during smelting.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 22.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, indices, and news. It covers Shanghai Futures for rebar across multiple terms and future contracts for regions including Turkey, China, Europe, and North America, with recent data from January 19-20, 2026. The platform includes sections for latest news on rebar, scrap, and iron-steel markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Loses Momentum After 62% Rally: Flat 2026 Performance Raises Questions</title><link>https://scanx.trade/stock-market-news/commodities/copper-loses-momentum-after-62-rally-flat-2026-performance-raises-questions/30449309</link><description>Domestic copper prices in India fell nearly 1% to ₹1,288.90/kg on Tuesday amid mixed global trends, with MCX January contracts at ₹1,292.10, down ₹10. After a 62% rally in 2025, copper shows flat performance in 2026 due to profit booking, though fundamentals remain supportive with support levels at ₹1,230-₹1,250.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 22, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 22, 2026, up 0.43% from the previous day, with a 5.23% monthly gain. On January 21, prices fell to 5.80 USD/Lbs amid demand concerns in China, where the Yangshan import premium halved.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Q4 Production Increases, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103732269/rio-tinto-q4-production-increases-lme-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-lower-overnight-smm-copper-morning-meeting-minutes</link><description>Rio Tinto reported Q4 2025 attributable copper production of 240,000 mt, up 5% year-over-year and 18% quarter-over-quarter, with full-year 2025 production reaching 883,000 mt, an 11% cumulative increase. LME copper futures opened at $12,915.5/mt and closed at $12,761.5/mt, down 0.27%, with trading volume at 89,000 lots.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>More PV Manufacturers Expected to Adopt Copper Metallization in 2026</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-india.com/2026/01/22/more-pv-manufacturers-expected-to-adopt-copper-metallization-in-2026/</link><description>2026 is expected to mark the first year of large-scale mass production for high-copper paste solutions in photovoltaic manufacturing, driven by surging silver prices and sustainability concerns. Gigawatt-scale TOPCon customers and Tier-1 cell manufacturers are accelerating adoption of copper metallization to reduce silver consumption while maintaining conversion efficiency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining Announces 2025 Production Results and 2026 Guidance</title><link>https://www.inderes.fi/releases/lundin-mining-corporation-lundin-mining-announces-2025-production-results-and-2026-guidance</link><description>Lundin Mining forecasts copper production to remain stable at approximately 310,000 to 335,000 tonnes annually in 2026, consistent with 2025 production levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Strike Zone Mining Podcast for January 22 2026</title><link>https://www.netnewsledger.com/2026/01/21/strike-zone-mining-podcast-for-january-22-2026/</link><description>Ontario fast-tracks Canada Nickel's Crawford Nickel Project under the 'One Project, One Process' framework. The project near Timmins is positioned for batteries and green steel with plans for mining, processing, and downstream facilities. This accelerates development amid growing demand for electrification metals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>inaugurazione dell'opera "Per aspera ad astra" di Donato Savin</title><link>https://www.grand-paradis.it/en/news/2026/22-gennaio-2026-inaugurazione-dell%E2%80%99opera-aspera-ad-astra-di-donato-savin</link><description>An artwork titled "Per aspera ad astra" by Donato Savin will be inaugurated on January 22, 2026 at Cogne Acciai Speciali's headquarters in Aosta (Via Paravera 16). This event marks a cultural initiative at the company's main facility.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Tenaris posts 2% rise in quarterly net sales</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/italy-s-tenaris-posts-2-rise-in-quarterly-net-sales-ce7d5dd2de8cf321</link><description>Italian steel pipe maker Tenaris reported a 2% increase in net sales for the third quarter, driven by higher sales across its operations. As the world's leading producer of steel pipes for oil and gas industries, Tenaris generates 95.4% of revenue from pipe production with geographic distribution across North America (45.6%), Asia/Pacific/Middle East/Africa (25.5%), Europe (9.6%), and South America (19.3%).</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired isOplus's oil and gas division for $10 million, gaining pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coating capabilities rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy. The acquisition strengthens Tenaris's offshore market offerings and enables anti-corrosion coating application across facilities in Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rose to 3,140.90 USD/T on January 22, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices reached 3,140.90 USD/T on January 22, 2026, up 0.68% from the previous day and up 19.38% year-over-year. Over the past month, aluminum prices have risen 6.56%, reflecting ongoing market tightness and supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Extends Decline from Record High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures in the US fell to $5.75 per pound, continuing pullback from record high of $6.1 on January 14 as softening demand outweighed tight supply concerns. The Yangshan import premium fell more than 50%, indicating drop in buying amid record high base metal prices pressuring corporate margins.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US copper faces uncertain 2026 outlook</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2771940-viewpoint-us-copper-faces-uncertain-2026-outlook</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts copper prices averaging $5.17/lb in 2026, up from $4.82/lb in 2025, amid narrowing surpluses. Citigroup predicts prices above $5.90/lb by Q2 2026, while Bank of America and TD Cowen also raised forecasts. The copper market saw a 94,000t surplus in the first three quarters of 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Japanese Copper Smelters Still in Talks for 2026 Charges with Miners</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2026-01-22/japanese-copper-smelters-still-talks-2026-charges-miners</link><description>Japanese copper smelters are negotiating 2026 treatment and refining charges with global miners, seeking terms different from those set by China. The negotiations are challenging as smelting capacity expands faster than mined supply, with some miners and smelters agreeing to $0 per metric ton charges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Andy Home: US aluminium consumers are paying the rising cost of tariffs</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2026/01/22/andy-home-us-aluminium-consumers-are-paying-the-rising-cost-of-tariffs</link><description>US aluminum 'all-in price' exceeds $5,000 per metric tonne due to a $560 physical delivery premium on top of tariffs. Prices rose over 17% in the past year amid supply strains. Consumers face shortages impacting automotive, aerospace, and other industries.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Can Recycling Alone Meet Copper Demand? Let’s Talk Facts</title><link>https://resolutioncopper.com</link><description>Resolution Copper discusses whether recycling can satisfy growing copper demand for technologies like EVs, renewables, power grids, and electronics. The article highlights copper's essential role in modern infrastructure and sustainable energy systems. It emphasizes the need for new mining to complement recycling amid surging demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Alcoa Corporation Reports Fourth Quarter and Full Year 2025 Results</title><link>https://news.alcoa.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2026/Alcoa-Corporation-Reports-Fourth-Quarter-and-Full-Year-2025-Results/default.aspx</link><description>Alcoa reported its FY25 financial results with aluminium production increasing 5% primarily due to restarts of smelters in Brazil, Spain, and Norway. The company expects 2026 alumina segment production to range between 9.7 and 9.9 million metric tons, an increase from 2025 driven by productivity improvements.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa shares dip despite 25% earnings boost in FY25</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/23/alcoa-shares-dip-despite-25-earnings-boost-in-fy25/</link><description>Alcoa achieved a 25% earnings boost in FY25 with alumina production dipping 4% due to the full curtailment of the Kwinana refinery, while aluminium production rose 5%. The company also announced a US$200 million joint venture with Japan's Sojitz Corporation to build a gallium extraction plant at its Wagerup refinery in Western Australia.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Overseas alumina transaction</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103734707</link><description>A transaction of 30,000 metric tons of alumina was traded overseas at $305/mt FOB East Australia on January 23, 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>South32 continues stable aluminium performance</title><link>https://aluminiumtoday.com/news/south32-continues-stable-performance-despite-headwinds</link><description>Australian aluminium company South32 reported a 3% increase in alumina production in the December 2025 half year, maintaining stable performance despite industry headwinds.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 23.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides daily updates on global iron and steel prices, including futures for rebar in Shanghai and various regional markets as of January 20-21, 2026. The platform tracks indices, news, and analyses for the iron and steel industry. It features sections on rebar, scrap, and market trends with real-time data.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking in 2026: Cleaner Routes, Tougher Trade Rules and Smarter Supply Chains</title><link>https://www.metallic-group.com/articles/steelmaking-in-2026-cleaner-routes-tougher-trade-rules-and-smarter-supply-chains/</link><description>The steel industry in 2026 is being reshaped by decarbonization technology, tighter trade rules including the EU CBAM effective January 1, 2026, and growing demand for emissions data. The industry is adopting modular technology approaches including EAF modernization, DRI-EAF hydrogen-ready systems, and CCUS upgrades.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global steel industry battles surplus supply, protectionism</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/global-steel-industry-battles-surplus-supply-protectionism/</link><description>India is expected to produce an additional 11.4 million metric tons of crude steel in 2026, increasing from an estimated 154 million metric tons in 2025. The global steel industry continues to face challenges from surplus supply and protectionist trade measures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Nederland unveils packaging steel line with TCCT technology</title><link>https://www.packaginginsights.com/news/tata-steel-nederland-packaging-steel-tcct.html</link><description>Tata Steel Nederland commissioned a new production line using Trivalent Chromium Coating Technology (TCCT) for sustainable packaging steel production that complies with future EU chemical legislation. The technology, combined with Protact polymer-coated packaging steel, reduces chemicals, costs, and supply chain complexity while maintaining food safety standards.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper falls to near two-week low</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40403555</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange dropped 1% to USD12,686 per metric ton in official open outcry activity. This marks a near two-week low amid ongoing market pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Storm Copper Resource Upgraded Ahead of PFS</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/23/northern-neighbors/storm-copper-resource-upgraded-ahead-of-pfs/9500.html</link><description>American West Metals upgraded the Storm Copper resource, which is now 20% larger with 65% of the copper in the higher confidence indicated category. The upgrade reflects improved geological understanding ahead of the prefeasibility study.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Which Copper Developer's Shares Are Flying After a Positive Economic Study for Their Proposed Mine?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/23/which-copper-developers-shares-are-flying-after-a-positive-economic-study-for-their-proposed-mine/</link><description>Celsius Resources completed a definitive feasibility study for a 35-year copper-gold mine project with a maiden ore reserve of 130.2 million tonnes, expecting US$230 million in annual EBITDA during the first 10 years. The company's shares rose 15% following the announcement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper, Gold Set to Be 'Big Winners' in 2026</title><link>https://mining.com.au/copper-gold-set-to-be-big-winners-in-2026/</link><description>White &amp; Case's Mining &amp; Metals 2026 report identifies copper and gold as expected 'big winners' following strong price growth in 2025. Copper reached US$12,000 per tonne in December 2025 due to output reductions from major mines including Escondido, Collahuasi, and Grasberg.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>AWS to Source Low Carbon Nuton Copper from Rio Tinto for U.S. Data Center Infrastructure</title><link>https://esgnews.com/aws-to-source-low-carbon-nuton-copper-from-rio-tinto-for-u-s-data-center-infrastructure/</link><description>AWS and Rio Tinto have partnered to source low-carbon copper produced through Nuton's innovative biohydrometallurgical process, which uses naturally occurring microorganisms to extract copper from primary sulphide ores. The technology eliminates traditional concentrators and smelters, reducing water use and emissions while producing 99.99% pure copper cathode at the mine gate. AWS will provide data and analytics expertise to optimize the process and accelerate commercial deployment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: ESDM estimates Indonesia's nickel production to fall by up to 15% in 2026</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5111197-flash-esdm-estimates-indonesias-nickel-production-to-fall-by-up-to-15-in-2026</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources plans to lower nickel ore production targets for 2026 to 250-260 million tonnes, down from the original 379 million tonnes, representing a 10-15% decrease from 2025 levels. The government aims to maintain supply-demand balance in the global nickel market and support nickel prices, while remaining open to importing nickel ore from the Philippines at current levels of 10-15 million tonnes annually.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia targets nickel prices at $19,000–$20,000 in 2026 after output cuts</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-targets-nickel-prices-at-19-000-20-000-in-2026-after-output-cuts</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources expects global nickel prices to stabilize following the country's announced output cuts for 2026. The production reductions are part of a strategic shift from maximizing supply to maximizing value in the global nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Parabellum Resources Confirms High-Grade Nickel-Cobalt Mineralisation at Miandetta</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/23/parabellum-resources-confirms-high-grade-nickel-cobalt-mineralisation-at-miandetta/</link><description>Parabellum Resources completed Phase 3 drilling at the Miandetta prospect in New South Wales, confirming shallow, high-grade nickel-cobalt mineralisation within the top 50 metres. The company identified notable results including 7 metres at 0.92% nickel and 0.05% cobalt, with mineralization in saprolite material suitable for atmospheric acid leach processing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices showed mixed movements on January 23, 2026, rising to 3175.35 USD/T (up 1.10%) in one report and falling to 3,132 USD/T (down 0.28%) in another. Over the past month, prices have risen between 5.92% and 7.39%, with yearly gains of 18.77% to 20.42%. The commodity remains supported near multi-year highs amid ongoing market volatility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AMU: For LME high grade aluminum, how high is high in a post China cost curve?</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/23/amu-for-lme-high-grade-aluminum-how-high-is-high-in-a-post-china-cost-curve/</link><description>LME aluminum cash prices reached $3,220/t recently, with forecasts predicting up to $4,000/t and 2026 averages in the $3,000s amid a structural shift away from cheap Chinese capacity. The rise is fueled by bullish sentiment, cost-push inflation, and the need for new non-Chinese primary capacity investments. High energy and power risks are limiting supply flexibility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CRU: Fewer imports tighten US steel supply, supporting domestic prices</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/23/cru-fewer-imports-tighten-us-steel-supply-supporting-domestic-prices/</link><description>Lower finished steel imports have supported US domestic prices, with HR coil prices up more than $40 per metric ton month-on-month due to higher seasonal demand and tighter supply. US long products prices also rose amid tight supply and higher scrap costs. Brazilian slab export prices increased by $10/mt to $480/mt fob Brazil.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global steel output falls to 2-year low in December</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/23/global-steel-output-falls-to-2-year-low-in-december/</link><description>Global raw steel production declined 0.4% from November to 139.6 million metric tons in December, marking the lowest monthly production in two years. China accounted for 48.9% of global production at 68.2 million metric tons, its lowest since December 2023, while rest-of-world production rose 1.7% to 71.4 million metric tons.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 2.12% Higher at $5.9110 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601235457/comex-copper-ends-the-week-212-higher-at-59110-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for January delivery rose 12.25 cents per pound, or 2.12%, to $5.9110 over the week, up six of the past nine weeks. On the day, it gained 16.85 cents or 2.93%, marking the largest one-day increase since January 5, 2026. The settlement is the seventh highest this year, off 1.66% from its 52-week high of $6.0105.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to 5.94 USD/Lbs on January 23, 2026, up 2.84% daily, supported by supply risks from a Chilean mine strike offsetting restarts elsewhere and strong demand from renewables and US shipments. Chinese smelters increased exports amid high global prices and domestic property strains. Prices extended a decline from a January record high of 6.11 USD/Lbs due to softening demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel market plays the Indonesia's numbers game – by Andy Home (Reuters) January 23, 2026</title><link>https://republicofmining.com/2026/01/23/nickel-market-plays-the-indonesias-numbers-game-by-andy-home-reuters-january-23-2026/</link><description>Indonesia will cut annual mining permits for nickel ore to 250-260 million wet tons in 2026 from 379 million tons in 2025, according to an energy ministry official. This reduction is part of efforts to manage supply and support market prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian to Acquire Submarine Cable Survey &amp; Installation Solutions Leader ACSM</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/agcm-inspection</link><description>Prysmian announced the acquisition of ACSM, a Spain-based submarine cable installation company, for EUR169 million. The deal strengthens Prysmian's global leadership in submarine cables and expands its service offerings for energy and telecommunications sectors, with closing expected in February 2026.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel Industry Newsletter 1/23/26</title><link>https://steelindustrynews.substack.com/p/steel-industry-newsletter-12326</link><description>The newsletter covers recent steel industry developments including Nucor's pricing strategies, Louisiana securing a site for Hyundai Steel's new mill, and Worthington Steel's $2.4 billion acquisition of Kloeckner &amp; Co. Global steel output has hit near two-year lows amid ongoing trade and tariff pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Dynamics, Inc. (NASDAQ: STLD) Quarterly Earnings Preview</title><link>https://site.financialmodelingprep.com/market-news/steel-dynamics-quarterly-earnings-preview</link><description>Steel Dynamics is preparing to release quarterly earnings on January 26, 2026, with analysts expecting EPS of $1.72 (a 26.5% increase from $1.36 last year) and revenue of approximately $4.54 billion (a 17.2% increase). The company maintains a strong financial position with a debt-to-equity ratio of 0.42 and current ratio of 3.11.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>PRYSMIAN TO ACQUIRE SUBMARINE CABLE SURVEY &amp; INSTALLATION SOLUTIONS LEADER ACSM</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en</link><description>Prysmian plans to acquire Spain-based ACSM, a submarine cable installation company, for €169 million ($198 million). The acquisition will bring subsea surveying, seabed preparation, and installation capabilities in-house, with the transaction expected to close by February.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose to 3,129 CNY/T on January 23, 2026, up 0.68% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 1.10%, though still 5.68% lower than a year ago. Recent news highlights steel rebar futures steadying near five-month highs due to China's record December exports.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel prices today, January 24th: World iron ore prices recover to $114/ton, domestic steel prices remain stable</title><link>https://baonghean.vn/en/gia-thep-hom-nay-241-quang-sat-the-gioi-phuc-hoi-len-114-usdtan-thep-noi-dia-duy-tri-on-dinh-10321275.html</link><description>World iron ore prices recovered to $114 USD per ton on January 24, 2026. Domestic steel prices in Vietnam remained stable amid global recovery trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 24.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>Daily update on global iron and steel prices, news, analyses, and comments for January 24, 2026, covering industry trends and market developments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel rose to 18,710 USD/T on January 23, 2026, up 3.37% from the previous day, after reaching 18,564.13 USD/T earlier that day with a 2.56% increase. Nickel futures fell to around $17,800 per tonne, reversing from a nineteen-month high of $18,700, due to profit-taking and softening Chinese demand. Over the past month, prices have risen 18.54%, and are up 19.15% year-over-year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 24 Jan 2026</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2026/01/24/the-market-in-numbers-24-jan-2026/</link><description>Nickel prices stood at 8.1034 USD/lb on January 24, 2026, down 0.76% daily but up 8.23% monthly.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 1.3 percent - week 3, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-13-percent-week-3-2026-1431863.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending January 24, 2026, was 1.778 million net tons at a 76.9% capacity utilization rate, up 1.3% from the prior week. Year-to-date production through January 24 is up 3.4% from the same period in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 1.3 percent - week 3, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-13-percent-week-3-2026-1431863.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending January 24, 2026, reached 1.778 million net tons, up 1.3% from the previous week at 1.756 million net tons, with capacity utilization at 76.9%. This represents a 4.6% increase from the same week in 2025. Adjusted year-to-date production through January 24 was 6.016 million net tons at 75.9% capacity utilization, up 3.4% year-over-year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price rallies back above $13,000 on supply worries</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-rallies-back-above-13000-on-supply-worries/</link><description>Copper surged over 3% to $13,173.50/t on the LME, a one-week high, driven by long-term supply concerns amid exploding AI demand and investor shifts to hard assets. US critical minerals status and potential tariffs under Trump add upward pressure. Year-to-date in 2026, prices have risen more than 6%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price spikes more than 10% as Chinese buying fuels metals surge</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-spikes-more-than-10-as-chinese-buying-fuels-metals-surge/</link><description>Nickel prices spiked over 10% in London to a high of $18,785 a ton on the LME, the biggest gain in over three years, driven by surging Chinese investor interest and mounting risks to Indonesian production. This extends a 30% rise since mid-December despite oversupply, marking a reversal from excess output and weak EV battery demand. Trading dynamics show Chinese influence with high-volume rallies during Asian hours.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] Refined high-grade NPI prices set to rise further next week</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103736898/smm-nickel-flash-refined-high-grade-npi-prices-set-to-rise-further-next-week</link><description>Refined nickel prices continued rising, with the most-traded SHFE nickel contract (2602) closing at 148,010 yuan/mt on Friday, up 2.52% week-on-week, hitting a weekly high of 150,000 yuan/mt. The LME nickel 3M contract also advanced amid the rally.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia cuts 2026 nickel quota, global prices jump immediately</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/60514/indonesia-cuts-2026-nickel-quota-global-prices-jump-immediately</link><description>Indonesia cut its 2026 nickel quota, leading to immediate strengthening of nickel prices on the LME and Asian exchanges due to growing concerns over tighter supply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Zijin officially puts Julong Copper Mine Phase 2 into production</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2026/01/25/zijin-officially-puts-julong-copper-mine-phase-2-into-production/</link><description>Zijin Mining announced that Phase 2 of the Julong Copper Mine project was officially completed and put into production on January 23, 2026. This expansion enhances the mine's production capacity, supporting global copper supply amid rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Jan '26 Futures Price</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/futures/quotes/ALF26</link><description>Aluminum Jan '26 futures traded at 3,097.50, up 1.20% with a +36.75 gain. Over the past month, prices rose 7.29% from lows, and 52-week performance shows a 16.56% increase. The dollar index decline supported the rally amid stock market gains.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Record high prices pressure Chinese aluminium demand</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2774952-record-high-prices-pressure-chinese-aluminium-demand</link><description>Chinese aluminum prices hit a record 25,075 yuan/t ($3,592/t) due to tight supply and strong sentiment, pressuring demand as some producers consider early Lunar New Year holidays. Social inventories rose to 714,000t by January 8, signaling ample supply amid weak spot demand. Traders anticipate further stock builds in January-February due to high prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Analysis: Processing Fees for Aluminum Billets Remain ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103725189</link><description>On January 5, 2026, SMM A00 aluminum prices surged 850 yuan/mt post-New Year's, causing billet processing fees to drop 0–160 yuan/mt but stay positive initially. By January 6, another 600 yuan/mt rise pushed fees negative despite production costs of 200–300 yuan/mt. The analysis examines producer and trader dynamics behind this trend.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Why Is Alcoa Corporation Stock Gaining Friday?</title><link>https://www.benzinga.com/markets/earnings/26/01/50090888/alcoa-cashes-in-on-higher-aluminum-prices-eyes-more-output-in-2026</link><description>Alcoa reported strong Q4 2025 results with increased alumina and aluminum production, projecting 2026 alumina output at 9.7–9.9 million metric tons and aluminum at 2.4–2.6 million metric tons due to productivity gains and smelter restarts. The Aluminum segment saw a 21% quarter-over-quarter revenue increase from higher pricing and shipments. Cash balance stood at $1.6 billion with $537 million from operations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Gain Support from Macro Tailwinds, Consolidating at High Levels in the Short Term - SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103737147/aluminum-prices-gain-support-from-macro-tailwinds-consolidating-at-high-levels-in-the-short-term-smm-aluminum-morning-me</link><description>SHFE aluminum futures showed slight gains amid supply disturbances including tax policy expectations, compliance checks, transportation issues, and environmental production restrictions in China. Domestic and Indonesian aluminum projects are ramping up steadily, but industry's operating rate is expected to trend downward short-term. Market selling improved slightly, though downstream buying remains weak.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Industry Newsletter 1/23/26</title><link>https://steelindustrynews.substack.com/p/steel-industry-newsletter-12326</link><description>Nucor continues to hold CSP steel price for the 4th week amid January 2026 market analysis. Highlights include Nucor raising HRC to $960/ton, US steel mills hiking coating extras, and global trade imbalances. Other news covers tariffs, production, and corporate developments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 19-month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/519806</link><description>Nickel increased to $18,908/T, the highest level since June 2024. Over the past 4 weeks, nickel has gained significantly as market sentiment remains bullish due to supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price Update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103738363</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price was 149,800-157,800 yuan/mt with an average price of 153,800 yuan/mt, up 5,250 yuan/mt from the previous trading day, reflecting continued strength in Asian markets.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Delayed publication of NPI FOB Indonesia price: pricing notice</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/delayed-publication-of-npi-fob-indonesia-price-pricing-notice/</link><description>Fastmarkets delayed the publication of its Nickel pig iron (10-14% Ni content, fob Indonesia) price assessment originally due on January 20, 2026, due to a technical error, with the database now updated. This price is part of the Steel Raw Materials package and relates to Indonesian nickel production capacities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EGA signs deal to build first US aluminium plant in almost five decades</title><link>https://www.thenationalnews.com/business/2026/01/26/ega-signs-deal-to-build-first-us-aluminium-plant-in-almost-five-decades/</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium (EGA) and Century Aluminum announced a joint venture to build a new primary aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, with a $4 billion investment. The facility will produce 750,000 tonnes of aluminum annually, more than doubling current U.S. production, and create 1,000 permanent jobs plus 4,000 construction positions. Construction is expected to begin by the end of 2026, with production starting before the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum joins EGA project to build first U.S. smelter in almost 50 years</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/CENX/century-aluminum-joins-ega-project-to-build-first-u-s-smelter-in-oq49xwngoo58.html</link><description>Century Aluminum (NASDAQ: CENX) and Emirates Global Aluminium announced a joint development agreement for a 750,000-tonne-per-year primary aluminum smelter in Inola, Oklahoma, with EGA holding 60% and Century 40% ownership. This marks the first new U.S. primary smelter since 1980 and will address the current situation where 85% of domestic aluminum needs are met by imports. Construction is targeted for the end of 2026 with production expected by the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Joins EGA Project to Build First U.S. Smelter in Almost 50 Years</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/281637/Century-Aluminum-Joins-EGA-Project-to-Build-First-U.S.-Smelter-in-Almost-50-Years</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Century Aluminum entered into a joint development agreement to construct the first new primary aluminum production plant in the United States since 1980 in Inola, Oklahoma. The facility will produce 750,000 tonnes annually using EGA's advanced technology, creating 1,000 permanent jobs and 4,000 construction jobs while more than doubling current U.S. production capacity. Detailed engineering is underway with construction expected to start by the end of 2026 and production by the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Major Aluminum Project in Oklahoma Promises Thousands of Jobs</title><link>https://ktul.com/news/local/major-aluminum-project-in-oklahoma-promises-thousands-of-jobs</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Century Aluminum announced a partnership to develop the first new primary aluminum smelter in the U.S. in nearly five decades in Inola, Oklahoma, with planned annual production of 750,000 metric tons. The project will use EGA's most advanced smelting technology and is expected to create approximately 1,000 permanent jobs and 4,000 construction jobs while significantly strengthening domestic aluminum supply. The facility will be located at the Tulsa Port of Inola, providing access to national shipping routes through the Mississippi River system.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Joins EGA Project to Build First U.S. Smelter in Almost 50 Years</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/press-release/century-aluminum-joins-ega-project-build-first-us-smelter-almost-50-years-2026-01-0</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium (EGA) and Century Aluminum have agreed to build a new primary aluminum smelter in Oklahoma, the first in the U.S. since 1980, using advanced EGA technology to double domestic production. The facility will address import dependency for this critical mineral, benefiting industries like automotive, aerospace, and defense while creating manufacturing jobs. Construction is slated to start by late 2026, with production by the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Falls as China Output Declines</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures fell toward CNY 3,100 per ton, hitting a two-week low after official data showed China’s steel production sank to a seven-year low in 2025 despite strong exports. Annual output dropped 4.4% to 961 million tons, falling below the 1 billion threshold and highlighting weak domestic demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nucor increases HRC spot price by $5/ton</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/26/nucor-increases-hrc-spot-price-by-5-ton/</link><description>Nucor's consumer spot price for hot-rolled coil increased to $965 per short ton, up $5 per short ton from the prior week. The West Coast joint venture price also rose $5 to $1,015 per short ton, with lead times of 3 to 5 weeks continuing.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel Falls as China Output Declines</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>China’s steel production fell to a seven-year low of 961 million tons in 2025, down 4.4% year-over-year, due to weak domestic demand despite strong exports. December output hit a two-year low of 68.2 million tons amid property sector strains and government curbs on new capacity. Member mills slightly increased early January output but remained 3.3% below last year's pace.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Steel Production Drops 2% in 2025 Amid Market Pressures – Worldsteel</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/global-steel-production-drops-2-in-2025-amid-market-pressures-worldsteel-2026-1-26/98324</link><description>Global crude steel production by World Steel Association members fell 3.7% year-over-year to 139.6 million tonnes in December 2025, with full-year 2025 output at 1,803.8 million tonnes, down 2.0% from 2024. Asia and Oceania saw the steepest decline at 6.3%, while the Middle East surged 13.9%. EU-27, Other Europe, and South America showed positive growth.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Daily Report on 26 January 2026</title><link>https://www.ferroalloynet.com/report/nickel_daily_report_on_26_january_2026.html</link><description>Daily report on nickel market trends and prices for January 26, 2026, providing updates relevant to recent developments in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Supply-Demand Marginal Changes Limited, Aluminum Prices ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103739462</link><description>LME aluminum closed at $3,195.5/mt, up 0.69%, while SHFE aluminum 2603 closed at 24,380 yuan/mt, up 0.68%. Spot primary aluminum prices edged down, with mainstream transactions at a discount, and aluminum scrap prices showed divergence amid weak downstream demand. The market is expected to hover at highs this week but faces downside pressures ahead of Chinese New Year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Press Metal to gain from higher aluminium prices</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2026/01/27/press-metal-to-gain-from-higher-aluminium-prices</link><description>Press Metal is expected to benefit from higher aluminum prices and favorable alumina costs, with revised LME assumptions at US$2,950 per tonne for 2026. Alumina prices fell 54% year-on-year to US$310 per tonne, improving cost ratios. Forecasts for the company lifted by 5-18% for 2025-2027.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Oklahoma Smelter: $4B Investment Plan</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/americas-aluminum-supply-chain-vulnerability-2026/</link><description>Century Aluminum announces a $4 billion joint venture for an Oklahoma smelter project, reinforcing efforts to bolster America's aluminum supply chain. This initiative highlights vulnerabilities in domestic production and aims to enhance sustainability and security through expanded capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Digitalization: The Key to Steel Decarbonization</title><link>https://www.metalconstructionnews.com/articles/digitalization-the-key-to-steel-decarbonization/</link><description>Digital tools are essential for verifying emission reduction claims and improving manufacturing efficiency in steel production. Digitalization enables supply chain transparency and traceability, helping build trust in low-emissions steel by monitoring sustainability credentials throughout production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Daily Topic of China Commodity Data (January 27, 2026)</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-30081.html</link><description>On January 26, 2026, SunSirs monitored 96 commodities with year-on-year price increases, including 15 in the non-ferrous sector. Recent updates highlight LME copper rises alongside oil price falls and gold breaking $5,000. The commodity price index BPI reached 952 points, up 9 points from the previous day.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Immediate transition to copper is technically and economically feasible</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/2026/01/27/immediate-transition-to-copper-is-technically-and-economically-feasible/</link><description>Rising silver prices are prompting large solar manufacturers to switch to copper for cell metallization, with Chinese firms like Longi adopting copper-based technology. Experts from ISC Konstanz and UNSW indicate that copper-metallized solar modules perform comparably to silver ones with acceptable efficiency trade-offs. This shift could mark 2026 as a milestone in reducing PV industry reliance on costly silver.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>DRC plans to export 100,000 metric tons of copper to the US</title><link>https://news.mongabay.com/2026/01/drc-plans-to-export-100000-metric-tons-of-copper-to-the-us/</link><description>The Democratic Republic of Congo plans to ship 100,000 metric tons of copper from the Tenke Fungurume Mine to the U.S. by end of January, amid U.S. investment in critical minerals. The mine, operated by CMOC Group and Gécamines, supports growing demand from renewables and AI applications. Gécamines aims for long-term sales of up to 500,000 tons of copper from its stakes.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Freeport-McMoRan Boosts 2026, 2027 Capex, Advancing Copper Projects</title><link>https://www.industrialinfo.com/news/article/freeport-mcmoran-boosts-2026-2027-capex-advancing-copper-projects--352397</link><description>Freeport-McMoRan plans $4.3-$4.5 billion in capex for 2026-2027 to expand U.S. copper production by over 50% in the next 4-5 years, focusing on innovation and facilities. The company supplies 70% of U.S. refined copper and anticipates strong global demand from power grids, renewables, and tech. Q4 2025 results were solid despite Grasberg disruptions, with operations resuming in Q2 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Record Copper Prices Highlight the Urgency of New U.S. Supply</title><link>https://www.mining.com/sponsored-content/record-copper-prices-highlight-the-urgency-of-new-u-s-supply/</link><description>Copper prices hit records above $6/lb on COMEX and $13,387/ton on LME due to supply disruptions at mines like Grasberg and Mantoverde, plus trade concerns. Forecasts predict deficits and 24% demand growth by 2035 from electrification. Gunnison Copper restarted production at Johnson Camp Mine in Arizona, advancing sulfide-leaching tech and planning a PEA update.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices experienced a significant correction on January 27 as Trump announced an increase</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103740650/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-correction-on-january-27-as-trump-announced-an-increase</link><description>On January 27, SMM #1 refined nickel prices dropped significantly to an average of 148,100 yuan/mt, down 5,700 yuan/mt from the previous day, amid Trump's announcement of higher tariffs on South Korean goods. SHFE nickel futures also declined 2.48% to 145,200 yuan/mt in the morning session. Despite the correction, nickel prices are likely to rise due to Indonesia's nickel ore quota cuts and supply disruptions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Jump After Top Producer Indonesia Signals 2026 Output Cut</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news/3112-51714-nickel-prices-jump-after-top-producer-indonesia-signals-2026-output-cut</link><description>Indonesia plans to cut nickel production quotas in 2026 to balance supply and demand, causing spot nickel prices to rise to $16,500/tonne from $15,800/tonne and LME three-month contract up 6.4%. The move aims to curb surplus and support prices, similar to DRC's cobalt strategy. Indonesia's market share has grown to 60.2% by 2024.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Challenges and opportunities of the EU battery and raw materials industries</title><link>https://www.pubaffairsbruxelles.eu/event/challenges-and-opportunities-of-the-eu-battery-and-raw-materials-industries-january-27/</link><description>An event on January 27 discusses EU strategies for a domestic EV battery value chain, emphasizing nickel and other raw materials for sustainability and reducing China dependency. Speakers from the Nickel Institute highlight opportunities in battery recycling and secure supply chains via initiatives like RESourceEU. The focus is on metals' role in green mobility and the twin transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian, Versalis Launch Chemical Recycling Chain for Plastic Cable Waste in Italy</title><link>https://esgnews.com/prysmian-versalis-launch-chemical-recycling-chain-for-plastic-cable-waste-in-italy/</link><description>Prysmian and Versalis have established a strategic partnership for chemical recycling of plastic cable insulation. The pilot project will begin in Italy in the second half of 2026, using Versalis's Hoop® technology to recover up to 60% of difficult-to-recycle XLPE insulation.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>AGCM Inspection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/agcm-inspection</link><description>The Italian Competition Authority (AGCM) conducted an inspection at Prysmian's Italian subsidiary regarding a possible anti-competitive arrangement involving price coordination and commercial sales conditions in the Italian low-voltage copper cable market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>