<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:22:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Indonesia nickel smelter forecasts ore demand will reach 350 million tons by 2026</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/12/31/indonesia-nickel-smelter-forecasts-ore-demand-will-reach-350-million-tons-by-2026</link><description>An Indonesian nickel smelter forecasts nickel ore demand to reach 350 million tons by 2026, with imports potentially increasing to 50 million tons as a balancing mechanism. New production capacity is expected online next year amid annual growth of 40-50 million tons. Indonesia plans to reduce mineral production quotas for 2026 to boost prices and revenues.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices surge as Indonesia plans one-third cut in 2026 RKAB quotas</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/analysis/5108592-nickel-prices-surge-as-indonesia-plans-one-third-cut-in-2026-rkab-quotas</link><description>Indonesia's government plans to cut nickel ore mining quotas to 250 million metric tonnes in 2026, down one-third from 379 million tonnes in 2025, sparking market concerns and a surge in nickel prices. Estimated ore consumption is 327 million wmt, creating a potential gap of 77 million wmt, even with up to 25 million tonnes of imports from the Philippines. SHFE nickel futures rose over Yuan 15,000/tonne from December 19-26.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits nine-month high as Indonesia plans to cut output</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-nine-month-high-as-indonesia-plans-to-cut-output/</link><description>Nickel prices hit a nine-month high after Indonesia announced plans to reduce output in 2026 to better match supply with demand and boost prices, as stated by Energy and Mineral Resources Minister Bahlil Lahadalia. The government controls supply via mining quotas (RKABs), with LME nickel rising as much as 4.7% to $16,560 a ton. Indonesian production is central to next year's nickel price outlook.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia nickel smelter group forecasting 2026 ore demand to hit up to 350 million tons</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/indonesia-nickel-smelter-group-forecasting-2026-ore-demand-to-hit-up-to-350-million-tons/</link><description>Indonesia's nickel smelter group forecasts 2026 nickel ore demand to reach up to 350 million tons. This projection aligns with broader industry expectations for increased consumption amid growing production capacities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia navigates nickel market with output cuts, policy shifts</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/122925-indonesia-navigates-nickel-market-with-output-cuts-policy-shifts</link><description>Indonesia plans to cut nickel output in 2026 to support prices and is reversing mining quota policies to regulate supply volatility. These measures aim to stabilize the nickel market amid global demand pressures.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FPX Nickel Joins Mining Association of Canada and UN Global Compact</title><link>https://esgnews.com/fpx-nickel-joins-mining-association-of-canada-and-un-global-compact/</link><description>FPX Nickel has joined the Mining Association of Canada and its Towards Sustainable Mining program, as well as the UN Global Compact, to strengthen its sustainability leadership. These steps align the company with principles on human rights, labor, environment, and anti-corruption while advancing the Baptiste Nickel Project responsibly. The initiatives build on FPX's 2024 Sustainability Report and emphasize stakeholder trust and Indigenous community engagement.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>How 'Phytomining' Could Put the Green in the Green Transition</title><link>https://thetyee.ca/News/2026/01/01/Phytomining-Green-Transition/</link><description>Phytomining uses plants to extract metals like nickel from soil, potentially reducing environmental destruction and human rights abuses associated with traditional mining. This innovative approach could support the green transition by providing a more sustainable method for sourcing critical minerals. The article explores its potential to curb mining impacts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris has acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems for district heating and anti-corrosion coatings in Europe. The acquired business unit has been rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy, enabling anti-corrosion coatings to be applied at Tenaris facilities in Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil. This strategic move aims to reduce delivery times, ensure quality, lower costs, and minimize environmental impact in the offshore market.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion titled “Nuclear: the future of the Italian boilermaking industry” last week at Fondazione Dalmine in Italy, partnering with UCC and featuring experts from industry and institutions. The event focused on nuclear energy's role in Europe’s energy transition, Italy’s manufacturing potential, and technologies like small modular reactors. Tenaris’s Italian mill recently obtained accreditation for ASME III standard materials for nuclear facilities, emphasizing quality and safety.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy's Antitrust Authority (AGCM) has initiated an investigation into major low-voltage copper cable manufacturers, including Prysmian Cavi e Sistemi Italia Srl and others, for alleged price-fixing since 2005. Inspections were conducted yesterday at company offices, supported by Guardia di Finanza. Prysmian shares fell 1.26% in response, though analysts view the impact as negligible given the small revenue share from this market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Year-end aluminium ingot inventory alert sounded! Domestic inventory buildup in Q1 2026 a foregone conclusion</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/year-end-aluminium-ingot-inventory-alert-sounded-domestic-inventory-buildup-in-q1-2026-a-foregone-conclusion-116772</link><description>Domestic aluminium production rose 1.9% year-on-year in December due to new capacities in Inner Mongolia and Xinjiang, increasing aluminium ingot supply. Casting volumes grew 7.7% month-on-month, pressuring inventories, with projections of 730,000 tonnes by end-January 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Off-Season, coupled with high aluminium prices, the proportion of liquid aluminium declined in December</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/off-season-coupled-with-high-aluminium-prices-the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminium-declined-in-december-116778</link><description>Entering January 2026, operating aluminium capacity is expected to increase month-on-month with new projects coming online. High prices and off-season demand contributed to declining liquid aluminium proportions in December.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>EU carbon tax from 2026 set to dent India's steel, aluminium exports</title><link>https://www.maritimegateway.com/eu-carbon-tax-from-2026-set-to-dent-indias-steel-aluminium-exports-gtri/</link><description>Starting January 1, 2026, the EU's CBAM will impose payments on carbon-intensive imports, challenging Indian steel and aluminium exports through price reductions of 15-22%. Coal-fired aluminium production faces high carbon costs, impacting competitiveness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Driving Innovation for a Sustainable Future</title><link>https://www.aluminium-exhibition.com/germany/en-gb/blog/pressemitteilungen/alude2026-showpreparations.html</link><description>ALUMINIUM 2026 in Düsseldorf emphasizes sustainability, particularly secondary aluminum for decarbonization, alongside topics like metal processing, primary production, recycling, automation, casting, and surface finishing. It features cross-sector applications in mobility, construction, and manufacturing, with proven formats like themed pavilions and new accents for innovation and networking. Event director Patrick Herman positions it as a driver for collaboration and societal progress in a sustainable aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[CES Innovation Awards® 2026 Honoree] Portable SSD T7 Resurrected</title><link>https://semiconductor.samsung.com/news-events/tech-blog/ces-innovation-awards-2026-honoree-portable-ssd-t7-resurrected/</link><description>Samsung's Portable SSD T7 Resurrected earns a CES Innovation Award 2026 for its enclosure made from 100% recycled aluminum, maximizing sustainable material use. This design innovation addresses environmental challenges while maintaining high performance in a portable SSD. It showcases advancements in recycled materials for consumer electronics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US steel tariffs cause scrap supply glut</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2769786-viewpoint-us-steel-tariffs-cause-scrap-supply-glut</link><description>US ferrous scrap prices are expected to edge up in January due to slower winter supply flows, but long-term steel tariffs will sustain high scrap supply and limit major increases into 2026. US flat and long steel prices have climbed in December, diverging from declining Turkish rebar prices. Domestic HRC prices in India have risen recently amid mill hikes and import duty extensions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Baosteel hikes January 2026 prices due to rising raw material costs, market optimism</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/chinas-baosteel-hikes-january-2026-prices-due-to-rising-raw-material-costs-market-optimism/158231</link><description>China's Baosteel has raised steel prices for January 2026, ending three months of flat pricing amid rising raw material costs and market optimism. Steel demand in China remains weak despite the hike.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU carbon tax from 2026 set to dent India's steel, aluminium exports</title><link>https://www.maritimegateway.com/eu-carbon-tax-from-2026-set-to-dent-indias-steel-aluminium-exports-gtri/</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) starting January 1, 2026, will impose payments on carbon-intensive imports, potentially forcing Indian steel exporters to accept 15-22% price cuts to retain market access. Blast furnace steel faces highest costs, while scrap-based methods are less affected. This comes amid India-EU free trade talks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel demand to grow 8 per cent in FY26 amid price pressures: Icra</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/steel/steel-demand-to-grow-8-per-cent-in-fy26-amid-price-pressures-icra/articleshow/126038567.cms</link><description>Icra forecasts 8% steel demand growth in FY26 despite price pressures, with domestic HRC prices averaging Rs 50,500 per tonne. Operating profit per tonne is also projected amid these trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>2026 Forecast: Steel Price Trends and the "Ripple Effect" on Fastener Costs</title><link>https://www.highfasteners.com/ru/news/detail/2026-forecast-steel-price-trends-and-the-ripple-effect-on-fastener-costs</link><description>Iron ore prices stabilized at $120-$130/ton exiting 2025, with steel mills restocking heavily ahead of 2026. The forecast discusses steel price trends and their impact on fastener costs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Jindal Steel Surges: Expansion Fuels Massive Capacity Hike and Analyst Buy Call</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/industrial-goodsservices/Jindal-Steel-Surges-Expansion-Fuels-Massive-Capacity-Hike-and-Analyst-Buy-Call/69567b214342f77179f63c1a</link><description>Jindal Steel &amp; Power Limited is expanding its Angul facility, commissioning a new blast furnace (BF-II) with 4.6 mtpa capacity, raising iron-making capacity from 10.42 mtpa to 15.02 mtpa and nearly doubling hot metal capacity to 10.65 mtpa. It also added 3 mtpa via BOF-II, increasing total steelmaking capacity to 12.6 mtpa from 9.6 mtpa. Phase II plans include further expansions by March 2027, targeting 17.02 mtpa iron-making and 15.6 mtpa steel-making capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US steel tariffs cause scrap supply glut</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2769786-viewpoint-us-steel-tariffs-cause-scrap-supply-glut</link><description>US steel tariffs are causing a glut in ferrous scrap supply as North American dealers and exporters flood the domestic market, expected to continue into 2026 amid steady steel production and dampened prices from China. US flat and long steel prices are climbing, while Turkish rebar prices decline, encouraging domestic scrap sales. Scrap prices may edge up in January due to winter supply slowdowns, but tariffs will persist in preventing major increases.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU carbon tax from 2026 set to dent India's steel, aluminium exports</title><link>https://www.maritimegateway.com/eu-carbon-tax-from-2026-set-to-dent-indias-steel-aluminium-exports-gtri/</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) transitions to payments from January 1, 2026, challenging Indian steel and aluminium exports with carbon costs passed to suppliers via price cuts of 15-22%. Blast furnace steel and coal-based aluminium face highest impacts; exporters must adapt production for viability amid India-EU FTA talks. India remains a net steel importer, with exports up 32.6% but domestic consumption rising.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel production in 2026 may remain at 7.2 million tons - GMK Center forecast</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/steel-production-in-2026-may-remain-at-7-2-million-tons-gmk-center-forecast/</link><description>Ukraine's steel production is forecasted to stay at 7.2 million tons in 2026, with an optimistic scenario of 7.6 million tons and pessimistic at 6.3-6.6 million tons.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tariffs Pushed CPER Up 39%, Doubling S&amp;P 500 Returns</title><link>https://247wallst.com/investing/2026/01/01/tariffs-pushed-cper-up-39-doubling-sp-500-returns/</link><description>The United States Copper Index Fund (CPER) surged 39% in 2025, driven by a 50% tariff on copper imports effective August 1, more than doubling the S&amp;P 500's returns. Demand from electric vehicles and data centers supports prices, with JPMorgan forecasting $12,500 per metric ton through mid-2026. Future performance depends on tariff persistence and LME inventory levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Capstone Copper Provides Update on Labour Negotiations at Mantoverde Operation</title><link>https://capstonecopper.com/news/capstone-copper-provides-update-on-labour-negotiations-at-mantoverde-operation/</link><description>Union #2 at Capstone Copper's Mantoverde mine in Chile, representing 22% of the workforce, initiated a strike on January 2, 2026, after failed negotiations. Operations will continue at up to 30% of normal production during the strike. The company emphasizes safe reductions and its focus on copper production growth amid labor risks.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia hints at sharp drops in nickel supplies, sending prices higher</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/indonesia-hints-at-sharp-drops-in-nickel-supplies,-sending-prices-higher-48042</link><description>Nickel prices on the London Metal Exchange jumped around 5% to their highest levels in several months following comments from Indonesia’s Minister of Energy and Mineral Resources about reducing nickel production starting in 2026 to rebalance supply and demand. Three-month nickel contracts rose to $16,560 per metric ton, the highest since March. The remarks triggered an immediate market rally.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia stops nickel mining after delay in work plan approval</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/my/node/787843</link><description>Vale Indonesia has halted nickel mining due to a delay in work plan approval. Nickel futures on the London Metal Exchange were 1% higher at US$16,855 a tonne by 11:15am Singapore time. The metal surged more than expected amid ongoing supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Forecast: Top Trends for Nickel in 2026</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/nickel-price-forecast-top-trends-nickel-2026</link><description>Analyst Manthey predicts nickel prices will remain under pressure throughout 2026 and struggle to hold above US$16,000. This outlook reflects expectations of continued market challenges. Supply and demand dynamics are key factors influencing the forecast.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash]: Nickel &amp; High-Grade NPI Prices Surge, Discount Widens</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103700968/SMM-Nickel-Flash:-Nickel-High-Grade-NPI-Prices-Surge-Discount-Widens</link><description>Nickel prices continued to rise this week, with SMM announcing domestic prices suspended during the New Year holiday and overseas prices resuming on Jan 2. High-grade NPI prices surged, widening the discount. This reflects ongoing bullish trends in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts nickel mining on delayed work plan approval</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/vale-indonesia-halts-nickel-mining-delayed-work-plan-approval</link><description>Vale Indonesia has suspended operations at its nickel mines due to a delay in receiving approval for its annual work plan from authorities. The company expects approval soon and states the delay will not impact overall operational sustainability. This occurs amid Indonesia's plans to cut nickel output, contributing to rising nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia stops nickel mining after delay in work plan approval</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/node/787843</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia has suspended nickel mining operations due to a delay in annual work plan approval from authorities. This halt affects one of Indonesia's largest nickel producers, which is investing in HPAL plants for EV battery materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The High-Risk, High-Reward Case for The Metals Company in 2026</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/high-risk-high-reward-case-metals-company-2026-2601/</link><description>The Metals Company (TMC) pioneers deep-sea mining with technological innovations like autonomous underwater vehicles and remotely operated platforms to extract polymetallic nodules rich in nickel and other battery metals. These advancements reduce costs and enable scaling, supported by partnerships such as Korea Zinc's investment, amid surging demand for clean-energy minerals. However, risks include environmental scrutiny, regulatory challenges, and competition from recycling and urban mining innovations promoting sustainability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel still capped by surplus</title><link>https://think.ing.com/articles/nickel-still-capped-by-surplus/</link><description>Indonesia's nickel supply growth, particularly via HPAL technology converting low-grade laterite ore to battery-grade nickel, will keep the market in surplus through 2026 despite EV demand. Environmental concerns over HPAL's acid use and waste are increasing scrutiny, potentially impacting future approvals and supply. Shifts to LFP batteries, which use less nickel, further cap demand for nickel-intensive chemistries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>BofA Sees Growth Potential for Prysmian from US Tariffs</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/bofa-sees-growth-potential-for-prysmian-from-us-tariffs-ce7d59dddf88f323</link><description>Bank of America projects that US copper tariffs imposed by President Trump could boost Prysmian's 2026 EBITDA by EUR500 million to EUR1 billion, representing up to 30% of estimates. The advantage stems from Prysmian's copper cable production now being almost entirely US-based following the Encore Wire acquisition, with potential 10% price increases in medium and low-voltage segments where imports face 41% average tariffs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance after reporting third-quarter revenue of EUR5.03 billion, 3% above consensus, driven by strong Renewable Transmission and Power Grids performance. Analysts note the company is likely not yet seeing copper tariff benefits, but expect significant positive impacts in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium hits $3,000 after 3 years as supply tightens</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/aluminium-hits-3-000-3-years-supply-tightens-2601/</link><description>Aluminium prices hit $3,000 per tonne for the first time in over three years due to tightening supply. The surge raises questions on investment strategies amid ongoing market dynamics. No further details on specific drivers provided in the snippet.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Move over gold and silver: Copper, aluminium head for monster rally in 2026; household goods to get costlier</title><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/commodities/move-over-gold-and-silver-copper-aluminium-head-for-monster-rally-in-2026-household-goods-to-get-costlier-13755091.html</link><description>Aluminum prices climbed past USD 3,000 a tonne for the first time in over three years, driven by supply constraints like China's smelting caps and Europe's reduced output. Demand from construction, renewables, and infrastructure remains strong, with futures up 17% last year. This rally is increasing costs for household goods like appliances.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The 2026 shifting focus reshapes the US critical minerals strategy beyond rare-earth</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/the-2026-shifting-focus-reshapes-the-us-critical-minerals-strategy-beyond-rare-earth-116706</link><description>US critical minerals policy in 2026 prioritizes domestic processing, energy efficiency, and lower-cost technologies for metals like aluminum amid rising electricity demand from AI data centers. It shifts from new mines to refining and smelting alternatives to reduce emissions and power costs. This supports high-risk minerals and technologies for domestic processing in energy and manufacturing sectors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steelmakers Prep for $1.6 Billion in 1Q Project Starts</title><link>https://www.industrialinfo.com/iirenergy/industry-news/article/us-steelmakers-prep-for-16-billion-in-1q-project-starts--350513</link><description>U.S. steelmakers like U.S. Steel and Cleveland-Cliffs are preparing over $1.6 billion in steel-manufacturing projects set to begin construction in Q1 2026, focusing on capacity expansions and restarts to meet rising demand. Key projects include restarting Furnace B at U.S. Steel's Granite City Steel Works and Cleveland-Cliffs replacing furnaces at Butler Steel Works for efficiency gains. Nippon Steel commits to no closures of U.S. Steel facilities before 2035.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Industry praises Trump tariffs, farmers feel the strain</title><link>https://katv.com/news/local/steel-industry-praises-trump-tariffs-farmers-feel-the-strain</link><description>US steel industry leaders praise Trump tariffs for countering global oversupply and subsidies from countries like China, benefiting domestic production without shortages. W&amp;W AFCO Steel, focused on infrastructure, reports positive impacts from tariffs driving fairer market dynamics. The company sources only domestic steel for projects like bridges and stadiums.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Sustainability Indicators Report 2025</title><link>https://worldsteel.org</link><description>The World Steel Association released its Sustainability Indicators Report 2025, presenting nineteen sustainability indicators for the steel industry along with a historical overview. This report underscores the industry's commitment to transparent data disclosure, continual improvement in environmental performance, and pathways to reduce CO2 emissions. It highlights steel's role in the circular economy and sustainable practices like water management and air quality control.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU's carbon border tax on heavy industry goods goes into effect, risking trade escalation</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2026/01/01/eus-carbon-border-tax-on-heavy-industry-goods-goes-into-effect-risking-trade-escalation</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) took effect on 1 January 2026, requiring steel and aluminium exporters to pay for CO2 emissions linked to their production. This measure aims to protect EU manufacturers from carbon leakage and encourage global adoption of carbon pricing and cleaner production methods. Critics argue it acts as protectionism, potentially raising costs and complicating trade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Roadmap for Iron &amp; Steel Manufacturing</title><link>https://www.aist.org</link><description>AIST unveiled the Roadmap for Iron and Steel Manufacturing, funded by the U.S. Department of Commerce and NIST, outlining technologies, infrastructure, and workforce strategies to decarbonize the U.S. iron and steel industry. The roadmap focuses on revolutionizing U.S. global leadership for a sustainable industrial supply chain. It emphasizes innovation to strengthen competitiveness while addressing environmental challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Exclusive interview with José Jiménez from Atlantic Copper - Transforming e-scrap</title><link>https://icm.ch/ierc-2026-interview-with-jose-jimenez-transforming-e-scrap-atlantic-copper</link><description>Atlantic Copper, a leading European copper producer, discusses its CirCular project, which valorizes e-scrap from recycled electronics using advanced metallurgical processes and circular economy principles. The initiative addresses resource scarcity, reduces landfill waste and CO₂ emissions, and aligns with the EU Green Deal, with production set to start in the second half of 2026. Sponsorship of IERC 2026 underscores their commitment to innovation, collaboration, and sustainability in copper production for electrification and renewable energy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Higher on Mine Suspension</title><link>https://www.admis.com/nickel-higher-on-mine-suspension/</link><description>Nickel rose 1.6% to $16,910, breaking 14-month highs due to Vale Indonesia's mine suspension and the government's plan to cut nickel ore output by a third in 2026. The move aims to support prices amid prior oversupply. Other metals like aluminum also gained on supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ultrahigh-Nickel Cathodes Near Density Limit</title><link>https://bioengineer.org/ultrahigh-nickel-cathodes-near-density-limit/</link><description>Researchers have developed ultrahigh-nickel single-crystalline oxide cathodes that achieve unprecedented particle sizes with pristine structural order, addressing capacity degradation and instability in lithium-ion batteries. These cathodes approach the theoretical density limit, enhancing volumetric capacity, cycle life, and safety for electric vehicles. The innovation supports industrial scalability and sustainable energy storage solutions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Year-End Aluminum Ingot Inventory Alert Sounded! Domestic Inventory Buildup in Q1 2026 a Foregone Conclusion - SMM Analysis</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701077/year-end-aluminum-ingot-inventory-alert-sounded-domestic-inventory-buildup-in-q1-2026-a-foregone-conclusion-smm-analysis</link><description>Domestic aluminum production increased 1.9% YoY and 4.0% MoM in December due to new capacities in Inner Mongolia and Xinjiang, boosting supply. Casting volumes rose, reducing liquid aluminum proportion to 75.1% expected in January 2026, pressuring ingot inventories to build up to around 730,000 mt by end-January. High prices and steady shipments amplify inventory pressure ahead of Chinese New Year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>National subsidy policy funds disbursed, inventory buildup reality limits upside potential for aluminium prices</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/national-subsidy-policy-funds-disbursed-inventory-buildup-reality-limits-upside-potential-for-aluminium-prices-116787</link><description>New aluminum projects in China and Indonesia ramped up production, with a new Inner Mongolia project powering on December 20, expecting further daily output growth. High prices and environmental controls suppressed downstream demand, leading to inventory buildup to 660,000 tonnes. Despite subsidy funds for consumer trade-ins boosting medium-term demand, weak spot consumption caps price upside.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vedanta's Q3 Production Update: Aluminium &amp; Zinc Surge, But Oil &amp; Gas Dips - Investor Alert!</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/Commodities/Vedantas-Q3-Production-Update-Aluminium-and-Zinc-Surge-But-Oil-and-Gas-Dips-Investor-Alert/69595c4b1ecad49ffda3e6bc</link><description>Vedanta Ltd reported a 1% rise in aluminium output for Q3 FY24 (December quarter). Mined metal production increased 4% at Zinc India and 28% at Zinc International, with saleable iron ore up 3%. Oil &amp; gas and steel production declined, reflecting mixed segment performance.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Q3 production: Aluminium, zinc, iron ore up; steel, oil &amp; gas down</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/metals-mining/vedanta-q3-production-aluminium-zinc-iron-ore-up-steel-oil-gas-down/articleshow/126325108.cms</link><description>Mining giant Vedanta Ltd reported rises in aluminium, zinc, and iron ore production during the December quarter. Aluminium output specifically increased, contributing to growth in key metal segments. Steel and oil &amp; gas production declined in the same period.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Sustainable Innovation Powers Aluminium Can Market Expansion</title><link>https://www.nextmsc.com/news/sustainable-innovation-powers-aluminium-can-market-expansion</link><description>Sustainability is driving growth in the aluminum can market, with Ball Corporation forecasting global demand of 470 billion units by 2026, particularly in India. The company emphasizes aluminum's infinite recyclability, innovations in retort technology and refill systems, and investments in low-carbon production like ELYSIS technology. Ball has reduced Scope 1 and 2 emissions by 21% by 2024 and aims for 85% recycled content.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever debut carbon-free aluminium aerosol packaging</title><link>https://worldaerosols.com/news/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-debut-carbon-free-aluminium-aerosol-packaging/</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever have launched an innovative aerosol can using 50% ELYSIS carbon-free aluminum and 50% post-consumer recycled content, eliminating direct GHG emissions from smelting. This breakthrough, ahead of COP30, combines low-carbon primary aluminum with high recycled content to decarbonize packaging in personal and home care sectors. Executives highlight its role in delivering tangible sustainability benefits and meeting consumer demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>2026 Steel Price Outlook: Will Scrap Steel Price continue late 2025 uptick or is this the same old seasonality story?</title><link>https://recycleyourmetal.com/2026-steel-price-outlook-will-scrap-steel-price-continue-late-2025-uptick-or-is-this-the-same-old-seasonality-story/</link><description>December 2025 steel scrap prices showed a slight increase, sparking hope for 2026, but historical data from 2023-2025 reveals recurring winter upticks followed by declines throughout the year. Philadelphia busheling prices peaked in early year periods before dropping significantly. Market participants question if current gains have lasting power beyond seasonality.[5]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SSAB Americas raises prices for rolled steel by at least $40/t</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/ssab-americas-raises-prices-for-rolled-steel-by-at-least-40-t/</link><description>The American division of Swedish steel manufacturer SSAB has announced a price increase of at least $40 per short ton for all its rolled steel products. This adjustment reflects ongoing market dynamics in the US steel sector.[7]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>CCTV+: Xi Outlines Main Directions for Developing New Quality Productive Forces</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2026/01/03/cctv-xi-outlines-main-directions-for-developing-new-quality-productive-forces/</link><description>Chinese President Xi Jinping emphasized technological innovation and upgrading in traditional industries like steel during inspections at Bensteel Group. He stressed the steel industry's role as a fundamental sector for the real economy and the need for sci-tech empowerment in manufacturing. Xi advocated continuing to strengthen manufacturing and mastering independent technologies for Chinese modernization.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Goldman Sachs Research: Copper prices to decline in 2026</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/goldman-sachs-research-copper-pries-to-decline-in-2026/</link><description>Goldman Sachs Research forecasts copper prices to decline to an average of $10,710 per metric ton in the first half of 2026, ranging $10,000-$11,000 for the year, due to a global supply surplus despite strong demand from grid and power infrastructure. Potential U.S. tariffs on refined copper imports of at least 25% could boost demand next year. Longer-term, prices are expected to rise, reaching $15,000 per metric ton by 2035 as demand outpaces supply from 2029.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Are Forecast to Decline Somewhat from Record Highs in 2026</title><link>https://www.goldmansachs.com/insights/articles/copper-prices-forecast-to-decline-from-record-highs-in-2026</link><description>Goldman Sachs Research predicts copper prices will decline to $10,000-$11,000 in 2026 from record highs, due to ongoing global supply surplus, despite rallies from lower interest rates, weaker USD, and AI spending. Chinese demand fell -8% year-on-year in Q4 2025. U.S. tariffs on refined copper imports by mid-2026 could increase demand, with long-term forecasts at $15,000 per tonne by 2035.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, silver, and copper prices surge again — here's the 2026 gold, silver, and copper outlook amid policy risks, supply deficits and structural demand</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/gold-silver-and-copper-prices-surge-again-heres-the-2026-gold-silver-and-copper-outlook-amid-policy-risks-supply-deficits-and-structural-demand/articleshow/126259059.cms</link><description>Copper ended 2025 near $5.6787 per pound, up 36% for the year, supported by AI infrastructure, data centers, green energy demand, and supply disruptions in Indonesia, Chile, and Peru. Analysts forecast higher metals prices in 2026 amid policy risks and tightening supply. Current prices hover around $5.51–$5.80 per pound.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price plunges in New York after hitting new high in London</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-nears-13000-on-tariffs-woes-supply-strain/</link><description>Copper prices surged toward $13,000 a tonne in London on Monday, up 1.6% after a 6.6% intraday jump, amid mine outages and U.S. tariff speculation driving a 35% yearly gain. New York futures plunged 6% to $5.56 a pound after erasing gains. Long-term strain expected from energy transition demand tripling by 2045, potentially causing deficits as early as 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Kamoa-Kakula smelter produces its first copper anodes</title><link>https://africanminingmarket.com/kamoa-kakula-smelter-produces-its-first-copper-anodes/24525/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced that the Kamoa-Kakula smelter in the DRC has produced its first copper anodes using its state-of-the-art 500,000-tonne-per-annum facility. This milestone advances on-site copper processing, enhancing efficiency and reducing reliance on external refineries. The development supports sustainable production amid growing global copper demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Jump After Top Producer Indonesia Signals 2026 Output Cut</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news/3112-51714-nickel-prices-jump-after-top-producer-indonesia-signals-2026-output-cut</link><description>Spot nickel rose to $16,500 a tonne from $15,800, with the LME three-month contract up 6.4% on Dec. 30, following Indonesia's plan to cut 2026 nickel production to balance supply and demand amid rising LME inventories. The country, now holding 60.2% of global market share, aims to curb surplus, support prices, and limit environmental impact. This mirrors DRC's cobalt production quotas to lift prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Analysis] 2025 Nickel Market Recap &amp; 2026 Outlook: Oversupply to Weigh on Prices</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103690997/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-2025-Nickel-Market-Recap-2026-Outlook:-Oversupply-to-Weigh-on-Prices-</link><description>Late December news of Indonesia planning significant 2026 nickel ore quota cuts sparked bullish sentiment, driving LME nickel prices to around $16,000/mt from yearly lows. The 2025 recap shows quarterly price fluctuations due to tariffs, inventories, and demand weakness, with social inventory up 41% YoY by mid-December. For 2026, oversupply is expected to pressure prices despite supply cut expectations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>How 2026 will reshape the US critical minerals resilience</title><link>https://www.mining.com/how-2026-will-reshape-the-us-critical-mineral-resilience/</link><description>Federal attention is shifting toward metals processing innovation beyond rare earths, with emphasis on technologies that reduce emissions and production costs while maintaining global competitiveness. Companies demonstrating reliable and cost-effective processing technologies will be positioned for federal funding as the US prioritizes critical mineral independence and sustainable mining practices.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Off-Season, coupled with high aluminium prices, the proportion of liquid aluminium declined in December</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/off-season-coupled-with-high-aluminium-prices-the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminium-declined-in-december-116778</link><description>High aluminum prices combined with the off-season led to a decline in the proportion of liquid aluminum in December. This reflects broader market trends affecting aluminum usage and supply dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,096 Yuan/MT on January 2, 2026, down 0.32% daily amid soft Chinese demand, with rebar futures maintaining pullbacks from recent highs. Forecasts predict trading at 3014.96 Yuan/MT by quarter-end and 2868.13 in 12 months. Recent news highlights steel rises on improving profitability and pressures from regulatory export concerns.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 931.97 USD/T on January 2, 2026, down 0.32% daily, though up 2.87% monthly and 31.63% yearly. Forecasts expect 949.49 USD/T by quarter-end and 1042.73 in 12 months. Recent updates note rises to 940 USD/T on December 31 amid improving trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM: Copper Wire &amp; Cable Industry's Jan Operating Rate to Edge Up MoM, Still Below Normal</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701113/SMM:-Copper-Wire-Cable-Industrys-Jan-Operating-Rate-to-Edge-Up-MoM-Still-Below-Normal</link><description>SMM reports that China's copper wire and cable industry's operating rate for January 2026 is expected to edge up month-over-month but remain below normal levels. Domestic prices are suspended during the New Year holiday, with overseas prices resuming on January 2. This reflects ongoing market adjustments amid high prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM: Copper Wire &amp; Cable Operating Rate Drops Further Amid High Prices, Holidays</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103700497/SMM:-Copper-Wire-Cable-Operating-Rate-Drops-Further-Amid-High-Prices-Holidays</link><description>SMM indicates that the operating rate in China's copper wire and cable sector has dropped further due to high copper prices and holiday effects. This trend highlights supply chain pressures in the industry. Contact details provided for further research reports.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Austral Resources Defies Weather, Exceeds Copper Output Targets</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/02/austral-resources-defies-weather-exceeds-copper-output-targets/</link><description>Austral Resources (ASX:AR1) exceeded its Q4 copper production targets with 2,643 tonnes despite extreme weather in Northwest Queensland. December production hit a record 910 tonnes since the 2023 restructure, with no environmental issues and stable processing operations. Access to the Rocklands site is restricted due to flooding, but recovery is expected soon.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Austral Resources Beats Q4 Copper Output Guidance Despite Record Weather</title><link>https://smallcaps.com.au/article/austral-resources-beats-q4-copper-output-guidance-despite-record-weather</link><description>Austral Resources surpassed Q4 copper production guidance of 2,610 tonnes, achieving 2,643 tonnes amid severe wet season weather. December output exceeded 910 tonnes, the highest post-2023 restructure, with Lady Annie and Mt Kelly sites maintaining full capacity. The company advances exploration with a 2026 drill program targeting oxide resources near processing facilities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries partners with Sphere Corp in landmark ENC deal</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/02/nickel-industries-partners-with-sphere-corp-in-landmark-enc-deal/</link><description>Nickel Industries announced a strategic partnership with Sphere Corp, valuing its ENC HPAL project at US$2.4 billion, with Sphere acquiring a 10% stake and entering an offtake agreement for nickel cathode. The ENC project targets annual production of 72,000 tonnes of nickel metal upon commissioning, expected in early Q1 2026. This deal marks the first offtake for ENC material into Western markets, targeting aerospace and EV sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Rockets 8% as SpaceX Supplier Buys Into US$2.4B ENC HPAL Project</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/nickel-industries/</link><description>Nickel Industries' shares rose 8% following Sphere Corp's investment in the US$2.4 billion ENC HPAL project. Sphere, a SpaceX supplier, is acquiring a stake, supporting the project's development for nickel production. The deal highlights growing interest in Nickel Industries' capacity expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/513911</link><description>Aluminum increased to 2999.00 USD/T, the highest since April 2022. Over the past 4 weeks, Aluminum gained 3.64%, and in the last 12 months, it increased 18.54%. The price rise reflects tightening supply conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel development minister sets agenda for growth in 2026</title><link>https://authorityngr.com/2026/01/02/steel-development-minister-sets-agenda-for-growth-in-2026/</link><description>Nigeria's Steel Development Minister outlines 2026 plans to revitalize Ajaokuta Steel Complex via MoUs with Chinese investors and original manufacturers, alongside $500 million in mini-LNG plants for power supply. Investments include a $400 million steel plant by Inner Galaxy Group in Ewekoro and Orbit Galvanised Steel Plant commissioning, boosting local production, jobs, and capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel fell to 16,760 USD/T on January 2, 2026, down 0.48% from the previous day, though it has risen 12.97% over the past month and 10.27% year-over-year. UK nickel futures surged to $15,600 per tonne, the highest since May, after hitting four-year lows, as markets reconsider oversupply views. Indonesia proposed a 34% reduction in nickel output for 2026 to address oversupply and deteriorating ore grades.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel reaches 14-month high following Vale Indonesia's halt to mining</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/01/02/nickel-reaches-14month-high-following-vale-indonesias-halt-to-mining</link><description>Nickel prices hit a 14-month high after Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to a delay in annual production plan approval. The LME three-month nickel rose 1.4% to $16,875 per metric ton. Indonesia's planned cut in ore production by a third by 2026 further supported prices amid previous oversupply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries says South Korea's Sphere to buy 10% stake in Indonesian project</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-industries-says-south-koreas-sphere-to-buy-10-stake-in-indonesian-project/</link><description>South Korea's Sphere Corp will acquire a 10% stake in Nickel Industries' Excelsior Nickel Cobalt HPAL project in Indonesia's Central Sulawesi, capable of producing MHP, nickel sulphate, and cathode. The deal values the project at $2.4 billion and includes offtake agreements, amid soaring nickel prices from Indonesia's output cut plans. Funding is expected early Q1 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>South Korea's Sphere to invest in Indonesian Ni project</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2771207-south-korea-s-sphere-to-invest-in-indonesian-ni-project</link><description>South Korea's Sphere will invest in a 10% stake of Nickel Industries' Excelsior nickel project in Indonesia, with production starting April-June 2026 and offtake of 10% nickel cathode. Indonesian MHP capacity is expanding significantly, with prices recently assessed at $132.50/mtu. The investment aligns with rising nickel prices from planned output cuts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel reaches 14-month high following Vale Indonesia's halt to mining</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/01/02/nickel-reaches-14month-high-following-vale-indonesias-halt-to-mining</link><description>Nickel prices surged to a 14-month high of $16,945 per metric ton after Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to a delay in production plan approval. This follows Indonesia's announcement to cut ore production by a third by 2026 to support prices amid oversupply. The event highlights sustainability efforts through regulated supply in nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to 3,023.10 USD/T on January 2, 2026, up 0.91% daily amid concerns of insufficient supply. China, the top producer, prioritizes preventing overcapacity after breaching its 45 million ton cap, forcing smelters to limit 2026 output. UK futures exceeded $3,000 for the first time since 2022 due to supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 36-week High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel increased to 941.00 USD/T, marking the highest level since April 2025. Over the past 4 weeks, Hot-Rolled Coil Steel gained 2.87%, and in the last 12 months, it rose 31.63%. This reflects upward momentum in steel prices amid recent market trends.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Winter weather a factor as scrap market debates January pricing</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/02/winter-weather-a-factor-as-scrap-market-debates-january-pricing/</link><description>US steelmakers are optimistic for 2026 with Section 232 tariffs supporting price hikes for long and flat products, but scrap price increases may be limited to $20-40/gt in January due to weather-reduced flows and historical trends. Mills like Oregon Steel Mills raised plate prices by $40/ton. Disagreement persists on scrap pricing amid barge issues and shifts in sourcing.[3]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines begins copper anode production at new Congo smelter</title><link>https://www.mining.com/ivanhoe-mines-begins-copper-anode-production-at-new-congo-smelter/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines started copper anode production on December 29, 2025, at its Kamoa-Kakula direct-to-blister smelter in the DRC, five weeks after heat-up and one week after first concentrate feed. The smelter has a 500,000 tonnes per annum capacity, the largest in Africa upon full ramp-up by year-end. 2026 production guidance is 380,000-420,000 tonnes, with sales boosted by 20,000 tonnes from destocking amid high copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Greenland grants 30-year permit to EU-backed Molybdenum mine</title><link>https://www.mining.com/greenland-grants-30-year-permit-to-eu-backed-molybdenum-mine/</link><description>Greenland Resources has received a 30-year permit for its Malmbjerg molybdenum mine, supported by the European Raw Materials Alliance. The project has off-take agreements with Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali and Finland's Outokumpu. Greenland’s Minister highlighted it as a step toward economic autonomy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices top $3000 for the first time since 2022 as supply risks grow</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/news/aluminum-prices-top-3000-for-the-first-time-since-2022-as-supply-risks-grow/articleshow/126303415.cms</link><description>Global aluminium prices surged to $3,000 per tonne, the highest in over three years. The increase is driven by China's production cap and rising demand in key sectors. Supply risks continue to support the upward trend.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Year-End Aluminum Ingot Inventory Alert Sounded! Domestic Inventory Buildup in Q1 2026 a Foregone Conclusion</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701077/year-end-aluminum-ingot-inventory-alert-sounded-domestic-inventory-buildup-in-q1-2026-a-foregone-conclusion-smm-analysis</link><description>Domestic aluminum production increased 1.9% year-over-year and 4.0% month-over-month in December, driven by ongoing commissioning of new electrolytic aluminum projects in Inner Mongolia and Xinjiang. Casting volumes are expected to continue increasing before Chinese New Year, with domestic aluminum ingot inventory projected to reach around 730,000 tonnes by end-January 2026, creating inventory buildup pressure in Q1.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Macro policies remain positive, aluminium prices hit new highs during the week</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/macro-policies-remain-positive-aluminium-prices-hit-new-highs-during-the-week-fundamental-negative-feedback-suppresses-post-holiday-upside-momentum-116785</link><description>New aluminum projects in China and Indonesia continued ramping up production, with a new Inner Mongolia facility successfully powering on December 20. However, high prices suppressed downstream demand, with the operating rate of leading domestic aluminum processing enterprises falling to 59.9%, while inventory is forecast to rise to 730,000 tonnes by end-January 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/513911</link><description>Aluminum prices reached $2,999 per tonne, the highest level since April 2022, as China faces pressure to restrain output growth in 2026 due to approaching its 45 million ton annual production cap. The commodity gained 3.64% over the past four weeks and 18.54% over the past 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises Past $3,000</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/te_news:514029:0-aluminum-rises-past-3-000/</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK surpassed $3,000 per tonne for the first time since 2022 at the turn of the year, driven by growing concerns about insufficient global supply amid structural constraints in production capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Move over gold and silver: Copper, aluminium head for monster rally in 2026</title><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/commodities/move-over-gold-and-silver-copper-aluminium-head-for-monster-rally-in-2026-household-goods-to-get-costlier-13755091.html</link><description>Aluminum prices climbed past $3,000 per tonne for the first time in over three years, lifted by structural supply constraints including China's smelting capacity caps and reduced European output due to high power costs. Strong long-term demand from construction, renewable energy, and infrastructure projects continues to support prices, with futures rising 17% in 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Higher on Mine Suspension</title><link>https://www.admis.com/nickel-higher-on-mine-suspension/</link><description>Nickel rose 1.6% to $16,910, breaking 14-month highs following the suspension of Vale's Indonesia mine. Recent support comes from Indonesia's announcement to cut nickel ore output by a third in 2026 to support prices. This occurs amid broader base metal movements, with demand in China remaining resilient.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts mining activities on delayed approval for 2026 output plan</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/vale-indonesia-halts-mining-activities-on-delayed-approval-for-2026-output-plan/</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to delays in obtaining government approval for its 2026 production plan. Indonesia's nickel smelter association FINI forecasts domestic demand will reach 340-350 million metric tons in 2026, representing an annual increase of up to 50 million tons.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel notches 14-month high after Vale Indonesia halts mining</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40400503</link><description>Nickel reached its highest price in more than 14 months following Vale Indonesia's suspension of mining activities. The price increase reflects market response to Indonesia's announced production cuts designed to support commodity prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>COMMODITIES 2026: Mexican Aluminum Prices Poised to Rise After Atypical Year</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/122425-commodities-2026-mexican-aluminum-prices-poised-to-rise-after-atypical-year-sources-say</link><description>Mexican aluminum industry sources expect 2026 to bring price increases and a more dynamic market despite ongoing Trump tariffs. Prices climbed back to $330/mt by year-end 2025, with some sources predicting premiums could surpass $400/mt.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 04.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides daily updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar 3-month term and various 1-month futures for Turkey, China, Europe, and North America, all showing no change as of 02.01.2026. The platform offers analyses and comments on industry trends. This reflects stable futures pricing at the start of 2026.[6]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fertiliser, steel prices fall; cement remains stable</title><link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1964990/fertiliser-steel-prices-fall-cement-remains-stable</link><description>Steel bar prices in Pakistan have fallen to a range of Rs220,000 to Rs230,000 per tonne from Rs240,000 to Rs250,000 per tonne as of early January 2026, due to weak demand. The Secretary General of the Pakistan Association of Large Steel Producers noted leading brands at Rs226,000 per tonne, with some as low as Rs215,000. This decline aligns with broader price reductions in fertilizers while cement prices remain stable amid rising construction demand.[4]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts mining amid delayed 2026 output approval</title><link>https://www.thejakartapost.com/business/2026/01/04/vale-indonesia-halts-mining-amid-delayed-2026-output-approval.html</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia suspended mining activities due to delays in government approval of its 2026 annual production plan (RKAB). The halt comes as Indonesia's government plans to cut nickel output quotas to support prices, with Deputy Mining Minister Yuliot Tanjung stating the approval is "currently being consolidated."</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris to invest in hydrogen steelmaking in Italy</title><link>https://eurometal.net/tenaris-to-invest-in-hydrogen-steelmaking-in-italy/</link><description>Tubemaker Tenaris has signed an agreement with Italian energy suppliers Edison and Snam for a project aimed at using hydrogen in steelmaking operations at the Tenaris Dalmine seamless tube plant in Italy. The project will study hydrogen supply and adapt the mill to use the gas in the steelmaking process, which could further lower CO2 emissions from the electric arc furnace-based steelmaker.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coatings. The business unit was rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy and will apply anti-corrosion coatings to line pipes at Tenaris facilities across Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil.</description><category>general</category></item></channel></rss>