<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:17:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New BIOEDGE steel incorporates renewable biocarbon for lower emissions</title><link>https://worldbiomarketinsights.com/new-bioedge-steel-incorporates-renewable-biocarbon-for-lower-emissions/</link><description>Steel Dynamics has launched innovative lower-embodied-carbon steel products named BIOEDGE™ and EDGE™, produced exclusively with electric arc furnace technology. BIOEDGE uses renewable biocarbon replacing traditional anthracite, significantly lowering Scope 1 emissions, and is paired with renewable energy certificates to reduce Scope 2 emissions, supporting sustainable manufacturing and decarbonization efforts.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory Drops in Two Regions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103592374/Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Drops-by-2000-mt-on-Oct-29-2025:-SMM</link><description>The inventory of aluminum billet in two domestic regions decreased by 2,000 mt on October 29, 2025. This drop reflects ongoing trends in aluminum prices and inventory levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa Corporation Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://news.alcoa.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/Alcoa-Corporation-Reports-Third-Quarter-2025-Results/default.aspx</link><description>Alcoa reported a 4 percent sequential increase in alumina production to 2.5 million metric tons in Q3 2025, driven primarily by higher output. The company also announced plans to shut its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia due to deteriorating bauxite ore grades, impacting future production capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>RUSAL Deploys AI-Powered Machine Hearing and Vision Technologies to Enhance Aluminium Production Efficiency</title><link>https://thecsruniverse.com/articles/rusal-deploys-ai-powered-machine-hearing-and-vision-technologies-to-enhance-aluminium-production-efficiency</link><description>RUSAL has implemented AI-powered machine hearing and vision technologies to improve aluminum production efficiency. This technological advancement is part of the company's efforts to optimize operations and reduce costs in a competitive market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>From Refinery Waste to Useful Materials and Green Fuel: New Research Could Revolutionize the Global Aluminum Industry</title><link>https://educationnewscanada.com/article/education/level/university/1/1167056/from-refinery-waste-to-useful-materials-and-green-fuel-new-research-could-revolutionize-the-global-aluminum-industry.html</link><description>New research from the University of New Brunswick could transform the aluminum industry by making smelting more efficient and sustainable. It involves turning refinery waste into green fuel and useful materials, reducing landfill waste and supporting a sustainable future. The research aims to create a closed-loop, low-energy aluminum digestion process.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>RUSAL Deploys AI-Powered Machine Hearing and Vision Technologies to Enhance Aluminium Production Efficiency</title><link>https://thecsruniverse.com/articles/rusal-deploys-ai-powered-machine-hearing-and-vision-technologies-to-enhance-aluminium-production-efficiency</link><description>RUSAL, a major aluminum producer, has implemented AI-powered machine hearing and vision technologies to improve production efficiency. This innovation aims to enhance operational performance and sustainability in aluminum production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Mill Price Adjustment</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103012401/Anhui-Changjiang-Steel-Raises-Guided-Prices-for-Building-Materials-on-October-29th</link><description>Anhui Changjiang Steel has raised its guided prices for building materials, including rebar, coiled rebar, and high-speed wire, by 20 units. This adjustment reflects recent market dynamics and pricing strategies in the steel sector. The move could influence broader steel market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hot Rolled Coil Futures See Steady Rise</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/m/page/commodity-news-detail/commodity-news-detail-27489.html</link><description>Hot rolled coil futures experienced a steady rise last week, which provided some boost to the spot market sentiment. This trend could indicate improving market conditions for steel products. However, broader market trends remain mixed.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Algoma Steel Group Inc. to Announce 2025 Third Quarter Results</title><link>https://m.fastbull.com/news-detail/press-release-algoma-steel-group-inc-to-announce-news_7200_0_2025_4_34523_3</link><description>Algoma Steel Group Inc. is set to announce its third-quarter results for 2025. This announcement could provide insights into the company's performance and the overall steel market conditions. The results may influence investor sentiment and market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Price Forecast Revised Upward</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/29/iron-ore-price-forecast-revised-upward/</link><description>Goldman Sachs has revised its iron ore price forecast upward for 2026 due to a tighter market and supportive macroeconomic factors. However, the firm maintains a bearish outlook for the long term, expecting prices to decline by Q4 2026. China's steel sector is facing oversupply challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rare-Earth Steel Production Trends and Applications</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/rare-earth-steel-production-2025-trends-applications/</link><description>The article discusses advancements in rare-earth steel production, focusing on sustainable production methods and expanding applications in sectors like aerospace and automotive. These advancements are expected to support decarbonization efforts and infrastructure modernization.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>304 Stainless Steel Bolt Market Size Report 2025</title><link>https://www.openpr.com/news/4243694/304-stainless-steel-bolt-market-size-report-2025</link><description>The global 304 Stainless Steel Bolt market is projected to grow significantly, driven by industrial development and equipment modernization. The market size is expected to increase from $448 million in 2024 to $739 million by 2031. The report analyzes market trends and competitive structures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rare-Earth Steel Production: Guide to REE-Enhanced Alloys</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/rare-earth-steel-production-2025-trends-applications/</link><description>This article discusses advanced rare-earth steel production methods emphasizing sustainability through resource efficiency, reduced waste, and recycling programs. It highlights technological advancements such as AI-driven quality control and hydrogen materials research supporting decarbonisation in transport and industrial sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rare-Earth Steel Revolution: Advanced Alloys Transform</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/rare-earth-steel-technology-2025/</link><description>The article covers environmental sustainability in rare-earth steel production, focusing on green chemistry, biotechnology, hydrogen-based metallurgy, and circular economy approaches like recycling and urban mining. It details efforts to reduce carbon emissions and improve resource utilization in steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Steady Amid Trade Deal Anticipation</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/29/copper-prices-steady-amid-trade-deal-anticipation/</link><description>Copper prices have stabilized near record highs as markets await confirmation of a U.S.-China trade agreement. The metal is supported by tightening supply conditions and a more optimistic demand forecast. However, details of the trade deal remain vague, contributing to trader caution.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Struggles for Clear Direction as Fed Decision, Trump-Xi Meeting Loom</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3WA08X:0-copper-struggles-for-clear-direction-as-fed-decision-trump-xi-meeting-loom/</link><description>Copper prices were little changed as investors awaited the Federal Reserve's rate decision and a potential meeting between U.S. President Donald Trump and Chinese leader Xi Jinping. The metal has been supported by supply-side issues and a brighter demand outlook in Europe.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>U.S. Government Shutdown Continues, Overnight Copper Prices First Fell Then Rose</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper prices initially fell but then rose overnight, closing higher on both the London Metal Exchange and the Shanghai Futures Exchange. The market saw improved procurement sentiment despite ongoing price pressure from buyers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Quantum Minerals Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.first-quantum.com/news/first-quantum-minerals-reports-third-quarter-2025-results/</link><description>Kansanshi mine reported copper production of 46,881 tonnes in Q3 2025, up by 6,778 tonnes from the previous quarter due to increased mill throughput from the Kansanshi S3 Expansion project. Sentinel mine produced 51,336 tonnes, an increase of 8,228 tonnes quarter-over-quarter, driven by improved ore fragmentation and crusher performance. Copper production guidance for 2025 is narrowed to 175,000 – 185,000 tonnes with expectations of higher production in Q4 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Steady Amid Trade Deal Anticipation</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/29/copper-prices-steady-amid-trade-deal-anticipation/</link><description>Copper prices remain stable near record highs as markets await a US-China trade agreement. Anglo American announced that production at its Collahuasi copper mine in Chile is expected to fall below previous forecasts for 2026, revising output from 470,000 tonnes to between 380,000 and 410,000 tonnes. This downgrade adds to already tight supply conditions, supporting elevated copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Copper Demand Projected to Outpace Supply by Over 500,000 Tonnes In 2025, Driving Upward Price Pressure</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-copper-demand-projected-to-outpace-supply-by-over-500-000-tonnes-in-2025--driving-upward-price-pressure-302563846.html</link><description>Copper demand continues to rise due to its critical role in infrastructure, agriculture, renewable energy, and electrification. Supply constraints, geopolitical challenges, and the need for resource resilience are driving copper prices higher. The metal is essential for smart farming, energy transmission, and electric vehicles, underscoring the importance of sustainable and innovative copper technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>A Fireside Conversation with BHP Americas President Brandon Craig</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/whats-behind-copper-hype-fireside-conversation-bhp-americas-president-brandon-craig</link><description>This event discusses copper's critical role in the modern economy and the challenges of tightening supply, declining ore grades, and geopolitical risks. It highlights the importance of innovation and investment to secure copper supply chains and maintain technological and economic leadership, especially in the U.S. and allied countries.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fluctuated at lows on October 29 as the US government shutdown is expected to continue</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103593505/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fluctuated-at-lows-on-October-29-as-the-US-government-shutdown-is-expected-to-continue</link><description>On October 29, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 120,400 and 123,400 yuan/mt, averaging 121,900 yuan/mt, which was down 250 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. The price fluctuation occurred amid expectations that the US government shutdown would continue, impacting market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel stabilizes amid US-China trade uncertainty</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-stabilizes-amid-us-china-trade-uncertainty-47588</link><description>Nickel prices remained largely unchanged amid ongoing uncertainty in US-China trade relations. Goldman Sachs forecasted a 6% decline in nickel prices to $14,500 per metric ton by December 2026, citing the need for Indonesian producer margins to shrink to curb supply growth and address the market surplus.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On October 29, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103592974/</link><description>The LME nickel price settled at $15,320 per metric ton on Friday, marking a 1.39% week-over-week increase. Meanwhile, the most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 122,150 yuan/mt, also showing gains, reflecting a positive short-term trend in nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Quantum Minerals Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.first-quantum.com/news/first-quantum-minerals-reports-third-quarter-2025-results/</link><description>First Quantum Minerals reported a 44% increase in nickel production in Q3 2025, reaching 5,767 tonnes due to higher throughput and improved recoveries. The company also lowered nickel unit cost guidance reflecting operational performance, indicating improved efficiency in nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Intermediate Product Market Outlook for 2026</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103589711/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-Intermediate-Product-Market-Outlook-for-2026</link><description>Indonesia's nickel production is expected to reach about 680 kt in metal content in 2026, up over 45% year-over-year, driven by new project ramp-ups and capacity expansions. The Indonesian government’s control of ore prices and quota releases will increase costs, while demand growth is limited due to shifts in electric vehicle policies and battery material market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel mining threatens Raja Ampat ecosystems, communities</title><link>https://news.mongabay.com/2025/10/nickel-mining-threatens-raja-ampat-ecosystems-communities-conservation-report/</link><description>An environmental report highlights the threat expanding nickel mining poses to Raja Ampat's coral reefs, forests, and Indigenous communities. Despite environmental concerns, the government maintained Gag Nikel’s mining permit due to compliance with environmental standards. Global automakers like Tesla and Volkswagen are linked to this supply chain through nickel supply agreements with Indonesian processors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada G7 Critical Minerals Supply Deals Secure Chains</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-partnerships-g72025/</link><description>Canada is a key player in G7 critical minerals strategy, ranking 5th globally in nickel production with 170,000-180,000 tonnes annually, mainly from the Sudbury basin. While Canada has strong nickel production, it faces processing gaps, exporting most cobalt concentrates for refining abroad. Government initiatives aim to boost domestic processing capacity for battery-grade materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low Amid Oversupply</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to $15,226 per tonne on October 29, 2025, pressured by oversupply from Indonesia's expanded nickel sector. Indonesia's nickel mining quotas were reduced by 120 million tons this year, cutting global supply by 35%, but markets remain oversupplied with LME nickel stockpiles rising to over 250,000 tonnes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada G7 Critical Minerals Supply Deals Secure Chains</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-partnerships-g72025/</link><description>Canada is enhancing its critical minerals supply chains through strategic partnerships with G7 countries. These partnerships focus on integrated manufacturing networks and advanced processing technologies to optimize material yields and reduce environmental impact. The initiative aims to secure premium products and competitive advantages in the critical minerals market.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Falls to 2,884.60 USD/T on October 29, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped to 2,884.60 USD per tonne on October 29, 2025, down 0.52% from the previous day, despite a 7.56% increase over the past month and a 10.23% rise year-to-date. The market outlook suggests aluminum could trade around 2,889.07 USD/tonne by the end of the quarter, with a forecast of 3,019.77 USD/tonne in 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Algoma Steel Group Reports Financial Results for the Third Quarter 2025</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/29/3176935/0/en/Algoma-Steel-Group-Reports-Financial-Results-for-the-Third-Quarter-2025.html</link><description>Algoma Steel Group reported its financial results for the third quarter of 2025. The company maintained limited operations to align with market conditions and is transitioning to a new EAF facility, which will increase production capacity and reduce carbon emissions. The transition is expected to be completed by mid-November 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices in London Hit Record High on Supply Fears — Commodities Roundup</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510298529/copper-prices-in-london-hit-record-high-on-supply-fears-commodities-roundup</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange reached a record high due to concerns over global supply disruptions and weaker production forecasts from major miners. Glencore adjusted its copper output guidance downward, while Anglo American warned of lower production from its Collahuasi plant in Chile. This has driven three-month copper futures to $11,173.50 per metric ton.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Green Gold Rush: Demand Soars Amidst Global Energy Transition</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-10-29-coppers-green-gold-rush-demand-soars-amidst-global-energy-transition</link><description>Copper demand is surging due to its critical role in electric vehicles and renewable energy infrastructure. EVs consumed 1.7 million tonnes of copper in 2025, with projections to increase by 2.6 million tonnes by 2035. Copper is essential for wind and solar power systems, grid infrastructure, and energy storage, underpinning the global shift to sustainable energy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>World Copper Announces Anticipated Closing Date for the Sale of the Zonia Project</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/272355</link><description>World Copper Ltd. announced the expected closing of the sale of its Zonia Copper Project in Arizona on October 30, 2025. This transaction is part of the company's strategic development and exploration efforts in copper resources.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>NexMetals Seeks $46.5M Capital Raise to Revive Botswana Nickel Production</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/2910-49923-nexmetals-seeks-46-5m-capital-raise-to-revive-botswana-nickel-production</link><description>NexMetals Mining plans a $46.5 million equity placement to fund the restart of nickel production at its Selebi and Selkirk projects in Botswana. The projects have updated resource estimates totaling approximately 358,000 tonnes of nickel, aiming to revive nickel mining in Botswana for the first time since 2016.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nano One Awarded C$5M Contribution from NRCan to Scale and Commercialize One-Pot™ LFP</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=6902726269800269ef101bc0</link><description>Nano One received a C$5 million non-repayable contribution from Natural Resources Canada to scale production of lithium iron phosphate cathode materials, supporting cleaner and more sustainable battery supply chains. This government-backed funding reinforces Canada's leadership in battery material innovation.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Italy's Tenaris posts 2% rise in quarterly net sales</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/tenaris-results-zero/</link><description>Tenaris, an Italian steel pipe maker, reported a 2% increase in quarterly net sales, driven by higher sales in North America. The company's financial performance reflects its resilience in the market. Tenaris will discuss these results further in a conference call.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Announces 2025 Third Quarter Results</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/29/3176915/0/en/Tenaris-Announces-2025-Third-Quarter-Results.html</link><description>Tenaris has released its third-quarter results for 2025, which will be discussed in a conference call. The company's financial performance includes various operational metrics and strategic updates. The call will provide further insights into Tenaris's current market position and future outlook.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Not Only Tariffs on Trucks: Trump Administration's Proclamation Amends the Tariff Landscape on Automobiles, Steel, and Aluminum</title><link>https://www.globaltradelawblog.com/2025/10/29/not-only-tariffs-on-trucks-trump-administrations-proclamation-amends-the-tariff-landscape-on-automobiles-steel-and-aluminum/</link><description>The Trump Administration issued a proclamation reducing aluminum and steel tariffs by up to 25% for USMCA-qualifying suppliers operating in Canada or Mexico, aiming to support new US production capacity. This adjustment affects tariffs on aluminum imports and is part of broader efforts to create a domestic ecosystem in related industries.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>An actionable path to cutting carbon emissions in steel production</title><link>https://www.ucl.ac.uk/news/2025/oct/actionable-path-cutting-carbon-emissions-steel-production</link><description>Researchers at UCL developed a database and economic model identifying cost-effective strategies to reduce carbon emissions from nearly 4,900 steel plants worldwide. A medium pathway retrofitting approach could cut 22.4 billion tonnes of CO2 by 2050 at an average cost of $24.7 per tonne, balancing cost and impact while enabling significant emissions reductions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Industrial Metals Navigate a Bifurcated Market Amidst China's Slowdown and Green Revolution</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-29-industrial-metals-navigate-a-bifurcated-market-amidst-chinas-slowdown-and-green-revolution</link><description>The industrial metals market in 2025 is shaped by the global energy transition and AI demand, driving a projected 40% increase in copper demand by 2030. This structural shift impacts manufacturing, construction, and technology sectors, with green technologies gaining advantage despite challenges like tariffs and China's property slump.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese firms drive aluminium expansion in Indonesia, raise surplus fears</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/chinese-firms-drive-aluminium-expansion-in-indonesia-raise-surplus-fears/</link><description>Chinese firms are expanding aluminum production in Indonesia, which could lead to a global surplus. This expansion raises concerns about potential oversupply in the market. Goldman Sachs predicts a global aluminum surplus in the coming years.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Domestic Secondary Aluminum Alloy Ingot Inventory Up 100 mt WoW by Oct 30</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103595882/SMM-Flash-News:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Alloy-Ingot-Inventory-Up-100-mt-WoW-by-Oct-30</link><description>As of October 30, domestic secondary aluminum alloy ingot inventory increased by 100 mt week-over-week. Technical indicators suggest a short-term bullish trend for aluminum alloy futures. This reflects ongoing market dynamics in the aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa Corporation to Host Investor Day on October 30, 2025</title><link>https://news.alcoa.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/Alcoa-Corporation-to-Host-Investor-Day-on-October-30-2025-6251b550c/default.aspx</link><description>Alcoa Corporation is hosting an Investor Day event expected to cover discussions on the company's markets, operations, strategies, opportunities, technologies, and capital allocation. This event may include insights into aluminum technology innovation and sustainability initiatives.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nucor Raises Prices for Thick-Gauge Rolled Steel</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/nucor-raises-prices-for-thick-gauge-rolled-steel-by-60-t-starting-in-november/</link><description>Nucor is raising prices for thick-gauge rolled steel by $60 per ton starting in November. The new theoretical price for standard thickness A36 base rolled products is estimated to be around $1,335 per ton.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany Announces €6 Billion Industrial Decarbonization Program</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103558468</link><description>Germany has announced a €6 billion program to accelerate emissions reduction in key sectors, including steel. The initiative aims to support the decarbonization of industries like steel and cement.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Reaches Record High Amid Supply Fears</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103594814/</link><description>Copper prices surged to a new all-time high on the London Metal Exchange, with spot copper reaching around $11,137 per tonne. This increase is attributed to supply fears following disruptions at major mines and reduced production forecasts from leading producers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anaconda Copper Mine 2025: Innovations &amp; Sustainability</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/anaconda-copper-mine-2025-innovations-sustainability</link><description>The Anaconda Copper Mine exemplifies the integration of digital, automated, and environmentally focused technologies in mining. It highlights AI, digital monitoring, eco-rehabilitation, and rapid automation as key sustainability practices shaping the future of copper mining with a focus on resource stewardship and community resilience.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Battery-powered appliances make it easy to switch from gas to electric</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2025/battery-powered-appliances-make-switch-easy-gas-electric-1030</link><description>Copper, a company scaling production of battery-equipped appliances, raised $28 million to meet growing demand supporting the electric transition. Their technology aims to improve energy resilience by integrating local energy storage in homes, reducing reliance on fossil fuels and enhancing grid efficiency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mining for the climate: Chile attracts German investment</title><link>https://table.media/?p=f3679ae7-65e4-4fc3-959a-2ba8fc5e91c5</link><description>Chile, the world's largest copper producer, is accelerating efforts to supply raw materials for the energy transition while aiming to reduce mining emissions to zero by 2040. The country seeks German partnerships to support sustainable mining practices and climate-friendly economic transformation.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Can Innovation Make Ocean Mining Sustainable?</title><link>https://www.azomining.com/Article.aspx?ArticleID=1896</link><description>With rising mineral demand, the sustainability of deep-sea mining depends on technological advances and strong environmental protections. Innovations are critical to balancing mineral extraction with ecological preservation in ocean mining.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Rebound Slightly on October 30 as US Fed Cuts Interest Rate</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103596109/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Rebound-Slightly-on-October-30-as-US-Fed-Cuts-Interest-Rate-by-25-Basis-Points-as-Expected</link><description>Nickel prices saw a slight rebound on October 30 following the US Federal Reserve's interest rate cut. The SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,200 yuan/mt, up 300 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. This increase reflects market responses to broader economic conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Announces 2025 Third Quarter Results</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/10/30/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/tenaris-announces-2025-third-quarter-results/2211615</link><description>Tenaris has announced its third-quarter results for 2025, which include a net sales figure of $2.978 billion and an operating income of $597 million. The company will hold a conference call to discuss these results. The financial performance highlights Tenaris's ongoing operations and strategic initiatives.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian has been awarded the tender for the construction of the submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia under the Elmed Project. This project aims to create an energy bridge between Europe and Africa, enhancing energy security. The contract could reach a value of around €460 million.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Could Be a Relative Winner From Trump's Copper Tariff</title><link>https://m.fastbull.com/news-detail/prysmian-could-be-a-relative-winner-from-trumps-news_8600_0_2025_3_929_3/8600_NAT.GAS</link><description>Prysmian could benefit from President Trump's proposed copper tariff due to its vertically integrated copper operation in the U.S. This gives Prysmian a competitive edge over smaller players.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell slightly to $2,872.55 per tonne on October 30, down 0.42% from the previous day, but have risen 6.50% over the past month and 9.43% year-over-year. Aluminum futures hit a 3-year high in October amid tight supply, influenced by China's output cap of 45 million tons.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US aluminum scrap trade faces 2025 shake-up amid tariffs and global demand</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5101605-us-aluminum-scrap-trade-faces-2025-shake-up-amid-tariffs-and-global-demand</link><description>US aluminum scrap imports rose 31% in the first half of 2025 despite new tariffs, reaching about 430,000 tonnes. However, the 25% aluminum import tariff effective March 12, 2025, caused recyclers to shift toward domestic recovery, reshaping the scrap trade dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>UAE Delivers First Batch of Low-Carbon Aluminium Powered by Nuclear Energy from Barakah</title><link>https://gccbusinesswatch.com/news/uae-delivers-first-batch-of-low-carbon-aluminium-powered-by-nuclear-energy-from-barakah/</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Emirates Nuclear Energy Company have delivered the UAE’s first batch of low-carbon aluminium produced using clean electricity from the Barakah Nuclear Energy Plant. This aluminium, branded MinimAL, represents a significant step in decarbonising heavy industry by using nuclear power as a constant, carbon-free energy source. The product has been supplied to Egypt’s CANEX Aluminum, marking a milestone in cross-border clean industry collaboration.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Honeywell Unveils Breakthrough Technology to Produce Low-Cost, High-Quality Renewable Fuels from Biomass</title><link>https://thecsruniverse.com/articles/honeywell-unveils-breakthrough-technology-to-produce-low-cost-high-quality-renewable-fuels-from-biomass</link><description>Honeywell announced a new Biocrude Upgrading technology that converts agricultural and forestry waste into renewable fuels such as marine fuel, gasoline, and sustainable aviation fuel. This technology offers a cost-effective, scalable solution for decarbonizing sectors like shipping and aviation by producing drop-in renewable fuels that require no engine modifications. It addresses key challenges of cost and feedstock availability, supporting India’s clean energy transition goals.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>ASI Certifies Shandong Innovation Group Co., Ltd. Against Performance Standard V3.1 and Chain of Custody V2</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/asi-certifies-shandong-innovation-group-co-ltd-against-performance-standard-v3-1-and-chain-of-custody-v2-116022</link><description>Shandong Innovation Group Co., Ltd. has been certified by the Aluminium Stewardship Initiative (ASI) against the latest sustainability standards for recycling, remelting aluminium scrap, and producing aluminium alloys. The certification covers multiple facilities in China with a combined annual production capacity exceeding five million tonnes. This recognition underscores the company's commitment to sustainable aluminium production and supports sectors like automotive lightweighting and electronics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>UAE Aluminum Curtain Wall Market Forecast &amp; Opportunity Report 2025</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/30/3177615/0/en/UAE-Aluminum-Curtain-Wall-Market-Forecast-Opportunity-Report-2025-A-950-Million-Industry-by-2030-Driven-by-Urbanization-Sustainable-Construction-and-Rising-Demand-for-Energy-Effici.html</link><description>The UAE aluminum curtain wall market is projected to grow significantly, driven by urbanization and a rising demand for sustainable construction. A key trend is the adoption of smart facades integrating sensors, solar panels, and automated shading to optimize energy efficiency in buildings. This aligns with the UAE’s sustainability goals and is prompting innovation in high-performance aluminum curtain wall systems.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China Base Metals Demand 15th Five-Year Plan 2025 Guide</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/base-metals-demand-china-15th-five-year-plan-2025/</link><description>China’s 15th Five-Year Plan emphasizes increased recycled aluminium use, energy efficiency, and technology upgrades to reduce carbon intensity in line with environmental policies. The plan supports a shift toward circular economy principles with a target to raise recycled nonferrous metals to 24% of total supply by 2025. These policies create price premiums and encourage innovation in aluminium recycling and sustainable production technologies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US-China Trade Deal Optimism Fuels Asian Steel Production Surge, But October Slowdown Looms</title><link>https://lagrand.ch/us-china-trade-deal-optimism-fuels-asian-steel-production-surge-but-october-slowdown-looms-202510300353/</link><description>Asian steel production saw a surge from May to September 2025, peaking in August, driven by optimism over a potential US-China trade deal. However, October data shows a significant slowdown in overall plant activity, despite some Chinese producers maintaining high output levels, suggesting broader supply issues in the region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World Copper Announces Closing of Sale of Zonia Copper Project</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=690354b4126e28028c37aae9</link><description>World Copper Ltd. completed the sale of its Zonia Copper Project in Arizona to Edge Copper Corporation for $10.5 million in cash and shares, resulting in World Copper owning approximately 31.3% of Edge Copper. The transaction was finalized under a court-approved plan of arrangement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Arca Climate Technologies inks 10-year carbon removal offtake deal with Microsoft</title><link>https://www.mining.com/arca-climate-technologies-inks-10-year-carbon-removal-offtake-deal-with-microsoft/</link><description>Arca Climate Technologies signed a 10-year carbon removal offtake agreement with Microsoft, focusing on repurposing mining byproducts like tailings and waste rock to accelerate carbon mineralization. This process transforms CO2 into solid minerals, providing durable carbon removal, reducing mine waste, and creating jobs, with plans to scale from pilot projects to million-tonne operations.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Gold and Copper: The Unseen Forces Powering Market Returns</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-30-gold-and-copper-the-unseen-forces-powering-market-returns-blackrock-unveils-overlooked-opportunities</link><description>Copper prices have surged over 27% in 2025, driven by sustained demand from green energy and digital transformation. Market experts like BlackRock suggest copper's price rise reflects a fundamental supply-demand imbalance, indicating a new higher baseline for copper driven by decarbonization and digitalization trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ceria Group Produces First Green Nickel, Pushes Ahead with Smelter Expansion</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/ceria-group-produces-first-green-nickel-pushes-ahead-with-smelter-expansion</link><description>PT Ceria Nugraha Indotama (Ceria Group) has commenced production of green nickel at its smelter in Indonesia and is continuing with expansion plans. This marks a milestone in Indonesia's push toward more sustainable nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian reported third-quarter revenue of €5.03 billion, beating consensus estimates, driven by strong growth in Renewable Transmission and Power Grids units. The company raised its full-year 2025 guidance, supported by a stable high-voltage backlog of about €16 billion and solid organic growth in key segments.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian upgrades 2025 guidance</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/06-10-am-prysmian-upgrades-2025-guidance-ce7d5dd3dd8ef426</link><description>Following strong performance in the first nine months of 2025, Prysmian upgraded its full-year guidance, citing excellent contributions from its Transmission business and North American region. The company emphasizes its leadership in cable solutions and its strategic focus on energy transition and digital transformation.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Mexico &amp; US make 90% progress in tariff negotiations, while steel and aluminum issues remain to be concluded</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/mexico-us-make-90-progress-in-tariff-negotiations-while-steel-and-aluminum-issues-remain-to-be-concluded/157524</link><description>Mexico and the US have made 90% progress in tariff negotiations, but issues related to steel and aluminum tariffs are still pending resolution. This ongoing negotiation could impact aluminum trade dynamics between the two countries.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory Rises to 98,500 mt on Oct 31, 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103597334/SMM:-Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-Rises-to-98500-mt-on-Oct-31-2025</link><description>Domestic aluminum billet inventory in two key locations rose to 98,500 metric tons as of October 31, 2025. The Shanghai Futures Exchange (SHFE) aluminum price remains in an upward channel, reflecting ongoing market strength despite inventory increases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nothing should be left on table to keep Rio Tinto's aluminum smelter open, says Australian minister</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/nothing-should-be-left-on-table-to-keep-rio-tintos-aluminum-smelter-open-says-australian-minister/</link><description>The Australian Minister emphasized that all possible measures should be taken to keep Rio Tinto's aluminum smelter operational, highlighting the importance of maintaining production capacity in the country.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory Rises to 98,500 mt on Oct 31, 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103597334/SMM:-Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-Rises-to-98500-mt-on-Oct-31-2025</link><description>According to SMM statistics, the inventory of aluminum billet in two domestic locations increased to 98,500 metric tons as of October 31, 2025, indicating changes in supply and demand dynamics within the domestic aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Update: Slight Daily Gain Amid Monthly Decline</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China rose to 3,092 CNY/T on October 31, up 0.13% from the previous day, but have fallen 0.10% over the past month and are down nearly 5% year-on-year. Analysts expect further declines, forecasting a price of 3,022.85 CNY/T by the end of the quarter and 2,890.00 CNY/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Dips Slightly, Remains Up Sharply Year-on-Year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-rolled coil (HRC) steel fell to 844.08 USD/T on October 31, down 0.70% from the previous day, but prices are up 4.72% over the past month and 18.32% year-on-year. Forecasts suggest HRC steel may trade at 827.34 USD/T by the end of the quarter but could rise to 892.84 USD/T in a year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Steel Consumption Falls 5.7% Year-on-Year in First Three Quarters of 2025</title><link>https://in.marketscreener.com/news/china-s-steel-consumption-in-the-first-three-quarters-of-2025-fell-5-7-y-y-association-says-ce7d5cdad080f62c</link><description>China's steel consumption dropped 5.7% year-on-year in the first nine months of 2025, according to industry association data. This decline reflects ongoing weak domestic demand despite strong export growth earlier in the year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's steel consumption in the first three quarters of 2025 fell 5.7% y/y, association says</title><link>https://in.marketscreener.com/news/china-s-steel-consumption-in-the-first-three-quarters-of-2025-fell-5-7-y-y-association-says-ce7d5cdad080f62c</link><description>China's steel consumption dropped 5.7% year-on-year in the first three quarters of 2025, according to industry association data. This decline reflects ongoing challenges in the Chinese steel market amid broader economic pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP POSCO Partner on Near Zero Emissions Steel Technology</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/steel-manufacturing-hydrogen-technology-reshapes-2025/</link><description>BHP and POSCO have partnered to develop POSCO's HyREX hydrogen reduction ironmaking technology aimed at near-zero emissions steel production. A demonstration plant with 300,000 tonnes annual capacity is planned at Pohang Steelworks, targeting commissioning by early 2028, marking a significant step toward decarbonizing the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hydrogen-Based Low Emissions Iron: Tech &amp; Benefits</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/hydrogen-steel-production-emissions-reduction-2025/</link><description>Hydrogen-based steel production technology is set to transform the global steel industry by enabling distributed production closer to end markets, reducing emissions and transportation costs. This shift favors renewable energy-rich regions and smaller, flexible facilities, with ongoing advancements in hydrogen production and integration with carbon capture systems promising further environmental benefits.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Declines from 3-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/497786</link><description>US copper futures fell to $5.09 per pound from a three-month high of $5.17 due to a stronger dollar and uncertain demand outlook despite ongoing supply concerns. The easing of US-China trade barriers and a fatal mudslide at an Indonesian mine affecting over 3% of global supply also influenced market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/base-metals-investing/copper-investing/copper-forecast/</link><description>Copper prices were volatile in Q3 2025, reaching record highs of $5.81 per pound on COMEX driven by tariff fears and supply-demand fundamentals. After a sharp decline in August, prices rebounded in September and early October, breaking above $5 per pound as supply fundamentals strengthened.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices fell to $5.06 per pound on October 31, down 0.43% from the previous day but remain near three-month highs. The market is influenced by US-China trade developments, a recent Fed rate cut, and ongoing supply disruptions from major miners and mine incidents in Chile and Indonesia.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Rally Hits Record $11200 Per Ton in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-price-rally-2025-supply-demand-momentum/</link><description>Copper prices surpassed $11,200 per ton in 2025 amid supply disruptions and strong demand from the energy transition. Goldman Sachs projects prices to remain between $10,000 and $11,000 per ton in 2026-2027, balancing supply recovery and demand growth, while potential supply disruptions could push prices higher.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>ENAMI's New Smelter Approved, LME Copper Fell Sharply Last Night</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103597243/ENAMIs-New-Smelter-Approved-LME-Copper-Fell-Sharply-Last-Night-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Chilean state-owned ENAMI received environmental permits to build a new $1.7 billion copper smelter as part of modernizing its Hernan Videla Lira smelter in northern Atacama. The new facility will process up to 850,000 metric tons of copper concentrates annually and produce up to 240,000 metric tons of copper cathode via electrorefining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Capstone Copper Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://capstonecopper.com/news/capstone-copper-reports-third-quarter-2025-results/</link><description>Capstone Copper reported Q3 2025 sulphide copper production of 44,904 tonnes at a C1 cash cost of $2.00/lb, a significant improvement from Q3 2024. The Pinto Valley Mine experienced a 29% production decline due to lower grades and mill throughput impacted by drought-related water constraints, but throughput improved in October 2025 with full mill operations resuming.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Declines from 3-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/497786</link><description>US copper futures fell from a three-month high due to a stronger dollar and uncertain demand outlook despite ongoing supply concerns. Supply shocks include lower output from major miners like Glencore and Anglo American and a halt in operations at a Freeport-McMoRan mine in Indonesia responsible for over 3% of global supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Eurasian Resources Mercuria Copper Deal: $100M Agreement</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/eurasian-resources-mercuria-copper-deal-2025/</link><description>Eurasian Resources and Mercuria signed a $100 million strategic agreement focusing on copper production capacity in the Democratic Republic of Congo. The deal supports annual output exceeding 200,000 tonnes and integrates mining with on-site processing, impacting global supply and spot market dynamics by stabilizing contracted volumes over three years.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Plans Angola Copper Drill Program by Q4 2025</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/3110-49997-ivanhoe-mines-plans-angola-copper-drill-program-by-q4-2025</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced a 6,400-meter diamond drilling campaign in Angola's Moxico and Cuando Cubango provinces starting Q4 2025. This marks the company's first major copper exploration in Angola following permit acquisition in 2023, aiming to expand its footprint in Africa’s copper sector amid strong global demand driven by renewable energy and electrification.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Patriot Expands Copper-Gold Footprint in Zambia</title><link>https://mining.com.au/patriot-expands-copper-gold-footprint-in-zambia/</link><description>Patriot Resources expanded its copper-gold footprint within the Kitumba Project in Zambia after completing a phase one trenching program. The company identified a potential 200m strike zone and is preparing for ground magnetics and induced polarisation surveys to map subsurface sulphidic zones, advancing its exploration efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices dropped slightly on October 31 while spot premiums strengthened</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103598443/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-dropped-slightly-on-October-31-while-spot-premiums-strengthened</link><description>On October 31, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 120,500 and 123,400 yuan/mt, averaging 121,950 yuan/mt, which was down 250 yuan/mt from the previous day. Despite the slight price drop, spot premiums showed signs of strengthening.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Posts Net Profit Beat and Cuts Copper, Nickel Cost Outlook</title><link>https://blockchain.news/flashnews/vale-posts-net-profit-beat-and-cuts-copper-nickel-cost-outlook-trading-watch-for-mining-stocks-and-commodities</link><description>Brazilian mining giant Vale reported a stronger-than-expected net profit for the quarter and lowered its cost outlook for copper and nickel production. This development suggests potential stabilization of nickel prices around $8.00 per pound amid operational efficiencies and fluctuating global demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/base-metals-investing/nickel-investing/nickel-forecast/</link><description>Nickel prices were volatile in the first half of 2025 but stabilized in Q3 amid ongoing oversupply concerns. Prices ranged mostly between $15,000 and $15,500 per metric ton, with market uncertainty influenced by US trade policies and the end of the EV tax credit.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices Q3 2025 review: China restocking lifts sulphate and MHP as LME oversupply persists</title><link>https://source.benchmarkminerals.com/article/nickel-prices-q3-2025-review-china-restocking-lifts-sulphate-and-mhp-as-lme-oversupply-persists</link><description>During Q3 2025, nickel prices remained at five-year lows due to persistent oversupply on the London Metal Exchange, although restocking in China helped lift prices for nickel sulphate and mixed hydroxide precipitate (MHP). The market continues to face supply-demand imbalances despite these regional demand boosts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Eramet’s Weda Bay nickel ore sales surge in Q3 after RKAB revision</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/eramet-s-weda-bay-nickel-ore-sales-surge-in-q3-after-rkab-revision</link><description>French mining group Eramet reported a sharp rebound in nickel ore sales from its Weda Bay operations in Indonesia during the third quarter, following a revision to its mining work plan (RKAB). The article notes a significant increase in sales volume, though full details require a login to access.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel x Biomining</title><link>https://www.worldfund.vc/knowledge/nickel-x-biomining</link><description>World Fund explores innovative climate tech solutions to reduce the high carbon emissions of nickel production, which currently exceeds those of copper, aluminum, and lithium. The article highlights the need for new supply chains or refining processes to ensure resilient, low-cost, and low-emission nickel supply, especially given the concentration of production in China and Indonesia. Two promising innovation pathways and startups in alternative nickel production are discussed.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>What if an EV was made without metals or minerals?</title><link>https://thedriven.io/2025/10/31/what-if-an-ev-was-made-without-metals-or-minerals/</link><description>Sandvik unveiled an electric car made without metals or minerals to highlight the critical role of mining in sustainable development and the green transition. The article emphasizes the need to scale sustainable mining practices for lithium, nickel, and cobalt to meet net-zero goals by 2050. It also describes the future of mining as autonomous, electrified, and digitalized to optimize resource extraction with minimal environmental impact.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cobalt-Free EV Cathodes: Sustainable Battery Solutions</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/cobalt-free-cathodes-electric-vehicles-2025/</link><description>Research on cobalt-free cathodes, including nickel-iron-aluminium compositions, aims to reduce reliance on critical materials like cobalt and nickel in EV batteries. The article discusses technical challenges such as performance optimization and manufacturing scaling, alongside government policy support to promote sustainable battery technologies. Advances in battery recycling and circular economy approaches are also highlighted.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals Production Alliance: Global Strategy</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-landscape-2025-energy-transition/</link><description>The alliance focuses on sustainable competitive advantages through technology innovation, environmental standards, and transparent market mechanisms for critical minerals including nickel. It emphasizes supply chain traceability using blockchain and digital certification to ensure ethical sourcing and quality. The strategy aims to diversify supply, reduce price volatility, and create high-tech jobs in refining, processing, and environmental remediation.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>