<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:15:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Honeywell Unveils Breakthrough Technology to Produce Low-Cost, High-Quality Renewable Fuels from Biomass</title><link>https://thecsruniverse.com/articles/honeywell-unveils-breakthrough-technology-to-produce-low-cost-high-quality-renewable-fuels-from-biomass</link><description>Honeywell announced a new Biocrude Upgrading technology that converts agricultural and forestry waste into renewable fuels such as marine fuel, gasoline, and sustainable aviation fuel. This technology offers a cost-effective, scalable solution for decarbonizing sectors like shipping and aviation by producing drop-in renewable fuels that require no engine modifications. It addresses key challenges of cost and feedstock availability, supporting India’s clean energy transition goals.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>ASI Certifies Shandong Innovation Group Co., Ltd. Against Performance Standard V3.1 and Chain of Custody V2</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/asi-certifies-shandong-innovation-group-co-ltd-against-performance-standard-v3-1-and-chain-of-custody-v2-116022</link><description>Shandong Innovation Group Co., Ltd. has been certified by the Aluminium Stewardship Initiative (ASI) against the latest sustainability standards for recycling, remelting aluminium scrap, and producing aluminium alloys. The certification covers multiple facilities in China with a combined annual production capacity exceeding five million tonnes. This recognition underscores the company's commitment to sustainable aluminium production and supports sectors like automotive lightweighting and electronics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>UAE Aluminum Curtain Wall Market Forecast &amp; Opportunity Report 2025</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/30/3177615/0/en/UAE-Aluminum-Curtain-Wall-Market-Forecast-Opportunity-Report-2025-A-950-Million-Industry-by-2030-Driven-by-Urbanization-Sustainable-Construction-and-Rising-Demand-for-Energy-Effici.html</link><description>The UAE aluminum curtain wall market is projected to grow significantly, driven by urbanization and a rising demand for sustainable construction. A key trend is the adoption of smart facades integrating sensors, solar panels, and automated shading to optimize energy efficiency in buildings. This aligns with the UAE’s sustainability goals and is prompting innovation in high-performance aluminum curtain wall systems.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China Base Metals Demand 15th Five-Year Plan 2025 Guide</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/base-metals-demand-china-15th-five-year-plan-2025/</link><description>China’s 15th Five-Year Plan emphasizes increased recycled aluminium use, energy efficiency, and technology upgrades to reduce carbon intensity in line with environmental policies. The plan supports a shift toward circular economy principles with a target to raise recycled nonferrous metals to 24% of total supply by 2025. These policies create price premiums and encourage innovation in aluminium recycling and sustainable production technologies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US-China Trade Deal Optimism Fuels Asian Steel Production Surge, But October Slowdown Looms</title><link>https://lagrand.ch/us-china-trade-deal-optimism-fuels-asian-steel-production-surge-but-october-slowdown-looms-202510300353/</link><description>Asian steel production saw a surge from May to September 2025, peaking in August, driven by optimism over a potential US-China trade deal. However, October data shows a significant slowdown in overall plant activity, despite some Chinese producers maintaining high output levels, suggesting broader supply issues in the region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World Copper Announces Closing of Sale of Zonia Copper Project</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=690354b4126e28028c37aae9</link><description>World Copper Ltd. completed the sale of its Zonia Copper Project in Arizona to Edge Copper Corporation for $10.5 million in cash and shares, resulting in World Copper owning approximately 31.3% of Edge Copper. The transaction was finalized under a court-approved plan of arrangement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Arca Climate Technologies inks 10-year carbon removal offtake deal with Microsoft</title><link>https://www.mining.com/arca-climate-technologies-inks-10-year-carbon-removal-offtake-deal-with-microsoft/</link><description>Arca Climate Technologies signed a 10-year carbon removal offtake agreement with Microsoft, focusing on repurposing mining byproducts like tailings and waste rock to accelerate carbon mineralization. This process transforms CO2 into solid minerals, providing durable carbon removal, reducing mine waste, and creating jobs, with plans to scale from pilot projects to million-tonne operations.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Gold and Copper: The Unseen Forces Powering Market Returns</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-30-gold-and-copper-the-unseen-forces-powering-market-returns-blackrock-unveils-overlooked-opportunities</link><description>Copper prices have surged over 27% in 2025, driven by sustained demand from green energy and digital transformation. Market experts like BlackRock suggest copper's price rise reflects a fundamental supply-demand imbalance, indicating a new higher baseline for copper driven by decarbonization and digitalization trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ceria Group Produces First Green Nickel, Pushes Ahead with Smelter Expansion</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/ceria-group-produces-first-green-nickel-pushes-ahead-with-smelter-expansion</link><description>PT Ceria Nugraha Indotama (Ceria Group) has commenced production of green nickel at its smelter in Indonesia and is continuing with expansion plans. This marks a milestone in Indonesia's push toward more sustainable nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian reported third-quarter revenue of €5.03 billion, beating consensus estimates, driven by strong growth in Renewable Transmission and Power Grids units. The company raised its full-year 2025 guidance, supported by a stable high-voltage backlog of about €16 billion and solid organic growth in key segments.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian upgrades 2025 guidance</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/06-10-am-prysmian-upgrades-2025-guidance-ce7d5dd3dd8ef426</link><description>Following strong performance in the first nine months of 2025, Prysmian upgraded its full-year guidance, citing excellent contributions from its Transmission business and North American region. The company emphasizes its leadership in cable solutions and its strategic focus on energy transition and digital transformation.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit 6-Month High as Supply Concerns Grow</title><link>https://oilprice.com/Energy/Energy-General/Aluminum-Prices-Hit-6-Month-High-as-Supply-Concerns-Grow.html</link><description>Aluminum prices reached their highest level since early 2025 amid fears of supply deficits as China nears its 45-million-ton output cap. Despite subdued demand in the US and tariff pressures, long-term deficit concerns support a bullish outlook, although near-term price direction remains uncertain.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Hitachi Energy unveils innovations for a sustainable energy future at CIIE 2025</title><link>https://www.hitachienergy.com/news-and-events/press-releases/2025/10/hitachi-energy-unveils-innovations-for-a-sustainable-energy-future-at-ciie-2025</link><description>Hitachi Energy showcased innovations to improve grid reliability and support green hydrogen production, collaborating with major steel enterprises. Their eco-efficient gas-insulated switchgear (GIS) technology reduces reliance on SF₆, a potent greenhouse gas, aiding grid decarbonization. These advancements contribute to sustainable steel production by enhancing energy infrastructure and supporting green technologies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris reduced pipe sales to 2.95 million tons in January-September</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/tenaris-reduced-pipe-sales-to-2-95-million-tons-in-january-september/</link><description>Tenaris, the international pipe company, reported a 2% decrease in pipe sales for January-September 2025, totaling 2.95 million tons compared to the same period last year. The decline reflects ongoing market adjustments in the steel and pipe industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>FTSE MIB Hits Three-Week High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/italy/stock-market/news/498089</link><description>Tenaris shares rose 4.8% in Italy, contributing to the FTSE MIB's three-week high, as strong corporate earnings and positive market sentiment boosted heavyweight stocks. The index is on track for its fourth monthly advance, with financials and industrials leading gains.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 3.04% Lower at $5.0780 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2025103013281/comex-copper-settles-304-lower-at-50780-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for November delivery dropped 3.04% to $5.0780 per pound, marking the largest one-day percentage decline since October 10, 2025. Despite this drop, copper remains up 27.40% year-to-date and 5.68% month-to-date, though it is off 12.37% from its 52-week high reached in July 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mexico &amp; US make 90% progress in tariff negotiations, while steel and aluminum issues remain to be concluded</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/mexico-us-make-90-progress-in-tariff-negotiations-while-steel-and-aluminum-issues-remain-to-be-concluded/157524</link><description>Mexico and the US have made 90% progress in tariff negotiations, but issues related to steel and aluminum tariffs are still pending resolution. This ongoing negotiation could impact aluminum trade dynamics between the two countries.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory Rises to 98,500 mt on Oct 31, 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103597334/SMM:-Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-Rises-to-98500-mt-on-Oct-31-2025</link><description>Domestic aluminum billet inventory in two key locations rose to 98,500 metric tons as of October 31, 2025. The Shanghai Futures Exchange (SHFE) aluminum price remains in an upward channel, reflecting ongoing market strength despite inventory increases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nothing should be left on table to keep Rio Tinto's aluminum smelter open, says Australian minister</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/nothing-should-be-left-on-table-to-keep-rio-tintos-aluminum-smelter-open-says-australian-minister/</link><description>The Australian Minister emphasized that all possible measures should be taken to keep Rio Tinto's aluminum smelter operational, highlighting the importance of maintaining production capacity in the country.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory Rises to 98,500 mt on Oct 31, 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103597334/SMM:-Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-Rises-to-98500-mt-on-Oct-31-2025</link><description>According to SMM statistics, the inventory of aluminum billet in two domestic locations increased to 98,500 metric tons as of October 31, 2025, indicating changes in supply and demand dynamics within the domestic aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Update: Slight Daily Gain Amid Monthly Decline</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China rose to 3,092 CNY/T on October 31, up 0.13% from the previous day, but have fallen 0.10% over the past month and are down nearly 5% year-on-year. Analysts expect further declines, forecasting a price of 3,022.85 CNY/T by the end of the quarter and 2,890.00 CNY/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Dips Slightly, Remains Up Sharply Year-on-Year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-rolled coil (HRC) steel fell to 844.08 USD/T on October 31, down 0.70% from the previous day, but prices are up 4.72% over the past month and 18.32% year-on-year. Forecasts suggest HRC steel may trade at 827.34 USD/T by the end of the quarter but could rise to 892.84 USD/T in a year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Steel Consumption Falls 5.7% Year-on-Year in First Three Quarters of 2025</title><link>https://in.marketscreener.com/news/china-s-steel-consumption-in-the-first-three-quarters-of-2025-fell-5-7-y-y-association-says-ce7d5cdad080f62c</link><description>China's steel consumption dropped 5.7% year-on-year in the first nine months of 2025, according to industry association data. This decline reflects ongoing weak domestic demand despite strong export growth earlier in the year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's steel consumption in the first three quarters of 2025 fell 5.7% y/y, association says</title><link>https://in.marketscreener.com/news/china-s-steel-consumption-in-the-first-three-quarters-of-2025-fell-5-7-y-y-association-says-ce7d5cdad080f62c</link><description>China's steel consumption dropped 5.7% year-on-year in the first three quarters of 2025, according to industry association data. This decline reflects ongoing challenges in the Chinese steel market amid broader economic pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP POSCO Partner on Near Zero Emissions Steel Technology</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/steel-manufacturing-hydrogen-technology-reshapes-2025/</link><description>BHP and POSCO have partnered to develop POSCO's HyREX hydrogen reduction ironmaking technology aimed at near-zero emissions steel production. A demonstration plant with 300,000 tonnes annual capacity is planned at Pohang Steelworks, targeting commissioning by early 2028, marking a significant step toward decarbonizing the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hydrogen-Based Low Emissions Iron: Tech &amp; Benefits</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/hydrogen-steel-production-emissions-reduction-2025/</link><description>Hydrogen-based steel production technology is set to transform the global steel industry by enabling distributed production closer to end markets, reducing emissions and transportation costs. This shift favors renewable energy-rich regions and smaller, flexible facilities, with ongoing advancements in hydrogen production and integration with carbon capture systems promising further environmental benefits.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Declines from 3-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/497786</link><description>US copper futures fell to $5.09 per pound from a three-month high of $5.17 due to a stronger dollar and uncertain demand outlook despite ongoing supply concerns. The easing of US-China trade barriers and a fatal mudslide at an Indonesian mine affecting over 3% of global supply also influenced market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/base-metals-investing/copper-investing/copper-forecast/</link><description>Copper prices were volatile in Q3 2025, reaching record highs of $5.81 per pound on COMEX driven by tariff fears and supply-demand fundamentals. After a sharp decline in August, prices rebounded in September and early October, breaking above $5 per pound as supply fundamentals strengthened.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices fell to $5.06 per pound on October 31, down 0.43% from the previous day but remain near three-month highs. The market is influenced by US-China trade developments, a recent Fed rate cut, and ongoing supply disruptions from major miners and mine incidents in Chile and Indonesia.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Rally Hits Record $11200 Per Ton in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-price-rally-2025-supply-demand-momentum/</link><description>Copper prices surpassed $11,200 per ton in 2025 amid supply disruptions and strong demand from the energy transition. Goldman Sachs projects prices to remain between $10,000 and $11,000 per ton in 2026-2027, balancing supply recovery and demand growth, while potential supply disruptions could push prices higher.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>ENAMI's New Smelter Approved, LME Copper Fell Sharply Last Night</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103597243/ENAMIs-New-Smelter-Approved-LME-Copper-Fell-Sharply-Last-Night-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Chilean state-owned ENAMI received environmental permits to build a new $1.7 billion copper smelter as part of modernizing its Hernan Videla Lira smelter in northern Atacama. The new facility will process up to 850,000 metric tons of copper concentrates annually and produce up to 240,000 metric tons of copper cathode via electrorefining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Capstone Copper Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://capstonecopper.com/news/capstone-copper-reports-third-quarter-2025-results/</link><description>Capstone Copper reported Q3 2025 sulphide copper production of 44,904 tonnes at a C1 cash cost of $2.00/lb, a significant improvement from Q3 2024. The Pinto Valley Mine experienced a 29% production decline due to lower grades and mill throughput impacted by drought-related water constraints, but throughput improved in October 2025 with full mill operations resuming.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Declines from 3-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/497786</link><description>US copper futures fell from a three-month high due to a stronger dollar and uncertain demand outlook despite ongoing supply concerns. Supply shocks include lower output from major miners like Glencore and Anglo American and a halt in operations at a Freeport-McMoRan mine in Indonesia responsible for over 3% of global supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Eurasian Resources Mercuria Copper Deal: $100M Agreement</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/eurasian-resources-mercuria-copper-deal-2025/</link><description>Eurasian Resources and Mercuria signed a $100 million strategic agreement focusing on copper production capacity in the Democratic Republic of Congo. The deal supports annual output exceeding 200,000 tonnes and integrates mining with on-site processing, impacting global supply and spot market dynamics by stabilizing contracted volumes over three years.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Plans Angola Copper Drill Program by Q4 2025</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/3110-49997-ivanhoe-mines-plans-angola-copper-drill-program-by-q4-2025</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced a 6,400-meter diamond drilling campaign in Angola's Moxico and Cuando Cubango provinces starting Q4 2025. This marks the company's first major copper exploration in Angola following permit acquisition in 2023, aiming to expand its footprint in Africa’s copper sector amid strong global demand driven by renewable energy and electrification.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Patriot Expands Copper-Gold Footprint in Zambia</title><link>https://mining.com.au/patriot-expands-copper-gold-footprint-in-zambia/</link><description>Patriot Resources expanded its copper-gold footprint within the Kitumba Project in Zambia after completing a phase one trenching program. The company identified a potential 200m strike zone and is preparing for ground magnetics and induced polarisation surveys to map subsurface sulphidic zones, advancing its exploration efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices dropped slightly on October 31 while spot premiums strengthened</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103598443/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-dropped-slightly-on-October-31-while-spot-premiums-strengthened</link><description>On October 31, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 120,500 and 123,400 yuan/mt, averaging 121,950 yuan/mt, which was down 250 yuan/mt from the previous day. Despite the slight price drop, spot premiums showed signs of strengthening.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Posts Net Profit Beat and Cuts Copper, Nickel Cost Outlook</title><link>https://blockchain.news/flashnews/vale-posts-net-profit-beat-and-cuts-copper-nickel-cost-outlook-trading-watch-for-mining-stocks-and-commodities</link><description>Brazilian mining giant Vale reported a stronger-than-expected net profit for the quarter and lowered its cost outlook for copper and nickel production. This development suggests potential stabilization of nickel prices around $8.00 per pound amid operational efficiencies and fluctuating global demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/base-metals-investing/nickel-investing/nickel-forecast/</link><description>Nickel prices were volatile in the first half of 2025 but stabilized in Q3 amid ongoing oversupply concerns. Prices ranged mostly between $15,000 and $15,500 per metric ton, with market uncertainty influenced by US trade policies and the end of the EV tax credit.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices Q3 2025 review: China restocking lifts sulphate and MHP as LME oversupply persists</title><link>https://source.benchmarkminerals.com/article/nickel-prices-q3-2025-review-china-restocking-lifts-sulphate-and-mhp-as-lme-oversupply-persists</link><description>During Q3 2025, nickel prices remained at five-year lows due to persistent oversupply on the London Metal Exchange, although restocking in China helped lift prices for nickel sulphate and mixed hydroxide precipitate (MHP). The market continues to face supply-demand imbalances despite these regional demand boosts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Eramet’s Weda Bay nickel ore sales surge in Q3 after RKAB revision</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/eramet-s-weda-bay-nickel-ore-sales-surge-in-q3-after-rkab-revision</link><description>French mining group Eramet reported a sharp rebound in nickel ore sales from its Weda Bay operations in Indonesia during the third quarter, following a revision to its mining work plan (RKAB). The article notes a significant increase in sales volume, though full details require a login to access.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel x Biomining</title><link>https://www.worldfund.vc/knowledge/nickel-x-biomining</link><description>World Fund explores innovative climate tech solutions to reduce the high carbon emissions of nickel production, which currently exceeds those of copper, aluminum, and lithium. The article highlights the need for new supply chains or refining processes to ensure resilient, low-cost, and low-emission nickel supply, especially given the concentration of production in China and Indonesia. Two promising innovation pathways and startups in alternative nickel production are discussed.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>What if an EV was made without metals or minerals?</title><link>https://thedriven.io/2025/10/31/what-if-an-ev-was-made-without-metals-or-minerals/</link><description>Sandvik unveiled an electric car made without metals or minerals to highlight the critical role of mining in sustainable development and the green transition. The article emphasizes the need to scale sustainable mining practices for lithium, nickel, and cobalt to meet net-zero goals by 2050. It also describes the future of mining as autonomous, electrified, and digitalized to optimize resource extraction with minimal environmental impact.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cobalt-Free EV Cathodes: Sustainable Battery Solutions</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/cobalt-free-cathodes-electric-vehicles-2025/</link><description>Research on cobalt-free cathodes, including nickel-iron-aluminium compositions, aims to reduce reliance on critical materials like cobalt and nickel in EV batteries. The article discusses technical challenges such as performance optimization and manufacturing scaling, alongside government policy support to promote sustainable battery technologies. Advances in battery recycling and circular economy approaches are also highlighted.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals Production Alliance: Global Strategy</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-landscape-2025-energy-transition/</link><description>The alliance focuses on sustainable competitive advantages through technology innovation, environmental standards, and transparent market mechanisms for critical minerals including nickel. It emphasizes supply chain traceability using blockchain and digital certification to ensure ethical sourcing and quality. The strategy aims to diversify supply, reduce price volatility, and create high-tech jobs in refining, processing, and environmental remediation.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to Over 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>UK aluminum futures rose above $2,900 per tonne in October, marking the highest price in over three years. This increase is driven by tight near-term supply and strong long-term demand, with China emphasizing prevention of overcapacity in metal production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nucor raises prices for thick-gauge rolled steel by $60/t starting in November</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/nucor-raises-prices-for-thick-gauge-rolled-steel-by-60-t-starting-in-november/</link><description>Nucor announced a price increase of $60 per ton for thick-gauge rolled steel products starting November 2025. The new theoretical price for standard thickness A36 base rolled products is estimated at around $1,335 per ton, reflecting market adjustments amid ongoing demand dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel prices fall slightly amid mixed market signals</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China fell to 3,067 CNY/ton on October 31, 2025, down 0.68% from the previous day, continuing a slight downward trend over the past month. Prices are down 6.2% compared to the same time last year, with forecasts suggesting a moderate decline over the next 12 months due to market uncertainties.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's steel production will fall below 1 billion tonnes in 2025, but the industry imbalance persists</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/10/31/chinas-steel-production-will-fall-below-1-billion-tonnes-in-2025-but-the-industry-imbalance-persists</link><description>China's crude steel production is expected to drop below 1 billion tonnes in 2025, continuing government efforts to reduce output and restructure the sector. Despite the production cut, a supply-demand imbalance remains due to a prolonged downturn in the steel-intensive real estate market and a surge in exports of lower-value steel billets. The steel industry faces challenges including rising material costs and the need for significant investment to meet carbon neutrality goals by 2060.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>New Capacity Additions and Production Resumptions Advance Aluminum Operating Rate Outside China</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103599862</link><description>Aluminum production outside China increased by 2.6% year-on-year in October 2025, with an average operating rate of 89.0%. Century Aluminum temporarily halted one potline at its Iceland smelter due to electrical failure, while Alcoa's Q3 production rose 1% quarter-on-quarter, aided by the San Ciprián plant restart. The operating capacity of a new Indonesian project is expected to ramp up in November, with the aluminum operating rate outside China projected to increase slightly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-Year High Amid Tight Supply and Output Caps</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,892.55 per tonne on October 31, 2025, reaching a three-year high due to tight supply and China's output cap of 45 million tons annually. Supply pressures include the suspension of one potline at Iceland's Grundartangi smelter and Alcoa's planned shutdown of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia. These factors, combined with strong demand from electrification sectors, have contributed to a nearly 25% drop in primary aluminum stocks at the LME this year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Rebounds from 3-Month Low as China Curbing Capacity</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China climbed to around CNY 3,100 per ton, near two-month highs, following new government measures to curb steelmaking capacity in key regions. This policy aims to rebalance supply and demand amid weak domestic demand and a prolonged property downturn, improving profit margins for steel producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Month 5.42% Higher at $5.0655 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510318014/comex-copper-ends-the-month-542-higher-at-50655-data-talk</link><description>Comex Copper for November delivery gained 5.42% over the month to $5.0655 per pound, marking three consecutive months of gains and the largest three-month net increase since March 2025. Despite a slight recent decline, copper prices remain significantly higher than the 52-week low and have risen over 16% in the last three months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM: October's product-wise aluminium processing PMI mostly dropped below 50 mark</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/smm-octobers-product-wise-aluminium-processing-pmi-mostly-dropped-below-50-mark-116038</link><description>In October, aluminum processing PMI mostly fell below 50, indicating contraction in production activity. High aluminum prices increased costs and squeezed profits, while end-use demand remains weak, suggesting continued pressure on the industry unless prices or demand improve.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Fully optimised for sustainability</title><link>https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/global/article/detail/T0409378EN/fully-optimised-for-sustainability?language=en</link><description>BMW Group's light metal foundry in Landshut has been recertified by the Aluminium Stewardship Initiative (ASI) for its sustainable use of aluminium. Over a third of its annual aluminium needs are met with solar aluminium, and nearly two-thirds come from recycled sources.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>When going green becomes the new profit curve for aluminium. Or ...</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/when-going-green-becomes-the-new-profit-curve-for-aluminium-or-does-it-115807</link><description>The aluminium industry faces a critical juncture as demand is projected to rise by 80% by 2050, but it remains a major emitter. Producers must invest in green technologies now to remain competitive and avoid regulatory and market penalties.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>European Green Aluminium Summit 2025 to Tackle Sustainability and Policy Challenges</title><link>https://glassbalkan.com/news/european-green-aluminium-summit-2025-to-tackle-sustainability-and-policy-challenges/</link><description>The 3rd European Green Aluminium Summit will be held in Düsseldorf, Germany, on November 11–12, 2025, focusing on green aluminium production, recycling, and circular economy strategies. The event will address EU climate policies and innovations in low-carbon aluminium technologies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The 3rd European Green Aluminium Summit 2025</title><link>https://netzerocompare.com/events/the-3rd-european-green-aluminium-summit-2025</link><description>This summit will explore aluminium's role in Europe's green transition, highlighting technological innovations, regulatory impacts, and sustainability practices. It will feature discussions on low-carbon production, recycling, and EU climate legislation.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Brazilian Aluminium Can Summit 2025 brings together global leaders to discuss the future of the aluminium can industry</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/brazilian-aluminium-can-summit-2025-brings-together-global-leaders-to-discuss-the-future-of-the-aluminium-can-industry-116006</link><description>The Brazilian Aluminium Can Summit 2025 will gather industry leaders to discuss innovation, decarbonization, and the circular economy in the aluminium can sector. The event will highlight sustainability and competitiveness in the global aluminium packaging industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Parts Trends 2025: Innovation &amp; Sustainability</title><link>https://www.accio.com/business/aluminum-parts-trends</link><description>The aluminium parts market is growing, driven by demand in automotive, construction, and packaging sectors. Emphasis on recycled aluminium and low-carbon production is becoming a competitive advantage for businesses.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>First brake caliper made from 100% recycled aluminium sets a benchmark in sustainability</title><link>https://www.aftermarketinternational.com/en/news/latest-news/9552-first-brake-caliper-made-from-100-recycled-aluminium-sets-a-benchmark-in-sustainability.html</link><description>Brembo has introduced the first brake caliper made entirely from recycled aluminium, reducing CO₂ emissions by 70% over its lifecycle without compromising performance. This innovation highlights the potential for sustainable materials in automotive components.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Gerdau Reports Strong US Steel Demand Growth in 4Q</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/us-steel-recovery-market-dynamics-2025/</link><description>Gerdau's North American steel operations saw an 11% revenue increase in Q3 2025, driven by strong U.S. market demand. Crude steel production rose 11.6% year-over-year, with sales volumes also increasing. The extended order backlog of 70 days, above the historical average, indicates sustained demand momentum into early 2026, fueled by infrastructure and renewable energy projects.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Brazilian Steel Market Faces Import Competition Stalling Prices</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/brazil-steel-market-pressures-2025-imports/</link><description>Brazil's steel industry is under pressure from high import competition, which is stalling domestic steel price increases despite attempts to raise prices. Several Brazilian steel plants are operating at losses due to margin compression and ongoing import challenges. An antidumping investigation is underway but will extend uncertainty until late 2026, threatening the sustainability of local production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Personnel changes on the Executive Board of thyssenkrupp Steel</title><link>https://www.thyssenkrupp-steel.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/personnel-changes-on-the-executive-board-of-thyssenkrupp-steel.html</link><description>Thyssenkrupp Steel announced executive board changes effective November 1, 2025, including Wilfried von Rath taking on additional HR responsibilities and Marie Jaroni assuming interim responsibility for production operations and strategic management. These changes aim to strengthen leadership as the company navigates future challenges in steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Issues 2025 Third-Quarter Financial Results and Overview of Construction and Exploration Activities</title><link>https://www.ivanhoemines.com/news-stories/news-release/ivanhoe-mines-issues-2025-third-quarter-financial-results-overview-of-construction-and-exploration-activities/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines reported that during Q3 2025, their Kamoa-Kakula copper complex milled 3.46 million tonnes of ore, producing 71,226 tonnes of copper. Year-to-date copper production reached 316,393 tonnes, with 2025 guidance maintained at 370,000 to 420,000 tonnes. The Phase 3 concentrator operated at 30% above design capacity, and dewatering of the Kakula Mine is progressing, with higher-grade mining expected from November.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Glencore 9-month Own-sourced Copper Production Down - Nasdaq</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/glencore-9-month-own-sourced-copper-production-down-narrows-fy-copper-production-outlook</link><description>Glencore reported a 17% decline in own-sourced copper production for the first nine months of 2025, totaling 583,500 tonnes, due to lower head grades and recoveries from planned mine sequencing. The company revised its full-year copper production guidance to 850,000 to 875,000 tonnes, down from the previous 850,000 to 890,000 tonnes range.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Adhi Kartiko nine-month profit soars on stronger nickel sales</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/adhi-kartiko-nine-month-profit-soars-on-stronger-nickel-sales</link><description>PT Adhi Kartiko Pratama Tbk, an IDX-listed nickel mining firm, reported a significant increase in its nine-month profit, attributed to stronger nickel sales. The article is paywalled, so further details on production or capacity are not available.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale posts net profit beat, cuts cost outlook for copper, nickel</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/vale-posts-net-profit-beat-cuts-cost-outlook-for-copper-nickel/</link><description>Vale, a major global miner, reported better-than-expected net profits and announced a reduction in its cost outlook for both copper and nickel operations. The article does not provide specific details on nickel production or capacity changes.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why Nickel is Set to Skyrocket: The EV and Renewable Energy Revolution</title><link>https://neoenergy.co.id/why-nickel-is-set-to-skyrocket-the-ev-and-renewable-energy-revolution</link><description>Nickel is becoming a cornerstone in the shift towards sustainable energy, especially in electric vehicle (EV) batteries and renewable energy storage systems. Companies like PT. Anugrah Neo Energy Materials are producing advanced nickel materials aligned with environmental, social, and governance (ESG) standards to support the growing demand for battery-grade nickel in EVs and grid storage.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Pioneering the Future of Sustainable Nickel: TGEM and BGM's Strategic Joint Venture in the US and Albania</title><link>https://tgem.group/pioneering-the-future-of-sustainable-nickel-tgem-and-bgms-strategic-joint-venture-in-the-us-and-albania/</link><description>TGEM and BGM have signed a memorandum of understanding to develop sustainable Class 1 Nickel supply chains critical for the US and European EV markets. The joint venture will establish processing facilities using TGEM’s STAL Technology to produce Mixed Hydroxide Precipitate (MHP) for battery supply chains, emphasizing sustainable practices and innovation in nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's Nickel Mining for EV Boom Threatens Environment</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/news/indonesias-nickel-mining-for-ev-boom-threatens-environment-2/</link><description>Indonesia, the world’s top nickel producer, faces environmental challenges as its nickel mining expands rapidly to meet EV battery demand. While nickel is crucial for the clean energy transition, mining activities threaten biodiversity and ecosystems, raising concerns about balancing economic benefits with environmental sustainability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ambatovy Nickel Project Weathers Madagascar's Political Upheaval</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/ambatovy-nickel-project-madagascar-2025-production-2025/</link><description>The Ambatovy nickel project in Madagascar has maintained operational stability despite political turmoil, ensuring uninterrupted supply of battery-grade nickel. This stability is critical for global EV manufacturers relying on consistent nickel availability, highlighting the importance of diversified and reliable nickel sources amid regional supply uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Steel fell to 3,067 CNY/T on October 31, 2025, down 0.68%</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,067 CNY per ton on October 31, 2025, down 0.68% from the previous day. Over the past month, steel prices have declined by 0.90% and are down 6.78% compared to the same time last year. Steel is expected to trade at 3,022.85 Yuan/MT by the end of this quarter and 2,890.00 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel price trends and forecasts</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) Steel price decreased to 789 USD/T, the lowest since February 2025. Over the past month, HRC Steel prices rose 5.09% and are up 18.63% year-over-year. Analysts expect HRC Steel to trade at 827.34 USD/T by the end of this quarter and 892.84 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Issues 2025 Third-Quarter Financial Results Overview of Construction and Exploration Activities</title><link>https://www.ivanhoemines.com/news-stories/news-release/ivanhoe-mines-issues-2025-third-quarter-financial-results-overview-of-construction-and-exploration-activities/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines reported Q3 2025 copper production of 71,226 tonnes, with year-to-date output at 316,393 tonnes, maintaining its annual guidance of 370,000–420,000 tonnes. Production was impacted by seismic activity and flooding at the Kakula Mine, but the Phase 3 concentrator operated above design capacity, and new power supply is expected from November 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Q3 Profits Shrink on Copper Mine Disruption</title><link>https://www.mining.com/ivanhoe-q3-profits-shrink-on-copper-mine-disruption/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines saw a significant drop in Q3 2025 profits due to seismic activity and flooding at its Kamoa-Kakula copper complex, resulting in lower copper production and sales. Despite the disruption, the company remains on track to meet its revised annual production guidance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals Report (11.01.2025): Trump-Xi Rare Earth Deal Buys Time Not Security While Copper Soars to New Records</title><link>https://investornews.com/market-opinion/critical-minerals-report-11-01-2025-trump-xi-rare-earth-deal-buys-time-not-security-while-copper-soars-to-new-records/</link><description>Copper equities led gains in the S&amp;P Global Metals &amp; Mining Index, driven by strong market sentiment and record copper prices. The report highlights ongoing global efforts to secure critical minerals supply chains amid geopolitical developments.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals Report (11.01.2025): Trump-Xi Rare Earth Deal Buys Time Not Security While Copper Soars to New Records</title><link>https://investornews.com/market-opinion/critical-minerals-report-11-01-2025-trump-xi-rare-earth-deal-buys-time-not-security-while-copper-soars-to-new-records/</link><description>Nickel prices remained volatile around $16,500 per tonne amid concerns over supply chain consolidation, particularly with the European Commission investigating the sale of Anglo American's nickel assets to a Chinese state-backed company. The report highlights geopolitical tensions impacting nickel supply security, alongside a rally in copper prices driven by tightening inventories and infrastructure optimism.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Diamond Drilling Underway on Goodwin Copper-Nickel-Cobalt Project</title><link>https://www.juniorminingnetwork.com/junior-miner-news/press-releases/792-tsx-venture/sxl/190502-slam-exploration-presenting-at-the-51st-annual-new-orleans-investment-conference.html</link><description>Diamond drilling is in progress on the Goodwin copper-nickel-cobalt project in New Brunswick's Bathurst Mining Camp, indicating ongoing exploration and potential capacity expansion in nickel production. This project reflects continued investment in nickel resources amid evolving market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's nickel mining for EV boom threatens environment</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/news/indonesias-nickel-mining-for-ev-boom-threatens-environment-2/</link><description>Indonesia, the world’s top nickel producer, is expanding nickel mining to meet rising EV battery demand, but this growth threatens biodiversity and ecosystems. The country enforces domestic processing to maximize economic benefits, yet environmental activists warn of pollution and ecological harm from mining activities amid the EV boom.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's top cable maker sees US copper tariff as opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Italy's Prysmian, the world's largest copper cable maker, views the US government's planned 50% tariff on copper as an opportunity to strengthen the American supply chain. Prysmian, which acquired Texas-based Encore Wire, is in regular contact with US officials and expects the tariff to apply to both raw metal and semi-finished products like cable.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>When going green becomes the new profit curve for aluminium. Or does it?</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/when-going-green-becomes-the-new-profit-curve-for-aluminium-or-does-it-115807</link><description>The aluminium industry faces a critical juncture with an expected 80% rise in demand by 2050, driven by the energy transition. To meet this demand sustainably, the sector must invest heavily in technologies like inert-anode smelting to eliminate direct emissions, requiring about USD 200 billion by 2050. This investment is essential to maintain competitiveness amid tightening regulations and market pressures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ferrous pricing remains on narrow path</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/steel-recycling-ferrous-scrap-prices-usa-rmdas-davis-turkey-india/</link><description>U.S. steel production increased by 2.2% through September 2025 compared to 2024, with 66.7 million tons produced in the first nine months. Ferrous scrap prices remained stable in a narrow range, with some volatility in September negatively impacting scrap sellers. U.S. mills are expected to show stable to rising demand for recycled steel in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cleveland-Cliffs and Posco sign partnership to mitigate steel import tariffs</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-11-02/business/industry/ClevelandCliffs-and-Posco-sign-partnership-to-mitigate-steel-import-tariffs/2434627</link><description>Posco signed a strategic partnership with Cleveland-Cliffs, the second-largest U.S. steelmaker, to mitigate trade risks including the 50% U.S. steel import tariff. Posco is considering investing in Cleveland-Cliffs, potentially acquiring a 20% stake valued at approximately $1.2 billion. Cleveland-Cliffs specializes in high value-added flat steel products for the automotive industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel demand weak for three years</title><link>https://www.thedailystar.net/business/economy/news/steel-demand-weak-three-years-4024826</link><description>Crude steel production is forecast to fall by 11% year-on-year in 2025, following a 10% drop in 2024. Industry insiders indicate ongoing weakness in steel demand over the past three years, impacting production volumes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel announces significant increases to Galvalume coating extras</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103580107/</link><description>U.S. Steel announced significant price increases for its Galvalume coating extras effective November 2, 2025, with hikes ranging up to 30%. This reflects rising costs and market demand for coated steel products.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Turkey's Raw Steel Production Sees New Surge: 1% Increase</title><link>https://www.yatirimmasasi.com/en/haberler/turkiyenin-ham-celik-uretiminde-yeni-yukselis-1-artis</link><description>Turkey's crude steel production increased by 1% in the January-September 2025 period, reaching 28.1 million tons, with a 7.2% rise in September alone. This growth reflects Turkey's strengthening position in the global steel market, supported by government incentives and efforts to reduce import dependency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cleveland-Cliffs and Posco sign partnership to mitigate steel import tariffs</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-11-02/business/industry/ClevelandCliffs-and-Posco-sign-partnership-to-mitigate-steel-import-tariffs/2434627</link><description>Posco has signed a strategic partnership with Cleveland-Cliffs, the second-largest U.S. steelmaker, to mitigate the impact of U.S. steel import tariffs. Posco is considering investing in Cleveland-Cliffs, potentially acquiring a significant stake to navigate trade risks and strengthen their market position.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel announces significant increases to Galvalume coating extras</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103580107</link><description>U.S. Steel announced price increases ranging from 30% to 49% for its Galvalume coating extras effective November 2, 2025, reflecting adjustments in response to market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ArcelorMittal gets environmental clearance for Anakapalli steel plant in Andhra Pradesh</title><link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/states/andhra-pradesh/2025/Nov/02/arcelormittal-gets-environmental-clearance-for-anakapalli-steel-plant-in-andhra</link><description>ArcelorMittal Nippon Steel's 8.2 MTPA greenfield integrated steel plant in Anakapalli district has received environmental clearance. The plant will use advanced, energy-efficient, and low-emission technologies meeting global sustainability standards, supporting India's position in sustainable steel production and catalyzing regional industrial growth.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Centre gives green clearance to planned AMNS steel plant at Nakkapalli</title><link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/centre-gives-green-clearance-to-planned-amns-steel-plant-at-nakkapali-101762026038309.html</link><description>The Union Ministry of Environment, Forests and Climate Change has recommended environmental clearance for the ArcelorMittal Nippon Steel plant at Nakkapalli, Andhra Pradesh. The plant, India's largest greenfield steel manufacturing initiative, will employ advanced, low-emission technologies and is expected to anchor the Andhra Pradesh Industrial Corridor.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price rally could cool after surge to record high - MINING.COM</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-rally-could-cool-after-surge-to-record-high/</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange rose as much as 1.5% to $11,200 per metric ton, surpassing the previous record high set in May 2024. The rally was driven by concerns over mine supply shortages and optimism about a US-China trade deal, although analysts caution that without sustained demand growth, the rally may slow. Major producers like Glencore and Anglo American reported lower copper output in the first nine months of 2025, tightening supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Higher Ahead of Trump-Xi Meeting</title><link>https://www.admis.com/copper-prices-higher-ahead-of-trump-xi-meeting/</link><description>Copper prices rose on optimism about a US-China trade deal, with benchmark copper on the LME up 0.6% at $11,026 per metric ton and US futures also up 0.6%. The rise was supported by data showing China's industrial profits grew at their fastest pace in nearly two years in September, although the Yangshan copper premium shrank, indicating slower purchase pace.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits 12-week High - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/496064</link><description>Copper prices increased to $5.21 per pound, the highest level since July 2025, gaining 7.03% over the past four weeks and nearly 20% over the last 12 months. The rise reflects ongoing supply concerns and market tightness despite some demand weakness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper hits 17-month peak on US-China trade deal optimism</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/copper-hits-17-month-peak-on-us-china-trade-deal-optimism/articleshow/124851490.cms</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange reached a 17-month high, trading at around $11,011 per metric ton, driven by easing trade tensions between the US and China and expectations of stronger growth and demand. The optimism about the trade deal has spurred buying in the copper market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price soars for 2 consecutive trading days</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/nickel-price-soars-for-2-consecutive-trading-days/98804</link><description>Nickel prices on the London Metal Exchange (LME) surged by US$145/ton to US$11,930/ton on November 2nd, marking a significant two-day rally. This sharp increase reflects heightened volatility and potential short-term bullish sentiment in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures dropped below $15,100 per tonne, the lowest in over a month, as oversupply from Indonesia continues to pressure the market. LME inventories have reached 308,000 tons, the highest since 2020, driven by a surge in Indonesian production and increased Chinese refining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures dropped below $15,100 per tonne, the lowest in over a month, due to continued oversupply from Indonesia flooding global supply chains. LME inventories reached a record high of 308,000 tons, with a significant share originating from Indonesia and China. In response, Indonesia has tightened production quotas and shortened mining permit validity to better regulate output and stabilize prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>