<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 05:18:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Thyssenkrupp pauses steel production at two sites citing Asian pressure</title><link>https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20251211-thyssenkrupp-pauses-steel-production-at-two-sites-citing-asian-pressure</link><description>Europe's largest steelmaker Thyssenkrupp is pausing steel production at its Gelsenkirchen, Germany, and Isbergues, France, sites for about two weeks due to a surge in low-cost Asian imports, leading to underutilized capacity. The French site will also operate at 50% capacity for at least four months starting January. The company calls for swift EU trade protection measures to restore sustainable operations, amid ongoing challenges from high energy costs and competition.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Imports Down 16.7% In September vs. August</title><link>https://www.steel.org/2025/12/steel-imports-down-16-7-in-september-vs-august/</link><description>US steel imports dropped 16.7% in September compared to August, with year-to-date finished import market share at 19%. The decline reflects ongoing tariff impacts and market dynamics affecting import volumes. This data highlights a continued reduction in reliance on foreign steel supplies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Weyerhaeuser and Aymium Enter Agreement to Rapidly Scale Biocarbon Market</title><link>https://investor.weyerhaeuser.com/2025-12-11-Weyerhaeuser-and-Aymium-Enter-Agreement-to-Rapidly-Scale-Biocarbon-Market</link><description>Weyerhaeuser and Aymium have partnered to expand biocarbon manufacturing, providing a sustainable alternative for steel production to replace traditional coal-based carbon. This initiative scales production of biocarbon derived from wood residuals, supporting decarbonization in the steel industry. The agreement accelerates the market for low-emission materials in heavy industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price rally resumes on supply warning</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-rally-resumes-on-supply-warning/</link><description>Copper rebound pushed three‑month LME futures toward a near record as warnings of a sizable supply shortfall and mine disruptions supported prices, with LME three‑month futures settling at $11,556.50/ton after an intraday gain; the article cites structural supply concerns and demand drivers such as EVs, data centers and renewable energy boosting the bullish case.[4][6] It also notes a prior record near $11,771/ton and that short‑term moves were influenced by China demand data and the US interest‑rate decision.[4][6]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rises with Fed rate cut, worries about outflows to US stocks</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-rises-with-fed-rate-cut-worries-about-outflows-to-us-stocks/</link><description>Copper prices rose after a US Federal Reserve rate cut, with buying supported by flows out of US copper stocks and continued concern about supply tightness; the article links the rate decision to the rally and notes movements across related metals.[7] It reports market reaction to monetary policy alongside physical market flows as drivers of price moves.[7]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rises to record high on rate cut - Markets</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40397059</link><description>Markets report that copper hit an all‑time high following a US Fed rate cut, with continuing flows into copper stocks cited as supporting the price surge and market commentary emphasizing tight fundamentals and demand from electrification and tech sectors.[8] The short item summarizes the market reaction to monetary policy and flow dynamics underlying the rally.[8]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[Nickel Midday Market Review] Nickel Prices Plunge Sharply</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103666272</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices averaged 118,850 yuan/mt on December 11, down 300 yuan/mt from the prior day amid Fed rate cut news overshadowed by weak fundamentals. SHFE nickel futures closed down 0.7% at 116,920 yuan/mt. Short-term prices expected in 114,000-118,000 yuan/mt range.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>ZincFive Wins Multiple Categories in the 2025 Power Technology Excellence Awards</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/business-wire/20251211321353/zincfive-wins-multiple-categories-in-the-2025-power-technology-excellence-awards</link><description>ZincFive has won awards in Innovation, Product Launch, Safety, and Environmental Excellence for its nickel-zinc battery technology, which offers high power density, inherent safety, and 25-50% lower lifetime greenhouse gas emissions than lead-acid or lithium-ion alternatives. The technology supports sustainability through recyclable materials and is deployed in nearly 2 gigawatts of systems for AI-driven data centers. This recognition underscores ZincFive's leadership in safe, sustainable power solutions for mission-critical infrastructure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>ZincFive Secures $30M in Oversubscribed Series F Financing to Power the Data Center Infrastructure Behind the AI Boom</title><link>https://theaiinsider.tech/2025/12/11/zincfive-secures-30m-in-oversubscribed-series-f-financing-to-power-the-data-center-infrastructure-behind-the-ai-boom/</link><description>ZincFive raised $30 million in oversubscribed Series F financing to expand its nickel-zinc battery technology, which provides superior power density, safety, and sustainability for data centers powering the AI boom. The funding supports scaling production of these environmentally friendly batteries as an alternative to traditional chemistries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Trading Economics summarizes recent aluminum market moves and notes that China — the world’s top producer — is expected to approach its 45-million-ton annual cap, limiting room for further production growth and affecting global supply expectations[2]. The page also highlights recent supply disruptions and planned smelter setbacks (for example in Indonesia) that are influencing prices and capacity outlooks[2].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trojan Horse</title><link>https://www.fdd.org/analysis/2025/12/11/trojan-horse/</link><description>FDD’s analysis highlights China’s dominant role in primary aluminum production (nearly 60% of global primary supply) and discusses strategic vulnerabilities tied to global dependence on Chinese aluminum capacity for defense‑relevant manufacturing[9]. The piece links production concentration to geopolitical and industrial-policy risks rather than immediate daily capacity changes[9].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[SMM High-grade NPI] Prices Edge Up Slowly, Yet Market Transactions Remain Sluggish</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103669774/High-grade-NPI-Prices-Rebound-Short-lived-Amid-Weak-Fundamentals-in-December</link><description>High-grade NPI prices edged up slowly on December 11 amid weak fundamentals in December's off-season. The average price of 10-12% high-grade NPI saw a rebound, but market transactions remained sluggish. This reflects ongoing challenges in the nickel pig iron segment tied to steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hovers Near 1-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/509178</link><description>Aluminum increased to 2917.00 USD/T, the highest since November 2025, with a 1.35% gain over the past 4 weeks. UK futures hovered near the one-month high due to improving demand, tight supply from China's production cap, setbacks in Indonesian smelters, and disruptions like the Iceland smelter suspension; prices have risen nearly 14% this year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Lifezone Metals Advances Kabanga Nickel Project Toward 2026 Final Investment Decision</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251211885509/en/Lifezone-Metals-Advances-Kabanga-Nickel-Project-Toward-2026-Final-Investment-Decision</link><description>Lifezone Metals has raised $75 million in H2 2025 to fund pre-FID activities for the Kabanga Nickel Project in Tanzania, one of the world's largest high-grade nickel sulfide deposits. The July 2025 Feasibility Study shows first-quartile costs with AISC of $3.36/lb nickel and after-tax NPV of $1.58 billion. The project advances toward a 2026 Final Investment Decision, de-risking for full-scale execution.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>CMR Green improves aluminum purity with German Steinert's technology</title><link>https://www.aluminum.yieh.com/en/cmr-green-improves-aluminum-purity-with-german-steinerts-technology/158262</link><description>CMR Green in India adopted Steinert sensor‑based sorting systems (induction, X‑ray, eddy‑current) across its plants to raise recycled aluminium alloy purity and recovery rates, improving operational stability and supporting reduced CO2 emissions versus primary production. The report notes the partnership enhances circularity and positions the firm as a premium recycled‑alloy supplier.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Australia Pledges Deal to Keep Giant Rio Tinto Aluminum Smelter Open</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2025121110462/australia-pledges-deal-to-keep-giant-rio-tinto-aluminum-smelter-open</link><description>Australian federal and state governments have agreed to collaborate with Rio Tinto's Tomago Aluminium, the country's largest smelter producing nearly 40% of Australia's aluminum (up to 590,000 metric tons yearly), to secure affordable power post-2028 and prevent closure due to high energy costs exceeding 40% of operations. The deal includes at least A$1 billion in investments over the next decade. Tomago, operational since 1983, is Australia's biggest electricity user.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum melted with Annular Fresnel solar at over 700°C</title><link>https://www.solarpaces.org/aluminum-melted-with-annular-fresnel-solar-at-over-700c/</link><description>Researchers demonstrated an annular Fresnel solar furnace capable of reaching temperatures above 700°C to melt and cast aluminum, showing a practical, low‑cost route for solar-driven aluminum recycling and production of branded ingots during field trials conducted in 2024–2025. The team argues the approach could enable near‑zero‑carbon aluminum recycling at scale in high‑DNI regions such as northern Chile, supporting circular-economy goals and interest from multinationals seeking ‘green aluminum’.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tomago Aluminium welcomes continued collaboration on future operations</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2025/tomago-aluminium-welcomes-continued-collaboration-on-future-operations</link><description>Tomago Aluminium and partners confirmed ongoing collaboration regarding the smelter's future operations, reflecting discussions about operational strategy and the site’s long‑term viability amid evolving energy and sustainability considerations. The release underscores stakeholder engagement around the aluminum operation’s future and potential transitions tied to decarbonization pathways.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Panasonic Group to showcase AI driven business solutions and circular‑design recycling advances</title><link>https://news.panasonic.com/global/press/en251212-2</link><description>Panasonic described BIPV developments and next‑generation recycling infrastructure that enable precise disassembly and high‑purity separation of materials (including metals), aiming to produce high‑quality recycled materials and advance circularity by fiscal 2028. The announcement emphasizes design for maintainability and material recovery that can support sustainable metal (including aluminum) recycling streams.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 12.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>Steel Radar's market page compiles the latest prices, indices and short market notes for global iron and steel exchanges, providing snapshot price data (including Shanghai rebar futures) and links to recent price movements and news updates relevant to traders and analysts.[3]  The page is structured as a running market bulletin with dated price lines and short topical items for rebar, scrap and iron markets.[3]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Utility Global and Kyocera Join Forces to Scale H2Gen® Manufacturing Globally for Economic Industrial Decarbonization</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/12/utility-global-and-kyocera-join-forces-to-scale-h2gen-manufacturing-globally-for-economic-industrial-decarbonization/</link><description>Utility Global and Kyocera are partnering to scale production of H2Gen systems, combining Utility's electrochemical cell technology with Kyocera's manufacturing expertise for hydrogen production using industrial off-gases. This enables economic decarbonization in hard-to-abate sectors like steel by producing clean hydrogen without electricity, lowering costs and emissions. The technology targets blast furnace steel production, which accounts for over 70% of global steel output and 85% of industry emissions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Whyalla Steelworks Hydrogen Integration Transforms Australian Green Steel Production</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/direct-reduction-australia-steelmaking-revolution-2025/</link><description>Whyalla Steelworks is integrating hydrogen-based direct reduction iron (DRI) technology to revolutionize green steel production in Australia. This innovation aims to reduce carbon emissions through sustainable steelmaking processes. The development marks a significant step toward low-emission steel manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Capital demands soar for new copper supply</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/market-intelligence/en/news-insights/research/2025/12/capital-demands-soar-for-new-copper-supply</link><description>Development costs for copper projects have escalated, with delays in 13 of 22 analyzed projects; Capstone Copper's Santo Domingo saw a 55% capex increase to boost annual output to 68,500 metric tons. Barrick's Reko Diq in Pakistan targets 377,000 metric tons annually from 2028 with high capex. Capital intensity averages high across regions, underscoring supply challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 14,602.75 USD/T on December 12, 2025, down 0.05% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have declined 2.39%, and are down significantly year-over-year. Forecasts indicate prices at 14,909.70 USD/MT by quarter-end.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] Upstream-Downstream Contradictions Surface as NPI Market Stagnates</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103668628/SMM-Nickel-Flash:-Upstream-Downstream-Contradictions-Surface-as-NPI-Market-Stagnates</link><description>On December 12, upstream nickel offers increased but sales remained difficult, with most transactions at average levels. Supply side challenges highlight contradictions between upstream and downstream markets. NPI market shows stagnation.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries lifts 2025 nickel sales and receives green light for growth</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/12/12/nickel-industries-lifts-2025-nickel-sales-and-receives-green-light-for-growth/</link><description>Nickel Industries received approval to raise its 2025 nickel ore sales quota from 9 million to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes, restarting sales from Hengjaya Mine. A five-year environmental permit supports 2026 growth targeting 19 million wmt annually. This boosts near-term revenue to Indonesia Morowali Industrial Park.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Boosts Nickel-Ore Sales Quota</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/12/nickel-industries-boosts-nickel-ore-sales-quota/</link><description>Nickel Industries boosted its 2025 nickel ore sales quota from 9 to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes from Hengjaya Mine, resuming stockpiled ore sales to Indonesia Morowali Industrial Park. Five-year AMDAL environmental approval underpins 2026 quota expansion. Expected to enhance revenue streams.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries lifts 2025 nickel sales and receives green light for growth</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/12/12/nickel-industries-lifts-2025-nickel-sales-and-receives-green-light-for-growth/</link><description>Nickel Industries has increased its 2025 nickel ore sales quota to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes and secured a five-year environmental permit enabling innovative in-pit tailings storage and a limonite slurry pipeline for its ENC HPAL plant. This technology aims to position ENC as the lowest carbon and cost-intensive HPAL globally while improving traceability and reducing environmental impact. The company anticipates approval for a 2026 quota of 19 million wmt and focuses on commissioning the Excelsior Nickel Cobalt project for EV battery supply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China wins the race against the US in aluminum recycling output, capacity and expansion</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5106786-china-wins-the-race-against-the-us-in-aluminum-recycling-output-capacity-and-expansion</link><description>Mysteel reports that China has more than doubled its secondary (recycled) aluminum output since 2010 and now accounts for roughly 38–40% of global recycled aluminum production; the piece notes significant new secondary projects in 2024 that added over 2.05 million tonnes of planned capacity and brought total secondary capacity to about 17.62 million tonnes[1]. The article contrasts China’s rapid expansion of recycled aluminum with the US, where secondary production growth has been modest and the economy has become secondary-dominant rather than primary-focused[1].</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3045 CNY/T on December 12, 2025, down 0.03% from the previous day, amid demand uncertainties in China. Steel rebar futures dropped toward CNY 3,040 per ton, the lowest in a month, despite Beijing's reaffirmation of broad economic support measures. Over the past month, prices have fallen 0.10%, and are down 7.36% year-over-year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 906.07 USD/T on December 12, 2025, down 0.10% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 5.97%, and are up 34.37% compared to the same time last year. The update reflects trading on a contract for difference tracking the benchmark market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Canada Says Tighter Limits on Steel Imports to Take Effect on Dec. 26</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512125888/canada-says-tighter-limits-on-steel-imports-to-take-effect-on-dec-26-update</link><description>Canada's finance department announced that new limits on steel imports will take effect on December 26 to support the domestic steel sector amid U.S. tariffs. The measures reduce imports from non-free-trade countries like China, Turkey, and Brazil to 20% of 2024 levels before a 50% tariff applies, and limit FTA countries (excluding U.S. and Mexico) to 75% of 2024 levels. This follows Algoma Steel's plan to cut 1,000 jobs due to unsustainable blast furnace production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>New Delhi Supports Tata Steel Indo–Sweden Partnership For Cleaner Industry, Innovation</title><link>https://urbanacres.in/new-delhi-supports-tata-steel-indo-sweden-partnership-for-cleaner-industry-innovation/</link><description>The article reports that New Delhi has extended support to Tata Steel under the Indo–Sweden Industry Transition Partnership to advance low‑carbon steel technologies and circular processes, including projects that recover metals from steel slag and convert residues into low‑carbon cement additives, presented at COP30 and launched at the Swedish Embassy in New Delhi.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green steel innovation: Tata Steel to establish HIsarna technology plant in Jamshedpur; Aims for sustainable production with 1 MTPA capacity</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/ranchi/green-steel-innovation-tata-steel-to-establish-hisarna-technology-plant-in-jamshedpur-aims-for-sustainable-production-with-1-mtpa-capacity/articleshow/125916951.cms</link><description>Tata Steel has approved engineering and regulatory work to build a ~1 million tonnes per annum HIsarna demonstration plant in Jamshedpur, deploying a low‑carbon ironmaking route that can use lower‑grade ore and eliminate coke while integrating slag reuse to cut emissions.[2]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest News &amp; Updates (industry perspectives on decarbonisation, hydrogen pilots, circularity)</title><link>https://www.responsiblesteel.org/news</link><description>ResponsibleSteel's news update highlights industry progress and challenges in steel decarbonisation: hydrogen‑based pilots, increased integration of renewable electricity, and a stronger focus on circular scrap‑based production, while noting barriers such as green hydrogen cost and infrastructure constraints.[3]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Steel Tracker — recent entries and analysis on low‑carbon investments and technology needs</title><link>https://www.industrytransition.org/green-steel-tracker/</link><description>LeadIT's Green Steel Tracker continues to log public announcements of low‑carbon steel investments and publishes analyses (including hydrogen and renewable electricity demand for EU transition), tracking industry commitments and gaps in net‑zero targets among major producers.[4]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>How technology is reshaping metal recycling</title><link>https://www.recyclingproductnews.com/article/44035/how-technology-is-reshaping-metal-recycling</link><description>The piece explains how digitalisation, sensors and advanced analytics are improving metal recycling quality and efficiency for the steel supply chain, citing technologies such as laser‑induced plasma spectroscopy for material composition analysis and control systems that reduce downtime and energy use.[5]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Weyerhaeuser and Aymium to rapidly scale biocarbon market (metallurgical‑grade biocarbon for iron &amp; steel)</title><link>https://www.pulpapernews.com/20251212/17289/weyerhaeuser-and-aymium-rapidly-scale-biocarbon-market</link><description>Weyerhaeuser and Aymium announced plans to scale production of metallurgical‑grade biocarbon as a drop‑in replacement for coal and coke in iron and steel production, targeting up to 1.5 million tonnes annually at full scale to reduce carbon intensity of metallurgical processes.[6]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex copper ends the week 1.83% lower at $5.2835 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512125886/comex-copper-ends-the-week-183-lower-at-52835-data-talk</link><description>Front‑month Comex copper for December delivery fell 9.85 cents per pound (1.83%) for the week, closing at $5.2835, marking the largest one‑week percentage decline since early November and snapping a two‑week winning streak. The report notes copper remains well above its 52‑week low and up roughly 32% year‑on‑year, while intraday volatility included a larger single‑day drop that was the biggest since late October[4].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper — Price, Chart, Historical Data, News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Trading Economics reports copper fell to $5.28 per pound on December 12, 2025 (down ~2.4% from the prior day) after reaching multi‑month highs earlier; the site also notes copper is up roughly 27–32% year‑on‑year and reached an all‑time high in July 2025. The page synthesizes price moves, recent drivers including Chinese stimulus expectations and a U.S. Fed rate cut, and includes linked short market updates on rallies and pullbacks[1].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CRU: Data center demand drives US rebar toward June 2023 highs</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/12/12/cru-data-center-demand-drives-us-rebar-toward-june-2023-highs/</link><description>US rebar prices rose in early December due to strong data center demand, approaching $1,000/metric ton, the highest since June 2023, supported by fewer imports and extended mill lead times. Structurals prices also increased amid supply tightness, while wire rod remained flat as end-use consumption lagged. Infrastructure activity around AI data centers boosted demand, though sustainability is questioned.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel Bounces after Testing 4-Year Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures in the UK reached $14,800 per tonne, rebounding after hitting a four-year low of $14,455 on November 20th as markets reassess oversupply. The Indonesian government announced new rules granting nickel refining permits only to refiners producing specific products.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Government implements new measures to protect Canada's steel industry</title><link>https://www.canada.ca/en/department-finance/news/2025/12/government-implements-new-measures-to-protect-canadas-steel-industry.html</link><description>Canada is reducing tariff rate quotas for imported steel products effective December 26, 2025, to 20% of 2024 levels for non-FTA partners and 75% for non-CUSMA FTA partners. A 25% global tariff will apply to steel-derivative products, alongside extensions of tariff remissions on U.S. imports. These measures aim to protect Canadian steel from global pressures amid U.S. tariff negotiations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Government implements new measures to protect Canada's steel industry</title><link>https://www.canada.ca/en/department-finance/news/2025/12/government-implements-new-measures-to-protect-canadas-steel-industry.html</link><description>Canada's government is extending tariff remissions on imported steel to January 31, 2026, to support domestic supply chains amid U.S. tariffs. Measures aim to enhance resilience for sectors like manufacturing and agriculture while protecting jobs. This provides predictability as businesses shift from imported to Canadian steel sources.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Weekly Ratings, Targets, Forecast Changes - 12-12-25</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/12/15/weekly-ratings-targets-forecast-changes-12-12-25/</link><description>A broker trimmed its nickel price forecast by 4% for 2026 while lifting forecasts for copper and coking coal. The revision reflects expectations of supply disruptions supporting firmer commodity prices overall. Nickel outlook remains cautious amid sector adjustments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Strengthening the future: Steel for growth and resilience</title><link>https://www.mckinsey.com/capabilities/sustainability/our-insights</link><description>The global steel industry is at an inflection point with shifting patterns requiring innovation for growth and resilience amid sustainability pressures. Success involves capturing growth, improving productivity, and delivering sustainable solutions. This aligns with broader decarbonization efforts in materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Beijing Moves to Rein in Steel Exports With New Licensing Rule</title><link>https://www.caixinglobal.com/2025-12-13/beijing-moves-to-rein-in-steel-exports-with-new-licensing-rule-102392857.html</link><description>China's Ministry of Commerce and General Administration of Customs announced export licensing requirements for most steel products starting January 1, 2026, to curb surging low-priced shipments and illicit trade. Steel exports reached 110 million tons in 2024, forecasted at 110-130 million tons in 2025, with first-10-months 2025 exports at 97.7 million tons and prices down 8.7% to $695.4/ton. The measure covers crude iron, billets, coils, plates, pipes, and scrap, amid rising global trade remedy investigations against Chinese steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper eases after nearing $12,000, set for 3rd straight weekly jump</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-eases-after-nearing-12000-set-for-3rd-straight-weekly-jump/</link><description>Copper prices eased after earlier touching near $12,000 per tonne but remained on track for a third consecutive weekly gain, pressured by demand uncertainty out of top consumer China even as Chinese policymakers signalled measured economic support for 2026. The piece highlights the tension between strong recent rallies and short‑term profit‑taking or demand concerns that have driven intraday swings[7].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tight supply and AI demand drive copper prices higher</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-rally-forces-2025-supply-demand-imbalance/</link><description>The article attributes recent copper strength to tightening physical supply and rising demand tied to AI and energy‑transition trends, reporting prices around $11,952 per metric tonne as of December 12, 2025. It frames the rally as supported by structural demand growth (EVs, renewables, AI infrastructure) alongside inventory movements that have tightened availability[3].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME metal inventories update — Copper inventories reported (December 13)</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103087911/LME-Metal-Inventories-Updates-on-December-13</link><description>Metal.com’s inventory update shows LME copper stock movements on December 13, 2025, signaling ongoing shifts in exchange inventories that market participants watch for clues on near‑term physical tightness. The update provides transaction price ranges and inventory figures that help explain short‑term price volatility and regional flows affecting LME balances[8].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Metal Mania: Reuters on Copper, Tin, Zinc, Lithium, Cobalt and More</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/metal-mania-reuters-on-copper-tin-zinc-lithium-cobalt-and-more</link><description>Recycling and technological innovation are key to addressing growing metal demand, particularly for copper. In China, increased scrap copper from aging infrastructure could offset shortages through 'urban mining.' This reduces reliance on primary mining and supports supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[December 13 Morning Meeting Summary] Refined Nickel: Spot Premiums Update, Nickel Futures Rise</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103085889/%5BDec-13-Morning-Meeting%5D-Nickel-Spot-Premiums-Update-Nickel-Futures-Rise</link><description>Domestic refined nickel closed at 117,080 yuan/mt on Friday, up 1.99% week-over-week. LME nickel prices rebounded significantly to $14,850/mt on Friday. Spot premiums and futures showed upward movement in the morning meeting.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Had Slightly Increased This Week</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-21909.html</link><description>Shanghai nickel warehouse receipts inventory stood at 30,564 tons as of December 13th, up 985 tons week-over-week. Nickel prices showed a slight increase amid inventory buildup. Market trends indicate modest upward pressure despite ongoing supply dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 13 Dec 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/12/13/the-market-in-numbers-13-dec-2025/</link><description>Nickel price per pound recorded at 6.6005, down 0.90% as of December 13, 2025. This reflects broader metals market movements, with nickel under slight downward pressure. Part of daily metals and minerals pricing update.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries (ASX: NIC) Soars with Quota Approval: Is It a Buy?</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/nickel-industries-surges-on-quota-approval/</link><description>Indonesian authorities approved an increase to Nickel Industries' 2025 nickel ore sales quota from 9 million to 10.5 million wet metric tonnes. This allows resumption of deliveries from the Hengjaya Mine to the Indonesia Morowali Industrial Park, supported by a five-year AMDAL permit and in-pit tailings system. The approval addresses ongoing oversupply pressures amid rapid capacity expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. Announces Closing of Oversubscribed $1.96m Flow-Through Financing</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/6264300</link><description>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. closed an oversubscribed $1.96 million flow-through financing. This follows a news release on December 4, 2025, providing funds likely for critical minerals exploration including nickel-related activities. The financing supports the company's development in the critical minerals sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. Announces Closing of Oversubscribed $1.96m Flow-Through Financing</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/12/13/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/north-american-niobium-and-critical-minerals-corp-announces-closing-of-oversubscribed-196m-flow-through-financing/2242758</link><description>North American Niobium and Critical Minerals Corp. announced the closing of its oversubscribed $1.96 million flow-through financing. The update references a prior release from December 4, 2025. Funds will advance critical minerals projects, potentially including nickel production capacities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion titled “Nuclear: the future of the Italian boilermaking industry” at Fondazione Dalmine in Italy, partnering with UCC. Experts from industry and institutions discussed nuclear energy's role in Europe’s energy transition and Italy’s manufacturing potential, including small modular reactors. Tenaris’s Italian mill recently obtained accreditation for nuclear materials under ASME III standards.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (December 8, 2025 - December 12, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-december-8-2025-a-december-12-2025-on-the-ce7d50d8dd8df324</link><description>Tenaris published its weekly share buyback report for December 8-12, 2025, detailing purchases like 497,790 shares on MTA at a weighted average price. As of December 12, the company holds 51,262,421 treasury shares, equal to 4.78% of issued capital, with plans to cancel them. The report is available on Tenaris's IR website.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Electricity Scarcity Meets Aluminum Tariffs, and American Citizens Pick Up the Bill</title><link>https://cleantechnica.com/2025/12/13/electricity-scarcity-meets-aluminum-tariffs-and-american-citizens-pick-up-the-bill/</link><description>US Midwest aluminum premium surged to $1,300-$1,900 per ton after 2025 tariff escalations, 2.5-4 times higher than the prior $450-$550 range, driven by policy amid electricity constraints and import dependence. This diverges sharply from global LME prices, raising costs for US buyers and complicating new smelter investments due to higher WACC from policy volatility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 14.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel exchanges, including Shanghai Futures rebar prices as of December 12, 2025, showing no change at 0.00%. The platform covers indices, prices, and news for various futures terms across regions like China, Turkey, Europe, and North America. Latest sections include rebar news, scrap news, and iron and steel markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Semiconductors, Displays 'Clear'; Petrochemicals, Steel 'Cloudy'</title><link>https://www.chosun.com/english/industry-en/2025/12/14/FB35MN3WGJH4LLSAMPAWYIDMLU/</link><description>South Korea's steel industry faces 'cloudy' prospects in 2026 due to Chinese oversupply and U.S./EU import restrictions, with exports expected to drop 2.1%. The Korea Iron and Steel Association notes declining shipments to traditional markets despite gains in emerging ones like Latin America. This contrasts with 'clear' outlooks for semiconductors and displays.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper gives up record highs near $12,000 at the London Exchange</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/copper-news/copper-gives-up-record-highs-near-$12,000-at-the-london-exchange-47936</link><description>Three-month copper futures on the LME fell 0.35% to $11,829 per ton after touching an all-time high of $11,952, amid concerns that elevated prices could weigh on demand. The metal remains on track for weekly gains for the third consecutive week. In contrast, Shanghai Futures Exchange copper closed up 1.95% at 94.08 thousand yuan per ton.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>How tight supply, AI demand propelled copper price towards $12,000</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/how-tight-supply-ai-demand-propelled-copper-price-towards-12000/</link><description>Copper prices are up 35% this year, nearing $12,000 per metric ton, due to mining disruptions, US stockpiling, and soaring demand from AI data centers. Valued for its electrical conductivity, copper is vital for power grids, EVs, and energy transition infrastructure. Bullish sentiment is driven by tight supply narratives and macro news flows.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper eases after nearing USD12,000</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40397323</link><description>Copper prices eased after approaching $12,000 per ton, with ANZ expecting prices to remain above $11,000 in 2026 and potentially near $12,000 by year-end amid supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chile's weekend runoff puts Codelco future at stake</title><link>https://www.mining.com/chiles-weekend-runoff-puts-copper-future-at-stake/</link><description>Chile's presidential runoff on December 14 will impact the future of state copper giant Codelco, which faces over $20 billion in debt, aging infrastructure, and production declines to a 25-year low in 2022. Legal obligations to remit profits to the government limit reinvestment, threatening Chile's mining-driven economy projected to grow 2.5% in 2025. The election outcome could balance resource nationalism with economic pragmatism for the world's top copper producer.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM: Secondary Aluminum Alloy Ingot Social Inventory Dips to 48,862 mt on Dec 15</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103670223/SMM:-Secondary-Aluminum-Alloy-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-to-48862-mt-on-Dec-15</link><description>SMM statistics show the combined daily social inventory of secondary aluminum alloy ingots dipped to 48,862 mt on December 15. SMM expects aluminum prices to pull back slightly from high levels in the short term.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Aluminium Advances India's Low-Carbon Manufacturing Push with 1.57 Billion Units of Renewable Energy in FY25</title><link>https://solarquarter.com/2025/12/15/vedanta-aluminium-advances-indias-low-carbon-manufacturing-push-with-1-57-billion-units-of-renewable-energy-in-fy25/</link><description>Vedanta Aluminium consumed 1.57 billion units of renewable energy in FY25, reducing GHG emissions intensity by 8.96% since FY21 as part of its 2030 decarbonization roadmap. The company implemented energy-saving technologies like patented potlining, achieving 378 million units in savings, and plans to source 1,500 MW of renewable power. Partnerships and 'Communities of Practice' support goals for 30% low-carbon aluminum products.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US OCTG imports down 10.0 percent in August 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-octg-imports-down-100-percent-in-august-2025-1424489.htm</link><description>US imports of Oil Country Tubular Goods (OCTG) decreased by 10.0 percent in August 2025. This decline reflects ongoing trends in the steel import market, potentially influencing domestic pricing and supply dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Declines After China Moves to License Steel Exports</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-15/iron-ore-declines-after-china-moves-to-license-steel-exports</link><description>Iron ore futures declined as much as 1.6% after China announced a licensing system for exporting certain steel products starting January 1, 2026. The Ministry of Commerce requires exporters to seek permission for a broad range of steel used in construction, cars, and consumer goods. This comes as China's steel exports are on track for a 2025 record.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China November crude steel output hits a 23-month low</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/china-november-crude-steel-output-hits-a-23-month-low-ce7d50d8d188f126</link><description>China's crude steel output in November fell 3% from October, marking six straight months of declines due to thinner margins. This represents the lowest output in 23 months. The reduction impacts global steel supply dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Claws Back Gains With Base Metals After Friday's 3% Tumble</title><link>https://www.fxleaders.com/news/2025/12/15/copper-claws-back-gains-with-base-metals-after-fridays-3-tumble/</link><description>Copper prices rebounded by up to 1.5% on the London Metal Exchange after dropping 3% on Friday due to a selloff in AI-related shares. The recovery reflects a shift in focus to a tighter market outlook for 2026 amid mine disruptions, green energy demand, and potential US tariffs. As of 12:42 p.m. in Shanghai, copper was priced at $11,656.50 a ton after hitting a record near $12,000.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises on 2026 Supply Concerns Amid Tariff Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-rises-2026-supply-concerns-tariff-uncertainty-2512/</link><description>Copper prices climbed as much as 1.5% on the London Metal Exchange on Monday, recovering from Friday's 3% losses as investors refocused on long-term supply tightness. Demand from AI infrastructure and renewable energy, along with potential US tariffs and mine constraints, supports expectations for higher prices in 2026. Goldman Sachs forecasts prices between $10,000–$11,000 per ton next year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Plummets Amid Risk-Off Market Sentiment</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/15/copper-plummets-amid-risk-off-market-sentiment/</link><description>Copper prices fell more than 3% on Friday amid a risk-off sentiment triggered by profit-taking in AI stocks, reversing earlier weekly gains. ANZ analysts maintain a bullish outlook due to robust fundamentals, including supply disruptions, strong demand from EVs, energy infrastructure in China, and AI investments in the US. The pullback is seen as temporary, not derailing the upward trajectory.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>How tight supply, AI demand propelled copper towards $12,000</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/how-tight-supply-ai-demand-propelled-copper-towards-12000/</link><description>Copper prices approached $12,000 per metric ton driven by tight supply conditions and surging demand from AI applications. The rally highlights structural market imbalances favoring higher prices. Ongoing supply constraints and technology-driven consumption are key propellants.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Fortescue Bolsters Copper Pipeline with Alta Copper Buy</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/15/fortescue-bolsters-copper-pipeline-with-alta-copper-buy/</link><description>Fortescue Metals Group acquired the remaining 64% stake in Alta Copper for $C139 million to strengthen its long-term copper pipeline. Analysts at RBC Capital Markets view it as a low-risk, low-cost addition with minimal near-term impact on cash flow or earnings. The move diversifies Fortescue's portfolio toward copper for the energy transition while maintaining iron ore focus.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On December 15, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103671012/</link><description>On December 15, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 114,500–120,200 yuan/mt, averaging 117,350 yuan/mt, down 850 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects ongoing weakness in the Chinese nickel market. The update is part of non-ferrous metals pricing coverage.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Investing In Innovation: GBCCA Showcases New Technology To Close The Recycling Loop For Aluminium Cans</title><link>https://international-aluminium.org/investing-in-innovation-gbcca-showcases-new-technology-to-close-the-recycling-loop-for-aluminium-cans/</link><description>The Global Beverage Can Circularity Alliance (GBCCA) showcased robotics, AI, deposit return systems and home recycling equipment at Climate Week NYC as technologies to boost aluminium beverage-can recycling and help reach targets of ~100% recycling by 2050 (80% by 2030). The piece highlights how advanced sorting and household-level solutions can unlock lost material streams and accelerate circularity for aluminium cans.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Giants Hit Major Milestone with Low-Carbon Production</title><link>https://www.theenergymix.com/aluminium-giants-hit-major-milestone-with-low-carbon-production/</link><description>Elysis (Alcoa–Rio Tinto JV) reported scaling its carbon‑free "inert anode" technology to a 450‑kA cell, a step toward commercial low‑carbon aluminium production that could eliminate CO2 emissions from anodes if sustained at scale. The article discusses technical changes (including a vertical cell design), potential climate benefits, and questions about full‑scale cost and sustained operation.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>GMG Unveils Graphene Aluminium‑Ion Battery That Fully Charges In 6 Minutes</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/15/gmg-unveils-graphene-aluminium-ion-battery-that-fully-charges-in-6-minutes/</link><description>GMG announced a graphene aluminium‑ion battery using aluminium foil substrates and a chloride‑free hybrid electrolyte that reportedly enables very fast charging (full charge in ~6 minutes) and avoids lithium and copper, targeting automotive, grid and specialty applications as it advances toward scale‑up and patents. The story emphasizes potential cost/weight benefits and ongoing work to validate reliability, safety and manufacturability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Korea to overhaul steel industry, pledges $139 million in specialty steel R&amp;D subsidies</title><link>https://www.kedglobal.com/steel/newsView/ked202512150005</link><description>South Korea unveiled plans to overhaul its steel industry, including government-backed production cuts and increased output of high-value specialty steel. The government pledged $139 million in R&amp;D subsidies during a roundtable with steel executives. This addresses weakening exports due to global construction slump and Chinese supply pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US Copper Stakes Additional Claims to Accommodate Future Surface Facilities at the Moonlight-Superior Copper Project</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/278046/US-Copper-Stakes-Additional-Claims-to-Accommodate-Future-Surface-Facilities-at-the-MoonlightSuperior-Copper-Project</link><description>US Copper filed new claims to secure land for future surface facilities at its Moonlight-Superior project as it prepares for a prefeasibility study and permitting; the company projects average annual production of about 60 million pounds of copper if developed and highlights ongoing metallurgical studies leading into a 2026 PFS timetable.[4] The release positions the project as a potential domestic supplier to the U.S. market and outlines recent technical and economic work referenced in earlier studies.[4]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chile copper mining costs highest in Americas, threatening new investment, report says</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/chile-copper-mining-costs-highest-in-americas-threatening-new-investment-report-says/</link><description>A Cochilco report found Chile has the highest copper mining costs in the Americas for medium-capacity processing plants and the second-highest for large-scale operations, which could threaten new investment despite Chile’s large resource base and plans to expand capacity at major mines.[6] The story warns that elevated capital intensity and operating costs may limit the country’s ability to attract greenfield projects even as demand outlook supports expansion.[6]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Drop Amid Oversupply</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures fell to 14,295 USD/T on December 15, 2025, down 2.22% from the previous day due to persistent oversupply. Global inventories remain elevated, with LME stockpiles exceeding levels that continue to pressure market sentiment. Over the past month, prices have fallen 2.59%, and are down 8.77% year-over-year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel presents metals market review - 15 December 2025</title><link>https://nornickel.com/news-and-media/press-releases-and-news/nornickel-presents-metals-market-review-15-12-2025/</link><description>Nornickel forecasts the global nickel market to stay in surplus over 200 kt Ni in both 2025 and 2026. The base-case scenario highlights continued oversupply amid strong production growth. This review aligns with broader market data on elevated inventories.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel sharply hikes nickel surplus forecasts for this year and next</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-sharply-hikes-nickel-surplus-forecasts-for-this-year-and-next/</link><description>Russian mining giant Nornickel doubled its nickel surplus forecast for 2025 to 240,000 tons from 120,000 tons previously and more than doubled the 2026 forecast to 275,000 tons. The global nickel market has been in surplus for four years due to rapid supply growth, particularly from Indonesia. Nornickel attributes the surplus to continued production expansion outpacing demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel expects global nickel market surplus in 2025-2026</title><link>https://tass.com/economy/2058767</link><description>Nornickel forecasts a global nickel market surplus exceeding 200,000 tons in both 2025 and 2026, driven by production growth to 3.86 million tons in 2025 and 4.1 million tons in 2026, outpacing demand growth to 3.62 million and 3.83 million tons respectively. Over 66% of output will come from Indonesia, despite recent government measures to curb excess supply. The company notes that only Indonesia's production restraint can balance the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>High aluminium prices to lift Press Metal earnings</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/16/high-aluminium-prices-to-lift-press-metal-earnings</link><description>High aluminum prices are set to drive record profits for Press Metal amid foreign expansions and resilient market conditions. London Metal Exchange prices have strengthened to US$2,800 per tonne, the highest since 2022, supported by supply tightness, while low alumina costs provide a margin tailwind. HLIB Research raised earnings forecasts, maintained a 'buy' rating, and expects continued aluminum deficits into 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 16.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar prices listed as flat at 0.00 change on December 15, 2025. Various futures contracts for rebar and other steel products across regions like Turkey, China, Europe, and North America are tracked. The platform offers analyses and comments on industry trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673677/SMM:-High-Grade-NPI-Price-Falls-in-Dec-16-Sentiment-Dips</link><description>The SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI fell to 886.5 yuan/nickel unit (ex-factory, tax included) on December 16. Sentiment in the nickel pig iron market dipped amid price declines. This reflects ongoing trends in ferrous metals pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China, S Korea companies investigated for dumping</title><link>https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/biz/archives/2025/12/16/2003848943</link><description>Taiwan's Ministry of Finance launched anti-dumping investigations into cold-rolled, flat-rolled non-oriented electrical steel products from China and South Korea. The probe, prompted by China Steel Corp, targets companies like POSCO, Baoshan Iron &amp; Steel, and others amid rising imports harming local industry since 2023. This follows existing duties on stainless steel from the same countries.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper fell to 5.28 USD/Lbs on December 16, 2025, down 0.93% from the previous day, amid weak Chinese economic data including slowing industrial output and declining home prices. Despite this, prices rose to 5.34 USD/Lbs on December 15, up 1.14%, with monthly gains of 7.35%. Futures hovered around $5.3 per pound, pressured by soft demand in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Supply Shortages Coupled with the Federal Reserve's Interest Rate Cuts Pushed Copper Prices to a 15-Year High</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28829.html</link><description>Copper prices rose sharply last week to 93,903.33 RMB/ton as of December 12, a 15-year high, driven by global supply shortages from mine disruptions and a 'pull effect' into the US market. The Federal Reserve's interest rate cuts amplified bullish sentiment. Forecasts predict LME copper above $11,000 per ton in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/16/copper-prices-rise-on-supply-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices increased due to potential supply constraints in 2026, with strong demand from Chinese EV and energy sectors offsetting weak economic data like slower retail sales and industrial output. US demand remains robust from AI investments and reduced trade tensions. Other base metals like nickel and zinc declined.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Korea Zinc to Build Integrated Smelter; LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103672447/Korea-Zinc-to-Build-Integrated-Smelter-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Korea Zinc plans to build an integrated smelter, while LME copper prices showed intraday volatility and closed higher on the reported session; the report also notes changes in Chinese spot premiums, secondary copper market activity, and inventory movements that could constrain upside for prices in the near term.[1] The article discusses supply-side selling driven by year-end funding and weaker demand from high prices, and reports recent LME and SHFE inventory figures that affect market balance.[1]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/16/copper-prices-rise-on-supply-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices increased as markets focused on potential supply constraints for the coming year, with ANZ citing persistent disruptions and strong demand—particularly from Chinese imports tied to EVs and energy infrastructure—as supporting prices despite softer macro data from China.[3] The piece also notes weakness in other base metals and contextualizes copper strength with demand from the US (including AI-related investments).[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>World's largest copper mine drives Chile investment</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/16/worlds-largest-copper-mine-drives-chile-investment/</link><description>Coverage highlights Chile’s upgraded mining-investment outlook—driven largely by an expansion at BHP’s Escondida—boosting Cochilco’s estimate of mining investment through 2034 and underpinning expectations for future copper production capacity as Chile aims to capitalise on rising global demand.[5] The article links the Escondida expansion to broader investment in copper and lithium projects and cites forecasts of strong long-term copper demand growth.[5]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 16, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673145/</link><description>On December 16, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 111,700–117,800 yuan/mt, averaging 114,750 yuan/mt. This represents a decline of 2,650 yuan/mt from the previous day. The drop reflects ongoing market pressures in the refined nickel segment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI was 886.5 yuan/nickel unit</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673677/SMM:-High-Grade-NPI-Price-Falls-in-Dec-16-Sentiment-Dips</link><description>On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI fell to 886.5 yuan/nickel unit (ex-factory, tax included). This decline indicates dipping sentiment in the high-grade nickel pig iron market. Prices reflect broader base metals trends amid supply abundance.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel sees continued nickel surplus and tightening copper supply</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nornickel-sees-continued-nickel-surplus-and-tightening-copper-supply</link><description>Global metals producer Nornickel anticipates ongoing nickel market surplus amid rapid supply expansion. The article highlights Nornickel's outlook on nickel dynamics alongside tightening copper supply. It references Indonesia's significant role in nickel production.</description><category>copper</category></item></channel></rss>