<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:21:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Raw Material Prices Rise Sharply at the Start of the Year</title><link>https://steelnews.biz/raw-material-prices-rise-sharply-start-of-the-year/</link><description>2026 began with sharp price gains in industrial metals like copper, aluminium, and nickel, impacting steel production. Aluminium exceeded USD 3,000/tonne on LME amid tight capacity and demand; nickel rose 7.9-8.7% due to Indonesian production limits. Stainless steel futures on SHFE increased nearly 2%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Hyundai Steel builds DRI pilot facility to support US steel mill expansion</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/hyundai-steel-builds-dri-pilot-facility-to-support-us-steel-mill-expansion/158644</link><description>Hyundai Steel has constructed a DRI pilot facility to bolster the expansion of its US steel mill. This initiative aims to enhance production capabilities in the US market. Details on the facility's capacity or timeline were not specified in the report.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper prices near all-time high: Structural shift or speculative spike? Here’s where the red metal is headed</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/copper-prices-near-all-time-high-structural-shift-or-speculative-spike-heres-where-the-red-metal-is-headed/articleshow/126369601.cms</link><description>Copper prices are approaching all-time highs, prompting debate on whether this reflects a structural market shift or a speculative spike. The article analyzes future trends for the red metal amid ongoing market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices hit yet another record on supply and tariff fears</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-prices-hit-yet-another-record-on-supply-and-tariff-fears/</link><description>Copper prices surged to a record $13,225 a tonne on the London Metal Exchange, up 1.8% amid supply disruptions like strikes in Chile and delays in Ecuador, plus US tariff concerns diverting supply. The metal has gained 6.6% in 2026 so far after a 42% rise last year, driven by AI, energy transition demand, though some question if speculation is outpacing fundamentals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper surges past $13,000/t as bull run gains pace</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2772384-copper-surges-past-13-000-t-as-bull-run-gains-pace</link><description>The three-month copper price closed at $13,230/t, up 3.04% on the day and 5.8% since early January, fueled by investor safe-haven demand amid geopolitical tensions and potential US tariffs. Forecasts from Goldman Sachs, Bank of America, and others predict averages around $5.13-$5.25/lb in 2026 due to mine output shortfalls, though a slowing economy could temper gains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Record Copper Price Hits $13,000 on Supply Shortages</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/record-copper-price-2026-market-transformation/</link><description>Copper prices have surged above $13,000 per tonne due to supply shortages, rising AI demand, and mining disruptions. This marks a significant market transformation in early 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices near all-time high: Structural shift or speculative spike? Here's where the red metal is headed</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/copper-prices-near-all-time-high-structural-shift-or-speculative-spike-heres-where-the-red-metal-is-headed/articleshow/126369601.cms</link><description>Copper prices extended their rally, with MCX January 2026 futures rising over 1.3% to Rs 1330.45 per kg, nearing lifetime highs. The article discusses whether this reflects a structural shift or speculative activity in the copper market. It examines future directions for the red metal amid ongoing price surges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Record Copper Price Hits $13,000 on Supply Shortages</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/record-copper-price-2026-market-transformation/</link><description>Copper prices reached a record $13,000 due to supply shortages, with Citi projecting a 308,000-tonne deficit based on 26.9 million tonnes of refined copper production for 2026. Alternative analyses suggest ongoing market transformation from tight supplies. The surge signals broader challenges in meeting demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper surges to fresh record as inventories 'locked in the US'</title><link>https://theedgemalaysia.com/node/788196</link><description>Copper extended its rally past US$13,000/t as investors anticipate tighter supply, with inventories locked in US warehouses. The price surge reflects bets on constrained availability amid strong demand. No specific production capacity details are mentioned.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>How 2026 will reshape US critical minerals resilience</title><link>https://www.mining.com/how-2026-will-reshape-the-us-critical-mineral-resilience/</link><description>The article discusses how 2026 will drive innovation in metals processing for critical minerals like copper, focusing on sustainable technologies that reduce emissions and electricity costs amid competition from AI data centers. It highlights federal priorities for modernizing outdated processing methods for aluminum, copper, and others to strengthen domestic manufacturing. Innovations aim to create competitive cost structures and attract federal funding for efficient, sustainable practices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>RESEARCH: BMI lowers 2026 nickel price view to $15,500/tn from $16,000/tn</title><link>https://informistmedia.com/CommodityWire/42065/RESEARCH-BMI-lowers-2026-nickel-price-view-to-15-500-tn-from-16-000-tn</link><description>Fitch Solutions company BMI has lowered its 2026 nickel price forecast to $15,500 per tonne from $16,000 per tonne due to a persistent global supply glut. The market surplus is expected to widen to 250 kilotonnes in 2026 from 244 kilotonnes in 2025, driven by Indonesia's continued capacity additions despite policy risks. Demand is projected to grow 4.9% in 2026, supported by China's stainless steel and net-zero sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Surges to 1-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/514448</link><description>Nickel futures surged to $16,900 per tonne in January, up nearly 20% in three weeks, reaching a one-year high amid global supply reductions. Indonesia proposed a 34% cut in nickel output for 2026 to address oversupply and declining ore grades. Despite efforts, surpluses persist with LME stockpiles rising to 255,000 tonnes last year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nusa Nickel targets production, trading expansion in 2026</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nusa-nickel-targets-production-trading-expansion-in-2026</link><description>Nusa Nickel Corp plans to scale up its nickel production and trading activities in 2026. The company aims for expansion amid ongoing industry developments in Indonesia.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Flint Begins Scaled Production of Paper-Based Batteries</title><link>https://www.environmentenergyleader.com/stories/flint-begins-scaled-production-of-paper-based-batteries,110732</link><description>Flint has started scaled production of its safer, PFAS-free, non-flammable paper-based batteries using a cellulose architecture that avoids critical minerals like nickel. The new facility in Singapore employs a water-based manufacturing method that reduces carbon emissions and supports sustainability. This milestone enables pilots and demos at CES 2026, addressing safety and supply chain issues in traditional lithium-ion batteries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Off-Season, coupled with high aluminium prices, the proportion of liquid aluminium declined in December</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/off-season-coupled-with-high-aluminium-prices-the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminium-declined-in-december-116778</link><description>High aluminum prices combined with the off-season led to a decline in the proportion of liquid aluminum in December. This reflects broader market trends affecting aluminum usage and supply dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,096 Yuan/MT on January 2, 2026, down 0.32% daily amid soft Chinese demand, with rebar futures maintaining pullbacks from recent highs. Forecasts predict trading at 3014.96 Yuan/MT by quarter-end and 2868.13 in 12 months. Recent news highlights steel rises on improving profitability and pressures from regulatory export concerns.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 931.97 USD/T on January 2, 2026, down 0.32% daily, though up 2.87% monthly and 31.63% yearly. Forecasts expect 949.49 USD/T by quarter-end and 1042.73 in 12 months. Recent updates note rises to 940 USD/T on December 31 amid improving trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM: Copper Wire &amp; Cable Industry's Jan Operating Rate to Edge Up MoM, Still Below Normal</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701113/SMM:-Copper-Wire-Cable-Industrys-Jan-Operating-Rate-to-Edge-Up-MoM-Still-Below-Normal</link><description>SMM reports that China's copper wire and cable industry's operating rate for January 2026 is expected to edge up month-over-month but remain below normal levels. Domestic prices are suspended during the New Year holiday, with overseas prices resuming on January 2. This reflects ongoing market adjustments amid high prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM: Copper Wire &amp; Cable Operating Rate Drops Further Amid High Prices, Holidays</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103700497/SMM:-Copper-Wire-Cable-Operating-Rate-Drops-Further-Amid-High-Prices-Holidays</link><description>SMM indicates that the operating rate in China's copper wire and cable sector has dropped further due to high copper prices and holiday effects. This trend highlights supply chain pressures in the industry. Contact details provided for further research reports.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Austral Resources Defies Weather, Exceeds Copper Output Targets</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/02/austral-resources-defies-weather-exceeds-copper-output-targets/</link><description>Austral Resources (ASX:AR1) exceeded its Q4 copper production targets with 2,643 tonnes despite extreme weather in Northwest Queensland. December production hit a record 910 tonnes since the 2023 restructure, with no environmental issues and stable processing operations. Access to the Rocklands site is restricted due to flooding, but recovery is expected soon.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Austral Resources Beats Q4 Copper Output Guidance Despite Record Weather</title><link>https://smallcaps.com.au/article/austral-resources-beats-q4-copper-output-guidance-despite-record-weather</link><description>Austral Resources surpassed Q4 copper production guidance of 2,610 tonnes, achieving 2,643 tonnes amid severe wet season weather. December output exceeded 910 tonnes, the highest post-2023 restructure, with Lady Annie and Mt Kelly sites maintaining full capacity. The company advances exploration with a 2026 drill program targeting oxide resources near processing facilities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries partners with Sphere Corp in landmark ENC deal</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/02/nickel-industries-partners-with-sphere-corp-in-landmark-enc-deal/</link><description>Nickel Industries announced a strategic partnership with Sphere Corp, valuing its ENC HPAL project at US$2.4 billion, with Sphere acquiring a 10% stake and entering an offtake agreement for nickel cathode. The ENC project targets annual production of 72,000 tonnes of nickel metal upon commissioning, expected in early Q1 2026. This deal marks the first offtake for ENC material into Western markets, targeting aerospace and EV sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Rockets 8% as SpaceX Supplier Buys Into US$2.4B ENC HPAL Project</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/nickel-industries/</link><description>Nickel Industries' shares rose 8% following Sphere Corp's investment in the US$2.4 billion ENC HPAL project. Sphere, a SpaceX supplier, is acquiring a stake, supporting the project's development for nickel production. The deal highlights growing interest in Nickel Industries' capacity expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/513911</link><description>Aluminum increased to 2999.00 USD/T, the highest since April 2022. Over the past 4 weeks, Aluminum gained 3.64%, and in the last 12 months, it increased 18.54%. The price rise reflects tightening supply conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel development minister sets agenda for growth in 2026</title><link>https://authorityngr.com/2026/01/02/steel-development-minister-sets-agenda-for-growth-in-2026/</link><description>Nigeria's Steel Development Minister outlines 2026 plans to revitalize Ajaokuta Steel Complex via MoUs with Chinese investors and original manufacturers, alongside $500 million in mini-LNG plants for power supply. Investments include a $400 million steel plant by Inner Galaxy Group in Ewekoro and Orbit Galvanised Steel Plant commissioning, boosting local production, jobs, and capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel fell to 16,760 USD/T on January 2, 2026, down 0.48% from the previous day, though it has risen 12.97% over the past month and 10.27% year-over-year. UK nickel futures surged to $15,600 per tonne, the highest since May, after hitting four-year lows, as markets reconsider oversupply views. Indonesia proposed a 34% reduction in nickel output for 2026 to address oversupply and deteriorating ore grades.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel reaches 14-month high following Vale Indonesia's halt to mining</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/01/02/nickel-reaches-14month-high-following-vale-indonesias-halt-to-mining</link><description>Nickel prices hit a 14-month high after Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to a delay in annual production plan approval. The LME three-month nickel rose 1.4% to $16,875 per metric ton. Indonesia's planned cut in ore production by a third by 2026 further supported prices amid previous oversupply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries says South Korea's Sphere to buy 10% stake in Indonesian project</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-industries-says-south-koreas-sphere-to-buy-10-stake-in-indonesian-project/</link><description>South Korea's Sphere Corp will acquire a 10% stake in Nickel Industries' Excelsior Nickel Cobalt HPAL project in Indonesia's Central Sulawesi, capable of producing MHP, nickel sulphate, and cathode. The deal values the project at $2.4 billion and includes offtake agreements, amid soaring nickel prices from Indonesia's output cut plans. Funding is expected early Q1 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>South Korea's Sphere to invest in Indonesian Ni project</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2771207-south-korea-s-sphere-to-invest-in-indonesian-ni-project</link><description>South Korea's Sphere will invest in a 10% stake of Nickel Industries' Excelsior nickel project in Indonesia, with production starting April-June 2026 and offtake of 10% nickel cathode. Indonesian MHP capacity is expanding significantly, with prices recently assessed at $132.50/mtu. The investment aligns with rising nickel prices from planned output cuts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel reaches 14-month high following Vale Indonesia's halt to mining</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/01/02/nickel-reaches-14month-high-following-vale-indonesias-halt-to-mining</link><description>Nickel prices surged to a 14-month high of $16,945 per metric ton after Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to a delay in production plan approval. This follows Indonesia's announcement to cut ore production by a third by 2026 to support prices amid oversupply. The event highlights sustainability efforts through regulated supply in nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to 3,023.10 USD/T on January 2, 2026, up 0.91% daily amid concerns of insufficient supply. China, the top producer, prioritizes preventing overcapacity after breaching its 45 million ton cap, forcing smelters to limit 2026 output. UK futures exceeded $3,000 for the first time since 2022 due to supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 36-week High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel increased to 941.00 USD/T, marking the highest level since April 2025. Over the past 4 weeks, Hot-Rolled Coil Steel gained 2.87%, and in the last 12 months, it rose 31.63%. This reflects upward momentum in steel prices amid recent market trends.[1]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Winter weather a factor as scrap market debates January pricing</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/02/winter-weather-a-factor-as-scrap-market-debates-january-pricing/</link><description>US steelmakers are optimistic for 2026 with Section 232 tariffs supporting price hikes for long and flat products, but scrap price increases may be limited to $20-40/gt in January due to weather-reduced flows and historical trends. Mills like Oregon Steel Mills raised plate prices by $40/ton. Disagreement persists on scrap pricing amid barge issues and shifts in sourcing.[3]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines begins copper anode production at new Congo smelter</title><link>https://www.mining.com/ivanhoe-mines-begins-copper-anode-production-at-new-congo-smelter/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines started copper anode production on December 29, 2025, at its Kamoa-Kakula direct-to-blister smelter in the DRC, five weeks after heat-up and one week after first concentrate feed. The smelter has a 500,000 tonnes per annum capacity, the largest in Africa upon full ramp-up by year-end. 2026 production guidance is 380,000-420,000 tonnes, with sales boosted by 20,000 tonnes from destocking amid high copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Greenland grants 30-year permit to EU-backed Molybdenum mine</title><link>https://www.mining.com/greenland-grants-30-year-permit-to-eu-backed-molybdenum-mine/</link><description>Greenland Resources has received a 30-year permit for its Malmbjerg molybdenum mine, supported by the European Raw Materials Alliance. The project has off-take agreements with Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali and Finland's Outokumpu. Greenland’s Minister highlighted it as a step toward economic autonomy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash climbs to $2,985.5/t as opening stocks ease 0.49% to 509,250t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-climbs-to-2-985-5-t-as-opening-stocks-ease-0-49-to-509-250t-116796</link><description>LME aluminum cash prices reached $2,985.5 per tonne as warehouse inventory declined to 509,250 tonnes. The 3-month contract strengthened to $3,010 per tonne, with December 2026 futures also showing gains of approximately 1.10 percent.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>L&amp;T wins Orders (Major*) for Minerals &amp; Metals Business</title><link>https://www.larsentoubro.com/pressreleases/2026-01-02-lt-wins-orders-major-for-minerals-metals-business</link><description>Larsen &amp; Toubro's Minerals &amp; Metals business secures major orders from Steel Authority of India (SAIL) for expanding IISCO Steel Plant capacity from 2.5 MTPA to 6.5 MTPA. The package includes engineering, procurement, and installation for Coke Oven Battery, By-Product Plant, Basic Oxygen Furnace, and material handling. This supports India's steel manufacturing through innovation, capacity augmentation, and sustainable development.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (December 29, 2025 – January 2, 2026) on the Share Buyback Program</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-december-29-2025-a-january-2-2026-on-the-s-ce7e59d9d089f225</link><description>Under its Second Tranche of the USD1.2 billion Share Buyback Program, Tenaris repurchased 3,320,025 ordinary shares from December 29, 2025, to January 2, 2026, for approximately USD64.2 million. As of January 2, 2026, the company holds 62,328,172 treasury shares, equating to 5.81% of total issued share capital, with plans to cancel them in due course. Details of the transactions are available on Tenaris's investor relations website.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel Rebar Set to Drop 7% in 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Chinese steel rebar futures were trading at CNY 3,085 per tonne, maintaining pullback from December highs and set to close the year around 7% lower amid soft demand for ferrous metals. Falling input costs including coal and coke are expected to support profitability among steelmakers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Details Late-December Share Buybacks Under $1.2 Billion Program</title><link>https://www.tipranks.com/news/company-announcements/tenaris-details-late-december-share-buybacks-under-1-2-billion-program</link><description>Tenaris repurchased 3.32 million shares between December 29, 2025 and January 2, 2026 for €54.6 million under its $1.2 billion buyback program. Treasury holdings reached 5.81% of total issued capital, with the company planning to cancel these shares in due course.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices top $3000 for the first time since 2022 as supply risks grow</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/news/aluminum-prices-top-3000-for-the-first-time-since-2022-as-supply-risks-grow/articleshow/126303415.cms</link><description>Global aluminium prices surged to $3,000 per tonne, the highest in over three years. The increase is driven by China's production cap and rising demand in key sectors. Supply risks continue to support the upward trend.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Year-End Aluminum Ingot Inventory Alert Sounded! Domestic Inventory Buildup in Q1 2026 a Foregone Conclusion</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701077/year-end-aluminum-ingot-inventory-alert-sounded-domestic-inventory-buildup-in-q1-2026-a-foregone-conclusion-smm-analysis</link><description>Domestic aluminum production increased 1.9% year-over-year and 4.0% month-over-month in December, driven by ongoing commissioning of new electrolytic aluminum projects in Inner Mongolia and Xinjiang. Casting volumes are expected to continue increasing before Chinese New Year, with domestic aluminum ingot inventory projected to reach around 730,000 tonnes by end-January 2026, creating inventory buildup pressure in Q1.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Macro policies remain positive, aluminium prices hit new highs during the week</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/macro-policies-remain-positive-aluminium-prices-hit-new-highs-during-the-week-fundamental-negative-feedback-suppresses-post-holiday-upside-momentum-116785</link><description>New aluminum projects in China and Indonesia continued ramping up production, with a new Inner Mongolia facility successfully powering on December 20. However, high prices suppressed downstream demand, with the operating rate of leading domestic aluminum processing enterprises falling to 59.9%, while inventory is forecast to rise to 730,000 tonnes by end-January 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits 3-year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/513911</link><description>Aluminum prices reached $2,999 per tonne, the highest level since April 2022, as China faces pressure to restrain output growth in 2026 due to approaching its 45 million ton annual production cap. The commodity gained 3.64% over the past four weeks and 18.54% over the past 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises Past $3,000</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/te_news:514029:0-aluminum-rises-past-3-000/</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK surpassed $3,000 per tonne for the first time since 2022 at the turn of the year, driven by growing concerns about insufficient global supply amid structural constraints in production capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Move over gold and silver: Copper, aluminium head for monster rally in 2026</title><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/commodities/move-over-gold-and-silver-copper-aluminium-head-for-monster-rally-in-2026-household-goods-to-get-costlier-13755091.html</link><description>Aluminum prices climbed past $3,000 per tonne for the first time in over three years, lifted by structural supply constraints including China's smelting capacity caps and reduced European output due to high power costs. Strong long-term demand from construction, renewable energy, and infrastructure projects continues to support prices, with futures rising 17% in 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Higher on Mine Suspension</title><link>https://www.admis.com/nickel-higher-on-mine-suspension/</link><description>Nickel rose 1.6% to $16,910, breaking 14-month highs following the suspension of Vale's Indonesia mine. Recent support comes from Indonesia's announcement to cut nickel ore output by a third in 2026 to support prices. This occurs amid broader base metal movements, with demand in China remaining resilient.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts mining activities on delayed approval for 2026 output plan</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/vale-indonesia-halts-mining-activities-on-delayed-approval-for-2026-output-plan/</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations due to delays in obtaining government approval for its 2026 production plan. Indonesia's nickel smelter association FINI forecasts domestic demand will reach 340-350 million metric tons in 2026, representing an annual increase of up to 50 million tons.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel notches 14-month high after Vale Indonesia halts mining</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40400503</link><description>Nickel reached its highest price in more than 14 months following Vale Indonesia's suspension of mining activities. The price increase reflects market response to Indonesia's announced production cuts designed to support commodity prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel's New Era: Rising Prices, Growing EV Demand, and Major Projects Moving Forward</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickels-new-era-rising-prices-growing-ev-demand-and-major-projects-moving-forward-8868</link><description>The nickel market is shifting due to Indonesia's supply management, driving prices from $14,200 to $16,500 per ton since mid-December 2025, with projections up to $18,500-$20,000. Policies include shorter mining licenses, mine closures, and bans on new processing plants, countering prior surpluses. North American projects and EV demand signal stronger conditions for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>COMMODITIES 2026: Mexican Aluminum Prices Poised to Rise After Atypical Year</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/122425-commodities-2026-mexican-aluminum-prices-poised-to-rise-after-atypical-year-sources-say</link><description>Mexican aluminum industry sources expect 2026 to bring price increases and a more dynamic market despite ongoing Trump tariffs. Prices climbed back to $330/mt by year-end 2025, with some sources predicting premiums could surpass $400/mt.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 04.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides daily updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar 3-month term and various 1-month futures for Turkey, China, Europe, and North America, all showing no change as of 02.01.2026. The platform offers analyses and comments on industry trends. This reflects stable futures pricing at the start of 2026.[6]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fertiliser, steel prices fall; cement remains stable</title><link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1964990/fertiliser-steel-prices-fall-cement-remains-stable</link><description>Steel bar prices in Pakistan have fallen to a range of Rs220,000 to Rs230,000 per tonne from Rs240,000 to Rs250,000 per tonne as of early January 2026, due to weak demand. The Secretary General of the Pakistan Association of Large Steel Producers noted leading brands at Rs226,000 per tonne, with some as low as Rs215,000. This decline aligns with broader price reductions in fertilizers while cement prices remain stable amid rising construction demand.[4]</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts mining amid delayed 2026 output approval</title><link>https://www.thejakartapost.com/business/2026/01/04/vale-indonesia-halts-mining-amid-delayed-2026-output-approval.html</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia suspended mining activities due to delays in government approval of its 2026 annual production plan (RKAB). The halt comes as Indonesia's government plans to cut nickel output quotas to support prices, with Deputy Mining Minister Yuliot Tanjung stating the approval is "currently being consolidated."</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris to invest in hydrogen steelmaking in Italy</title><link>https://eurometal.net/tenaris-to-invest-in-hydrogen-steelmaking-in-italy/</link><description>Tubemaker Tenaris has signed an agreement with Italian energy suppliers Edison and Snam for a project aimed at using hydrogen in steelmaking operations at the Tenaris Dalmine seamless tube plant in Italy. The project will study hydrogen supply and adapt the mill to use the gas in the steelmaking process, which could further lower CO2 emissions from the electric arc furnace-based steelmaker.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coatings. The business unit was rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy and will apply anti-corrosion coatings to line pipes at Tenaris facilities across Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Rise Slightly on January 5, South Korean President Lee Jae-myung Makes First Visit to China</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701928/</link><description>Nickel prices rose slightly on January 5 according to the SMM midday review. The update coincides with South Korean President Lee Jae-myung's first visit to China. This reflects ongoing market movements in nickel amid regional developments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum starts the year on a bullish note</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/aluminum-price-january-2026-china-europe-warehouse-inventory-reduced-recycling/</link><description>Aluminum prices have surpassed $3,000 per ton on U.S. and European exchanges, with the Comex exchange listing aluminum at $3,050.75 per metric ton. Supply-side factors driving the price increase include declining output in China due to government-imposed smelting capacity caps and production constraints in Europe from high electricity prices, while demand from construction and renewable sectors remains robust.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>PRICE INCREASE ANNOUNCEMENT - January 5, 2026</title><link>https://cemcosteel.com/news/price-increase-announcement-january-5-2026/</link><description>Domestic steel mills announced sharp price increases for all January 2026 orders across all markets. The hikes are driven by various market factors pressuring steel pricing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Korea steel industry faces triple hit from structural slump, tariffs, and ...</title><link>https://biz.chosun.com/en/en-industry/2026/01/05/3DZRG5TYKVB57LQZMJRZMGCGMA/</link><description>Korea's steel industry anticipates ongoing challenges in 2026 due to structural downturns, tariff burdens, and weak demand in real estate and construction. Cumulative crude steel production from January to November 2025 was 56.1 million tons, down 3.7% year-over-year, potentially reaching the lowest in 15 years. Experts highlight a mismatch between production capacity and demand in both domestic and export markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Shanghai copper kicks off 2026 strong on supply jitters</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/shanghai-copper-kicks-off-2026-strong-on-supply-jitters-ce7e59d9d08df321</link><description>Shanghai copper opened the year strongly due to intensified supply concerns from a strike at a Chilean mine. The most-active copper contract rose amid these jitters. This reflects broader market sensitivity to production disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Capstone Copper (ASX:CSC) Drops on Chile Strike</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/capstone-copper-drops-on-chile-strike/</link><description>Capstone Copper's shares fell 4% to A$14.51 following a strike by workers at its Mantoverde mine in Chile starting January 2, 2026. The strike impacts operations at this key copper facility. This event highlights vulnerabilities in copper supply chains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On January 5, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701837/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on January 5 stood at 133700-142600 yuan/mt, with an average price of 138150 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 600 yuan/mt from the previous day. The report highlights the latest spot pricing trends in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Sphere joins Nickel Industries ENC move in Indonesia</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/news/market-updates/sphere-joins-nickel-industries-enc-move-in-indonesia</link><description>Sphere has joined Nickel Industries' ENC move in Indonesia, signaling new developments in nickel operations or investments. This activity occurs amid rising nickel prices and production adjustments in the region. Details on the specific collaboration or capacity implications remain limited in the report.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Why Alcoa (AA) Is Up 5.2% After Aluminum Tops $3,000 Amid Supply Strains And ESG Demand</title><link>https://simplywall.st/stocks/us/materials/nyse-aa/alcoa/news/why-alcoa-aa-is-up-52-after-aluminum-tops-3000-amid-supply-s</link><description>Alcoa's stock rose 5.2% as LME aluminum prices exceeded $3,000 per ton due to supply constraints in China and Europe tightening inventories, alongside strong demand from construction and renewables. The company benefits from its lower-carbon aluminum production aligning with ESG trends. Upcoming Q4 2025 earnings on January 22 will reveal impacts on sales and margins.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium surges as cash offer hits USD 3,022.5 per tonne</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-surges-as-cash-offer-hits-usd-3-022-5-per-tonne-116808</link><description>LME aluminum cash offer reached USD 3,022.5 per tonne on January 5, extending gains supported by lower inventories and stronger demand factors. Global supply constraints continue to bolster prices amid robust sector outlooks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nucor holds HR spot price at $950/ton</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/05/nucor-holds-hr-spot-price-at-950-ton/</link><description>Nucor maintained its consumer spot price for hot-rolled coil unchanged at $950 per short ton for a third consecutive week. The steelmaker's West Coast joint venture, California Steel Industries, also kept prices steady at $1,000/st, with lead times continuing at 3 to 5 weeks.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metal Market Update: Steel &amp; Aluminum Prices Heading Into 2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9wBLv3trcMA</link><description>Sheffield Metals announced steel price increases going into Q1 2026, driven by mill maintenance downtime, the Nippon/US Steel situation, and coating extras. The video discusses how tariffs and inventory restocking are stretching lead times, with price increases expected to take effect in mid to late January.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SGH and Steel Dynamics confirm the submission of a NBIO to acquire BlueScope Steel Ltd.</title><link>https://ir.steeldynamics.com/sgh-and-steel-dynamics-confirm-the-submission-of-a-nbio-to-acquire-bluescope-steel-ltd/</link><description>SGH and Steel Dynamics submitted a Non-Binding Indicative Offer for SGH to acquire 100% of BlueScope Steel via scheme of arrangement, followed by on-selling North American operations like the North Star mill to Steel Dynamics. The firms argue BlueScope's Australia/ROW and North American businesses are not strategically compatible and would thrive separately. The proposal aligns with SGH's industrial focus and complements SDI's steel operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel extracted from Mati City supplies global EV battery market</title><link>https://mb.com.ph/2026/01/05/nickel-extracted-from-mati-city-supplies-global-ev-battery-market</link><description>Hallmark Mining Corp in Mati City, Davao Oriental, Philippines, extracts nickel laterite ore shipped to China and Indonesia for EV batteries, supporting global clean energy transition. The Philippines, second-largest nickel producer, complies with environmental standards and plans mine rehabilitation. Demand for battery-grade nickel is expected to grow through 2040 amid decarbonization efforts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>AISI: Weekly raw steel mill output ticks up</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/05/aisi-weekly-raw-steel-mill-output-ticks-up/</link><description>US steel mills produced an estimated 1,704,000 short tons of raw steel in the week ending January 3, up 9,000 tons from the previous week, though output remains low compared to recent months. The mill capability utilization rate was 74.4%, up slightly from the prior week but down from last year. Production increased in most regions, with the South seeing a decline.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Night Session SHFE Aluminum Rises Over 2%, Breaking Through 24100 yuan/mt, Multiple Positive Factors Support Aluminum Prices</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103702543/night-session-shfe-aluminum-rises-over-2-breaking-through-24100-yuanmt-multiple-positive-factors-support-aluminum-prices</link><description>SHFE aluminum 2602 contract surged 2.20% to close at 24,165 yuan/mt during the January 5 night session, driven by positive supply factors amid year-end trading. Spot prices in major Chinese regions rose 100-300 yuan/mt, though high prices suppressed downstream demand, with operating rates declining. Medium-term demand from policy support is expected, but environmental restrictions impact production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>New Heat-Resistant Alloys: In Japan, 3D Printing Pushes the Limits of Aluminum</title><link>https://www.3dnatives.com/en/heat-resistant-alloys-in-japan-06012026/</link><description>Researchers at Nagoya University developed new aluminum alloys using metal 3D printing technology that achieve greater mechanical strength and heat tolerance, with one variant maintaining both strength and flexibility at temperatures up to 300°C. The breakthrough uses laser powder bed fusion to trap iron and other elements in metastable forms, creating alloys with copper, manganese, and titanium that are lightweight, durable, and recyclable, with promising applications in automotive and aerospace components.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Australia's BlueScope Steel mulls US$8.8 bn takeover bid | Business</title><link>https://www.bssnews.net/business/348350</link><description>Australia's BlueScope Steel is evaluating a Aus$13.2 billion (US$8.8 billion) joint takeover bid from US-based Steel Dynamics and Australian firm SGH. Under the proposal, SGH would acquire all shares and sell BlueScope's North American operations to Steel Dynamics while retaining the rest. BlueScope stated it is considering the indicative proposal against its own forecasts for improvements in costs, productivity, cashflow, and earnings.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Australia's BlueScope Steel mulls US$8.8 billion takeover bid</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/international-business/australias-bluescope-steel-mulls-us8-8-billion-takeover-bid/articleshow/126363796.cms</link><description>Australia's BlueScope Steel is assessing a joint Aus$13.2 billion takeover bid from Steel Dynamics and SGH, marking the fourth attempt by the US firm to acquire its American operations. The plan involves SGH buying all shares and on-selling North American assets to Steel Dynamics. BlueScope is weighing the offer against its internal value projections, having rejected prior bids as undervaluing the company.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BlueScope Steel Rejects US Steel Dynamics' Bids</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/06/bluescope-steel-rejects-us-steel-dynamics-bids/</link><description>BlueScope Steel has rejected multiple takeover bids from US-based Steel Dynamics, including all-cash, partial, and mixed proposals aimed at its US assets. The board cited concerns over valuation, execution risks, funding, and regulatory approvals despite premiums offered. The rejections underscore BlueScope's confidence in its independent strategy as Australia's leading steel manufacturer.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to 6.02 USD/Lbs on January 6, 2026, up 1.82% from the previous day, with futures climbing above $5.8 per pound amid tightening global supply and concerns over potential US tariffs redirecting shipments. Over the past month, prices have risen 12.46% and are up 45.08% year-over-year. This continues a strong upward trend into the new year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>With the copper price hitting a new record, how can you get exposure?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/06/with-the-copper-price-hitting-a-new-record-how-can-you-get-exposure/</link><description>Copper prices hit a record high amid supply disruptions at major mines like Grasberg in Indonesia, Kamoa-Kakula in Congo, and El Teniente in Chile, straining the supply chain with falling ore grades and high US stockpiles. Refined copper is forecasted to face a 600,000-tonne deficit in 2026 after a 200,000-tonne deficit in 2025. Companies like BHP boosted production to over two million tonnes in FY25, while Rio Tinto upgraded its 2025 guidance to 860,000-875,000 tonnes.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Soar to Record High</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/06/copper-prices-soar-to-record-high/</link><description>Copper prices reached a record $13,000 per tonne driven by mine outages, including a strike at Mantoverde in Chile, and accidents in Indonesia and Congo, alongside rising demand for energy transition applications. In 2025, prices surged 42%, the best annual gain since 2009. Potential US import tariffs have spurred shipments to the US, reducing supplies elsewhere and impacting global inventory flows.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Already up 15% in 2026, how high can this penny stock rise?</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/06/already-up-15-in-2026-how-high-can-this-penny-stock-rise/</link><description>Nickel Industries Ltd (ASX: NIC), a nickel pig iron producer, has surged nearly 15% in early 2026 trading to $0.95, driven by rising nickel prices, an increased ore sales permit, and a strategic partnership. Broker Bell Potter maintains a buy rating with a $1.30 price target, citing LME nickel's recent surge from an 8-month low to a 14-month high as a key catalyst amid market volatility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Forecast: Top Trends for Nickel in 2026</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/nickel-price-forecast-top-trends-nickel-2026</link><description>Analyst Manthey forecasts nickel prices to remain under pressure throughout 2026, struggling to hold above US$16,000 per ton due to ongoing market dynamics. This outlook highlights persistent challenges in the nickel market despite recent volatility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>MEMR allows limited mining output amid 2026 RKAB delays</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/memr-allows-limited-mining-output-amid-2026-rkab-delays-2</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources permits mining companies to operate at up to 25% of 2026 planned output until March 31 due to delays in RKAB approvals, amid plans to curb nickel output for price support. PT Vale Indonesia suspended mining operations without approval. The circular addresses transition issues during quota adjustments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>NALCO Shares Skyrocket to Record High as Aluminum Prices Breach $3000 Mark</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/69082752063c3cf834b9cba6/Commodities/NALCO-Shares-Skyrocket-to-Record-High-as-Aluminum-Prices-Breach-dollar3000-Mark/695ca8acef4ed95f98fa520c</link><description>NALCO shares surged 6% to a record high on January 6, driven by global aluminum prices crossing $3,000/tonne, the highest in over three years. Supply constraints in China and Europe, plus strong demand from construction and renewables, fuel the rally. The stock has risen 30% in the past month and 74% over 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>On January 6, 2026, the Foshan aluminum market witnessed a stark divergence</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103705694</link><description>The SMM A00 (Foshan) aluminum price jumped 610 yuan/mt on January 6, 2026, highlighting a stark divergence in the Foshan aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>NALCO Shares Skyrocket to Record High as Aluminum Prices Breach $3000 Mark</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/Commodities/NALCO-Shares-Skyrocket-to-Record-High-as-Aluminum-Prices-Breach-dollar3000-Mark/695ca8acef4ed95f98fa520c</link><description>NALCO shares rose 6% to a record high on Jan. 6, 2026, driven by aluminum prices topping $3,000/tonne from China's capacity caps, European constraints, and demand in construction/renewables. The stock gained 30% in the past month despite mixed analyst targets. LME prices hit levels unseen since 2022.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMU price ranges: Sheet and plate prices continue to rise into 2026</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/06/smu-price-ranges-sheet-and-plate-prices-continue-to-rise-into-2026/</link><description>Steel sheet and plate prices rose across the board to start 2026 due to limited spot availability at mills, expectations of higher scrap prices, and hopes for stronger demand. Hot-rolled coil averages $930 per short ton, up $20 from prior assessment, with cold-rolled coil at $1,090 and extended lead times reported. Mills are adjusting contracts amid anticipated scrap cost increases.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Extends Rally, Bursting Through $13000 a Ton - Commodities Roundup</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601064165/copper-extends-rally-bursting-through-13000-a-ton-commodities-roundup</link><description>Copper prices extended their rally, breaking through $13,000 a ton, driven by market movements in commodities. The article covers broader commodity updates but highlights the continued upward momentum in copper amid supply concerns. No specific production details are provided in the excerpt.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Melissa “Mel” Sanderson to Champion Critical Minerals Sustainability at Future Minerals Forum 2026</title><link>https://investornews.com/market-opinion/melissa-mel-sanderson-to-champion-critical-minerals-sustainability-at-future-minerals-forum-2026/</link><description>Melissa Sanderson, Co-Chair of the Critical Minerals Institute, will speak at FMF 2026 on sustainable critical minerals development, emphasizing ESG integration and responsible supply chains. The forum, hosted by Saudi Arabia, covers exploration, investment, and policy for minerals supporting energy transition and tech innovation. Her expertise from diplomacy and mining promotes aligning public policy with private sector for resilient ecosystems.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Surge on Huge Volumes | Rebound fueled by mounting supply risks during broad metals rally</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-spikes-more-than-10-as-chinese-buying-fuels-metals-surge/nickel-prices-surge-on-huge-volumes-rebound-fueled-by-mounting-supply-risks-during-broad-metals-rally/</link><description>Nickel prices surged more than 10% on huge trading volumes, driven by mounting supply risks and a broad metals rally. Chinese buying fueled the spike amid concerns over supply disruptions. The rebound highlights strong speculative interest in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Surge on Huge Volumes | Rebound fueled by mounting supply risks during broad metals rally</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-spikes-more-than-10-as-chinese-buying-fuels-metals-surge/nickel-prices-surge-on-huge-volumes-rebound-fueled-by-mounting-supply-risks-during-broad-metals-rally/</link><description>Nickel prices surged more than 10% on huge trading volumes, driven by Chinese buying and mounting supply risks. The rebound occurs amid a broader metals rally, with focus on potential supply constraints.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Steelmakers in US maintain steady output</title><link>https://www.cdrecycler.com/news/steel-production-usa-december-2025-early-2026-rising-recycling/</link><description>US steelmakers ended 2025 with over 89.3 million tons produced through December 27, up 3.4% from 2024, and continued with 1.7 million tons in the week ending January 3, a 0.5% rise week-over-week and 1.4% higher than last year. Capacity utilization stood at 74.4%, down from 75.6% a year ago due to added EAF capacity. Steady production is pressuring recycled steel prices upward.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: Mexican flat steel could recover in 2026</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2771433-viewpoint-mexican-flat-steel-could-recover-in-2026</link><description>Mexico's flat steel market anticipates recovery in 2026 after two years of contraction, supported by potential US tariffs, rising US HRC prices, and falling imports. January-November 2025 steel production fell 9% year-over-year to 15.47 million tons, while consumption dropped 10% to 23 million tons. Mills raised HRC prices twice in December amid these dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper surges past $13,000/t as bull run gains pace</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2772384-copper-surges-past-13-000-t-as-bull-run-gains-pace</link><description>Copper prices have surged past $13,000/t amid expectations of a 650,000–850,000t copper concentrate supply shortfall in 2026. The benchmark annual TC/RC settlement between Jiangxi Copper and Antofagasta concluded at $0/t and 0.0¢/lb, down significantly from 2025 levels, signaling tight supply risks. Market participants forecast strong copper prices in early 2026 due to insufficient mine output.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Analysis] Market Speculative Enthusiasm Soars, Overnight Multiple SHFE Nickel Contracts Hit Limit Up</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103706977/smm-analysis-market-speculative-enthusiasm-soars-overnight-multiple-shfe-nickel-contracts-hit-limit-up</link><description>Multiple SHFE nickel contracts hit limit-up during the night session on January 6, 2026, with the most-traded 2602 contract closing at 147,720 yuan/mt, while LME nickel reached $18,785/mt. Speculative funds flooded in amid concerns over global supply stability from U.S.-Venezuela relations and Indonesia's policies, pushing spot SMM #1 refined nickel to an average of 150,150 yuan/mt, up 6,700 yuan/mt. Inventories are building, but smelters are increasing production significantly.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel drops from 19-month high as metals rally takes breather</title><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/nickel-drops-from-19-month-high-as-metals-rally-takes-breather-13760604.html</link><description>Nickel futures fell 1.2% to $18,295 a ton on the LME after spiking as much as 10.5% to near $18,800 a ton on Tuesday. The drop came as the broader metals rally paused following recent sharp gains. Nickel, used in stainless steel and batteries, saw high volatility in early Shanghai trading.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel prices surpass $17000, reaching 15-month high</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-prices-surpass-17000-reaching-15-month-high/158632</link><description>LME nickel futures closed at $17,003/ton on January 5, marking the highest level since October 2024 and a 15-month high. The surge reflects strong market momentum in base metals. Prices continued to climb in subsequent sessions amid broader trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Analysis] Market Speculative Enthusiasm Soars, Overnight Multiple SHFE Nickel Contracts Hit Limit Up</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103706977/smm-analysis-market-speculative-enthusiasm-soars-overnight-multiple-shfe-nickel-contracts-hit-limit-up</link><description>SHFE nickel contracts hit limit-up on January 6 night session, with the main 2602 contract closing at 147,720 yuan/mt amid soaring speculative enthusiasm. Smelters are ramping up production, with December output up 22% MoM and January expected to rise 18% MoM, while inventories continue to build at LME (255,000 mt) and domestic levels (59,000 mt). Focus remains on Indonesia's quota implementation amid tightening expectations versus actual surplus.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Low-Carbon Nickel Sulfate Emerges as Key Innovation in Energy &amp; Material Technologies for Environmental Protection, Boosting New Energy Sector</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/102932622/low-carbon-nickel-sulfate-emerges-as-key-innovation-in-energy-material-technologies-for-environmental-protection-boostin</link><description>Low-carbon nickel sulfate is highlighted as a pivotal innovation in energy and material technologies to enhance environmental protection. It supports the growing global demand for sustainable solutions in the new energy sector. This development boosts the transition to cleaner energy applications.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia cuts nickel mining quota to support prices, imports needed in 2026</title><link>https://www.digitimes.com/news/a20260107PD206/nickel-2026-2025-production.html</link><description>Indonesia has reduced its nickel mining quota to bolster prices amid expectations of increased imports in 2026. This policy adjustment aims to stabilize the nickel market and support sustainable production levels. It reflects efforts to balance supply with global demand for nickel in technology applications.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali, a leading Italian steel producer, has launched the pilot phase of its 'Green Hydrogen in Cogne' project at its Aosta plant. The company installed a 1.008 MW Anion Exchange Membrane electrolyzer capable of producing 165 tons of hydrogen per year, which will power one of its 70 furnaces entirely and prevent up to 26 tons of carbon emissions per ton of hydrogen. The project is supported by €7.9 million in funding from Italy's National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>