<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:14:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US-Australia Critical Minerals Deal: Strategic Impact</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/us-australia-critical-minerals-partnership-2025/</link><description>The US-Australia partnership targets critical minerals including nickel to reduce supply chain vulnerabilities and support advanced manufacturing, renewable energy, and defense. The deal emphasizes accelerating lithium, cobalt, and nickel projects to secure battery material supplies essential for electric vehicles and energy storage.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Australian battery innovation receives $25M boost from ARENA</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/australian-battery-innovation-receives-25m-boost-from-arena/</link><description>The Australian Renewable Energy Agency (ARENA) awarded $25 million to Relectrify to commercialize its AC1 battery energy storage system, which delivers alternating current directly from battery cells without a separate inverter. This technology reduces battery degradation and improves energy delivery efficiency, supporting sustainable energy storage solutions.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Botswana Mining Diversification: Key Minerals &amp; Strategy</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/botswana-mining-diversification-critical-minerals-strategy-2025/</link><description>Botswana is pursuing sustainable mining diversification with a focus on critical minerals like nickel, emphasizing environmentally friendly processing and maximizing resource recovery. The strategy aims to foster long-term economic sustainability, community participation, and technological innovation to position Botswana as a leader in responsible mining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,862.80 per tonne on October 23, 2025, up 1.89% from the previous day and reaching a three-year high. The price increase is driven by tight supply conditions, including China's aluminum output cap of 45 million tons, which is expected to be breached this year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME Aluminium cash price rises 0.92% on October 23, inventories down 4,850t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-price-rises-0-92-on-october-23-inventories-down-4-850t-115932</link><description>The LME aluminium cash price increased by 0.92% to USD 2,843 per tonne on October 23, 2025, accompanied by a decline in inventories by 4,850 tonnes, indicating tightening supply conditions in the market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa to own just 5pc of WA plant to bust China's dominance of gallium supply</title><link>https://www.boilingcold.com.au/alcoa-to-own-just-5pc-of-wa-plant-to-bust-chinas-dominance-of-gallium-supply/</link><description>Alcoa will own only 5% of a new gallium plant in Western Australia aimed at reducing China's dominance in gallium supply, a critical mineral used in semiconductors and electronics. The plant leverages Alcoa's Wagerup alumina refinery and aligns with government interests to diversify supply chains outside China.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ford lowers annual guidance, citing fire at supplier's aluminum plant</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/transport-logistics/ford-lowers-annual-guidance-citing-fire-suppliers-aluminum-plant</link><description>Ford Motor Company reduced its profit guidance due to a fire at Novelis' aluminum plant in Oswego, New York, which supplies aluminum for Ford's F-150 trucks. The disruption is expected to reduce production by up to 100,000 units through the end of 2025, with Novelis aiming to restart affected operations by December.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME Aluminium cash price rises 0.92% on October 23, inventories down 4,850t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-price-rises-0-92-on-october-23-inventories-down-4-850t-115932</link><description>The London Metal Exchange (LME) aluminium cash price increased by 0.92% to USD 2,843 per tonne on October 23, 2025, while aluminium inventories declined by 4,850 tonnes, indicating tightening supply conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Investing In Innovation: GBCCA Showcases New Technology To Close The Recycling Loop For Aluminium Cans</title><link>https://international-aluminium.org/investing-in-innovation-gbcca-showcases-new-technology-to-close-the-recycling-loop-for-aluminium-cans/</link><description>The GBCCA presented breakthrough technologies at the International Aluminium Institute event during Climate Week NYC, focusing on autonomous sorting and recovery of aluminium cans from municipal waste. Innovations include robotics and AI systems, advanced material recovery facilities, large-scale deposit return machines, and next-generation home recycling systems, all aimed at accelerating aluminium circularity and supporting decarbonisation through recycling.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AL Circle x Takuo Harato: Advancing sustainability and innovation in the global aluminium industry</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/al-circle-x-takuo-harato-advancing-sustainability-and-innovation-in-the-global-aluminium-industry-115903</link><description>Takuo Harato, an alumina production technology consultant, discussed key sustainability challenges in the aluminium industry, emphasizing the need for carbon neutrality and green aluminium production. He highlighted energy efficiency improvements in refining processes, such as heat exchanger and heat recovery systems, as critical steps to reduce energy consumption and carbon emissions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Evonik Strengthens Asian Presence with New Aluminum Specialty Production Facility</title><link>https://www.evonik.com/en/news/press-releases/2025/10/evonik-strengthens-asian-presence-with-new-aluminum-specialty-pl.html</link><description>Evonik opened its new state-of-the-art fumed alumina production plant 'Alu5' in Yokkaichi, Japan, producing AEROXIDE®, an advanced fumed aluminum oxide that enhances performance and durability in electric mobility, electronics, and sustainable coatings. The facility reduces lead times and carbon footprint, supporting sustainable innovation and regional growth in Asia.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ET Startup Awards 2025: Chakr Innovation eyes international foray and new technology</title><link>https://economictimes.com/tech/startups/et-startup-awards-2025-chakr-innovation-eyes-international-foray-and-new-technology/articleshow/124769968.cms</link><description>Chakr Innovation is developing clean-tech solutions including an aluminium-air energy storage technology as an alternative to lithium-ion batteries, leveraging India's abundant aluminium reserves. The startup is scaling commercial deployments and overcoming challenges related to hardware manufacturing and regulatory support under India's National Clean Air Programme.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global crude steel production falls 1.6% in September</title><link>https://www.aa.com.tr/en/economy/global-crude-steel-production-falls-16-in-september/3725089</link><description>Global crude steel production decreased by 1.6% in September compared to the same period last year, primarily due to a 4.6% decline in Chinese production. Despite this, countries like the US and India saw increases in production. Türkiye's production rose by 3.3% to 3.2 million tons.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Weekly Overseas Copper News Roundup Oct 20-24</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103585546/Weekly-Overseas-Copper-News-Roundup-Oct-20-24</link><description>Antofagasta reported Q3 2025 copper production of 161,800 metric tons, up 1% quarter-on-quarter, with full-year production expected at the low end of 660,000–700,000 metric tons. Freeport-McMoRan's Q3 copper production declined year-on-year to 912 million pounds due to a mudslide incident and lower ore grades but profits exceeded expectations due to rising copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Angola Opens First Major Copper Mine in $250 Million Push Beyond Oil</title><link>https://thevoiceofafrica.com/2025/10/23/angola-opens-first-major-copper-mine-in-250-million-push-beyond-oil/</link><description>Angola launched its first large-scale copper mine, the Tetelo project, valued at $250 million and owned by China's Shining Star Icarus. The mine is expected to produce 25,000 metric tons of copper concentrate annually during its first two years, transitioning from open-pit to underground mining in 2026, supporting Angola's economic diversification and positioning it as a key player in the global clean energy minerals market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Antofagasta 9-month Copper Production Rises</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/antofagasta-9-month-copper-production-rises</link><description>Antofagasta reported copper production of 476,600 tonnes for the first nine months of 2025, a 3% increase year-on-year, driven by higher output at Centinela Concentrates. The company expects full-year 2025 copper production to be at the lower end of its guidance range of 660,000 to 700,000 tonnes, with a forecasted increase in 2026 at Los Pelambres.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>More high-grade copper discovered at Rae</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/10/24/northern-neighbors/more-high-grade-copper-discovered-at-rae/9325.html</link><description>New discoveries of high-grade copper have been reported at the Rae project, indicating promising exploration results that could enhance copper production capacity in the region.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Torchlight and Innovation Mining Unite as RZOLV Technologies</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/story/news/35649525/torchlight-and-innovation-mining-unite-as-rzolv-technologies-on-the-tsxv-with-disruptive-new-mining-technology</link><description>Torchlight Innovations Inc. has merged with Innovation Mining to form RZOLV Technologies, marking a significant step in clean-technology mining. RZOLV offers a non-toxic, water-based process as an alternative to cyanide and smelting, reducing environmental impact. The company has commenced trading on the TSX Venture Exchange.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Russia's Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/10/23/russias-nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast</link><description>Nornickel reaffirmed its nickel production forecast for 2025 at 196,000 to 204,000 tons despite challenges from equipment modernization and import substitution programs. The company reported an 18% increase in nickel production in Q3 compared to Q2, attributing earlier declines to a transition to new mining equipment and seasonal port disruptions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel Nickel Production Forecast: 196-204K Tons 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/nornickel-2025-production-outlook-market-confidence/</link><description>Nornickel confirmed its 2025 nickel production target of 196,000 to 204,000 metric tons amid ongoing equipment modernization challenges. The company is undergoing a gradual replacement of Western mining equipment to ensure operational independence, causing temporary production adjustments but expected to improve long-term efficiency.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia (INCO) Targets 71,234 Tons of Nickel Production in 2025</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/vale-indonesia-inco-targets-71234-tons-of-nickel-production-in-2025</link><description>Vale Indonesia aims to produce approximately 71,234 tons of nickel-in-matte in 2025, exceeding its 2024 target. This production increase reflects the company's growth plans in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Raul Gil: Submarine cables and high-tech solutions to counter low-tech attacks</title><link>https://www.cabletechnologynews.co.uk/prysmian-raul-gil-submarine-cables-and-high-tech-solutions-to-counter-low-tech-attacks/</link><description>At the Italian Energy Summit 2025, Raul Gil, EVP Transmission at Prysmian, discussed the importance of security and innovative technologies in submarine cables. This underscores Prysmian's commitment to advancing cable technology and protecting critical infrastructure in Italy and beyond.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Macro and Fundamentals Resonate Positively, Aluminum Prices Expected to Fluctuate at Highs</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices showed bullish momentum with the most-traded contract closing at 21,265 yuan/mt on October 23, up 0.64%. Technical indicators suggest prices will hover at highs with resistance around 21,400–21,580 yuan/mt and support near 20,730–20,930 yuan/mt, though caution is advised for potential retreat from these highs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper price hovers near $11,000 as test of record high beckons</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-hovers-near-11000-as-test-of-record-high-beckons/</link><description>Copper prices remain just below $11,000 per ton, close to record highs, as supply concerns persist following operational issues at major mines like Grasberg in Indonesia. Freeport-McMoRan confirmed the Grasberg mine remains halted, with an update on the outlook expected next month.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Macro and Fundamentals Resonate Positively, Aluminum Prices Expected to Fluctuate at Highs [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103585036/Macro-and-Fundamentals-Resonate-Positively-Aluminum-Prices-Expected-to-Fluctuate-at-Highs-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>On October 23, the most-traded SHFE aluminum contract closed at 21,265 yuan/mt, up 0.64%, with prices expected to hover at highs in the short term. Technical indicators show a bullish trend, with resistance projected between 21,400-21,580 yuan/mt and support between 20,730-20,930 yuan/mt, though caution is advised for potential pullbacks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Here's why these three Aluminium-linked stocks are in focus on Friday</title><link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/market/hindalco-nalco-vedanta-share-price-lme-aluminium-rates-key-factors-behind-surge-tariff-impact-19724756.htm</link><description>Shares of Hindalco Ltd., Nalco Ltd., and Vedanta Ltd. rose over 3% on October 24 as LME aluminum prices crossed $2,850 per tonne. The surge is attributed to tight global supply, a smelter shutdown in Iceland affecting 100 kt of production, and prospects of global monetary easing. US-listed Alcoa Corp shares gained 12% following CEO comments that current prices cover tariff impacts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Stocks Rally as LME Prices Surge Past $2,850 Per Tonne</title><link>https://scanx.trade/stock-market-news/stocks/aluminum-stocks-rally-as-lme-prices-surge-past-2-850-per-tonne/22821187</link><description>Indian aluminum stocks including Hindalco, Nalco, and Vedanta saw price increases between 0.30% and 1.60% as LME aluminum prices surged past $2,850 per tonne. The rally is driven by tight global supply-demand dynamics, a smelter shutdown in Iceland, and expectations of global monetary easing. Alcoa Corporation's shares jumped 12% after CEO remarks on tariff impacts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Evonik Strengthens Asian Presence with New Aluminum Specialty Plant in Japan</title><link>https://www.evonik.com/en/news/press-releases/2025/10/evonik-strengthens-asian-presence-with-new-aluminum-specialty-pl.html</link><description>Evonik has opened its first advanced fumed alumina production facility 'Alu5' in Yokkaichi, Japan, producing AEROXIDE®, a high-performance fumed aluminum oxide. The plant supports regional growth, reduces lead times and carbon footprint, and enhances supply security for industries including electric mobility and electronics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Norsk Hydro: Solid results amid uncertain markets</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/24/3172590/0/en/Norsk-Hydro-Solid-results-amid-uncertain-markets.html</link><description>Norsk Hydro reported a decrease in adjusted EBITDA for Aluminium Metal in Q3 2025 due to currency effects despite higher sales volumes and lower alumina costs. Global primary aluminium consumption remained flat, with growth in China offsetting declines elsewhere. Extrusion demand in Europe was flat year-over-year but down seasonally from the previous quarter.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium producer Norsk Hydro's Q3 core profit lags expectations</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/aluminium-producer-norsk-hydros-q3-core-profit-lags-expectations-157673/</link><description>Norsk Hydro reported an 18.6% decline in third-quarter core profit, impacted by lower alumina prices and a stronger Norwegian crown, partially offset by increased production volumes. The results reflect ongoing market challenges in the aluminium sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Can a-metal Democratize Access to Laser Fusion Technology?</title><link>https://www.3dnatives.com/en/can-a-metal-democratize-access-to-laser-fusion-technology-24102025/</link><description>a-metal, a startup spun off from ETH Zurich, is developing compact, affordable metal 3D printing solutions using laser powder bed fusion to make metal additive manufacturing accessible to SMEs. Their technology aims to reduce machine size and complexity while increasing robustness, enabling broader adoption of metal 3D printing for sustainable manufacturing.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel prices hit five-year low; weak trend likely to persist in near term</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/steel/steel-prices-hit-five-year-low-weak-trend-likely-to-persist-in-near-term-bigmint/articleshow/124776337.cms</link><description>Domestic steel prices have dropped to a five-year low, trading between Rs 47,000-48,000 per tonne due to multiple factors including surging imports and weak export demand. Hot rolled coil prices hover around Rs 47,150 per tonne, while re-bar prices range from Rs 46,500-47,000 per tonne, levels last seen during the 2020 pandemic slowdown.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel fell to 3,035 CNY/T on October 24, 2025, down 0.16% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices declined slightly to 3,035 CNY per tonne on October 24, 2025, down 0.16% from the previous day. Over the past month, steel prices have fallen 1.37% and are down 6.41% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect prices to continue declining to around 2,875.97 CNY/MT within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Ministry to Address Import Issues with Industry Stakeholders on October 27</title><link>https://infra.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/construction/steel-ministry-to-address-import-issues-with-industry-stakeholders-on-october-27/124737235</link><description>The Ministry of Steel will hold an Open House on October 27, 2025, to address steel import-related concerns amid rising imports that have pressured domestic steel prices and market share. The session aims to facilitate direct interaction with industry stakeholders to discuss issues related to SIMS, NOC, QCO, and other import matters.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of October 24, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-24-oct-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's share price experienced a slight increase of 0.34%, actively trading at ₹1,145.00 as of October 24, 2025. This reflects a positive upturn in the company's stock performance amid current market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel prices hit five-year low; weak trend likely to persist in near term</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/steel/steel-prices-hit-five-year-low-weak-trend-likely-to-persist-in-near-term-bigmint/articleshow/124776337.cms</link><description>Domestic steel prices in India have dropped to a five-year low, influenced by rising imports and stable raw material costs. The Ministry of Steel is set to discuss these issues with industry stakeholders. India remains a net importer of steel despite increased exports.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU's Proposed Tariffs on Steel to Address Excess Capacity and Enable Decarbonization Could Worsen Trade Tensions</title><link>https://www.energypolicy.columbia.edu/eus-proposed-tariffs-on-steel-to-address-excess-capacity-and-enable-decarbonization-could-worsen-trade-tensions/</link><description>The EU's proposed tariffs on steel aim to address excess capacity and promote decarbonization but may exacerbate trade tensions. The regulation could impact global steel trade dynamics and compliance with trade norms.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tetelo Copper Ore Project Is Expected to Commence Production; LME Copper Rose Sharply Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103585001/Tetelo-Copper-Ore-Project-Is-Expected-to-Commence-Production-LME-Copper-Rose-Sharply-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>The Tetelo copper mine project in Angola is set to start production, marking a significant development for the country's mining sector. Meanwhile, LME copper prices rose sharply overnight, reaching a high of $10,876 per tonne before closing at $10,817 per tonne. This increase reflects ongoing supply disruptions and robust demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40388913/copper-prices-rise</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange rose 1.6% to USD10,834 a metric ton, marking its highest level since October 14. This increase is attributed to ongoing market dynamics and supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Strides Higher on Hopes for Stimulus After China Plenum</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-strides-higher-on-hopes-for-stimulus-after-china-plenum/</link><description>Copper prices have increased due to expectations that China will introduce new stimulus measures in its five-year plan. This potential stimulus could bolster demand from China, the world's top metals consumer.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tetelo Copper Ore Project Is Expected to Commence Production</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103585001/Tetelo-Copper-Ore-Project-Is-Expected-to-Commence-Production-LME-Copper-Rose-Sharply-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>The Tetelo copper mine project in Uíge Province, Angola, controlled by Chinese company Shining Star Icarus, is expected to start production soon. The project involves an initial open-pit mining phase with an annual output of about 25,000 metric tons of copper concentrates, transitioning to underground mining in the second half of 2026, marking a significant expansion of Angola's copper capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia may allow copper miner Amman Mineral to export copper concentrate</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/update-1-indonesia-may-allow-copper-miner-amman-mineral-to-export-copper-concentrate-157667/</link><description>Indonesia is considering allowing copper miner Amman Mineral International to resume copper concentrate exports after a fire at its smelter caused technical constraints. The government banned concentrate exports in mid-2023 to boost domestic processing but may grant exemptions under force majeure conditions, with the export permit process underway.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco and Ennomotive Launch Global Challenge to Reduce Mining Dust</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/codelco-and-ennomotive-launch-an-international-challenge-to-control-dust-generated-by-the-interaction-between-underground-and-open-pit-mining/</link><description>Codelco and Ennomotive have launched a global challenge to find solutions for reducing airborne dust generated by the interaction between underground and open-pit mining operations. The challenge seeks technologies that can efficiently measure, control, and mitigate dust with minimal human intervention and low environmental impact. Solutions must be compatible with daily operations and withstand extreme weather conditions.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Ore Concentrate &amp; Refining Process: Top Innovations</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-ore-concentrate-refining-process-top-innovations</link><description>The copper industry is adopting advanced technologies like AI monitoring, satellite imaging, and closed-loop systems to enhance sustainability and efficiency. Innovations include bioleaching for low-grade ores and blockchain for traceability. These advancements aim to reduce environmental impact while improving operational efficiency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME nickel prices rebound on Oct 24, boosted by higher demand in China</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-prices-rebound-on-oct-24-boosted-by-higher-demand-in-china/137254</link><description>LME nickel futures prices rebounded on October 24, closing at US$22,248/ton, up by US$299. The spot price also rose by US$302, reaching US$22,151/ton, driven by increased demand in China.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low Amid Oversupply from Indonesia</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to around $15,241 per tonne on October 24, down 0.61% from the previous day, with futures dropping below $15,100 per tonne—the lowest in over a month. The decline is attributed to oversupply from Indonesia, which has pushed LME inventories to a record high of 308,000 tons.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Daily Review] Nickel Prices Rebounded on October 24 as the Fourth Plenary Session Sent Positive Signals</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103586265/%5BSMM-Nickel-Daily-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Rebounded-on-October-24-as-the-Fourth-Plenary-Session-Sent-Positive-Signals</link><description>On October 24, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,900 yuan/mt, up 750 yuan/mt from the previous day. The rebound in nickel prices was influenced by positive signals from the Fourth Plenary Session.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Philippines poised to gain as nickel steadies, gold peaks in 2026</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/business/2025/10/24/2482003/philippines-poised-gain-nickel-steadies-gold-peaks-2026</link><description>Nickel prices are expected to remain subdued in the near term before recovering later in the decade. The Philippines is positioned to benefit from this trend, while gold prices are projected to reach record highs in 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SPC Nickel evaluates Lockerby East's potential</title><link>https://mining.com.au/spc-nickel-evaluates-lockerby-easts-potential/</link><description>SPC Nickel has started a 1,000m diamond drilling program at the Lockerby East Project in Ontario, Canada, to assess potential new nickel-copper-platinum group metals discoveries. The project targets high-quality Sudbury-style massive sulphide mineralization with promising grades and proximity to past producing mines.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Philippines poised to gain as nickel steadies, gold peaks in 2026</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/business/2025/10/24/2482003/philippines-poised-gain-nickel-steadies-gold-peaks-2026</link><description>Nickel prices are expected to remain subdued in the near term but recover later in the decade, positioning the Philippines to benefit from steady nickel production. The outlook also notes gold prices are projected to reach record highs in 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Unleashing sustainable nickel production for a net zero future</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/unleashing-sustainable-nickel-production-for-a-net-zero-future/34671/</link><description>This article explores how optimizing nickel production, particularly through High Pressure Acid Leaching (HPAL), can reduce environmental impact and carbon footprint, supporting a sustainable battery industry globally. It highlights efforts in pollution prevention, biodiversity conservation, energy efficiency, and supply chain transparency to improve nickel production sustainability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Woes: Innovations Steering a Sustainable EV Future</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-supply-woes-innovations-steering-a-sustainable-ev-future-aemc/</link><description>The article discusses trends in battery technology emphasizing nickel's role and strategies to manage nickel demand sustainably. It covers material innovation like low-nickel batteries, battery recycling to create a circular economy, and boosting domestic battery production and mining capacities supported by financial incentives such as the U.S. Inflation Reduction Act.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel Nickel Production Forecast: 196-204K Tons 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/nornickel-2025-production-outlook-market-confidence/</link><description>Nornickel maintains its 2025 nickel production forecast despite equipment modernization challenges, signaling confidence in operational stability amid growing demand for battery metals. The company is undergoing a transition to domestic mining equipment to improve long-term efficiency and reduce reliance on Western suppliers.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>US and Australia Launch Critical Minerals Partnership for 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/us-australia-critical-minerals-partnership-2025-2/</link><description>The US and Australia have formed a $1 billion partnership to enhance critical minerals supply chains, focusing on increasing battery material recycling efficiency to 40% by 2030 and advancing circular economy principles. The partnership also targets market transparency, fair trading practices, and innovation in alternative materials to reduce supply risks.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>New Technology Set to Revolutionize Nickel Pollution Cleanup</title><link>https://albanian-minerals.com/new-technology-set-to-revolutionize-nickel-pollution-cleanup/</link><description>A new technology has been developed to significantly improve nickel pollution cleanup, aiming to enhance environmental protection related to nickel mining and processing. This innovation supports cleaner air and water by addressing nickel contamination more effectively.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Launches Pilot Phase of Green Hydrogen Project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has launched the pilot phase of its green hydrogen project in Aosta, Italy. The project aims to reduce carbon emissions by using electrolysis to produce green hydrogen. The project is supported by funding from Italy's National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali to Benefit from Enhanced Energy Performance</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will enhance its energy performance and reduce environmental impact through a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA. This agreement supports regional decarbonization targets and improves economic competitiveness.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Continuous Casting Machine Modernization at Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://uk.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/DANIELI-C-OFFICINE-MECCAN-69524/news/Danieli-C-Officine-Meccaniche-S-p-A-Continuous-casting-machine-modernization-at-Cogne-Acciai-Spe-47435416/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has contracted Danieli Service for a modernization project at its works in Aosta, Italy. The project focuses on modernizing a continuous casting machine.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Base Metals Market Navigates Volatility: Aluminum Shines ...</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-10-24-base-metals-market-navigates-volatility-aluminum-shines-zinc-squeezed-lead-lingers-amidst-shifting-global-dynamics</link><description>Aluminum has been a standout performer in 2025, with LME aluminum forwards rising 5.06% in the first nine months and continuing to climb in October, reaching $2,857.50 USD/T on October 24. The price increase is driven by strong demand from energy transition sectors and supply constraints including China's production cap and alumina supply disruptions, pushing the market into an anticipated deficit for 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,859.90 USD/T on October 24, 2025, down 0.11% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices slightly declined to $2,859.90 per tonne on October 24, 2025, down 0.11% from the previous day, but have risen 7.47% over the past month and 6.91% year-on-year. The market remains tight due to China's aluminum output cap and strong demand, with forecasts expecting prices around $2,805.80 by the end of the quarter and $2,929.65 in 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Oct '25 (ALV25) - Futures</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/futures/quotes/ALV25</link><description>Aluminum futures for October 2025 traded at a high of 2,776.75, showing a 9.29% increase over the past month and a 6.23% rise over three months. The 52-week performance shows a 2.48% increase compared to the previous year, indicating sustained upward momentum in aluminum prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Base Metals Market Navigates Volatility: Aluminum Shines ...</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-24-base-metals-market-navigates-volatility-aluminum-shines-zinc-squeezed-lead-lingers-amidst-shifting-global-dynamics</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged by 5.06% in the first nine months of 2025 and continued climbing into October, reaching a three-year peak near $2,900 per ton. This rise is driven by strong demand from electric vehicles, renewable energy infrastructure, and lightweight construction, alongside supply constraints such as China's cap on aluminum production and alumina supply disruptions, pushing the global market into an anticipated deficit for 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US aluminum scrap trade faces 2025 shake-up amid tariffs and global demand</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5101605-us-aluminum-scrap-trade-faces-2025-shake-up-amid-tariffs-and-global-demand</link><description>The US aluminum scrap trade experienced significant changes in early 2025 due to tariffs and shifting global demand. Imports of aluminum scrap rose 31% in the first half of 2025 compared to the previous year, despite a 25% import tariff introduced in March, which led recyclers to increasingly rely on domestic recovery.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa said it will invest about $60 million to modernize part of its aluminum smelter in Massena, New York</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103582998</link><description>Alcoa announced a $60 million investment to modernize part of its aluminum smelter in Massena, New York, following the signing of a new 10-year hydropower agreement. This modernization aims to enhance production efficiency and sustainability at the facility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Can circular aluminium provide a blueprint for a post-plastic world?</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/can-circular-aluminium-provide-a-blueprint-for-a-post-plastic-world/61691/</link><description>Ellie Gabel discusses the benefits, challenges, and future potential of circular aluminium in driving a sustainable economy and reducing reliance on plastics. Aluminium's infinite recyclability and existing recycling infrastructure make it a strong candidate for replacing plastics in a circular economy, with recycled aluminium requiring only 5% of the energy used for virgin production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa invests $60M in US aluminium smelter &amp; signs 10-year energy pact</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/alcoa-invests-60m-in-us-aluminium-smelter-signs-10-year-energy-pact-at-the-same-time-115933</link><description>Alcoa Corporation announced a $60 million investment in its Massena Operations in New York, including upgrades to the anode baking furnace, alongside a 10-year renewable energy pact with New York Power Authority. This initiative aims to strengthen sustainable aluminium production in the US by combining renewable energy with advanced furnace technology.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The future of US aluminium hinges on energy, not tariff policy</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/the-future-of-us-aluminium-hinges-on-energy-not-tariff-policy-heres-why-115920</link><description>Industry leaders emphasize that affordable electricity, rather than tariffs, is the key to revitalizing US aluminium production. Aluminium smelting is highly energy-intensive, requiring long-term energy contracts at competitive rates to be financially viable, with current US industrial electricity prices posing a significant challenge compared to hydro-rich Canada.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Base Metals Market Navigates Volatility: Aluminum Shines Amidst Shifting Global Dynamics</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-24-base-metals-market-navigates-volatility-aluminum-shines-zinc-squeezed-lead-lingers-amidst-shifting-global-dynamics</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged in 2025 driven by strong demand from the energy transition sectors such as electric vehicles and renewable energy infrastructure. Supply constraints, including China's production caps and alumina disruptions, have tightened the market, pushing global aluminum supply into a deficit and highlighting its critical role in sustainable technologies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>"METALEX 2025" Ready to Spotlight Next-Generation Machinery Driving ASEAN Metalworking Toward Smart Manufacturing</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/10/24/metalex-2025-ready-to-spotlight-next-generation-machinery-driving-asean-metalworking-toward-smart-manufacturing/</link><description>METALEX 2025 conference features sessions on aluminum industry trends, smart manufacturing, and sustainability, including an International Symposium on Light Materials Technology focusing on Thailand's readiness as an aluminum innovation hub. The event highlights AI applications, robotics, and sustainable manufacturing technologies relevant to aluminum production and processing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel price rises slightly to 3,054 CNY/T on October 24, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices increased by 0.46% from the previous day, reaching 3,054 CNY/T. Despite this daily rise, steel prices have fallen 0.75% over the past month and are down 5.83% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect steel to trade at around 3,009 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,876 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 4-week High at 832 USD/T</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices rose to 815 USD/T on October 24, 2025, up 0.25% from the previous day, reaching a 4-week high of 832 USD/T. Over the past 12 months, HRC steel prices have increased by 13.64%, although recent weeks showed some volatility with a 12-week low recorded in late September.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Usiminas reports net loss of $651 million in Q3 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/usiminas-reports-net-loss-in-q3-2025-1416635.htm</link><description>Brazilian steel producer Usiminas posted a net loss of BRL 3.503 billion ($651.1 million) in Q3 2025, reversing from a net profit in the same quarter last year. The loss was mainly due to asset impairment and deferred tax recoverability issues, though excluding these, the company reported a net profit. Steel product sales volume declined by 2%, while iron ore sales increased by 9%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Stellar Steel to Invest $450 Million in New Steel Plant in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/chinas-stellar-steel-to-invest-450-million-in-new-steel-plant-in-nigeria-1416525.htm</link><description>China's Stellar Steel is investing $450 million in a new steel plant in Nigeria's Ogun State. The facility will produce hot-rolled coil steel, iron steel doors, and gas cylinders, aiming to reduce Nigeria's reliance on imported steel products. Operations are expected to begin by mid-2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Usiminas Reports Net Loss in Q3 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/usiminas-reports-net-loss-in-q3-2025-1416635.htm</link><description>Usiminas reported a net loss of BRL 3.503 billion ($651.1 million) for Q3 2025, primarily due to asset impairments. The company's steel sales declined by 2%, while iron ore sales increased by 9%. Despite the loss, Usiminas noted stable cash flow.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Brazil's Steel Demand to Slow: Usiminas</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2746392-brazil-s-steel-demand-to-slow-usiminas</link><description>Usiminas expects Brazil's steel demand to slow in the fourth quarter, following seasonal trends. The company reported a decline in crude steel production and rolled steel output. Despite recent price increases, Usiminas forecasts stable steel prices for the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Sassda Spearheads Stainless Steel Master Plan As Sector Roadmap to 2030</title><link>https://infrastructurenews.co.za/2025/10/24/sassda-spearheads-stainless-steel-master-plan-as-sector-roadmap-to-2030/</link><description>The Southern Africa Stainless Steel Development Association (Sassda) has launched a new Stainless Steel Master Plan to guide the sector's growth and sustainability to 2030. The plan involves a wide range of stakeholders to align industrial growth with sustainability and social objectives. It aims to realize stainless steel's potential as a high-value contributor to South Africa's economy.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price tumbles as Trump threatens massive new tariffs on China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-tumbles-as-trump-threatens-massive-new-tariffs-on-china/</link><description>Copper prices dropped nearly 5% to below $10,400 per ton on the London Metal Exchange after President Trump threatened a significant increase in tariffs on Chinese goods. This caused market turmoil, reversing recent rallies driven by supply setbacks in major copper mines and raising concerns about trade tensions impacting the metal's demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to $5.09 per pound on October 24, 2025, up 0.29% from the previous day and showing a 7.74% increase over the past month. The metal is up 17.33% compared to the same time last year, with expectations to trade around $5.08 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.59 in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price rises on mine struggles, Goldman bull flag</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-rises-on-mine-struggles-goldman-bull-flag/</link><description>Copper prices climbed nearly 2% as major miners issued conservative production outlooks, exacerbating supply concerns amid global mine disruptions. Chile’s Antofagasta expects to hit the low end of its 2025 production target and provided a 2026 forecast below analyst expectations, signaling ongoing tightness in the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump reverses Biden-era copper smelter pollution limits to boost mineral security</title><link>https://www.financialexpress.com/world-news/us-news/trump-reverses-biden-era-copper-smelter-pollution-limits-to-boost-mineral-security/4021001/</link><description>The Trump administration has rolled back stricter emission limits on copper smelters, providing a two-year compliance exemption to support domestic production. The policy targets the two operational U.S. smelters, citing concerns over industrial base erosion and reliance on foreign processing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump reverses Biden-era rules on copper smelters</title><link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/trump-reverses-biden-copper-smelter-rules-10325538/</link><description>President Trump has revoked Biden-era pollution rules for copper smelters, offering a two-year exemption to the two remaining U.S. facilities. The administration framed the move as essential for maintaining mineral independence and reducing reliance on foreign copper processing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Products Market worth $645.86 billion by 2035 at 5.6%</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/24/3172837/0/en/Copper-Products-Market-worth-645-86-billion-by-2035-at-5-6-says-MarketsandMarkets.html</link><description>The copper products market is projected to grow significantly due to demand from construction, power, electronics, and industrial manufacturing sectors. Copper’s recyclability and durability make it a preferred material for sustainable urbanization, smart city development, and energy-efficient systems, reinforcing its role in green infrastructure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Cobalt And Nickel Mining Companies: 2026 Sustainable Trends</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/cobalt-and-nickel-mining-companies-2026-sustainable-trends</link><description>By 2026, over 60% of cobalt and nickel mining companies will adopt sustainable extraction methods for battery supply chains. Innovations include AI-driven environmental monitoring, blockchain traceability, and recycling to reduce dependence on virgin mining. These technologies support environmental management and supply security in the growing battery metals market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel and NetCarb Advance Strategic Partnership to Unlock Zero-Carbon Industrial Cluster in Northeastern Ontario</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/canada-nickel-and-netcarb-advance-strategic-partnership-to-unlock-zero-carbon-industrial-cluster-in-northeastern-ontario-302591367.html</link><description>Canada Nickel and NetCarb are progressing in developing a proprietary carbon sequestration process that could sequester up to ten times more CO2 than current methods while producing valuable by-products like hydrogen and magnesium. This technology aims to position the Timmins Nickel District as a decarbonization hub and create new economic opportunities through sustainable nickel mining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Re-energising the nickel industry through sustainable battery production</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/re-energising-nickel-industry-through-sustainable-battery-production/29252/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals is developing the TECH Project, a carbon-negative facility in Australia that will produce high-grade, ethically sourced nickel for batteries using the patented DNi Process™. This environmentally friendly process recycles 98% of nitric acid, requires no tailings dam, and minimizes waste, supporting sustainable nickel laterite ore processing for the EV and energy storage sectors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Mining Tech Revolution: Driving Faster Adoption in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/mining-technology-adoption-critical-mineral-demand-2025/</link><description>The mining sector is accelerating technology adoption to meet surging demand for critical minerals like nickel, driven by renewable energy growth and EV market expansion. Challenges include declining ore grades and rising operational costs, making advanced mining technologies essential to sustain supply and support the global energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Engineering the future: how Tubacex innovation is advancing connection technologies for critical energy applications through the DESSERT project</title><link>https://www.tubacex.com/en/engineering-the-future-how-tubacex-innovation-is-advancing-connection-technologies-for-critical-energy-applications-through-the-dessert-project/</link><description>Tubacex is innovating in premium connection technologies and hydrogen energy through the DESSERT project, supporting safer hydrogen storage and utilization as a sustainable energy resource. This initiative highlights the company's commitment to advancing sustainable energy solutions and the energy transition.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>CVA to construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily benefiting Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will benefit from enhanced energy performance and reduced environmental impact through a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA, which will build four photovoltaic plants in Sicily with over 20 MW capacity. This partnership supports the company's decarbonisation goals and economic competitiveness within the 2026–2029 Strategic Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of its green hydrogen production project at its Aosta plant, using a 1.008 MW electrolyzer to produce 165 tons of hydrogen annually. Supported by €7.9 million from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan, the project aims to reduce carbon emissions and power one of the plant's furnaces entirely with green hydrogen.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has commenced operations at a pilot green hydrogen plant in Aosta, northern Italy, marking a significant step in its sustainability and decarbonisation efforts within the steel production sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hovers Near $11000 as Market Tightness Intensifies</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/supply-disruptions-copper-market-2025/</link><description>Copper futures reached $10,962.50 per metric ton in recent London trading, marking a 25% gain year-to-date amid supply-demand imbalances rather than speculative trading. Strong Chinese manufacturing and renewable energy investments underpin sustained copper demand, while geopolitical trade policies continue to influence market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[Copper Inventory] On October 25th, LME copper inventory decreased by 1,550 tonnes to 276,775 tonnes</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103008947/LME-Metal-Inventories-Update-on-October-25th</link><description>The London Metal Exchange reported a decrease in copper inventory by 1,550 tonnes on October 25, 2025, lowering total stocks to 276,775 tonnes, indicating tightening supply conditions in the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hovers Near $11000 as Market Tightness Intensifies</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/supply-disruptions-copper-market-2025/</link><description>Copper futures are trading near $10,962.50 per ton, up about 25% year-to-date, as supply-demand imbalances drive prices toward record levels. Strong Chinese industrial demand, especially in renewable energy and electric vehicles, continues to support the market amid global supply disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Reverses Biden Copper Smelter Rules in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/trump-copper-smelter-policy-reversal-2025/</link><description>President Trump has reversed Biden-era emission standards for copper smelters, granting a two-year exemption to the two remaining U.S. facilities. The move aims to bolster domestic mineral security by reducing regulatory burdens on the already limited U.S. copper smelting industry.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME nickel prices rise on Oct 25 due to bullish news</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-prices-rise-on-oct-25-due-to-bullish-news/144361</link><description>LME nickel futures increased by US$43 on October 25, closing at US$18,317 per ton, while the spot price also rose by US$43 to US$18,085 per ton, reflecting bullish market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell slightly to 15,325 USD/T on October 24, down 0.07% from the previous day. Despite a 0.56% rise over the past month, prices remain 5.07% lower than a year ago, with forecasts suggesting a decline to around 14,206 USD/MT in the next 12 months due to oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>PP Presisi secures Rp150 billion contract for Antam nickel project</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/pp-presisi-secures-rp150-billion-contract-for-antam-nickel-project</link><description>PT PP Presisi Tbk has secured a contract worth Rp150 billion for an Antam nickel project, strengthening its presence in Indonesia's mining sector. The deal highlights the ongoing development of nickel projects in the region. Further details about the project's scope and timeline are not provided.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Axpo Italia to supply green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill</title><link>https://yieh.com/ru/NewsItem/150822</link><description>Axpo Italia has signed a Power Purchase Agreement (PPA) to supply 15 GWh of green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill in Italy. This agreement supports Tenaris's efforts to reduce its carbon footprint.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Future Minerals Forum 2025: Transforming Global Mining Partnerships</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/global-minerals-summit-2025-strategic-importance/</link><description>The forum highlights the critical role of nickel and other minerals in the energy transition and addresses supply chain vulnerabilities such as geographic concentration and processing capacity limitations. It emphasizes the need for innovation and sustainability initiatives to meet projected demand and secure supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>