<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 05:24:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GT reassesses Finnish nickel-PGM project</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/16/northern-neighbors/gt-reassesses-finnish-nickel-pgm-project/9490.html</link><description>GT Resources is reassessing its Kaukua nickel-PGM project in Finland by analyzing over 4,600 historic pulps and 500 infill samples to standardize data. The program aims to update resource estimates ahead of potential development.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 3,140.70 USD/T on January 16, 2026, down 0.93% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 8.21%, and are up 17.10% compared to the same time last year. The price reflects trading on a contract for difference tracking the benchmark market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 3,140.70 USD/T on January 16, 2026, amid tightening supply and production disruptions. China is curbing overcapacity, set to breach its 45 million ton output cap, while new smelters in Indonesia face setbacks. Operations at smelters in Iceland, Mozambique, and Australia are suspended due to high energy costs, equipment failures, bauxite sourcing issues, and geopolitical risks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AMU: Labor agreement timelines converge in US aluminum</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/16/labor-contracts-unions-aluminum-2026-trade-prices/</link><description>Multiple collective bargaining agreements at U.S. aluminum producers are expiring or entering negotiations in 2026, potentially impacting operations. This convergence occurs amid trade protections, high aluminum prices, elevated Midwest premiums, and uneven demand. Facilities like Constellium’s Muscle Shoals and Ravenswood are approaching key bargaining phases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel traded flat at around 3,138-3,141 CNY/T on January 16, 2026, marking a slight 0.10% increase from the previous day. Over the past month, prices rose 1.65-1.75%, though they remain 5.68-5.77% lower than a year ago. Steel rebar futures gained on hopes of China stimulus, reaching CNY 3,130 per tonne amid discussions on fiscal measures to boost demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US-based Worthington Steel to acquire Klöckner &amp; Co for $2.4 billion</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Worthington Steel announced plans to acquire Klöckner &amp; Co for $2.4 billion, potentially impacting steel production and distribution capacities. This deal highlights consolidation trends in the global steel sector. Further details on production implications are emerging.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ferrexpo reduced production by 9% y/y in 2025</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Ukrainian producer Ferrexpo reported a 9% year-on-year decline in production for 2025, affecting steel-related output. This reduction comes amid ongoing market challenges. The news was published in the context of recent steel market updates.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Nederland Opens New Production Line for Sustainable Food Packaging</title><link>https://www.tatasteel.com/newsroom/press-releases/india/2026/tata-steel-nederland-opens-new-production-line-for-sustainable-food-packaging/</link><description>Tata Steel Nederland has commissioned a new production line using innovative TCCT (Trivalent Chromium Coating Technology) for more sustainable packaging steel production, complying with future legislation. This patented technology, combined with Protact®, enhances food safety, reduces costs by eliminating extra lacquer layers, and simplifies supply chains. It sets a new European standard for eco-friendly steel packaging.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 1.14% Lower at $5.7885 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601165062/comex-copper-ends-the-week-114-lower-at-57885-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for January delivery fell 6.70 cents per pound, or 1.14%, to $5.7885 over the week, down two of the past three weeks. It declined 15.95 cents or 2.68% on the day, marking the largest one-day drop since January 7, 2026. Year-to-date, it is up 2.82%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper fell to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 16, down 3.40% from the previous day, amid reports of drops due to China curbing high-frequency trading and retreating from record highs. Over the past month, prices rose 7.88%, and year-over-year up 33.95%. Historically, it reached an all-time high of 6.11 USD/Lbs in January 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper theft ticks up as prices surge</title><link>https://www.foxbusiness.com/video/6387831862112</link><description>Copper thefts are increasing as prices surge, highlighting secondary market impacts of rising copper values. The video discusses trends in theft related to high commodity prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 17,825 USD/T on January 16, 2026, down 4.14% from the previous day, though up 24.09% over the past month. A later update shows prices at 17,566.63 USD/T, down 5.53% daily but up 22.29% monthly and 9.25% year-over-year. This reflects ongoing volatility amid broader market trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Extends Drop Amid Lack of Detail on Indonesia Output Cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-extends-drop-amid-lack-of-detail-on-indonesia-output-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices settled 4.1% lower at $17,155 per ton on the LME, extending declines from a 19-month high due to absent details on Indonesia's output cuts. Three-month futures dropped as much as 5.9% after peaking at $18,800 per ton. The pullback follows a rally driven by supply concerns from the top producer.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Arca &amp; Giga Metals To Explore CDR At Nickel Mine In Canada</title><link>https://carbonherald.com/arca-giga-metals-to-explore-cdr-at-nickel-mine-in-canada/</link><description>Arca Climate Technologies has a 10-year exclusive agreement to assess carbon dioxide removal potential at Giga Metals' Turnagain nickel project using ultramafic waste. The technology accelerates CO2 mineralization, targeting 220 million tonnes of removal, and builds on a decade of collaboration for ESG-enhanced nickel production. This aligns with Canada's critical minerals priorities and demonstrates innovative mining with societal benefits.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper's Bellwether: A Deep-Dive into Freeport-McMoRan (FCX)</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/finterra-2026-1-16-coppers-bellwether-a-deep-dive-into-freeport-mcmoran-fcx</link><description>This article examines Freeport-McMoRan's innovations in copper extraction, particularly its proprietary leaching technology that recovers copper from low-grade waste rock at costs under $1.00/lb, currently producing 300 million pounds annually. The company plans to double this output by 2028, effectively creating a major new mine without traditional environmental or capital costs. It also highlights FCX's newly completed $3.7 billion Manyar Smelter in Indonesia for downstream processing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 17.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel exchanges, showing Shanghai Futures rebar prices flat at 0.00 change on January 16, 2026, for 1-3 month terms. Other futures like Turkey, China, Europe, and North America 1-month terms also held steady as of January 15, 2026. The platform highlights ongoing price monitoring amid global market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper hits one-week low on profit-taking and China demand concerns</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-one-week-low-on-profit-taking-and-china-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices hit a one-week low on Friday due to profit-taking after a rally driven by speculative funds. Physical demand from buyers in China remained muted. This reflects recent market volatility in the commodity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Amazon to be first user of copper made by Rio Tinto venture</title><link>https://www.mining.com/amazon-to-be-first-user-of-copper-made-by-rio-tinto-venture/</link><description>Amazon Web Services will be the first to use copper produced at an Arizona mine using Nuton's bioleaching technology, which uses microorganisms to extract copper from sulfide ores. The technology reduces water usage by up to 80% and carbon emissions by as much as 60% compared to traditional copper production, while achieving recovery rates of up to 85%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Battery-Grade Nickel Sulphate Prices Rise on January 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103143543/smm-battery-grade-nickel-sulphate-prices-rise-on-january-17</link><description>On January 17, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price reached 26,516 yuan/mt. Quotations for battery-grade nickel sulphate showed an upward trend. This indicates rising prices in nickel derivatives amid recent market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Live Nickel Prices Today</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-prices-today/</link><description>Nickel prices retreated on January 17, 2026, as markets reassessed Indonesia's proposed output cuts. This follows recent volatility in the nickel market. The analysis highlights ongoing price adjustments amid supply uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Squeeze Intensifies as Indonesia Restricts Exports and Canada Accelerates Projects</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-supply-squeeze-intensifies-as-indonesia-restricts-exports-and-canada-accelerates-projects</link><description>Nickel prices surged to $18,650 following Indonesian supply restrictions confirmed by Vale's mining halt. Canada Nickel's Crawford project received Ontario's fast-track approval as a strategic alternative, while the Reid deposit resource increased 46% to 5 million tonnes of contained nickel with superior economics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia's ESDM confirms plan to reduce nickel production to 250-260 million tonnes for 2026</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5110162-flash-indonesias-esdm-confirms-plan-to-reduce-nickel-production-to-250-260-million-tonnes-for-2026</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources confirmed a nickel production target of 250-260 million tonnes for 2026, down from 379 million tonnes in 2025. The quota reduction aims to align with domestic processing capacity and support nickel prices, with global prices surging to $18,000/tonne following the announcement.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Can nickel prices hit $25,000 in 2026?</title><link>https://theoregongroup.substack.com/p/can-nickel-prices-hit-25000-in-2026</link><description>Nickel prices jumped to $16,500–$18,500 per ton in early January 2026, with Indonesia shifting from maximizing supply to maximizing value through production cuts. Only 55% of Indonesia's approved nickel ore production capacity was actually utilized in 2025, suggesting much of the supposed surplus was statistical illusion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Highlights Relevance of Pipestone XL Awaruite Nickel-Cobalt Alloy Discovery to Address U.S. Critical Mineral Supply Chain Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/280485/First-Atlantic-Nickel-Highlights-Relevance-of-Pipestone-XL-Awaruite-NickelCobalt-Alloy-Discovery-to-Address-U.S.-Critical-Mineral-Supply-Chain-Vulnerabilities-Identified-in-January-14-2026-White-House-Proclamation</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel announced preliminary metallurgical testing results for its Pipestone XL project, with magnetic concentrate averaging 1.3% nickel that can be upgraded to approximately 60% through flotation. The project also identified chromium as a potential recoverable mineral, addressing North America's lack of sufficient mined chromium concentrates.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Uranium and copper explode out of the blocks in early 2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1jQh6Xy-dX4</link><description>Both uranium and copper prices have exploded upward in the first weeks of 2026 due to positive supply-demand dynamics, with expectations of continued upward movement throughout the year. The video provides a weekly market update on January 17, highlighting strong performances in related ETFs and stocks.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 0.2 percent - week 2, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-02-percent-week-2-2026-1430700.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending January 17, 2026, was 1.756 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 75.9%, up 0.2% from the previous week. Year-to-date production through January 17, 2026, was 4.238 million net tons, representing a 2.9% increase from the same period last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices held flat at $17,806.3/ton over the weekend, consolidating recent volatility</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-prices-today/</link><description>Nickel prices remained stable over the weekend at $17,806.3 per ton as the market consolidated recent volatility. The market continues to monitor supply dynamics and geopolitical factors affecting price movements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Battery Metals: The Strategic Investment Case for 2026</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/battery-metals-the-strategic-investment-case-for-2026</link><description>Global nickel demand is forecast to grow over 7% annually and double to 5-6 million tonnes by 2030, driven by electric vehicle battery production. Canada Nickel's Crawford project and other Western projects are pursuing innovative approaches including carbon sequestration and net-zero nickel production to secure financing in a supply-constrained market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Top Power Press Manufacturers Navigate a Transforming Global Metalforming Market</title><link>https://natlawreview.com/press-releases/top-power-press-manufacturers-navigate-transforming-global-metalforming</link><description>Power press manufacturers are responding to tightening environmental regulations and market demands by developing equipment with improved hydraulic efficiency, reduced energy consumption, and enhanced safety systems. Innovation now focuses on sustainability through energy recovery technologies, digital twins for optimization, and intelligent design principles that reduce operating costs while meeting stricter emissions standards.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>China Aluminum Output at Record, Steel Below 1 Billion Tons</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/china-aluminum-output-at-record-steel-below-1-billion-tons/</link><description>China's aluminum output reached a record high, contrasting with steel production falling below 1 billion tons. Aluminum prices are set to benefit from this supply-demand mismatch.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CICC Expects Aluminum Prices to Continue Hitting New Highs</title><link>https://www.aastocks.com/en/usq/news/comment.aspx?id=NOW.1497023&amp;catg=4</link><description>CICC predicts aluminum prices will keep reaching new highs due to widening supply-demand gaps and supportive global fiscal policies. Low costs are expected to widen profits per ton as prices rise.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China's aluminium output hits record, steel below one billion tonnes</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/chinas-aluminium-output-hits-record-steel-below-one-billion-tonnes</link><description>China's aluminum production rose 2.4% to a record 45 million tonnes in 2025, with December output hitting 3.9 million tonnes. The government maintains a 45-million-tonne capacity cap since 2017 to curb oversupply and emissions, though forecasts predict slight capacity increases. This supports higher aluminum prices amid rising demand and supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China Aluminum Output at Record, Steel Below 1 Billion Tons</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/china-aluminum-output-at-record-steel-below-1-billion-tons/</link><description>China's aluminum output reached a record 45.02 million tons in 2025, up 2.4% from the previous year, marking annual increases throughout the decade. This contrasts with steel production falling below one billion tonnes. The data comes from the national statistics bureau.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China economy stumbles in Q4 with 4.5% growth as aluminum and coal outputs hit record</title><link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/china-economy-stumbles-in-q4-with-4-5-growth/</link><description>China's economy grew 4.5% in Q4 amid record aluminum and coal outputs, highlighting production strength despite slower overall growth. Aluminum production hit new highs, contributing to industrial output. This occurs as the economy faces broader challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Top Power Press Manufacturers Navigate a Transforming Global Metalforming Market</title><link>https://www.einpresswire.com/article/884407979/top-power-press-manufacturers-navigate-a-transforming-global-metalforming-market</link><description>Leading power press manufacturers are adapting to industry shifts by integrating automation, energy efficiency, and digital tools while addressing stricter environmental regulations on emissions and energy use. Innovations include optimized hydraulic systems for reduced oil usage, energy recovery technologies, and safety features like light curtains. These sustainable advancements lower operating costs and support eco-friendly metalforming for applications like automotive and aerospace components.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel prices today, January 19th: Global market shows strong divergence, domestic prices remain stable</title><link>https://baonghean.vn/en/gia-thep-hom-nay-191-thi-truong-the-gioi-phan-hoa-manh-gia-trong-nuoc-giu-on-dinh-10320645.html</link><description>Global steel markets exhibit strong divergence on January 19, while domestic prices in Vietnam remain stable. The article highlights varying trends across international regions amid ongoing market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Aluminum Output at Record, Steel Below 1 Billion Tons</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/china-aluminum-output-at-record-steel-below-1-billion-tons/</link><description>China's steel output is projected to stay below 1 billion tons, contrasting with record aluminum production. This mismatch is expected to support aluminum prices while influencing steel market trends.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Industrial Leads for the Week of January 19, 2026</title><link>https://www.enr.com/articles/62375-industrial-leads-for-the-week-of-january-19-2026</link><description>United States Steel Corp. plans to upgrade the hot strip mill at its Gary Works steel mill in Gary, Indiana. The project involves purchasing equipment to enhance production capacity at the facility.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>From Silver to Copper: How Solar Giants Are Innovating to Cut Costs and Boost Efficiency</title><link>https://now.solar/2026/01/19/from-silver-to-copper-how-solar-giants-are-innovating-to-cut-costs-and-boost-efficiency-investing-news-network/</link><description>Amid a 200% surge in silver prices, solar industry leaders are innovating by shifting to copper as a cost-effective alternative to reduce expenses and improve efficiency. This transition addresses rising material costs in photovoltaic production. The move supports sustainability by leveraging copper's availability for scaling solar technology.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review - Nickel prices adjusted and pulled back on January 19</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103726430/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-adjusted-and-pulled-back-on-january-19-while-chinas-gdp-grew-5-yoy-in-2025</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices fell to an average of 145,900 yuan/mt, down 3,450 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. The SHFE nickel futures contract pulled back sharply before rebounding, closing at 142,060 yuan/mt, down 1.6%. The market remains caught between expectations for Indonesian production cuts and the reality of high inventory and weak demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries posts Q4 earnings and lifts outlook</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/19/nickel-industries-posts-q4-earnings-and-lifts-outlook/</link><description>Nickel Industries Ltd reported December quarter adjusted EBITDA of US$35–40 million, impacted by delays in securing an increased RKAB permit for its Hengjaya Mine, leading to sharply reduced ore sales. The HNC HPAL operation achieved record quarterly earnings, and operations resumed in mid-December with strong early 2026 sales of 735,000 wmt of nickel ore by January 17. The company anticipates growth from the upcoming Excelsior Nickel Cobalt project to boost nickel production for electric vehicle batteries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Plunges from Over 2-Year High - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/515604</link><description>Nickel futures dropped to $17,100 per tonne from a two-year high of $18,875 due to reconsidered output cuts by Indonesia, which proposed a 34% reduction in 2026 nickel output amid oversupply concerns and deteriorating ore grades. Expected 2026 ore quotas of 250-260 million tonnes fall below smelter demand and last year's 379 million tonnes. Despite surpluses, demand from electric vehicles offsets weaker stainless steel usage.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries expecting strong 2026</title><link>https://www.miningnews.net/miners/news-analysis/4525811/nickel-industries-expecting-strong-2026</link><description>Nickel Industries missed approximately A$67 million in December quarter earnings due to Indonesian authorities' delay in approving a new sales quota. Despite this, the company reports a strong start to 2026 operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Flags Lower Quarterly EBITDA After RKAB Delay, But Hengjaya Mine Rebounds in Early 2026</title><link>https://www.tipranks.com/news/company-announcements/nickel-industries-flags-lower-quarterly-ebitda-after-rkab-delay-but-hengjaya-mine-rebounds-in-early-2026</link><description>Nickel Industries expects December quarter adjusted EBITDA of US$35–40 million, reduced by RKAB permit delays causing a plunge in Hengjaya Mine ore sales. The mine has rebounded with strong performance in early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The first Energy Release contract in the Aosta Valley is underway: agreement signed between the CVA Group and Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>CVA will construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily with over 20 MW capacity, expected to produce 593,600 MWh annually and be fully operational by 2026. This marks the first Energy Release agreement in the Aosta Valley and supports Cogne Acciai Speciali's green energy transition and reduced environmental impact. The partnership strengthens both companies' roles in decarbonization and aligns with the Regional Energy and Environmental Plan (PEAR VDA 2030) and European Green Deal.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italian steelmaker Cogne Acciai Speciali sourcing all energy from renewables</title><link>https://eurometal.net/italian-steelmaker-cogne-acciai-speciali-sourcing-all-energy-from-renewables/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is now sourcing all power needs in Europe from renewable energy and plans to build a 1-MW electrolyzer and hydroelectric plant by June 2026 at its main Italian site in Aosta. The electrolyzer will produce 210 normal cubic meters of hydrogen per hour, powered by renewable sources, as part of Italy's National Recovery and Resilience Plan funded by the European Union through NextGenerationEU.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali uses 100% renewable electricity in Europe</title><link>https://www.stainless.club/industry-news/read/cogne-acciai-speciali-uses-100-renewable-electricity-in-europe.html</link><description>Since January 2024, all electricity supplied to Cogne Acciai Speciali's European production plants has come from renewable sources. The Italian stainless steel longs producer has completed its transition to environmentally sustainable production across the EU.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has launched a green hydrogen pilot plant as part of the 'Green Hydrogen in Cogne' initiative, marking the first project to replace fossil natural gas with green hydrogen in an industrial heat treatment application.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Capital Flood Reshapes Aluminum's Price Logic: Between Belief and Doubt</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29819.html</link><description>China's electrolytic aluminum capacity reached 44.83 million tons by end-2025, hitting the regulatory ceiling and accounting for over 57% of global capacity, with output at 44.23 million tons. A production cut at Century Aluminum's Iceland smelter triggered global supply shocks and price surges. China's centralized capacity provides strong supply regulation power in the industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>BHP Upgrades Copper Output Guidance; Raises Cost of Potash Project (2nd Update)</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601194210/bhp-upgrades-copper-output-guidance-raises-cost-of-potash-project-again-2nd-update</link><description>BHP upgraded its fiscal year copper production guidance to 1.9-2.0 million metric tons, supported by strong performance at Escondida mine amid record-high prices from healthy demand and competitor supply disruptions. U.S. copper futures surged to all-time highs, with BHP noting a 29% jump in realized copper prices quarter-over-quarter. CEO highlights resilient Chinese demand and positive 2026 global growth outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Falls After China Restricts HF Trading</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK fell below $3,140 per tonne, retreating from an over three-year high hit on January 13th after China tightened restrictions on high-frequency trading. Chinese regulators ordered mainland exchanges to remove servers operated by high-frequency traders from their data centres. Over the past month, aluminum prices have risen 6.68%, up 18.38% from the same time last year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia says 2026 mining quota won't be enough to meet demand new</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2026-01-19/vale-indonesia-says-2026-mining-quota-wont-be-enough-meet-demand-new</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia's 2026 mining production quota is insufficient for smelter demand from new HPAL plants for EV batteries. The company resumed mining after quota approval delays and seeks additional quota. New plants in Pomalaa and Bahodopi require significant limonite nickel ore annually.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>January 20 SMM Cast Aluminum Alloy Morning Comment</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103727784</link><description>Aluminum prices continued to retreat on January 19, with SMM A00 spot aluminum closing at 23,870 yuan/mt, down 160 yuan/mt. The aluminum alloy 2603 futures contract closed at 22,910 yuan/mt, up slightly by 0.09%. Secondary aluminum alloy producers maintained stable offers amid firm costs, low inventory, and bullish expectations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum and copper prices take breather after explosive start to 2026</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-and-copper-prices-take-breather-after-explosive-start-to-2026/</link><description>Aluminum prices steadied at $3,197.50 a ton on the LME, the highest in more than three years, following an explosive start to 2026. Copper wavered around a record, while tin rose after rallying. Investors are assessing the next moves for metals amid recent volatility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China Aluminum Output Hits Record 45.02M Tons in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/china-energy-transition-aluminum-growth-2026/</link><description>China's aluminum production reached a record high of 45.02 million tonnes in 2025, exceeding the government's 45-million-ton cap. This surge highlights ongoing growth amid energy transition efforts. The output milestone underscores China's dominant role in global aluminum supply.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium's unifying approach to net-zero transformation</title><link>https://www.worldclimatefoundation.org/post/climate-nature-and-people-aluminium-s-unifying-approach-to-net-zero-transformation</link><description>The aluminum industry is advancing decarbonization through multiple innovations including ELYSIS zero-carbon smelting technology and CelestiAL solar-powered aluminum production by Emirates Global Aluminium. The sector is implementing a multi-faceted strategy combining clean energy investments with recycling revolution to achieve net-zero goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 937.08 USD/T on January 19, 2026, down 0.20% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 3.20% and are up 34.83% year-over-year. Data was last updated on January 20, 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel prices hiked again amid rising exports</title><link>https://tv.rediff.com/business/steel-prices-hiked-again-amid-rising-exports/367686</link><description>Steel prices in India were hiked again on Friday due to safeguard duties, rising exports, and higher input costs. Some mills increased hot-rolled coil (HRC) prices by 500-750 per tonne. HRC serves as a benchmark for flat steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Jan. 20</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20260120/40d7caee401e486c8f030ef3476e9c36/c.html</link><description>At 0200 GMT on Jan. 20, 2026, COMEX copper price stood at 5.82 USD, amid latest global metals updates including gold, iron ore, palladium, and platinum. Reflects current spot pricing in ongoing volatile market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP Boosts Copper Production Outlook for FY26</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/20/bhp-boosts-copper-production-outlook-for-fy26/</link><description>BHP has increased its fiscal year 2026 copper production guidance to between 1.9 and 2.0 million tonnes, driven by record throughput at the Escondida mine and strong asset performance. The company also reported gains in iron ore and coal production amid rising commodity prices. CEO Mike Henry highlighted strong operating momentum and a pathway to 2 million tonnes of copper production in the 2030s.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP lifts copper guidance after record half-year output</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/20/bhp-lifts-copper-guidance-after-record-half-year-output/</link><description>BHP upgraded its FY26 copper production guidance to 1,900–2,000 kt following record half-year output and strong performance at Escondida. Iron ore and coal production also rose, supported by higher prices including copper up 32%. Management emphasized a significant copper growth pipeline targeting around 2 Mt in the 2030s.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP Upgrades Copper Output Guidance; Raises Cost of Potash Project (Again) (2nd Update)</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601194210/bhp-upgrades-copper-output-guidance-raises-cost-of-potash-project-again-2nd-update</link><description>BHP Group raised its FY26 copper production guidance to 1.9-2.0 million metric tons, fueled by strong Escondida performance amid record-high copper prices. Second-quarter copper output was 490,500 tons, with first-half production flat year-over-year. Iron ore production increased, though prices face pressure from China negotiations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chile delays copper output peak, cuts short-term forecasts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/chile-delays-copper-output-peak-cuts-short-term-forecasts/</link><description>Chile, the world's largest copper producer, delayed its peak annual output goal above 6 million tons by several years and cut forecasts for 2026-2031 due to falling ore grades and mining plan adjustments. Production is expected to stabilize at current levels with gradual recovery toward the period's end. The revision was outlined in a Cochilco report.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On January 20, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103728813/</link><description>On January 20, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 140,900-151,800 yuan/mt, averaging 146,350 yuan/mt, up 450 yuan/mt from the previous day. This indicates a slight upward movement in Chinese refined nickel pricing amid ongoing market fluctuations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tariff Noise, Limited Signal</title><link>https://www.sucdenfinancial.com/en/market-insights/metals-outlook/daily-base-metals-analysis/2026-01-20/</link><description>Base metals, including nickel, recovered some of Friday's weakness on January 20, with expectations of transitioning into a rangebound phase in the near term. Dip-buying persisted, reflecting cautious market sentiment amid tariff discussions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>TECH Project high-grade nickel is primed to fuel the global green transition</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/tech-project-high-grade-nickel-is-primed-to-fuel-the-global-green-transition/32893/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals' TECH Project aims to become a leading source of high-grade, ethically derived nickel for EV batteries and green energy. The project features the DNi Process, an environmentally-friendly extraction method with 98% nitric acid recycling and no tailings dam requirements, positioning it as a carbon-negative production facility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel rose to 940 USD/T on January 20, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel increased to 940.09 USD/T, up 0.22% from the previous day. Over the past month, HRC Steel's price has risen 3.53%, and is up 36.05% compared to the same time last year. Trading Economics forecasts HRC Steel to trade at 956.97 USD/T by the end of Q1 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Final Thoughts - Steel Market Update</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/20/final-thoughts-1907/</link><description>Sheet steel prices climbed to new multi-month highs this week, with demand driven by data centers, energy transmission projects, and border fence construction. Extreme cold weather has reduced scrap flows, and the market has experienced a relatively calm start to 2026 without major price shocks.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AISI: Raw steel production rises 0.2%</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/20/aisi-raw-steel-production-rises-0-2/</link><description>US domestic mill production reached 1,756,000 short tons of raw steel in the week ending January 17, 2026, up 0.2% from the previous week and 3.3% higher than the same week last year. The mill capability utilization rate was 75.9%, with year-to-date production up 2.9% compared to the same period in 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises on Weaker Dollar</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures climbed above $5.9 per pound on Monday as the dollar weakened amid concerns over US President Donald Trump's tariff threats against European nations over Greenland. The market also assessed mixed economic signals from top consumer China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices rise amid mergers and strong demand forecasts</title><link>https://iol.co.za/business-report/economy/2026-01-20-copper-prices-rise-amid-mergers-and-strong-demand-forecasts/</link><description>Copper prices have rebounded as analysts predict strong demand, spurring merger activity in the mining sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Digital integration boosts safety, productivity, sustainability at Anglo American Barro Alto mine</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2026/01/20/digital-integration-boosts-safety-productivity-sustainability-at-anglo-american-barro-alto-mine/</link><description>Digital integration at Anglo American's Barro Alto mine, a nickel producer, enhances safety, productivity, and sustainability through advanced technologies. The project demonstrates how digitization supports responsible mining operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris resumes production lines at Koppel steel plant, plans to hire 80 workers</title><link>https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/tenaris-resumes-production-lines-koppel-steel-plant-plans-hire-80-workers/NO3STGZCOJG7ZENGDUBVAZ6PXM/</link><description>Tenaris is restarting heat treatment and finishing lines at its Koppel, Pennsylvania steel plant to increase production of steel pipe for the oil and gas industry, planning to hire 80 workers. The plant, acquired in 2020, had been idled during the Covid-19 pandemic but has seen $150 million in investments. Recent investments include $2 million for resuming these operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Produced More Copper, Slightly Less Iron Ore Last Year</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2026012010401/rio-tinto-produced-more-copper-slightly-less-iron-ore-last-year-update</link><description>Rio Tinto reported an 11% increase in copper output for 2025, producing 883,000 metric tons and surpassing its guidance forecast of 860,000-875,000 tons, with Q4 copper output at 240,000 tons, up 5% year-over-year. Growth was driven by rising production from the Oyu Tolgoi mine in Mongolia following its underground expansion.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tariff Talk, Safe-Haven Walk - Daily Base Metals Analysis</title><link>https://www.sucdenfinancial.com/en/market-insights/metals-outlook/daily-base-metals-analysis/2026-01-21/</link><description>Aluminium spreads eased back into contango, while the metal slipped below support at $3,110/t to settle near $3,099/t. This reflects ongoing market adjustments amid tariff discussions and safe-haven flows. Lead also breached key levels in the session.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>January 21, 2026, Jinshi Futures Morning Report: SHFE adjusts the ...</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/67659552/january-21-2026-jinshi-futures-morning-report-shfe-adjusts-the</link><description>China's primary aluminum production in December 2025 was estimated at 3.767 million tons, up from 3.646 million tons previously. Global primary aluminum output reached 6.296 million tons in December 2025. Rio Tinto reported 2025 aluminum production of 3.38 million tons, exceeding guidance.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Reviving Venezuela's Idle Aluminium Industry Challenges</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/venezuela-aluminum-resource-market-dynamics-2026/</link><description>The article discusses strategies and investment requirements to revive Venezuela's idle aluminum industry. It highlights challenges in restarting production capacity that has been dormant.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto copper output climbs as Oyu Tolgoi mine ramps up</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/node/789996</link><description>Rio Tinto Group's copper production climbed 5% in the fourth quarter driven by the expansion of underground operations at the Oyu Tolgoi mine. The company achieved copper equivalent production growth of 8% year-over-year in 2025, with shipments up 5%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto reports record iron ore quarter and soaring copper production</title><link>https://www.marketindex.com.au/news/rio-tinto-reports-record-iron-ore-quarter-and-soaring-copper-production</link><description>Rio Tinto exceeded Q4 production estimates with record copper output up 11%, while the Pilbara iron ore operation hit a quarterly record. The company demonstrated operational excellence across multiple commodity segments despite market pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Pulled Back on January 21, Fiscal Expenditure in 2026 to Increase Overall</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103731053/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-pulled-back-on-january-21-fiscal-expenditure-in-2026-to-increase-overall</link><description>On January 21, SMM #1 refined nickel prices ranged from 139,800-150,000 yuan/mt, averaging 144,900 yuan/mt, down 1,450 yuan/mt from the previous day. The SHFE nickel contract (2602) closed the morning session at 140,850 yuan/mt, down 1.16%, amid battles between Indonesian policy expectations and high inventory realities. Nickel prices may hover at highs if supply cut expectations persist.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Pulled Back on January 21</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103731053/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-pulled-back-on-january-21-fiscal-expenditure-in-2026-to-increase-overall</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices averaged 144,900 yuan/mt on January 21, down 1,450 yuan/mt amid high inventory and weak demand. The market balances expectations for Indonesian production cuts against current realities. SHFE nickel futures closed the morning session at 140,850 yuan/mt, down 1.16%.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Retreat From Recent Highs</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/517935</link><description>Nickel futures fell toward $18,000 per tonne after hitting $18,700, with Indonesia cutting 2026 nickel ore quotas by 34% to align with processing capacity. Chinese spot prices dropped amid profit-taking and soft demand, while SHFE futures declined 1.6%. Nickel Industries reported lower ore sales but resumed shipments in early January.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>MacroAsia unit's Palawan nickel project gets MGB clearance</title><link>https://business.inquirer.net/569726/macroasia-units-palawan-nickel-project-gets-mgb-clearance</link><description>MacroAsia Mining Corp. received approval for its Infanta nickel project in Palawan, planning to invest 12 million for extraction across 1,113 hectares. The project falls under Production Sharing No.220-5-IVB in Brooke's Point. The company anticipates nickel market recovery to enable full commercial production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Three Main Factors Drove the Strong Performance of Aluminum Prices in January</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29923.html</link><description>Aluminum prices rose 6.3% in January 2026, driven by rigid supply constraints, structural demand growth, and macroeconomic factors combined with low inventory levels. The market has experienced a slight recent decline after reaching highs on January 14th, but medium-to-long term outlook remains supported by supply and demand fundamentals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SunSirs: Three Main Factors Drove the Strong Performance of Aluminum Prices in January</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29923.html</link><description>Aluminum prices in East China rose 6.3% in January 2026 to 23,890 RMB/ton as of January 19, driven by supply constraints. China's 45 million ton capacity limit and rising molten aluminum proportion limit ingot supply, while overseas disruptions like Mozal's shutdown and Century Aluminium reductions create a global supply gap of 290,000 to 840,000 tons.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME copper prices rose ~0.4% as tight inventories</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103733527</link><description>LME copper prices rose about 0.4% due to tight inventories. Shanghai transaction prices averaged 99,830 yuan/mt, down slightly by 20 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Live Aluminum Prices Today</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-today/</link><description>Aluminum edged higher as intensifying supply risks offset a pause in downstream buying, with physical tightness continuing to support prices. The article provides current pricing analysis and explains aluminum's role as a critical energy metal classified by the U.S. Government in 2022.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>2026 Global Outlook for New Alumina Supply</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103732427/2026-global-outlook-for-new-alumina-supply</link><description>China's alumina capacity is expected to reach 118.92 million mt in 2026 with 8.6 million mt of new capacity, intensifying oversupply. Much of the new capacity in Guangxi will shift local supply from tight to surplus, pressuring prices. Overseas, Indonesia and India will add 1 million mt and 500,000 mt respectively, heightening global competition.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Unilever, Ball and Alcoa unveil “first” carbon-free aluminum aerosol can</title><link>https://www.packaginginsights.com/news/carbon-free-aluminum-aerosol-can.html</link><description>Ball Corporation, Unilever, and Alcoa have debuted the first aerosol can made with Elysis carbon-free smelting technology, combining 50% Elysis aluminum and 50% recycled content to eliminate direct GHG emissions from smelting. The innovation targets personal care products like deodorants and cleaning items, supporting decarbonization in aluminum packaging. Elysis, a partnership of Alcoa and Rio Tinto backed by Apple and governments, produces oxygen instead of CO2 during smelting.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 22.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, indices, and news. It covers Shanghai Futures for rebar across multiple terms and future contracts for regions including Turkey, China, Europe, and North America, with recent data from January 19-20, 2026. The platform includes sections for latest news on rebar, scrap, and iron-steel markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Loses Momentum After 62% Rally: Flat 2026 Performance Raises Questions</title><link>https://scanx.trade/stock-market-news/commodities/copper-loses-momentum-after-62-rally-flat-2026-performance-raises-questions/30449309</link><description>Domestic copper prices in India fell nearly 1% to ₹1,288.90/kg on Tuesday amid mixed global trends, with MCX January contracts at ₹1,292.10, down ₹10. After a 62% rally in 2025, copper shows flat performance in 2026 due to profit booking, though fundamentals remain supportive with support levels at ₹1,230-₹1,250.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 22, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 22, 2026, up 0.43% from the previous day, with a 5.23% monthly gain. On January 21, prices fell to 5.80 USD/Lbs amid demand concerns in China, where the Yangshan import premium halved.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Q4 Production Increases, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103732269/rio-tinto-q4-production-increases-lme-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-lower-overnight-smm-copper-morning-meeting-minutes</link><description>Rio Tinto reported Q4 2025 attributable copper production of 240,000 mt, up 5% year-over-year and 18% quarter-over-quarter, with full-year 2025 production reaching 883,000 mt, an 11% cumulative increase. LME copper futures opened at $12,915.5/mt and closed at $12,761.5/mt, down 0.27%, with trading volume at 89,000 lots.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>More PV Manufacturers Expected to Adopt Copper Metallization in 2026</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-india.com/2026/01/22/more-pv-manufacturers-expected-to-adopt-copper-metallization-in-2026/</link><description>2026 is expected to mark the first year of large-scale mass production for high-copper paste solutions in photovoltaic manufacturing, driven by surging silver prices and sustainability concerns. Gigawatt-scale TOPCon customers and Tier-1 cell manufacturers are accelerating adoption of copper metallization to reduce silver consumption while maintaining conversion efficiency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining Announces 2025 Production Results and 2026 Guidance</title><link>https://www.inderes.fi/releases/lundin-mining-corporation-lundin-mining-announces-2025-production-results-and-2026-guidance</link><description>Lundin Mining forecasts copper production to remain stable at approximately 310,000 to 335,000 tonnes annually in 2026, consistent with 2025 production levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Strike Zone Mining Podcast for January 22 2026</title><link>https://www.netnewsledger.com/2026/01/21/strike-zone-mining-podcast-for-january-22-2026/</link><description>Ontario fast-tracks Canada Nickel's Crawford Nickel Project under the 'One Project, One Process' framework. The project near Timmins is positioned for batteries and green steel with plans for mining, processing, and downstream facilities. This accelerates development amid growing demand for electrification metals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>inaugurazione dell'opera "Per aspera ad astra" di Donato Savin</title><link>https://www.grand-paradis.it/en/news/2026/22-gennaio-2026-inaugurazione-dell%E2%80%99opera-aspera-ad-astra-di-donato-savin</link><description>An artwork titled "Per aspera ad astra" by Donato Savin will be inaugurated on January 22, 2026 at Cogne Acciai Speciali's headquarters in Aosta (Via Paravera 16). This event marks a cultural initiative at the company's main facility.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Tenaris posts 2% rise in quarterly net sales</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/italy-s-tenaris-posts-2-rise-in-quarterly-net-sales-ce7d5dd2de8cf321</link><description>Italian steel pipe maker Tenaris reported a 2% increase in net sales for the third quarter, driven by higher sales across its operations. As the world's leading producer of steel pipes for oil and gas industries, Tenaris generates 95.4% of revenue from pipe production with geographic distribution across North America (45.6%), Asia/Pacific/Middle East/Africa (25.5%), Europe (9.6%), and South America (19.3%).</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired isOplus's oil and gas division for $10 million, gaining pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coating capabilities rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy. The acquisition strengthens Tenaris's offshore market offerings and enables anti-corrosion coating application across facilities in Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>