<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:15:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nornickel expects global nickel market surplus in 2025-2026</title><link>https://tass.com/economy/2058767</link><description>Nornickel forecasts a global nickel market surplus exceeding 200,000 tons in both 2025 and 2026, driven by production growth to 3.86 million tons in 2025 and 4.1 million tons in 2026, outpacing demand growth to 3.62 million and 3.83 million tons respectively. Over 66% of output will come from Indonesia, despite recent government measures to curb excess supply. The company notes that only Indonesia's production restraint can balance the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Gov. Beshear: AKFA Aluminum Solutions To Establish New Manufacturing Operation in Bowling Green, Creating 331 Quality Jobs</title><link>https://lexingtonky.news/2025/12/15/gov-beshear-akfa-aluminum-solutions-to-establish-new-manufacturing-operation-in-bowling-green-creating-331-quality-jobs/</link><description>AKFA Aluminum Solutions is establishing a new manufacturing operation in Bowling Green, Kentucky, creating 331 quality jobs. This development supports aluminum production expansion potentially tied to innovative and sustainable practices. Governor Beshear announced the project as a boost to the local economy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>High aluminium prices to lift Press Metal earnings</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/16/high-aluminium-prices-to-lift-press-metal-earnings</link><description>High aluminum prices are set to drive record profits for Press Metal amid foreign expansions and resilient market conditions. London Metal Exchange prices have strengthened to US$2,800 per tonne, the highest since 2022, supported by supply tightness, while low alumina costs provide a margin tailwind. HLIB Research raised earnings forecasts, maintained a 'buy' rating, and expects continued aluminum deficits into 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 16.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar prices listed as flat at 0.00 change on December 15, 2025. Various futures contracts for rebar and other steel products across regions like Turkey, China, Europe, and North America are tracked. The platform offers analyses and comments on industry trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673677/SMM:-High-Grade-NPI-Price-Falls-in-Dec-16-Sentiment-Dips</link><description>The SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI fell to 886.5 yuan/nickel unit (ex-factory, tax included) on December 16. Sentiment in the nickel pig iron market dipped amid price declines. This reflects ongoing trends in ferrous metals pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>China, S Korea companies investigated for dumping</title><link>https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/biz/archives/2025/12/16/2003848943</link><description>Taiwan's Ministry of Finance launched anti-dumping investigations into cold-rolled, flat-rolled non-oriented electrical steel products from China and South Korea. The probe, prompted by China Steel Corp, targets companies like POSCO, Baoshan Iron &amp; Steel, and others amid rising imports harming local industry since 2023. This follows existing duties on stainless steel from the same countries.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper fell to 5.28 USD/Lbs on December 16, 2025, down 0.93% from the previous day, amid weak Chinese economic data including slowing industrial output and declining home prices. Despite this, prices rose to 5.34 USD/Lbs on December 15, up 1.14%, with monthly gains of 7.35%. Futures hovered around $5.3 per pound, pressured by soft demand in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Supply Shortages Coupled with the Federal Reserve's Interest Rate Cuts Pushed Copper Prices to a 15-Year High</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28829.html</link><description>Copper prices rose sharply last week to 93,903.33 RMB/ton as of December 12, a 15-year high, driven by global supply shortages from mine disruptions and a 'pull effect' into the US market. The Federal Reserve's interest rate cuts amplified bullish sentiment. Forecasts predict LME copper above $11,000 per ton in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/16/copper-prices-rise-on-supply-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices increased due to potential supply constraints in 2026, with strong demand from Chinese EV and energy sectors offsetting weak economic data like slower retail sales and industrial output. US demand remains robust from AI investments and reduced trade tensions. Other base metals like nickel and zinc declined.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Korea Zinc to Build Integrated Smelter; LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103672447/Korea-Zinc-to-Build-Integrated-Smelter-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Korea Zinc plans to build an integrated smelter, while LME copper prices showed intraday volatility and closed higher on the reported session; the report also notes changes in Chinese spot premiums, secondary copper market activity, and inventory movements that could constrain upside for prices in the near term.[1] The article discusses supply-side selling driven by year-end funding and weaker demand from high prices, and reports recent LME and SHFE inventory figures that affect market balance.[1]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise on Supply Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/16/copper-prices-rise-on-supply-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices increased as markets focused on potential supply constraints for the coming year, with ANZ citing persistent disruptions and strong demand—particularly from Chinese imports tied to EVs and energy infrastructure—as supporting prices despite softer macro data from China.[3] The piece also notes weakness in other base metals and contextualizes copper strength with demand from the US (including AI-related investments).[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>World's largest copper mine drives Chile investment</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/16/worlds-largest-copper-mine-drives-chile-investment/</link><description>Coverage highlights Chile’s upgraded mining-investment outlook—driven largely by an expansion at BHP’s Escondida—boosting Cochilco’s estimate of mining investment through 2034 and underpinning expectations for future copper production capacity as Chile aims to capitalise on rising global demand.[5] The article links the Escondida expansion to broader investment in copper and lithium projects and cites forecasts of strong long-term copper demand growth.[5]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 16, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673145/</link><description>On December 16, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 111,700–117,800 yuan/mt, averaging 114,750 yuan/mt. This represents a decline of 2,650 yuan/mt from the previous day. The drop reflects ongoing market pressures in the refined nickel segment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI was 886.5 yuan/nickel unit</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103673677/SMM:-High-Grade-NPI-Price-Falls-in-Dec-16-Sentiment-Dips</link><description>On December 16, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI fell to 886.5 yuan/nickel unit (ex-factory, tax included). This decline indicates dipping sentiment in the high-grade nickel pig iron market. Prices reflect broader base metals trends amid supply abundance.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel sees continued nickel surplus and tightening copper supply</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nornickel-sees-continued-nickel-surplus-and-tightening-copper-supply</link><description>Global metals producer Nornickel anticipates ongoing nickel market surplus amid rapid supply expansion. The article highlights Nornickel's outlook on nickel dynamics alongside tightening copper supply. It references Indonesia's significant role in nickel production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Hyundai Steel and POSCO Accelerate $5.8 Billion U.S. Steel Mill Project in Louisiana</title><link>http://koreabizwire.com/hyundai-steel-and-posco-accelerate-5-8-billion-u-s-steel-mill-project-in-louisiana/340298</link><description>Hyundai Steel and POSCO are advancing a $5.8 billion electric arc furnace steel mill in Louisiana, targeting 2.7 million tons annual capacity by 2029 to supply Hyundai Motor Group's U.S. operations. The project integrates direct reduced iron production to cut carbon emissions by 70% and includes equity investments from Hyundai Steel (50%), POSCO (20%), and Hyundai Motor/Kia (15% each). Construction is expected to complete by 2028, financed through internal cash flow and borrowing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hyundai Steel and POSCO Accelerate $5.8 Billion U.S. Steel Mill Project in Louisiana</title><link>http://koreabizwire.com/hyundai-steel-and-posco-accelerate-5-8-billion-u-s-steel-mill-project-in-louisiana/340298</link><description>Hyundai Steel and POSCO are advancing a $5.8 billion electric arc furnace (EAF) steel mill in Louisiana, targeting 2.7 million tons of annual production by 2029 to supply Hyundai Motor Group's U.S. operations. The project integrates direct reduced iron (DRI) with EAF, using DRI and steel scrap to cut carbon emissions by about 70% compared to traditional blast furnaces. This supports low-carbon steel production while addressing U.S. market demands and trade policies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>America's copper grab is powering a record surge in prices</title><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/copper-price-forecast-outlook-us-stockpiling-global-supply-surplus-ai-2025-12</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper hit a record high of $11,952 per metric ton on the London Metal Exchange on Friday, now trading around $11,655, up 33% this year. US stockpiling ahead of potential tariffs is tightening global supplies, despite an expected 300,000-ton surplus next year. Production disruptions in Indonesia, Congo, and Chile, plus speculative AI-related bets, are driving premiums and vulnerability to reversals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper eases in cautious trade ahead of US data</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40397812</link><description>Copper prices retreated on Tuesday amid cautious trading ahead of US jobs data and year-end thinning liquidity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Glencore purchase is latest in flurry of Peru copper dealmaking</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/glencore-purchase-is-latest-in-flurry-of-peru-copper-dealmaking/</link><description>Mining.com reports Glencore’s acquisition of the Quechua project from Pan Pacific Copper as part of a broader push to nearly double its global copper output, noting the deal comes amid a wave of Peru copper transactions and high copper prices driven by supply constraints and difficulty bringing new mines online[3].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Tightens the World: Why This Metal Is Driving a New Market Phase</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/news/market-updates/copper-tightens-the-world-why-this-metal-is-driving-a-new-market-phase</link><description>Kalkine Media explains that global copper markets are in a structural reset caused by electrification, infrastructure demand and constrained mine supply, arguing these forces are tightening available copper and reshaping market dynamics going forward[4].</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel hesitates under pressure from Chinese data, oversupply concerns</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/nickel-hesitates-under-pressure-from-chinese-data,-oversupply-concerns-47954</link><description>LME nickel hovered near $14,295 per ton, down 2.22%, while SHFE nickel fell 2.36% amid weakness in Chinese economy and supply surpluses. Prices tested multi-month lows with LME closing at $14,346, down 1.65%. Morgan Stanley forecasts nickel drifting toward $15,500 per ton in 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of its 'Green Hydrogen in Cogne' project at the Aosta plant, deploying a 1.008 MW AEM electrolyzer to produce about 165 tonnes of green hydrogen per year to decarbonise part of its operations and power one furnace fully; the project is supported by €7.9 million from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan (NRRP).</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Yieh reports that Cogne Acciai Speciali has begun operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, using electrolysis to produce hydrogen for emissions reduction in its stainless and specialty steel production processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Outokumpu sells remaining longs business to Cogne</title><link>https://www.stainless.club/industry-news/read/outokumpu-sells-remaining-longs-business-to-cogne.html</link><description>Outokumpu has divested its remaining long products operations in Degerfors and Storfors (Sweden) to Italy’s Cogne Acciai Speciali, completing Outokumpu's exit from the longs business and allowing Cogne to expand its footprint in the Nordic and Baltic markets as part of a broader growth strategy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Introducing the Minerals Stewardship Consortium at MIT</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2025/introducing-minerals-stewardship-consortium-1216</link><description>MIT launched the Minerals Stewardship Consortium to convene industry, academia and policy leaders to develop responsible, scalable strategies for critical‑minerals production and stewardship, including copper. The consortium will pursue systems‑level innovation—digital mining tools, environmental monitoring, and social/ecological integration—to reduce environmental and social impacts while enabling resilient copper supply chains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Macro sentiment gradually cools, SHFE aluminum mainly drops back slightly at high levels [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103674703/Macro-sentiment-gradually-cools-SHFE-aluminum-mainly-drops-back-slightly-at-high-levels-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME aluminum settled at $2,882.5/mt, up 0.26%, while SHFE aluminum closed down 0.09% amid cooling macro sentiment. Aluminum scrap supply remains tight with resilient secondary prices due to high costs, but weakening demand and fluctuating prices lead to sluggish trading. Overall fundamentals lean bearish with rising inventories and declining alumina costs, expecting prices to hover at highs but pull back slightly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum US Midwest Premium reaches 90 cents/lb for the first time</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/aluminum-us-midwest-premium-reaches-90-cents-lb-for-the-first-time/</link><description>The US Midwest Premium for primary aluminum has reached 90 cents/lb for the first time, signaling strong regional demand and supply tightness in the US market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto adds aluminum markups as Trump tariffs drive up consumer costs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/rio-tinto-adds-aluminum-markups-as-trump-tariffs-drive-up-consumer-costs/</link><description>Rio Tinto introduced aluminum markups of 1-3 cents above the US Midwest premium amid Trump’s 50% tariffs, pushing total premiums to over 70% on top of the $2,830/ton base price. US LME warehouses are depleted, domestic stockpiles at 35 days of consumption, distorting the market structure. Analysts expect global benchmark prices above $3,000/ton amid supply shortages and policy impacts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Secondary Aluminum Alloy Ingot Inventories Decline on Dec 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103675387/SMM:-Secondary-Aluminum-Alloy-Ingot-Inventories-Decline-on-Dec-17</link><description>Secondary aluminum alloy ingot inventories declined on December 17, amid expectations of aluminum prices pulling back slightly from high levels in the short term.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>10 Thai Steel Associations urge government to tighten regulations</title><link>https://www.nationthailand.com/business/manufacturing/40059913</link><description>Ten Thai Steel Industry Associations are urging the government to enforce strict TIS standards before allowing induction furnace steel factories to reopen, prioritizing public safety amid low capacity utilization. They presented data to the Industry Minister proposing structural changes and confirm no market shortages or price hikes have occurred since closures. Factories must adopt refining processes like Ladle Furnace and gain approval to resume operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Worthington Steel Named a 2025 Supplier of the Year by Schaeffler Group USA Inc.</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251124926350/en/Worthington-Steel-Named-a-2025-Supplier-of-the-Year-by-Schaeffler-Group-USA-Inc.</link><description>Worthington Steel received Schaeffler's 2025 Supplier of the Year award for operational excellence, innovation, and collaboration in advancing sustainable motion technology. The company specializes in carbon flat-roll steel processing, electrical steel laminations, and value-added solutions like galvanizing and lightweighting to drive steel toward a more sustainable future. This recognition highlights Worthington's role in building resilient supply chains and supporting customers' strategic sustainability goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>New roadmap shows how to cut a surprisingly big source of emissions</title><link>https://www.japantimes.co.jp/environment/2025/12/17/climate-change/electrification-emissions-cut-roadmap/</link><description>A new University of California at Santa Barbara report outlines electrification strategies for the U.S. industrial sector, the third-largest source of carbon emissions, including steel production. Electrifying overlooked industries like steel, cement, ethanol, and others could reduce emissions by 26% by 2050, equivalent to about 1 billion tons from 2023 levels. The roadmap emphasizes ready-made climate solutions beyond high-profile sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On December 17, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103675604/</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged 111,900-118,700 yuan/mt, averaging 115,300 yuan/mt, up 550 yuan/mt from previous day. This reflects daily price assessment amid ongoing market activity.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] On December 17, the SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103675834/SMM:-High-grade-NPI-Price-Dips-Market-Sentiment-Factor-Declines-on-Dec-17</link><description>SMM average price for 10-12% high-grade NPI was 885 yuan/nickel unit (ex-factory, tax included), down 1.5% on December 17. Market sentiment declined, impacting high-grade nickel pig iron pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>EV giants' supply chains tied to nickel mining damage in PH</title><link>https://thephilbiznews.com/2025/12/17/ev-giants-supply-chains-tied-to-nickel-mining-damage-in-ph/</link><description>A Global Witness investigation links nickel mining in the Philippines, the world's largest raw nickel exporter, to deforestation, river pollution, and food insecurity in Cantilan, Surigao del Sur. Nickel ore from Marcventures Mining traces to Chinese traders supplying battery makers for Tesla, Volkswagen, Mercedes-Benz, BMW, and Audi. The report highlights risks in EV supply chains despite no alleged legal breaches.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to 2,902.40 USD/T on December 17, 2025, up 0.72% from the previous day, with a 4.07% increase over the past month and 14.81% year-over-year. UK aluminum futures hovered around $2,870 per tonne near a one-month high, supported by improving demand prospects, tight global supply, and China's stimulus measures against its property crisis.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[SMM Aluminum Express] Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Down 12,56 mt WoW on Dec 18</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103678358/SMM:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Down-1256-mt-WoW-on-Dec-18</link><description>Domestic secondary aluminum ingot inventory decreased by 12,56 mt week-over-week on December 18, 2025. SMM expects aluminum prices to mainly hover at highs in the short term.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>U.S. Recycled Steel Prices Rise in December 2025 After Subdued Period</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/metal-recycling/u.s.-recycled-steel-prices-rise-in-december-2025-after-subdued-period-2025-12-17/98018</link><description>Davis Index data showed U.S. recycled steel bids rose in December after a subdued May–November period, with prime grades up about $10/ton and some shredded and heavy melting scrap up $20/ton versus November; export prices for No.1/No.2 HMS cargoes from New York to Turkey climbed from roughly $305/ton in early November to about $331 by Dec. 10. Analysts note an oversupply of billets and slabs from China tempering activity in Turkey and India, while measures in the EU and other markets have tried to limit low-cost Chinese exports.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Correction to EU flat steel price assessments on December 17</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/correction-to-eu-flat-steel-price-assessments-on-december-17/</link><description>Fastmarkets issued a correction to several EU flat-steel domestic price assessments published for Dec. 17, adjusting cold-rolled coil and galvanized coil ranges (e.g., cold-rolled coil ex-works Southern Europe corrected to €730–750/ton). The notice updates Fastmarkets’ pricing database and invites market participants to provide feedback or price submissions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Dynamics forecasts Q4 earnings of $1.65-$1.69 per share</title><link>https://au.investing.com/news/company-news/steel-dynamics-forecasts-q4-earnings-of-165169-per-share-93CH-4175435</link><description>Steel Dynamics issued Q4 2025 guidance of $1.65–$1.69 per diluted share, attributing weaker sequential profitability to lower average selling values and reduced volumes driven by seasonal demand and extended maintenance outages that cut production by ~140–150k tons. The company noted recent improvements in flat-rolled steel prices as import volumes declined, while recycling and fabrication segments faced lower seasonal shipments and softer ferrous pricing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 1.1 percent - week 51, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-11-percent-week-51-2025-1424937.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending December 13, 2025, reached 1.753 million net tons, up 1.1% from the previous week and 5.3% from the same week in 2024, with capacity utilization at 76.5%. Adjusted year-to-date production through December 13, 2025, was 85.881 million net tons at 76.8% capacity utilization, a 3.4% increase year-over-year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>India's iron ore production rises just 0.5% y-o-y in 8MFY'26 even as crude steel output jumps 11%</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5107310-indias-iron-ore-production-rises-just-05-y-o-y-in-8mfy26-even-as-crude-steel-output-jumps-11</link><description>India's iron ore production grew only 0.5% year-over-year in the first eight months of FY2026, lagging behind an 11% rise in crude steel output to 109.491 million tons, causing supply shortfalls and higher prices. JSW Steel saw a 32% drop to 11.2 million tons due to mine issues, while NMDC surged 21% to 31.5 million tons; industry groups call for policy changes to boost domestic supply.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 1.45% Higher at $5.3635 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512176530/comex-copper-settles-145-higher-at-53635-data-talk</link><description>Front‑month Comex copper for December delivery gained 7.65 cents per pound (1.45%) to settle at $5.3635, marking its largest one‑day dollar and percentage gain since Dec. 11, 2025; the piece notes copper is up roughly 34.6% year‑over‑year and remains below its 2025 high of $5.795 set in July 2025.[1] The report summarizes short‑term session performance, month‑to‑date and year‑to‑date moves and provides settlement‑price based statistics for market context.[1]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper steadies near multi‑month highs as demand from China and US supports prices</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>TradingEconomics reports copper futures around $5.35/lb, near multi‑month highs, supported by strong demand from China and the US—citing EV and energy infrastructure growth in China and AI‑driven investment in the US—while noting month and year gains of roughly 5–33% depending on the series.[3] The page also records a Dec. 16 note that copper rebounded on short covering and contract rollovers ahead of expiry, despite softer Chinese underlying data.[3]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper higher on potential mine shortfalls, risk‑on sentiment</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40397997/copper-higher-on-potential-mine-shortfalls-risk-on-sentiment</link><description>Business Recorder reports copper rose amid worries about potential mine shortfalls that spurred speculative buying, with the piece citing London‑based benchmark moves and general risk‑on market sentiment as drivers of the gains.[7] The article emphasizes supply concerns as a key near‑term influence on copper prices.[7]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto’s Nuton technology produces first copper</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2025/rio-tintos-nuton-technology-produces-first-copper</link><description>Rio Tinto announced that its Nuton copper-processing technology has produced its first copper product; the company says Nuton will deliver materially lower environmental impacts versus conventional processing, including up to 80% less water use and up to 60% lower greenhouse‑gas intensity. The release frames Nuton as a scalable, lower‑footprint processing route intended to reduce water and emissions footprints for future copper projects.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco &amp; Hexagon sign MoU on collaboration from CAS to autonomy</title><link>https://im-mining.com/2025/12/17/codelco-hexagon-sign-mou-on-collaboration-from-cas-to-autonomy/</link><description>Chilean state miner Codelco and technology group Hexagon signed a memorandum of understanding to collaborate across Codelco Automation System (CAS) and autonomy initiatives aimed at improving operational efficiency and safety in copper operations. The partnership focuses on digitalization, autonomy and remote‑operation technologies to advance productivity and sustainability in large‑scale copper mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Climate‑friendly metals from deep‑sea ores</title><link>https://www.mpg.de/25794327/1127-eifo-sustainable-metals-from-deep-sea-mining-152925-x</link><description>Max Planck researchers described a process reported in Science Advances for extracting copper, nickel and cobalt from deep‑sea manganese nodules using smelting and hydrogen reduction; the method reportedly reduces CO2 emissions by over 90% (when using green hydrogen) and cuts energy use by nearly 20% compared with conventional carbon‑based reduction. The team frames deep‑sea ore processing as a potentially lower‑impact source of metals needed for electrification, while noting broader environmental considerations of seabed mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Prices Supported By Demand From EVs, Construction &amp; Renewable Energy Sectors</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NydAVFdv9Fc</link><description>Aluminum prices are being supported by strong demand from electric vehicles (EVs), construction, and renewable energy sectors. The video discusses current market dynamics driving these trends.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Aluminium scales Lanjigarh Refinery to 5 MTPA</title><link>https://news.webindia123.com/news/Articles/India/20251218/4395720.html</link><description>Vedanta Aluminium, India's largest producer, has scaled its Lanjigarh Refinery to 5 million tonnes per annum capacity. This expansion marks a key milestone in the company's growth and bolsters India's self-reliance in aluminium production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[SMM Aluminum Express] Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Down 1,256 mt WoW on Dec 18</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103678358/SMM:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Down-1256-mt-WoW-on-Dec-18</link><description>SMM statistics show social inventory of secondary aluminum ingots in China's mainstream consumption areas at 53,400 mt on December 18, down 1,256 mt week-on-week. This continues a slight destocking trend in the secondary aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US hot-rolled bar exports down 7.0 percent in August 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-hot-rolled-bar-exports-down-70-percent-in-august-2025-1425168.htm</link><description>SteelOrbis reports U.S. hot-rolled bar (rebar) export volumes fell year-on-year in August 2025, with rebar imports also notably lower in that month; the article is part of the site’s ongoing steel-news feed covering trade flows and market movements relevant to supply and price dynamics. The item highlights trade-volume changes that feed into broader pricing and market trend analysis.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Indian steelmakers face slower export outlook as new orders fade</title><link>https://indiaseatradenews.com/indian-steelmakers-face-slower-export-outlook-as-new-orders-fade/</link><description>Indian steelmakers are facing a slower export outlook due to fading new orders. Steel production in the country grew by 6% amid these challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Indian steel exports expected to moderate as global orders dry up</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/steel/indian-steel-exports-expected-to-moderate-as-global-orders-dry-up-elara-capital/amp_articleshow/126032627.cms</link><description>Indian steel exports are expected to moderate in coming months as global orders dry up, according to Elara Capital. This follows slower growth in overseas demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Glencore Acquires Peruvian Copper Project, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103676980/Glencore-Acquires-Peruvian-Copper-Project-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>SMM reports LME copper opened around $11,715/mt, fluctuated intraday and closed at $11,742.5/mt (up ~1.06%), with ample spot supply and average transactions noted on the spot market while end‑of‑year demand was weak; the note expects the price center to continue moving higher today and also highlights Glencore’s acquisition of a Peruvian copper project.[2] The bulletin also details domestic Chinese spot/import premiums, secondary copper indicators and macro commentary including Fed survey and Governor Waller remarks affecting expectations for rate cuts.[2]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Dec. 18</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20251218/044f1fd1ee064a8da1149293c1996436/c.html</link><description>Xinhua’s price snapshot at 0200 GMT lists copper at $5.36 per pound as part of a wider metals price update, providing a concise market quote to gauge intraday levels across exchanges.[4] The brief release is a data update rather than a narrative market analysis.[4]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Metals surge as rate‑cut hopes rise</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/18/metals-surge-as-rate-cut-hopes-rise/</link><description>ShareCafe reports a broad base‑metals rally led by copper, driven by rising expectations for interest‑rate cuts and signals of tightening supply; the article highlights strong Chinese import figures and US AI infrastructure investment as demand drivers, while noting market participants are watching upcoming US economic data for Fed policy direction.[5] It frames the rally within broader precious‑ and base‑metals moves and commentary from ANZ on rate cuts benefiting the sector.[5]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 18, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103678257/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price reached 113,100-120,100 yuan/mt on December 18, with an average of 116,600 yuan/mt, marking an increase of 1,300 yuan/mt from the previous day. This uptick reflects recent market movements in refined nickel pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Govt to revise nickel benchmark pricing, cobalt to face royalties: APNI</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/govt-to-revise-nickel-benchmark-pricing-cobalt-to-face-royalties-apni</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources plans to revise the nickel benchmark price formula in early 2026, introducing royalties on associated minerals like cobalt. APNI supports this, noting it could generate up to US$600 million in state revenue despite cobalt's low content in nickel ore, while urging focus on associated minerals over raising primary nickel royalties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rose to 2,914.35 USD/T on Dec. 18; one‑month and yearly gains noted</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Trading Economics reports aluminum price rose to 2,914.35 USD/tonne on December 18, 2025, reflecting a one‑month increase of about 3.6% and a year‑on‑year gain near 15.8%. The brief also notes prices are near a one‑month high amid improving demand prospects and tight global supply conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AM Green and Mitsui &amp; Co., Ltd. sign MoU to explore strategic collaboration</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/12/18/am-green-and-mitsui-co-ltd-sign-mou-to-explore-strategic-collaboration/</link><description>AM Green and Mitsui &amp; Co., Ltd. have signed a Memorandum of Understanding to explore strategic collaboration on low-carbon aluminum production, including potential investments in AM Green Metals' 1 MTPA primary aluminum smelter and 2 MTPA alumina refining operations powered by renewables. The partnership aims to support equity needs for the world’s first integrated green aluminum platform and explore offtake agreements and supply of auxiliary materials. This follows AM Green's prior MoU with the Andhra Pradesh government for a 1 MTPA green aluminum complex.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel industry supplier P.C. Campana moving manufacturing line to Vicksburg</title><link>https://magnoliatribune.com/2025/12/18/steel-industry-supplier-p-c-campana-moving-manufacturing-line-to-vicksburg/</link><description>P.C. Campana Inc., a supplier to the steel industry, will invest $3.43 million to relocate two manufacturing lines to Vicksburg, Mississippi, over the next three years, creating an estimated 17 jobs within five years and improving service to southern U.S. steelmakers. The move is supported by the Mississippi Development Authority and incentives under the MFLEX program.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron ore extends gains on improving steel margins, restocking hopes</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/iron-ore-extends-gains-on-improving-steel-margins-restocking-hopes/</link><description>Iron ore futures extended gains driven by improved steel margins and expectations of restocking among steel producers, supporting higher feedstock demand. The article links commodity movements to steel sector margin improvements and broader market sentiment about inventory replenishment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper prices diverge as investors weigh US rate outlook, AI boom</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3XP03E:0-copper-prices-diverge-as-investors-weigh-us-rate-outlook-ai-boom/</link><description>Reuters reports copper prices showed mixed moves as markets balanced expectations for U.S. interest rates against robust demand themes from AI-led investment in data centres and electrification; the article highlights investor uncertainty on the rate path as a key driver of short-term divergence. Market commentary also places the price action in the context of wider base metals performance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper drifts down as traders trim positions, await US data</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-drifts-down-as-traders-trim-positions-await-us-data/</link><description>A market note summarizes that copper, after gaining roughly 33% in 2025 and touching record highs, eased as traders reduced positions ahead of key U.S. data; analysts still see underlying support but near-term profit-taking and macro data risks weigh on prices. The story frames the pullback as part of a broader risk-off/positioning dynamic rather than a change in structural demand drivers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper: Price, Chart, Historical Data and Recent News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>TradingEconomics notes copper was trading around $5.36–$5.37 per lb in mid-December 2025, up significantly year-on-year and supported by strong demand from China and U.S. AI-driven investment; the page compiles recent intraday moves, month-to-date gains, and short news snippets on rebounds and falls tied to positioning and macro releases. This is a continuously updated market data and commentary page rather than a single authored article.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Kenadyr Metals Completes TSXV Reactivation, Name Change to Algo Grande Copper and 100% Acquisition of the Adelita Project</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/KNDYF/kenadyr-metals-completes-tsxv-reactivation-name-change-to-algo-aj0wgqxs5rzb.html</link><description>Algo Grande Copper, formerly Kenadyr Metals, has acquired 100% interest in the 5,895-hectare Adelita Copper-Gold-Silver Project in the Arizona-Sonora copper belt. The project features the high-grade Cerro Grande skarn discovery, with an inaugural drilling program underway and plans for Phase 2 drilling in Q2 2026 targeting expansions and porphyry sources. The company expects TSXV reactivation on or about December 23, 2025, under symbol ALGR.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining to sell Eagle nickel-copper mine to Talon Metals for about $84 million</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3XP05P:0-lundin-mining-to-sell-eagle-nickel-copper-mine-to-talon-metals-for-about-84-million/</link><description>Lundin Mining has agreed to sell its Eagle nickel-copper mine and Humboldt mill in the US to Talon Metals for approximately $84 million in a share-based transaction. This sale marks Lundin Mining's exit from US nickel production. The deal aims to create a pure-play American nickel-copper company for Talon Metals.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Woes: Innovations Steering a Sustainable EV Future</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-supply-woes-innovations-steering-a-sustainable-ev-future-aemc/</link><description>Analysis of how high-nickel NMC batteries are driving global nickel demand and the innovations (like LFP expansion, sodium‑ion batteries, smaller EV batteries, and recycling) that could reduce nickel dependence and improve supply-chain sustainability. The piece also highlights efforts by juniors and projects (e.g., Alaska Energy Metals Corporation’s Nikolai project) aiming to secure more sustainable nickel sources for the U.S. transition to electric vehicles.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Jinchuan Nickel‑Cobalt Research &amp; Design Institute makes breakthrough in reducing volume and weight of arsenic sulfide residue</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5107368-flash-jinchuan-nickel-cobalt-research-and-design-institute-makes-breakthrough-in-reducing-volume-and-weight-of-arsenic-sulfide-residue</link><description>Short industry flash reporting a technical breakthrough by Jinchuan’s Nickel‑Cobalt Research &amp; Design Institute that reduces the volume and weight of arsenic sulfide residue from processing, which could lower environmental liabilities and improve sustainability of nickel/cobalt refining operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Hits 5% Treasury Threshold as Controlling Shareholder Launches Accelerated Share Disposal</title><link>https://www.tipranks.com/news/company-announcements/tenaris-hits-5-treasury-threshold-as-controlling-shareholder-launches-accelerated-share-disposal</link><description>Tenaris has reached a 5% treasury threshold through repurchased ordinary shares. The controlling shareholder has filed an amendment to Schedule 13D and launched an accelerated share disposal. This development highlights recent financial maneuvers by the company and its major stakeholder.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Hyundai Steel brings in $582M Posco investment for Louisiana mill</title><link>https://www.manufacturingdive.com/news/hyundai-steel-582m-posco-investment-louisiana-mill/808280/</link><description>Posco will invest $582 million for a 20% stake in Hyundai Steel’s new electric arc furnace mill in Louisiana, set to produce 2.7 million metric tons of automotive steel plates annually starting in 2029. The $5.8 billion project supports local supply amid tariffs and growing US demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Show Strength</title><link>https://steelnews.biz/nickel-prices-show-strength/</link><description>Asian nickel and LME contracts showed gains mid‑December with the SHFE NI2601 and LME both stronger; commentary linked nickel strength partly to broader battery demand and correlated gains in lithium markets.[6]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Smelter's future secured but cost to taxpayers unclear</title><link>https://myallcoast.newsofthearea.com.au/smelters-future-secured-but-cost-to-taxpayers-unclear</link><description>The Australian federal government has confirmed taxpayer support to keep the troubled Tomago aluminum smelter running beyond 2028, securing over 1,000 jobs amid spiraling energy costs. Arrangements include fixed-price power purchase agreements and concessional finance for renewable energy projects, with Tomago Aluminium committing at least $1 billion for upgrades and decarbonization. The smelter produces up to 590,000 tonnes of aluminum annually, where electricity accounts for 40% of operating costs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel price fell slightly to 906.03 USD/T on December 19, 2025, down 0.11% from the previous day, after dropping to 906.08 USD/T on December 18. Over the past month, prices rose 5.97% but remain volatile, with forecasts expecting 911.35 USD/T by quarter-end and 997.25 in 12 months. Historical highs reached 1945 USD/T in 2021.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tighter supply lends support to global steel market</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/19/tighter-supply-lends-support-to-global-steel-market/</link><description>BMI forecasts global average steel prices to rise to $US625 per tonne in 2026 from $US600 in 2025, driven by tighter supply from reduced Chinese output and easing exports. China's crude steel production is expected to fall 4% to 936 million tonnes in 2026 after a 3% decline in 2025, due to capacity curbs. Lower iron ore prices support margins but do not lead to cheaper steel amid reduced output.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tighter supply lends support to global steel market</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/19/tighter-supply-lends-support-to-global-steel-market/</link><description>Market analysis says global steel prices are expected to rise modestly in 2026 amid supply tightening as Chinese crude steel output is forecast to fall (about 4% in 2026 after a 3% decline in 2025), reflecting efforts to rein in excess capacity; this reduced output is expected to tighten markets and support higher prices despite subdued iron ore levels. The piece highlights policy-driven capacity cuts in China (including decommissioning rules) and notes iron ore supply growth from new projects like Simandou influencing raw-material dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AD/CVD News: Corrosion-Resistant Steel, Molded Fiber Products, Quartz, Silicon, Solar Cells</title><link>https://www.strtrade.com/trade-news-resources/str-trade-report/trade-report/december/ad-cvd-news-corrosion-resistant-steel-molded-fiber-products-quartz-silicon-solar-cells</link><description>The International Trade Administration and/or ITC announced antidumping and countervailing duty actions affecting corrosion‑resistant steel from multiple countries, with AD orders and CVD orders taking effect Dec. 19, 2025; the roundup also covers related trade remedy determinations across several product categories. The report is a summary of recent AD/CVD developments relevant to steel trade and import measures in the U.S.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. November Inflation Pulls Back Beyond Expectations, LME Copper Fluctuates and Closes Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103679223/US-November-Inflation-Pulls-Back-Beyond-Expectations-LME-Copper-Fluctuates-and-Closes-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>SMM reports that LME copper opened around $11,726/tonne and after intraday swings closed slightly lower as traders weighed softer U.S. November inflation data that increased hopes for an earlier Fed rate cut; spot cathode supply remains ample while downstream demand is cautious, putting near-term upside under pressure. The piece also notes SHFE and secondary copper price moves and describes modest changes in spot premiums and market liquidity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Dec. 19</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20251219/da6477522e0f4e3e8f10dc28a4a3ed4a/c.html</link><description>Xinhua published a market snapshot from LSEG showing copper at $5.37 per lb (COMEX reference) as of 0200 GMT on Dec. 19, 2025, summarizing headline price levels across major metals. The brief bulletin is a price update rather than an in-depth market analysis.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining to exit US nickel through Eagle sale to Talon</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/lundin-mining-to-exit-us-nickel-through-eagle-sale-to-talon-2025-12-19</link><description>Canadian miner Lundin Mining has agreed to sell its Eagle nickel/copper mine and Humboldt mill in the US to Talon Metals. This transaction allows Lundin to exit its US nickel operations. The deal supports Talon's aim to create a pure-play American nickel-copper company.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Stark drilling extends sedimentary copper</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/12/19/northern-neighbors/stark-drilling-extends-sedimentary-copper/9411.html</link><description>Stark Copper's drilling has extended sedimentary copper mineralization at its project. The results confirm expansion of the copper system north of 60. Updated December 18, 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Optimism persists in Queensland amid copper smelter, coal royalty issues</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/optimism-persists-in-queensland-amid-copper-smelter-coal-royalty-issues/</link><description>Industry optimism continues in Queensland despite challenges with copper smelter developments and coal royalty issues. Queensland accounts for about half of relevant production. The article highlights ongoing positive sentiment in the sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining Announces Sale of the Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill to Talon Metals to Create a Pure Play American Nickel-Copper Company</title><link>https://www.sharecast.com/press_note/market_reports/lundin-mining-announces-sale-of-the-eagle-mine-and-humboldt-mill-to-talon-metals-to-create-a-pure-play-american-nickel-copper-company--21405059.html</link><description>Lundin Mining announced the sale of its Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill to Talon Metals, enabling Talon to become a pure-play American nickel-copper company. This mirrors the Mining Weekly report on the same transaction. The move shifts US nickel-copper assets.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel fell to 14,796 USD/T on December 19, 2025, down 0.43% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 2.36%. Forecasts indicate nickel expected to trade at 14,577.89 USD/MT by quarter-end and 13,795.43 in 12 months.[1]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On December 19, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103680547/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price reached 116,500–123,700 yuan/mt on December 19, averaging 120,100 yuan/mt, up 3,500 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects a rebound in spot prices amid market fluctuations.[2]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Gold Nears Record High on Rate Cut Bets</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/19/gold-nears-record-high-on-rate-cut-bets/</link><description>Nickel prices surged after reports of Indonesia considering a sharp cut to nickel ore production in 2026. This potential supply reduction boosted market sentiment amid broader metals movements.[6]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining to exit US nickel through Eagle sale to Talon</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/lundin-mining-to-exit-us-nickel-through-eagle-sale-to-talon-2025-12-19</link><description>Lundin Mining agreed to sell its Eagle nickel/copper mine and Humboldt mill in the US to Talon Metals in a share-based deal. This transaction marks Lundin's exit from US nickel operations.[8]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining to exit US nickel through Eagle sale to Talon</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/lundin-mining-to-exit-us-nickel-through-eagle-sale-to-talon-2025-12-19</link><description>Canadian miner Lundin Mining has agreed to sell its Eagle nickel/copper mine and Humboldt mill in the US to Talon Metals in a share-based deal. This transaction represents Lundin Mining's complete exit from the US nickel sector. The sale supports Talon's focus on domestic nickel production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,069 CNY/T on December 19, 2025, down 0.49% from the previous day, though rebar futures climbed above CNY 3,080 per ton to a two-week high amid expectations of improving steel margins in China. Falling input costs like coal and coke are supporting steelmaker profitability, with only 35% of Chinese mills profitable in November. Prices remain 4.51% lower year-over-year despite a slight monthly rise.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Industry Newsletter 12/19/25</title><link>https://steelindustrynews.substack.com/p/steel-industry-newsletter-121825</link><description>The newsletter covers recent steel industry developments including POSCO’s 20% stake in Hyundai Steel’s new US mill, Nucor’s galvanized price increase, US Steel restarting Granite City Works, and Nippon Steel’s $4 billion scrap-based mill plans in the US. It also mentions AHMSA bankruptcy impacting Mexico’s steel supply.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper futures hold above $5.4/lb as demand from China and US supports prices</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures remained near multi-month highs above $5.40 per pound, driven by strong demand from China and the U.S., with analysts citing growth in Chinese EV and energy infrastructure sectors and AI-related investment in the U.S. as supportive factors; prices have risen sharply month-to-date and year-on-year according to the site’s CFD tracking the benchmark market.[1]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM: Forecasts slight decline in copper cathode/rod operating rate for Dec 19–25</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103681312/SMM-Forecasts-Slight-Decline-in-Copper-Cathode-Rod-Operating-Rate-Next-Week-Dec-19-25</link><description>Shanghai Metals Market (SMM) data notes a small expected decline in operating rates for copper cathode and rod for the week of Dec 19–25, while reporting transaction price ranges and averages in yuan/mt that showed modest day-to-day movement; the piece provides short-term supply-side operating-rate and price detail for Chinese domestic markets.[6]</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>ICSG: Preliminary data indicates that world refined copper production grew by about 4.4% during the first ten months of 2025</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/icsg-preliminary-data-indicates-that-world-refined-copper-production-grew-by-about-4-4-during-the-ce7d50ddde8af423</link><description>Preliminary data from ICSG shows world refined copper production grew by about 4.4% in the first ten months of 2025. This growth reflects ongoing global supply dynamics amid rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ero Files Technical Report for the Xavantina Operations</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/gnwcq-2025-12-20-ero-files-technical-report-for-the-xavantina-operations</link><description>Ero Copper Corp. filed a Technical Report for its Xavantina Operations, updating the NI 43-101 mineral reserve and resource estimate announced on November 4, 2025. The company operates copper mines in Brazil including Caraíba and Tucumã, alongside the gold-producing Xavantina. It is also advancing the Furnas Copper-Gold Project.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Analysis: Nickel prices fluctuated sharply this week, falling first and then rising with spot inventory increasing slightly</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103681307/smm-analysis-nickel-prices-fluctuated-sharply-this-week-falling-first-and-then-rising-with-spot-inventory-increasing-slightly</link><description>SHFE and LME nickel moved in tandem—hitting weekly lows then rebounding—with SHFE nickel NI2601 settling at 117,180 yuan/mt on Dec 19; domestic social inventory rose slightly while downstream buying remained cautious ahead of year-end amid mixed macro cues.[2]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 20.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides the latest updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures rebar contracts showing no change at 0.00 on December 19, 2025. The platform offers real-time prices, news, analyses, and comments on the iron and steel industry. It tracks key exchanges and indices for market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices surge on Dec 20 amid weaker dollar, increased ...</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/NewsItem/151985</link><description>LME nickel futures reportedly jumped US$243/ton to close at US$15,356/ton on Dec 20, with spot prices also rising—moves attributed to a softer dollar and stronger risk flows supporting short‑term price strength.[4]</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining Announces Sale of the Eagle Mine and Humboldt Mill to Talon Metals</title><link>https://lundinmining.com/news/lundin-mining-announces-sale-of-the-eagle-mine-and-123223/</link><description>Lundin Mining is selling the Eagle Mine, the only primary nickel mine operating in the US, and Humboldt Mill to Talon Metals, creating a pure-play American nickel-copper company. Eagle has produced over 194,000 tonnes of nickel and 185,000 tonnes of copper since operations began, generating US$3.2 billion in revenue. The transaction unlocks synergies for shared processing and supports regional growth.</description><category>copper</category></item></channel></rss>