<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 05:16:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Kalgoorlie Nickel Project Secures Three-Year Major Status Extension</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/kalgoorlie-nickel-project-2025-critical-minerals-renewal/</link><description>The Kalgoorlie Nickel Project benefits from a three-year major status extension, leveraging laterite deposits with improved processing technologies for better recovery and sustainability. The joint venture between Ardea Resources, Sumitomo Metal Mining, and Mitsubishi Corporation combines Australian expertise with Japanese technology and market access to strengthen nickel production capacity.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices edged down slightly on October 20</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103576549/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-down-slightly-on-October-20-as-China-and-the-US-agreed-to-hold-a-new-round-of-trade-consultations-as-soon-as-possible</link><description>Nickel prices in China edged down slightly amid ongoing trade negotiations between China and the U.S. The SHFE nickel contract showed consolidation with prices expected to remain subdued due to weak fundamentals and external uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale scraps plans to build Quebec nickel sulphate facility</title><link>https://www.mining.com/vale-scraps-plans-to-build-quebec-nickel-sulphate-facility/</link><description>Vale has cancelled its C$325 million nickel sulphate plant project in Quebec after General Motors delayed its Ultium Cam battery expansion. The facility would have been North America's first fully domestic nickel sulphate plant, critical for lithium-ion battery production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali and CVA Agreement for Decarbonization</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA to enhance energy performance and reduce environmental impact. The agreement supports CVA's leadership in decarbonization and provides stable revenue flows for CVA through the Energy Release scheme. It aligns with Cogne's strategic goals for sustainability.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Falls Amid Renewed US-China Tensions</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell due to renewed tensions between the US and China, particularly over rare earth export controls. Despite this, aluminum prices remain high, supported by strong market fundamentals. The price dropped to $2,740 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Approaches Record on US-China Trade Uncertainty</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-approaches-record-on-us-china-trade-uncertainty/</link><description>Copper prices neared records due to uncertainty surrounding US-China trade talks and global supply disruptions. Prices reached as high as $10,691.50 per tonne in London and $5.0485 per lb. on the Comex. The market remains bullish amid mine disruptions and supply issues.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Arizona Sonoran soars on new copper ranking</title><link>https://www.mining.com/arizona-sonoran-soars-on-new-copper-ranking/</link><description>Arizona Sonoran Copper's shares hit a historic high after releasing a pre-feasibility study showing its Cactus project could become the third largest cathode copper producer in the U.S. The project is expected to produce about 103,000 tonnes annually over the first 10 years with strong economic metrics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The global copper conundrum</title><link>https://www.africanmining.co.za/2025/10/21/the-global-copper-conundrum/</link><description>This analysis discusses concerns over the long-term sustainability of copper supply, citing an imbalance between merger and acquisition activity and the discovery of new copper deposits. It raises questions about whether current innovation and investment levels can meet future demand amid tightening supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Rises, But Sentiment Bearish on Strong Supply -- Market Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510203761/how-china-took-over-worlds-rare-earths-industry-2</link><description>Nickel prices edged higher with the three-month LME contract rising slightly. Indonesia has increased efforts to address safety and environmental issues in nickel mining by revoking permits and suspending companies, which has eased concerns about overexpansion but market sentiment remains bearish due to expectations of strong Indonesian nickel supply continuing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Bunker Hill Provides October Project Update</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=68f616484300f3e8520eeaef</link><description>Bunker Hill Mining Corp. reported substantial progress toward restarting the Bunker Hill Mine in Idaho, targeting the first half of 2026 for restart. The company highlighted advances in project development including filter press concrete foundations and processing plant installations, supporting efforts to strengthen the US metals supply chain with nickel among key metals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali to construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will build four photovoltaic plants in Sicily with over 20 MW capacity, enhancing energy performance and reducing environmental impact. This initiative aligns with their 2026–2029 Strategic Plan and supports regional decarbonisation efforts, strengthening their partnership with CVA.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, Italy, marking a step towards sustainable steel production. This initiative reflects the company's commitment to innovation and environmental responsibility in the specialty steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Arizona Sonoran Copper Company Releases Pre-Feasibility Study for Cactus Project</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103580305/Russia-Ukraine-Peace-Plan-Progresses-Step-by-Step-LME-Copper-Plunged-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Arizona Sonoran Copper Company announced a pre-feasibility study for its wholly-owned Cactus Project in Arizona, projecting annual copper cathode production of approximately 103,000 metric tons for the first ten years. The project is expected to become the third largest copper cathode production site in the US with an estimated annual EBITDA of about $574 million.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Macro Tailwinds and Solid Fundamentals Support Aluminum Prices</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices are expected to hold up well in the short term due to macroeconomic tailwinds and solid market fundamentals. The SHFE aluminum contract showed a consolidating trend, fluctuating around 20,930 yuan/mt. Technical indicators suggest a bullish alignment.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tightening Fundamentals and Inventory Drawdown to Boost Aluminum Prices</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103578139/Tightening-fundamentals-and-inventory-drawdown-to-boost-aluminum-prices-in-the-short-term-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Aluminum prices are likely to be boosted by tightening market fundamentals and inventory drawdowns. The most-traded SHFE aluminum contract closed at 20,920 yuan/mt, showing a fluctuating upward trend. Market sentiment remains cautious due to insufficient trading volume.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>South32 Ltd (S32) Earnings: Alumina &amp; Aluminum Production Increase as FY26 Guidance Holds</title><link>https://www.smartkarma.com/home/newswire/earnings-alerts/south32-ltd-s32-earnings-alumina-aluminum-production-increase-as-fy26-guidance-holds/</link><description>South32 reported a 1.4% increase in alumina production to 1.29 million tons and a 0.6% rise in aluminum production to 311,000 tons in the first quarter. The company maintained its FY26 production guidance despite some fluctuations in other metal outputs. Production increases were supported by operations exceeding capacity and improved supply conditions, while negotiations for long-term electricity supply at Mozal Aluminium remain unresolved.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Dynamics Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/steel-dynamics-reports-third-quarter-2025-results-302589340.html</link><description>Steel Dynamics highlighted strong performance in its aluminum flat rolled products segment, with finished products for industrial, beverage can, and automotive sectors being qualified earlier than expected. The company is ramping up operations and expects stronger demand for aluminum flat rolled products heading into 2026. Additionally, Steel Dynamics produced its first biocarbon to lower carbon emissions in steel production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>South32 Production Guidance Steady Despite Share Slump</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/21/south32-production-guidance-steady-despite-share-slump/</link><description>South32 reaffirmed its FY26 production guidance across all operations, including aluminum, despite a nearly 10% share price decline this year. The company reported a 33% increase in manganese volumes and a 12% rise in payable copper equivalent production. CEO Graham Kerr emphasized the focus on maintaining momentum and capitalizing on strengthening base metals market conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum's Low-Carbon Revolution in Action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminum industry is undergoing a significant transformation with a focus on sustainability, innovation, and circular practices. Companies are adopting low-carbon production methods, renewable energy, and advanced recycling technologies. This shift is driven by changing environmental standards and market needs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit 3-Year High: Is It the Next Key Metal in the Clean Energy Shift?</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-hit-3-year-high-is-it-the-next-key-metal-in-the-clean-energy-shift/</link><description>Aluminum prices have reached a three-year high due to increased demand from electric vehicles, solar, and grid upgrades. The industry is shifting towards low-carbon production, with new projects in Europe, Canada, and the Middle East expected to increase global capacity for low-carbon aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium's Real Paradox – Energy Use vs Carbon Saving</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminiums-real-paradox-energy-use-vs-carbon-saving-uncover-the-role-of-recycling-in-this-from-our-latest-magazine-115858</link><description>The aluminum industry faces a paradox between energy use and carbon savings. Recycling is highlighted as a key solution, saving up to 95% of energy needed for primary aluminum production and reducing greenhouse gas emissions. The global recycling rate was 76% in 2024.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Falls Slightly on October 20, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel price fell to 812 USD/T on October 20, 2025, down 0.25% from the previous day and 2.05% over the past month, though still 15.18% higher than a year ago. Forecasts expect HRC steel prices to rise to 829.86 USD/T by the end of Q4 2025 and 893.93 USD/T within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Jin10 Futures Morning Report, October 21, 2025</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/63534555/jin10-futures-morning-report-october-21-2025-tuesday</link><description>The report highlights global iron ore shipments from October 13 to October 19, 2025, which increased by 1.26 million tonnes from the previous week. China's crude steel production in September 2025 was 73.49 million tons, marking a year-on-year decrease of 4.6%. Additionally, coal mines in the Shanyin County area halted production temporarily.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Pressured by Weak Demand</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel/news/494316</link><description>Steel rebar futures remain low due to sluggish demand and narrowing margins. China's crude steel production in September was 73.49 million metric tons, down 4.6% from a year earlier. Only about 57% of Chinese steel mills were profitable by the end of September.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ASI Honours Sustainability Leaders</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/asi-honours-sustainability-leaders-1554271/</link><description>The Australian Steel Institute's 2025 Steel Sustainability Awards recognized leading sustainability projects in the steel industry. Winners included the St Marys Integrated Project Office and Bradbury Park Playscape for their innovative and sustainable construction methods. These projects highlight the industry's focus on reducing waste and emissions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103578116/MMGs-Copper-Loss-Amounts-to-90000-mt-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, initially dropping to $10,601/mt before rising to a high of $10,714/mt and closing at $10,712.5/mt, up 0.99%. The SHFE copper contract also saw fluctuations, closing at 85,670 yuan/mt, up 0.48%. MMG reported copper losses of about 90,000 mt due to illegal mining at its Las Bambas mine.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Demand to Rise 24% to 43 MTPA, Tightening Supply: Report</title><link>https://www.mercomindia.com/copper-demand-to-rise-24-to-43-mtpa-tightening-supply-report</link><description>A report by Wood Mackenzie forecasts copper demand to increase by 24% to 42.7 million tons per annum, driven by global economic development and electrification. Factors like electric vehicles and industrialization in Asia are expected to significantly boost demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Ticks Higher on Strong China Industrial Data; Plenum in Focus</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-ticks-higher-on-strong-china-industrial-data-plenum-in-focus/</link><description>Copper prices rose following strong industrial data from China. Investors are also focusing on upcoming political events in China, which could impact market trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP starts FY strong as copper and iron-ore output lift in tightening markets</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/bhp-starts-fy-strong-as-copper-and-iron-ore-output-lift-in-tightening-markets-2025-10-21</link><description>BHP reported a 4% increase in group copper production, driven by record concentrator throughput at the Escondida mine. This production boost comes amid tightening markets for copper and iron ore.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Demand to Rise 24% to 43 MTPA, Tightening Supply: Report</title><link>https://www.mercomindia.com/copper-demand-to-rise-24-to-43-mtpa-tightening-supply-report</link><description>A Wood Mackenzie report forecasts copper demand to increase by 24% to 42.7 million tons per annum by 2035, driven by factors such as electric vehicles, renewable energy, AI data centers, and industrialization in India and Southeast Asia. The report highlights supply tightening amid rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Solis Minerals to Acquire Cucho Copper Project in Peru</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/21/solis-minerals-to-acquire-cucho-copper-project-in-peru/</link><description>Solis Minerals announced a binding agreement to acquire up to 75% interest in the Cucho Copper Project in Peru, a large-scale copper-molybdenum-silver porphyry system. The project has significant historical drilling data and potential for a major resource, with plans for exploration drilling in early 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tartana Minerals Returns Strong Copper-Gold Assays from Exploration at Muscleville Project in FNQ</title><link>https://smallcaps.com.au/tartana-minerals-strong-copper-gold-assays-exploration-muscleville-project/</link><description>Tartana Minerals reported strong copper and gold assay results from its Muscleville prospect in Queensland, Australia. The results confirm mineralization in new zones near the existing open pit, supporting future drilling targets and exploration potential.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP Resolution Copper Mine: 7 Innovations For 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/bhp-resolution-copper-mine-7-innovations-for-2025</link><description>The article details seven major technological and sustainability innovations at BHP's Resolution Copper Mine, including automated drilling, advanced ore processing, intelligent mine management, water recycling, sustainable land reclamation, renewable energy integration, and community engagement. These innovations are projected to significantly reduce CO2 emissions, increase efficiency, and boost annual copper output, setting a benchmark for sustainable copper mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Sandvik Mining Equipment Demand Drives Record Industry Growth</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/sandvik-mining-equipment-demand-2025-technological-innovation/</link><description>The article reports on surging global demand for Sandvik mining equipment, driven by the energy transition, infrastructure development, and stricter environmental regulations. It notes that copper and other critical minerals are central to this growth, with mining companies upgrading equipment for greater efficiency and lower emissions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On October 21, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel was 121,100-123,900 yuan/mt, with an average price of 122,500 yuan/mt, up 400 yuan/mt from the previous</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103578980/</link><description>Nickel prices edged up slightly on October 21, with the average price of SMM #1 refined nickel rising by 400 yuan/mt to 122,500 yuan/mt. This reflects a modest increase in the nickel market on that day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices edged up slightly on October 21 while China's GDP in the first three quarters rose 5.2% YoY</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103579044/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-up-slightly-on-October-21-while-Chinas-GDP-in-the-first-three-quarters-rose-52-YoY</link><description>Nickel prices showed a slight increase on October 21, with the average price of SMM #1 refined nickel at 122,500 yuan/mt, up 400 yuan/mt from the previous day. The report also notes China's GDP growth of 5.2% year-over-year for the first three quarters of 2025, which may influence market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Jin10 Futures Morning Report, October 21, 2025 (Tuesday)</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/63534555/jin10-futures-morning-report-october-21-2025-tuesday</link><description>The report covers broader commodity trends including iron ore shipments and steel production in China, with no direct update on nickel prices. However, it provides context on raw material supply and demand which can impact nickel market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On October 21, the price of SMM #1 refined nickel was up</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103578980/</link><description>The price of SMM #1 refined nickel increased by 400 yuan/mt to an average of 122,500 yuan/mt, reflecting a short-term price rise in refined nickel on October 21, 2025.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali transaction closing: Walsin Lihwa Corporation at 70% of capital</title><link>https://www.industrialvalvenews.com/featured/cogne-acciai-speciali-transaction-closing-walsin-lihwa-corporation-at-70-of-capital/</link><description>Walsin Lihwa Corporation has become the majority shareholder of Cogne Acciai Speciali with a 70% stake, while the Marzorati family retains 30%. Yu-Lon Chiao will succeed Eng. Giuseppe Marzorati as President starting December 1st, and Massimiliano Burelli has been appointed CEO to lead integration and growth plans.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris to launch TenarisShawcor White Jacket™ coating at the Hydrogen and CCUS Technology World Expo</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-to-launch-tenarisshawcor-white-jacket-coating-at-the-hydrogen-and-ccus-technology-world-expo</link><description>Tenaris is unveiling its new TenarisShawcor White Jacket™ coating system at the Hydrogen and Carbon Capture Technology World Expo in Hamburg, Germany. The coating is designed for severe onshore and underground pipeline applications, offering enhanced mechanical strength and resistance for hydrogen and carbon capture transportation pipelines.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash price rises to $2,780/t as opening stocks dip to 484,125t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-price-rises-to-2-780-t-as-opening-stocks-dip-to-484-125t-115905</link><description>The London Metal Exchange (LME) aluminium cash price increased to $2,780 per tonne on October 21, supported by falling stocks and steady demand. LME aluminium opening stocks declined 0.62% to 484,125 tonnes, while cancelled warrants dropped sharply, signaling potential moderation in physical demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum reshoring hits energy wall as AI and data centres surge</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5101754-aluminum-reshoring-hits-energy-wall-as-ai-and-data-centres-surge</link><description>Efforts to reshore aluminum production to the US are facing challenges due to surging energy demand from AI and data centers, which is straining power grids and complicating plans to boost domestic aluminum output.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>7 Critical Threats Facing the Global Aluminum Industry</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/aluminum-industry-threats-environmental-production-costs-2025/</link><description>The aluminum industry faces challenges including carbon emissions, evolving regulations like the EU's CBAM, and rising production costs. The energy-intensive Hall-Héroult process contributes significantly to greenhouse gas emissions, prompting stricter regulatory scrutiny. Companies are responding by investing in emissions monitoring, engaging with policymakers, and forming coalitions to balance compliance with competitiveness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Can circular aluminium provide a blueprint for a post-plastic world?</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/can-circular-aluminium-provide-a-blueprint-for-a-post-plastic-world/61691/</link><description>Circular aluminium offers significant sustainability benefits due to its infinite recyclability and existing recycling infrastructure, contrasting with plastics' recycling challenges. Producing recycled aluminium requires only 5% of the energy of virgin production, substantially reducing emissions. Expanding circular aluminium use could support a sustainable economy and reduce reliance on plastics, though broader adoption and improved recycling rates are needed.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Stainless Steel Daily Review: SS Futures Slightly Recover, Testing 12,700 Yuan/mt</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Steel-Billet</link><description>Stainless steel futures showed a recovery with prices climbing to 12,700 yuan/mt, supported by a rise in metal futures overall. Spot market enquiries increased, and market confidence improved, leading to higher quotations despite cautiousness about high prices. Stainless steel planned production in October is expected to approach 3.45 million mt, although downstream demand recovery remains limited.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Atico Produces 2.24 Million Pounds of Copper and 1,906 Ounces of Gold in Q3 2025</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/21/3170676/0/en/Atico-Produces-2-24-Million-Pounds-of-Cu-and-1-906-Ounces-of-Au-in-Third-Quarter-2025.html</link><description>Atico Mining Corporation reported production of 2.24 million pounds of copper and 1,906 ounces of gold in concentrates for the third quarter of 2025, representing decreases of 23% and 8% respectively compared to the same period in 2024. The company revised its mine plan to include lower-grade ore from lower mine zones, expecting improved production in the following quarter.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Asian Battery Metals Unlocks Mongolia's Copper-Nickel Potential with BHP Backing and High-Grade Discoveries</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/asian-battery-metals-unlocks-mongolias-copper-nickel-potential-with-bhp-backing-and-high-grade-discoveries</link><description>Asian Battery Metals reports encouraging metallurgical results from its Oval project in Mongolia, with copper recovery rates of 89–95% and concentrate grades of 18.5–24%, indicating strong economic potential. Nickel recovery is still being optimized, and the company is conducting detailed mineralogical studies in Japan and Australia to inform process design and assess byproduct potential from platinum group elements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Jeep Factory Halted for Three Weeks After Aluminum Plant Fire</title><link>https://www.claimsjournal.com/news/national/2025/10/22/333647.htm</link><description>A Stellantis NV plant in Michigan is shut down for several weeks due to a shortage of aluminum parts caused by a fire at a Novelis Inc. aluminum plant in Oswego, New York. The fire, which occurred on September 16, damaged the hot mill and other production areas, disrupting supply to automakers including Stellantis and Ford. Novelis expects to resume hot mill operations in the first quarter of 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Governments Announce Support for Alcoa's Gallium Critical Mineral Development Project in Western Australia</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251020262396/en/Governments-Announce-Support-for-Alcoas-Gallium-Critical-Mineral-Development-Project-in-Western-Australia</link><description>Alcoa is advancing a project to develop gallium, a critical mineral extracted from bauxite during alumina refining, with support from the US and Australian governments. Gallium is vital for technology and defense sectors. The project aims for a final investment decision and production in 2026, highlighting Alcoa's role in securing critical mineral supply chains linked to aluminum production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Century Aluminum Reports Electrical Equipment Failure Affecting One Potline at Grundartangi, Iceland Smelter</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/6225204</link><description>Century Aluminum reported an electrical equipment failure impacting one potline at its Grundartangi smelter in Iceland. The incident may affect aluminum production capacity at the facility, though specific details on the extent and duration of the impact were not provided.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel rose to 3,050 CNY/T on October 22, 2025, up 0.46% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices increased slightly to 3,050 CNY per ton on October 22, 2025, marking a 0.46% rise from the previous day. Despite this daily increase, steel prices have fallen 0.68% over the past month and are down 4.87% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect steel prices to trade at around 3,008.71 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and forecast a decline to 2,875.97 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel fell to 806.08 USD/T on October 22, 2025, down 0.85% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices declined by 0.85% to 806.08 USD per ton on October 22, 2025. Over the past month, HRC steel prices have fallen 2.65%, but remain 14.50% higher than a year ago. Forecasts suggest prices will rise to 829.86 USD/T by the end of the quarter and reach 893.93 USD/T within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nation's green initiatives a catalyst for global change</title><link>http://www.ecns.cn/m/news/economy/2025-10-22/detail-ihewipfr4342748.shtml</link><description>China has become a global leader in green technology innovation, including ultra-low emission steelmaking technologies that support clean and low-carbon transitions worldwide. The country has significantly expanded its new energy vehicle sector and renewable transitions, contributing to global green development momentum.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Electra Unveils Demonstration Facility along with Advanced Purchase Commitments for Clean Iron and Environmental Attributes</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/10/22/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/electra-unveils-demonstration-facility-along-with-advanced-purchase-commitments-for-clean-iron-and-environmental-attributes/2205419</link><description>Electra has launched a demonstration facility showcasing clean iron production technologies and secured advanced purchase commitments for clean iron and environmental attributes, highlighting progress in sustainable steelmaking innovations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Russia-Ukraine Peace Plan Progresses Step by Step, LME Copper Plunged Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103580305/Russia-Ukraine-Peace-Plan-Progresses-Step-by-Step-LME-Copper-Plunged-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper opened at $10,639.5/mt, initially rose to $10,658.5/mt, then fell to a low of $10,542/mt before closing at $10,596.5/mt, down 1.08%. SHFE copper also declined, closing at 85,020 yuan/mt, down 0.6%, amid significant trading volume and open interest.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper falls on stronger dollar, muted demand from China</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-falls-on-stronger-dollar-muted-demand-from-china/</link><description>Copper prices fell 0.3% to $15,175, pressured by a stronger US dollar and weaker demand from China, according to Reuters.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Teck Reports Unaudited Third Quarter Results for 2025</title><link>https://www.teck.com/news/news-releases/2025/teck-reports-unaudited-third-quarter-results-for-2025</link><description>Teck's Q3 2025 copper production at its Quebrada Blanca (QB) mine was 39,600 tonnes, down 12,900 tonnes from the same period last year due to tailings management facility development causing concentrator downtime. Annual copper production guidance for 2025 at QB is between 170,000 and 190,000 tonnes, with ongoing improvements in ultra-fines removal and sand placement techniques to enhance operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ageing Mines Tighten Global Copper Supply Lines</title><link>https://mining.com.au/ageing-mines-tighten-global-copper-supply-lines/</link><description>Copper-in-concentrate production from the combined Kamoa-Kakula operation fell nearly 16% in Q2 2025 and a further 36% in Q3 2025, contributing to tighter global copper supply lines. The decline highlights challenges from ageing mines impacting overall copper availability in the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP Iron Ore and Copper Production Guidance Targets 2026</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/bhp-strategic-production-framework-2026-iron-ore-copper/</link><description>BHP outlined its production guidance for iron ore and copper for 2026, emphasizing stable copper prices around USD $4.60 per pound driven by strong demand from energy transition applications. The company plans to focus on copper expansion projects and operational optimization amid supply-side constraints supporting price stability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Southern Copper Corporation Secures Mining Licence for Tía María Project</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103581284/</link><description>Southern Copper Corporation has obtained a mining licence for its USD 1.8 billion Tía María copper project in Peru's Arequipa region, advancing its development plans. This milestone supports the company's strategy to increase copper production capacity in the region.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Nickel Mining: 2026 Innovations For Sustainable Growth</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-nickel-mining-2026-innovations-for-sustainable-growth</link><description>This piece discusses upcoming innovations in copper and nickel mining, such as autonomous equipment and water recycling systems, which are set to improve efficiency and reduce environmental impact. These technologies will play a crucial role in sustainable mining practices by 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, Silver &amp; Copper: tech and sustainability trends</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_ca/insights/mining-metals/gold-silver-and-copper-tech-and-sustainability-trends</link><description>The article explores how copper companies are leveraging technology and sustainability to address supply gaps. This includes using digital innovations, advanced mineral processing, and recycling to enhance production and reduce environmental impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global nickel premiums stagnant amid falling LME nickel price</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/global-nickel-premiums-stagnant-amid-falling-lme-nickel-price/</link><description>The LME three-month nickel price closed at $16,316 per tonne on October 22, down from $17,424 per tonne a week earlier, marking the lowest close since September 18. Nickel premiums remained unchanged in China with thin liquidity, while import arbitrage losses slightly improved but remained negative.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices dropped to a four-year low, falling as much as 2.3% to $15,235 per tonne on the LME, driven by a pessimistic Federal Reserve outlook and stronger dollar expectations. Despite Indonesia considering deep cuts to nickel mining quotas to support prices, the market remains pressured by new supply and slowing electric vehicle sales.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>This 35-year-old is stockpiling $250,000 in nickels as a bet against inflation</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/marketwatch/20251021348/this-35-year-old-is-stockpiling-250000-in-nickels-as-a-bet-against-inflation-this-has-zero-downside</link><description>An individual is accumulating $250,000 worth of nickels as a hedge against inflation and potential future metal scarcity, despite nickel prices remaining unchanged this year. The strategy hinges on the possibility of coin debasement or increased metal value, although melting coins is currently illegal in the U.S.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel firm Anugrah Neo Energy eyes over $300 million IPO</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-firm-anugrah-neo-energy-eyes-over-300-million-ipo</link><description>Indonesian nickel mining and processing company Anugrah Neo Energy Materials is planning an initial public offering (IPO) aiming to raise over $300 million. The move highlights growing investor interest in nickel production amid rising global demand for battery metals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>EIB Pursuing Critical Minerals Investments in Australia</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/european-investment-bank-australia-critical-minerals-2025/</link><description>The European Investment Bank is targeting investments in Australia's critical minerals sector, including nickel, focusing on mining, processing, and recycling. The article discusses opportunities for sustainable development and circular economy initiatives aligned with global climate goals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to 3-Year High Amid Tight Supply</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged to a three-year high, reaching $2,809.80 per tonne, driven by tight supply conditions and strong demand from clean energy sectors. China's aluminum output cap and power shortages have limited smelting output, contributing to the price increase. The market expects prices to continue rising due to ongoing supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>NioCorp and IBC Advanced Alloys Successfully Cast Aluminum-Scandium Alloy for Potential Expansion into Al-Sc Alloy Parts</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/NB/nio-corp-and-ibc-advanced-alloys-successfully-cast-aluminum-scandium-zdzavznowdye.html</link><description>NioCorp and IBC Advanced Alloys announced the successful commercial production of a 0.2% aluminum-scandium (Al-Sc) alloy at IBC's foundry in Franklin, Indiana. The alloy met target purity and specifications, supporting further processing for cast, forged, extruded, and additive-manufactured parts. This development advances potential scandium applications in aerospace, automotive, electronics, and defense, with Elk Creek project aiming to produce about 100 tonnes/year of scandium oxide subject to financing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>UAE Delivers First Batch of Low-Carbon Aluminium Powered by Nuclear Energy from Barakah</title><link>https://gccbusinesswatch.com/news/uae-delivers-first-batch-of-low-carbon-aluminium-powered-by-nuclear-energy-from-barakah/</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Emirates Nuclear Energy Company have delivered the UAE's first batch of low-carbon aluminium produced using clean electricity from the Barakah Nuclear Energy Plant. This product, branded MinimAL, represents a significant step in industrial sustainability by using nuclear power to decarbonize aluminium production, with the aluminium supplied to Egypt's CANEX Aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The more sustainability and transparency, the better the decisions</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/the-more-transparency-the-better-the-decisions/59167/</link><description>Speira has ceased primary aluminium production to focus entirely on recycling, aiming to reduce energy use and CO2 emissions by up to 95% compared to primary production. The company invests in advanced recycling technologies to close material loops and improve circularity, especially recycling beverage cans multiple times a year to maximize sustainability benefits.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Recycled aluminium for sustainable shipbuilding</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/recycled-aluminium-for-sustainable-shipbuilding/54273/</link><description>Speira's recycled aluminium alloy, VIA Maris, offers a sustainable and mechanically superior material for the maritime industry, including yacht builder Arksen's hybrid propulsion vessels. This marine-grade aluminium helps reduce environmental impact while maintaining high performance, supporting the industry's shift toward sustainability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>NioCorp and IBC Advanced Alloys Successfully Cast Aluminum-Scandium Alloy for Potential Expansion into Al-Sc Alloy Parts</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/NB/nio-corp-and-ibc-advanced-alloys-successfully-cast-aluminum-scandium-zdzavznowdye.html</link><description>NioCorp and IBC Advanced Alloys announced the successful commercial production of a 0.2% aluminum-scandium alloy, meeting purity and specification targets. This advancement supports future applications in aerospace, automotive, electronics, and defense, with plans to produce up to 100 tonnes/year of scandium oxide pending project financing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>2Q 2025 Cost Report: As Steel, Aluminum Tariffs Rise to 50%, Feds OK US Steel Sale to Nippon Steel</title><link>https://www.enr.com/articles/60920-2q-2025-cost-report-as-steel-aluminum-tariffs-rise-to-50-feds-ok-us-steel-sale-to-nippon-steel</link><description>The U.S. government has increased tariffs on steel and aluminum imports to 50%, aiming to curb surges of Chinese steel exports. The American Iron and Steel Institute supports the tariff hike amid growing global steel overcapacity. Meanwhile, Nippon Steel's planned acquisition of U.S. Steel could restart significant blast furnace capacity, potentially tempering steel prices despite the tariff environment.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nucor raises prices for thick-gauge rolled steel by $60/t starting in November</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/nucor-raises-prices-for-thick-gauge-rolled-steel-by-60-t-starting-in-november/</link><description>Nucor announced a price increase of $60 per ton for thick-gauge rolled steel products effective November 2025. The new theoretical price for standard thickness A36 base rolled products is estimated to be around $1,335 per ton, reflecting ongoing adjustments in steel pricing amid market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Angola's First Major Copper Mine Starts Production</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/angolas-first-major-copper-mine-starts-production/</link><description>Angola's Tetelo copper mine, valued at $250 million and owned by China's Shining Star Icarus, is set to begin production, producing around 25,000 metric tons of copper concentrate annually in its first two years. The mine will start as an open-pit operation, transitioning to underground mining in the second half of 2026. This marks a significant step for Angola in diversifying its economy beyond oil and entering the clean energy minerals market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Angola expands beyond oil as first copper mine starts production</title><link>https://africa.businessinsider.com/local/markets/angola-expands-beyond-oil-as-first-major-copper-mine-starts-production/dwr07gr</link><description>Angola's Tetelo copper mine is about to commence production, aiming to diversify the economy beyond oil. The $250 million project is expected to produce 25,000 metric tons of copper concentrate annually during its first two years, starting with open-pit mining and moving underground in late 2026. This development highlights Angola's ambition to attract investment in critical minerals essential for renewable energy technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>AI Boom Pushes Copper Toward a Supply Crunch, BNEF Warns</title><link>https://www.mining.com/video/ai-boom-pushes-copper-toward-a-supply-crunch-bnef-warns/</link><description>A BloombergNEF report highlights that the AI boom is increasing copper demand, potentially leading to a supply crunch. This surge in demand, combined with energy transition projects and fragile mine supply, puts pressure on the copper market. Prices could reach $13,500 per tonne by 2028.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>PE eyes BHP's Nickel West as China tightens rare earth grip</title><link>https://www.marketsgroup.org/news/pe-eyes-bhps-nickel-west-as-china-tightens-rare-earth-grip</link><description>Private equity firms are showing interest in BHP's Nickel West assets in Australia as nickel prices have halved over three years due to a flood of low-cost Indonesian production, much of it under Chinese control. BHP's Nickel West has been running at a loss and is now up for sale, with potential buyers eyeing a piecemeal acquisition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Falls</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103583944/SMM-Flash-News:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Falls-100-mt-WoW-to-54700-mt-on-Oct-23</link><description>Domestic secondary aluminum ingot inventory has decreased, supported by rising raw material prices. This trend reflects the ongoing dynamics in the aluminum market, where supply and demand imbalances continue to influence prices. The decrease in inventory suggests a tightening market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Kaiser Aluminum Corporation Reports Third Quarter 2025 Financial Results</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251022822873/en/Kaiser-Aluminum-Corporation-Reports-Third-Quarter-2025-Financial-Results</link><description>Kaiser Aluminum Corporation announced Q3 2025 financial results with net sales of $844 million and net income of $40 million, up significantly from the previous year. The company serves aerospace, automotive, packaging, and general engineering markets with semi-fabricated specialty aluminum products. Kaiser raised its full-year 2025 adjusted EBITDA outlook, reflecting strong operational performance.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel rose to 3,061 CNY/T on October 23, 2025, up 0.33% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices increased slightly by 0.33% to 3,061 CNY per ton on October 23, 2025. Despite this short-term rise, steel prices have fallen 0.81% over the past month and are down 4.88% compared to the same time last year. Analysts expect steel prices to trade at around 3,009 Yuan/MT by the end of this quarter and forecast a decline to 2,876 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Poland's Cognor commissions new high-tech rolling mill in Siemianowice Śląskie</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/polands-cognor-commissions-new-high-tech-rolling-mill-in-siemianowice-lskie-1415747.htm</link><description>Polish steelmaker Cognor Group has completed the construction of a new hot rolling mill for bars and sections in Siemianowice Śląskie, Poland. The mill began production and is designed to deliver an annual output of about 450,000 mt of steel products. It incorporates automation, robotics, and AI-based process control to enhance productivity and product quality.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU steel and automotive industries urge pragmatic transition</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/eu-steel-and-automotive-industries-urge-pragmatic-transition-1415959.htm</link><description>The European Automobile Manufacturers’ Association (ACEA) and the European Steel Association (EUROFER) issued a joint statement calling for a realistic transition to maintain production and investment in Europe. Both industries face challenges like global steel overcapacity and high energy costs. They urge EU leaders to establish a framework that safeguards employment and competitiveness.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Peru's Tía María Copper Mine Project Approved, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103582567/Perus-T%C3%ADa-Mar%C3%ADa-Copper-Mine-Project-Approved-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Peru's Tía María copper mine project has been approved, marking a significant development in the country's mining sector. LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, closing at $10,658.5/mt, a gain of 0.59%. The project's approval is expected to boost investor confidence in Peru's mining environment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Update</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to $4.97 per pound on October 23, 2025, reflecting a slight increase from the previous day. Over the past month, copper has seen a significant price rise of about 4.65%. Analysts expect copper to reach $5.08 per pound by the end of the quarter.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>2025 Copper Supply Crisis: Disruptions Soar as Major Mines Cut or Halt Production</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103566538</link><description>Copper mine supply disruptions surged in 2025 with major mines like Grasberg in Indonesia and Quebrada Blanca in Chile reducing or suspending production. Grasberg's 2025 copper output is projected to drop to 488,000 tonnes from an earlier estimate of 750,000 tonnes due to a tailings leak accident. Teck Resources also lowered production guidance for Quebrada Blanca and Highland Valley Copper due to ongoing tailings dam work and declining ore grades.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Highly encouraging mineralised indicators as Phase 1 drilling nears the Southern Porphyry’s main target at Llahuin</title><link>https://www.shmining.com.au/2025/10/highly-encouraging-mineralised-indicators-as-phase-1-drilling-nears-the-southern-porphyrys-main-target-at-llahuin/</link><description>Southern Hemisphere Mining reports promising mineralised indicators in Phase 1 drilling at the Llahuin Copper Gold Project in Chile. Shallow epithermal veins with up to 1.7% copper and porphyry indicators have been intersected, confirming the presence of mineralised veins near the main target. The drilling is progressing beyond 800 meters downhole, approaching the primary porphyry target.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Data Centers Are Helping Drive a Surge in Copper Demand</title><link>https://www.fierce-network.com/cloud/data-centers-are-about-rock-copper-industry</link><description>The boom in data centers is driving up copper demand, contributing to supply shortages. This increased demand is part of a broader trend where copper is essential for electrification and digital infrastructure. The data center industry's growth exacerbates existing supply chain challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Remain Stable Amid Market Trends</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103583235/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price was reported at 120,800-123,500 yuan/mt with an average of 122,150 yuan/mt, showing a slight increase from the previous day. Nickel prices have been trending within a stable range recently. Global market dynamics, including supply and demand factors, continue to influence nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Sulphate Prices Remain Stable</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103583939/</link><description>The SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price was stable at 28,439 yuan/mt. This reflects ongoing stability in the nickel sulphate market, which is crucial for battery production. The stable pricing suggests consistent demand and supply conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Germany Halts Commemorative Silver Coin Production Amid Soaring Silver Prices</title><link>http://markets.chroniclejournal.com/chroniclejournal/article/marketminute-2025-10-23-germany-halts-commemorative-silver-coin-production-amid-soaring-silver-prices</link><description>Germany has halted the production of commemorative silver coins due to soaring silver prices. This decision reflects the increasing value of precious metals and their impact on numismatic markets. Although not directly related to nickel, it highlights broader trends in precious metals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Central Omega (DKFT) Achieves Nickel Ore Production of 2.07 Million Tons Through Q3 2025</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/central-omega-dkft-achieves-nickel-ore-production-of-207-million-tons-through-q3-2025</link><description>Central Omega (DKFT) has reported nickel ore production of 2.07 million tons through the third quarter of 2025, highlighting continued strong output from Indonesian nickel operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FPX Nickel Provides Update on Fall 2025 Community Open House Events</title><link>https://investingnews.com/fpx-nickel-provides-update-on-fall-2025-community-open-house-events/</link><description>FPX Nickel Corp. is hosting community open houses for its Baptiste Nickel Project in British Columbia, a large-scale, low-carbon nickel project with the potential to be one of the world's lowest carbon-intensive nickel producers. The project is notable for its sulphur-free, high-grade awaruite mineralization and has been recognized by the Province of British Columbia as a critical minerals initiative.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SK On's answer to China's battery sector ascent: high-nickel, high-voltage</title><link>https://www.digitimes.com/news/a20251022PD230/sk-on-battery-nickel-cost-demand.html</link><description>SK On is advancing its high-nickel cathode technology to improve fast-charging capability, cycle life, and system safety in electric vehicle batteries. This innovation aims to compete with China's battery sector by enhancing performance through high-nickel content and high-voltage designs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US-Australia Critical Minerals Deal: Strategic Impact</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/us-australia-critical-minerals-partnership-2025/</link><description>The US-Australia partnership targets critical minerals including nickel to reduce supply chain vulnerabilities and support advanced manufacturing, renewable energy, and defense. The deal emphasizes accelerating lithium, cobalt, and nickel projects to secure battery material supplies essential for electric vehicles and energy storage.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Australian battery innovation receives $25M boost from ARENA</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/australian-battery-innovation-receives-25m-boost-from-arena/</link><description>The Australian Renewable Energy Agency (ARENA) awarded $25 million to Relectrify to commercialize its AC1 battery energy storage system, which delivers alternating current directly from battery cells without a separate inverter. This technology reduces battery degradation and improves energy delivery efficiency, supporting sustainable energy storage solutions.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Botswana Mining Diversification: Key Minerals &amp; Strategy</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/botswana-mining-diversification-critical-minerals-strategy-2025/</link><description>Botswana is pursuing sustainable mining diversification with a focus on critical minerals like nickel, emphasizing environmentally friendly processing and maximizing resource recovery. The strategy aims to foster long-term economic sustainability, community participation, and technological innovation to position Botswana as a leader in responsible mining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Future Minerals Forum 2025: Transforming Global Mining Partnerships</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/global-minerals-summit-2025-strategic-importance/</link><description>The forum highlights the critical role of nickel and other minerals in the energy transition and addresses supply chain vulnerabilities such as geographic concentration and processing capacity limitations. It emphasizes the need for innovation and sustainability initiatives to meet projected demand and secure supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>