<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 05:17:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US and Australia Launch Critical Minerals Partnership for 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/us-australia-critical-minerals-partnership-2025-2/</link><description>The US and Australia have formed a $1 billion partnership to enhance critical minerals supply chains, focusing on increasing battery material recycling efficiency to 40% by 2030 and advancing circular economy principles. The partnership also targets market transparency, fair trading practices, and innovation in alternative materials to reduce supply risks.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>New Technology Set to Revolutionize Nickel Pollution Cleanup</title><link>https://albanian-minerals.com/new-technology-set-to-revolutionize-nickel-pollution-cleanup/</link><description>A new technology has been developed to significantly improve nickel pollution cleanup, aiming to enhance environmental protection related to nickel mining and processing. This innovation supports cleaner air and water by addressing nickel contamination more effectively.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Launches Pilot Phase of Green Hydrogen Project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has launched the pilot phase of its green hydrogen project in Aosta, Italy. The project aims to reduce carbon emissions by using electrolysis to produce green hydrogen. The project is supported by funding from Italy's National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali to Benefit from Enhanced Energy Performance</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will enhance its energy performance and reduce environmental impact through a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA. This agreement supports regional decarbonization targets and improves economic competitiveness.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Continuous Casting Machine Modernization at Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://uk.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/DANIELI-C-OFFICINE-MECCAN-69524/news/Danieli-C-Officine-Meccaniche-S-p-A-Continuous-casting-machine-modernization-at-Cogne-Acciai-Spe-47435416/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has contracted Danieli Service for a modernization project at its works in Aosta, Italy. The project focuses on modernizing a continuous casting machine.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Base Metals Market Navigates Volatility: Aluminum Shines ...</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-10-24-base-metals-market-navigates-volatility-aluminum-shines-zinc-squeezed-lead-lingers-amidst-shifting-global-dynamics</link><description>Aluminum has been a standout performer in 2025, with LME aluminum forwards rising 5.06% in the first nine months and continuing to climb in October, reaching $2,857.50 USD/T on October 24. The price increase is driven by strong demand from energy transition sectors and supply constraints including China's production cap and alumina supply disruptions, pushing the market into an anticipated deficit for 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,859.90 USD/T on October 24, 2025, down 0.11% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices slightly declined to $2,859.90 per tonne on October 24, 2025, down 0.11% from the previous day, but have risen 7.47% over the past month and 6.91% year-on-year. The market remains tight due to China's aluminum output cap and strong demand, with forecasts expecting prices around $2,805.80 by the end of the quarter and $2,929.65 in 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Oct '25 (ALV25) - Futures</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/futures/quotes/ALV25</link><description>Aluminum futures for October 2025 traded at a high of 2,776.75, showing a 9.29% increase over the past month and a 6.23% rise over three months. The 52-week performance shows a 2.48% increase compared to the previous year, indicating sustained upward momentum in aluminum prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Base Metals Market Navigates Volatility: Aluminum Shines ...</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-24-base-metals-market-navigates-volatility-aluminum-shines-zinc-squeezed-lead-lingers-amidst-shifting-global-dynamics</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged by 5.06% in the first nine months of 2025 and continued climbing into October, reaching a three-year peak near $2,900 per ton. This rise is driven by strong demand from electric vehicles, renewable energy infrastructure, and lightweight construction, alongside supply constraints such as China's cap on aluminum production and alumina supply disruptions, pushing the global market into an anticipated deficit for 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US aluminum scrap trade faces 2025 shake-up amid tariffs and global demand</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5101605-us-aluminum-scrap-trade-faces-2025-shake-up-amid-tariffs-and-global-demand</link><description>The US aluminum scrap trade experienced significant changes in early 2025 due to tariffs and shifting global demand. Imports of aluminum scrap rose 31% in the first half of 2025 compared to the previous year, despite a 25% import tariff introduced in March, which led recyclers to increasingly rely on domestic recovery.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa said it will invest about $60 million to modernize part of its aluminum smelter in Massena, New York</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103582998</link><description>Alcoa announced a $60 million investment to modernize part of its aluminum smelter in Massena, New York, following the signing of a new 10-year hydropower agreement. This modernization aims to enhance production efficiency and sustainability at the facility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Can circular aluminium provide a blueprint for a post-plastic world?</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/can-circular-aluminium-provide-a-blueprint-for-a-post-plastic-world/61691/</link><description>Ellie Gabel discusses the benefits, challenges, and future potential of circular aluminium in driving a sustainable economy and reducing reliance on plastics. Aluminium's infinite recyclability and existing recycling infrastructure make it a strong candidate for replacing plastics in a circular economy, with recycled aluminium requiring only 5% of the energy used for virgin production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa invests $60M in US aluminium smelter &amp; signs 10-year energy pact</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/alcoa-invests-60m-in-us-aluminium-smelter-signs-10-year-energy-pact-at-the-same-time-115933</link><description>Alcoa Corporation announced a $60 million investment in its Massena Operations in New York, including upgrades to the anode baking furnace, alongside a 10-year renewable energy pact with New York Power Authority. This initiative aims to strengthen sustainable aluminium production in the US by combining renewable energy with advanced furnace technology.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The future of US aluminium hinges on energy, not tariff policy</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/the-future-of-us-aluminium-hinges-on-energy-not-tariff-policy-heres-why-115920</link><description>Industry leaders emphasize that affordable electricity, rather than tariffs, is the key to revitalizing US aluminium production. Aluminium smelting is highly energy-intensive, requiring long-term energy contracts at competitive rates to be financially viable, with current US industrial electricity prices posing a significant challenge compared to hydro-rich Canada.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Base Metals Market Navigates Volatility: Aluminum Shines Amidst Shifting Global Dynamics</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-10-24-base-metals-market-navigates-volatility-aluminum-shines-zinc-squeezed-lead-lingers-amidst-shifting-global-dynamics</link><description>Aluminum prices have surged in 2025 driven by strong demand from the energy transition sectors such as electric vehicles and renewable energy infrastructure. Supply constraints, including China's production caps and alumina disruptions, have tightened the market, pushing global aluminum supply into a deficit and highlighting its critical role in sustainable technologies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>"METALEX 2025" Ready to Spotlight Next-Generation Machinery Driving ASEAN Metalworking Toward Smart Manufacturing</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/10/24/metalex-2025-ready-to-spotlight-next-generation-machinery-driving-asean-metalworking-toward-smart-manufacturing/</link><description>METALEX 2025 conference features sessions on aluminum industry trends, smart manufacturing, and sustainability, including an International Symposium on Light Materials Technology focusing on Thailand's readiness as an aluminum innovation hub. The event highlights AI applications, robotics, and sustainable manufacturing technologies relevant to aluminum production and processing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel price rises slightly to 3,054 CNY/T on October 24, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices increased by 0.46% from the previous day, reaching 3,054 CNY/T. Despite this daily rise, steel prices have fallen 0.75% over the past month and are down 5.83% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect steel to trade at around 3,009 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,876 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 4-week High at 832 USD/T</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices rose to 815 USD/T on October 24, 2025, up 0.25% from the previous day, reaching a 4-week high of 832 USD/T. Over the past 12 months, HRC steel prices have increased by 13.64%, although recent weeks showed some volatility with a 12-week low recorded in late September.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Usiminas reports net loss of $651 million in Q3 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/usiminas-reports-net-loss-in-q3-2025-1416635.htm</link><description>Brazilian steel producer Usiminas posted a net loss of BRL 3.503 billion ($651.1 million) in Q3 2025, reversing from a net profit in the same quarter last year. The loss was mainly due to asset impairment and deferred tax recoverability issues, though excluding these, the company reported a net profit. Steel product sales volume declined by 2%, while iron ore sales increased by 9%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Stellar Steel to Invest $450 Million in New Steel Plant in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/chinas-stellar-steel-to-invest-450-million-in-new-steel-plant-in-nigeria-1416525.htm</link><description>China's Stellar Steel is investing $450 million in a new steel plant in Nigeria's Ogun State. The facility will produce hot-rolled coil steel, iron steel doors, and gas cylinders, aiming to reduce Nigeria's reliance on imported steel products. Operations are expected to begin by mid-2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Usiminas Reports Net Loss in Q3 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/usiminas-reports-net-loss-in-q3-2025-1416635.htm</link><description>Usiminas reported a net loss of BRL 3.503 billion ($651.1 million) for Q3 2025, primarily due to asset impairments. The company's steel sales declined by 2%, while iron ore sales increased by 9%. Despite the loss, Usiminas noted stable cash flow.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Brazil's Steel Demand to Slow: Usiminas</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2746392-brazil-s-steel-demand-to-slow-usiminas</link><description>Usiminas expects Brazil's steel demand to slow in the fourth quarter, following seasonal trends. The company reported a decline in crude steel production and rolled steel output. Despite recent price increases, Usiminas forecasts stable steel prices for the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Sassda Spearheads Stainless Steel Master Plan As Sector Roadmap to 2030</title><link>https://infrastructurenews.co.za/2025/10/24/sassda-spearheads-stainless-steel-master-plan-as-sector-roadmap-to-2030/</link><description>The Southern Africa Stainless Steel Development Association (Sassda) has launched a new Stainless Steel Master Plan to guide the sector's growth and sustainability to 2030. The plan involves a wide range of stakeholders to align industrial growth with sustainability and social objectives. It aims to realize stainless steel's potential as a high-value contributor to South Africa's economy.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price tumbles as Trump threatens massive new tariffs on China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-tumbles-as-trump-threatens-massive-new-tariffs-on-china/</link><description>Copper prices dropped nearly 5% to below $10,400 per ton on the London Metal Exchange after President Trump threatened a significant increase in tariffs on Chinese goods. This caused market turmoil, reversing recent rallies driven by supply setbacks in major copper mines and raising concerns about trade tensions impacting the metal's demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to $5.09 per pound on October 24, 2025, up 0.29% from the previous day and showing a 7.74% increase over the past month. The metal is up 17.33% compared to the same time last year, with expectations to trade around $5.08 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.59 in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price rises on mine struggles, Goldman bull flag</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-rises-on-mine-struggles-goldman-bull-flag/</link><description>Copper prices climbed nearly 2% as major miners issued conservative production outlooks, exacerbating supply concerns amid global mine disruptions. Chile’s Antofagasta expects to hit the low end of its 2025 production target and provided a 2026 forecast below analyst expectations, signaling ongoing tightness in the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump reverses Biden-era copper smelter pollution limits to boost mineral security</title><link>https://www.financialexpress.com/world-news/us-news/trump-reverses-biden-era-copper-smelter-pollution-limits-to-boost-mineral-security/4021001/</link><description>The Trump administration has rolled back stricter emission limits on copper smelters, providing a two-year compliance exemption to support domestic production. The policy targets the two operational U.S. smelters, citing concerns over industrial base erosion and reliance on foreign processing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump reverses Biden-era rules on copper smelters</title><link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/trump-reverses-biden-copper-smelter-rules-10325538/</link><description>President Trump has revoked Biden-era pollution rules for copper smelters, offering a two-year exemption to the two remaining U.S. facilities. The administration framed the move as essential for maintaining mineral independence and reducing reliance on foreign copper processing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Products Market worth $645.86 billion by 2035 at 5.6%</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/24/3172837/0/en/Copper-Products-Market-worth-645-86-billion-by-2035-at-5-6-says-MarketsandMarkets.html</link><description>The copper products market is projected to grow significantly due to demand from construction, power, electronics, and industrial manufacturing sectors. Copper’s recyclability and durability make it a preferred material for sustainable urbanization, smart city development, and energy-efficient systems, reinforcing its role in green infrastructure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Cobalt And Nickel Mining Companies: 2026 Sustainable Trends</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/cobalt-and-nickel-mining-companies-2026-sustainable-trends</link><description>By 2026, over 60% of cobalt and nickel mining companies will adopt sustainable extraction methods for battery supply chains. Innovations include AI-driven environmental monitoring, blockchain traceability, and recycling to reduce dependence on virgin mining. These technologies support environmental management and supply security in the growing battery metals market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel and NetCarb Advance Strategic Partnership to Unlock Zero-Carbon Industrial Cluster in Northeastern Ontario</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/canada-nickel-and-netcarb-advance-strategic-partnership-to-unlock-zero-carbon-industrial-cluster-in-northeastern-ontario-302591367.html</link><description>Canada Nickel and NetCarb are progressing in developing a proprietary carbon sequestration process that could sequester up to ten times more CO2 than current methods while producing valuable by-products like hydrogen and magnesium. This technology aims to position the Timmins Nickel District as a decarbonization hub and create new economic opportunities through sustainable nickel mining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Re-energising the nickel industry through sustainable battery production</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/re-energising-nickel-industry-through-sustainable-battery-production/29252/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals is developing the TECH Project, a carbon-negative facility in Australia that will produce high-grade, ethically sourced nickel for batteries using the patented DNi Process™. This environmentally friendly process recycles 98% of nitric acid, requires no tailings dam, and minimizes waste, supporting sustainable nickel laterite ore processing for the EV and energy storage sectors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Mining Tech Revolution: Driving Faster Adoption in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/mining-technology-adoption-critical-mineral-demand-2025/</link><description>The mining sector is accelerating technology adoption to meet surging demand for critical minerals like nickel, driven by renewable energy growth and EV market expansion. Challenges include declining ore grades and rising operational costs, making advanced mining technologies essential to sustain supply and support the global energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Engineering the future: how Tubacex innovation is advancing connection technologies for critical energy applications through the DESSERT project</title><link>https://www.tubacex.com/en/engineering-the-future-how-tubacex-innovation-is-advancing-connection-technologies-for-critical-energy-applications-through-the-dessert-project/</link><description>Tubacex is innovating in premium connection technologies and hydrogen energy through the DESSERT project, supporting safer hydrogen storage and utilization as a sustainable energy resource. This initiative highlights the company's commitment to advancing sustainable energy solutions and the energy transition.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>CVA to construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily benefiting Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali will benefit from enhanced energy performance and reduced environmental impact through a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA, which will build four photovoltaic plants in Sicily with over 20 MW capacity. This partnership supports the company's decarbonisation goals and economic competitiveness within the 2026–2029 Strategic Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of its green hydrogen production project at its Aosta plant, using a 1.008 MW electrolyzer to produce 165 tons of hydrogen annually. Supported by €7.9 million from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan, the project aims to reduce carbon emissions and power one of the plant's furnaces entirely with green hydrogen.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has commenced operations at a pilot green hydrogen plant in Aosta, northern Italy, marking a significant step in its sustainability and decarbonisation efforts within the steel production sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel rose to 3054 CNY/T on October 24, 2025, up 0.46% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices increased slightly to 3,054 CNY per tonne on October 24, 2025, up 0.46% from the previous day. However, over the past month, steel prices have fallen by 0.75% and are down 5.83% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect steel to trade at 3,022.85 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,890 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>CRU: JSW Steel powers to four-fold profit rise</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/24/cru-jsw-steel-powers-to-four-fold-profit-rise/</link><description>India's JSW Steel reported a 307% year-on-year jump in net profit to INR16.5 billion ($188 million) in fiscal Q2 2025-26. The report also notes global steel production declined through August 2025, with August marking the second-lowest monthly production this year, down 13% from March.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures rose to $5.09 per pound, reaching over one-week highs due to ongoing supply disruptions including mine collapses and halted operations in Indonesia and Chile. Prices have increased 7.74% over the past month and 17.33% year-over-year, supported by supply tightness and geopolitical factors affecting trade.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel futures fall to over 1-month low as oversupply persists</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures dropped to their lowest level in over a month, pressured by persistent oversupply from Indonesia, where production capacity has surged since the 2020 ore export ban. LME nickel stockpiles have risen sharply this year, reflecting weak demand from stainless steel manufacturers despite growing nickel use in electric vehicles.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hunting e-waste: India pushes for recycling of critical minerals</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/hunting-e-waste-india-pushes-for-recycling-of-critical-minerals-dismantlers-crushers-and-shredders-to-join-chain/articleshow/124821185.cms</link><description>India is expanding its electronic waste recycling capacity to recover critical minerals including nickel, lithium, and cobalt. The government launched a Rs 1,500 crore Incentive Scheme for Critical Mineral Recycling to reduce import dependence and promote sustainable recovery from e-waste and spent lithium-ion batteries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cash Aluminium Climbs to USD 2852.5/t on LME</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/cash-aluminium-climbs-to-usd-2-845-t-on-lme-inventories-shed-nearly-4-600t-115956</link><description>The cash price of aluminum on the London Metal Exchange (LME) rose to USD 2852.5/t, with a 0.33% increase. This rise is accompanied by a decrease in warehouse stocks by 4550 tonnes. The reduction in inventory levels supports the upward trend in aluminum prices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel rose to 3,054 CNY/T on October 24, 2025, up 0.46% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices increased slightly to 3,054 CNY per tonne on October 24, 2025, marking a 0.46% rise from the previous day. However, over the past month, steel prices have fallen by 0.75% and are down 5.83% compared to the same time last year. Steel is expected to trade at 3,022.85 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,890.00 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hovers Near $11000 as Market Tightness Intensifies</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/supply-disruptions-copper-market-2025/</link><description>Copper futures reached $10,962.50 per metric ton in recent London trading, marking a 25% gain year-to-date amid supply-demand imbalances rather than speculative trading. Strong Chinese manufacturing and renewable energy investments underpin sustained copper demand, while geopolitical trade policies continue to influence market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[Copper Inventory] On October 25th, LME copper inventory decreased by 1,550 tonnes to 276,775 tonnes</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103008947/LME-Metal-Inventories-Update-on-October-25th</link><description>The London Metal Exchange reported a decrease in copper inventory by 1,550 tonnes on October 25, 2025, lowering total stocks to 276,775 tonnes, indicating tightening supply conditions in the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hovers Near $11000 as Market Tightness Intensifies</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/supply-disruptions-copper-market-2025/</link><description>Copper futures are trading near $10,962.50 per ton, up about 25% year-to-date, as supply-demand imbalances drive prices toward record levels. Strong Chinese industrial demand, especially in renewable energy and electric vehicles, continues to support the market amid global supply disruptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Reverses Biden Copper Smelter Rules in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/trump-copper-smelter-policy-reversal-2025/</link><description>President Trump has reversed Biden-era emission standards for copper smelters, granting a two-year exemption to the two remaining U.S. facilities. The move aims to bolster domestic mineral security by reducing regulatory burdens on the already limited U.S. copper smelting industry.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME nickel prices rise on Oct 25 due to bullish news</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-prices-rise-on-oct-25-due-to-bullish-news/144361</link><description>LME nickel futures increased by US$43 on October 25, closing at US$18,317 per ton, while the spot price also rose by US$43 to US$18,085 per ton, reflecting bullish market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell slightly to 15,325 USD/T on October 24, down 0.07% from the previous day. Despite a 0.56% rise over the past month, prices remain 5.07% lower than a year ago, with forecasts suggesting a decline to around 14,206 USD/MT in the next 12 months due to oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>PP Presisi secures Rp150 billion contract for Antam nickel project</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/pp-presisi-secures-rp150-billion-contract-for-antam-nickel-project</link><description>PT PP Presisi Tbk has secured a contract worth Rp150 billion for an Antam nickel project, strengthening its presence in Indonesia's mining sector. The deal highlights the ongoing development of nickel projects in the region. Further details about the project's scope and timeline are not provided.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Axpo Italia to supply green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill</title><link>https://yieh.com/ru/NewsItem/150822</link><description>Axpo Italia has signed a Power Purchase Agreement (PPA) to supply 15 GWh of green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill in Italy. This agreement supports Tenaris's efforts to reduce its carbon footprint.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Alcoa invests $60M in US aluminium smelter &amp; signs 10-year energy pact at the same time</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/alcoa-invests-60m-in-us-aluminium-smelter-signs-10-year-energy-pact-at-the-same-time-115933</link><description>Alcoa Corporation announced a $60 million investment in its Massena, New York smelter and a new 10-year renewable energy agreement with the New York Power Authority, effective April 2026. The deal secures nearly 240 megawatts of renewable energy and supports sustainable aluminum production in the U.S., with potential for extension.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weekly Recap: Aluminium's low-carbon revolution in action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminium industry is undergoing a transformation focused on sustainability, innovation, and circular practices. Key developments include Taural India's adoption of Vedanta Aluminium's low-carbon Restora and green sand-casting techniques, reducing casting emissions by up to 80%, and Egypt's 'Dandara' Solar Energy project aiming to cut Egypt Aluminium's greenhouse gas emissions by 30% using renewable energy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>UAE Delivers First Batch of Low-Carbon Aluminium Powered by Nuclear Energy from Barakah</title><link>https://gccbusinesswatch.com/news/uae-delivers-first-batch-of-low-carbon-aluminium-powered-by-nuclear-energy-from-barakah/</link><description>Emirates Global Aluminium and Emirates Nuclear Energy Company have produced the UAE's first low-carbon aluminium using clean electricity from the Barakah Nuclear Energy Plant. This product, branded MinimAL, demonstrates nuclear energy's role in decarbonising heavy industries by providing constant, carbon-free power, and has been supplied to Egypt's CANEX Aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>BMW Group joins Aluminium Stewardship Initiative</title><link>https://www.press.bmwgroup.com/usa/article/detail/T0135476EN_US/bmw-group-joins-aluminium-stewardship-initiative?language=en_US</link><description>BMW Group has joined the Aluminium Stewardship Initiative to support the development of stringent sustainability standards across the aluminium value chain. The company emphasizes aluminium's role in lightweight construction and its use of recycled or renewable electricity-produced aluminium to reduce CO2 emissions, reinforcing BMW's leadership in sustainable mobility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market at Inflection Point as Indonesia Signals Q1 2026 Tightness</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-market-at-inflection-point-as-indonesia-signals-q1-2026-tightness</link><description>Nickel prices are testing the upper end of their 3-4 month range with potential upward movement expected as Chinese markets return from holiday. Indonesian supply management plans and government interventions in critical minerals are creating a structural shift, signaling tightness in Q1 2026 and significant revaluations in nickel-related stocks.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>CMOC Group's Strategic Expansion in Congo and Its Implications for Energy Transition Metals</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/cmoc-group-strategic-expansion-congo-implications-energy-transition-metals-2510/</link><description>CMOC Group is investing $1.08 billion in the Democratic Republic of Congo to boost copper output by 100,000 tons annually, supporting the global energy transition. The project balances growth with sustainability, aiming to meet rising copper demand amid geopolitical and ESG risks, reflecting the metal's critical role in green economy supply chains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Future Minerals Forum 2025: Transforming Global Mining Partnerships</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/global-minerals-summit-2025-strategic-importance/</link><description>The forum highlights the critical role of nickel and other minerals in the energy transition and addresses supply chain vulnerabilities such as geographic concentration and processing capacity limitations. It emphasizes the need for innovation and sustainability initiatives to meet projected demand and secure supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Governor Hochul Announces New Alcoa Power Contract Supporting 500 Jobs &amp; Long-Term Investment in the North Country</title><link>https://www.wnylabortoday.com/news/2025/10/26/new-york-state-labor-news/governor-hochul-announces-new-alcoa-power-contract-supporting-500-jobs-long-term-investment-in-the-north-country-the-usw-praises-all-involved-for-maintaining-good-union-jobs-that-serve-as-the-bedrock-of-our-communities/</link><description>New York Governor Kathy Hochul announced a new power supply contract between NYPA and Alcoa, supporting 500 jobs and a $60 million plant modernization through 2028. The agreement, bolstered by state grants and tax credits, ensures Alcoa's continued presence in Massena and regional economic stability.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>[SMM Analysis] Nickel prices pulled back this week due to fundamental pressure and inventory levels increased further</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575414/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-pulled-back-this-week-due-to-fundamental-pressure-and-inventory-levels-increased-further</link><description>Nickel prices declined under fundamental pressure with SHFE nickel futures closing down 1.89% week-on-week and LME nickel prices down 0.53%. The market is characterized by cost support at the bottom and inventory pressure at the top, with improved trading sentiment despite the price pullback.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion on the future of the Italian boilermaking industry focused on nuclear energy, held at Fondazione Dalmine in Italy. The event gathered industry and institutional experts to discuss nuclear energy's strategic role in Europe's energy transition and Italy's manufacturing potential. Tenaris's Italian mill recently obtained accreditation to supply certified materials for nuclear facilities, aligning with the highest technical and quality standards.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Axpo Italia to supply green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill in Italy</title><link>https://yieh.com/ru/NewsItem/150822</link><description>Under a Power Purchase Agreement, Axpo Italia will provide 15 GWh of green energy to Tenaris' Dalmine seamless steel pipe mill in Italy, supporting the mill's sustainability and energy efficiency goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Tenaris to invest US$200 million in Colombian mill</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-tenaris-to-invest-us200-million-in-colombian-mill/56956</link><description>Tenaris plans to invest US$200 million to build a new heat treatment mill and install advanced technology for ultrasound inspection and finishing. This investment aims to enhance production capabilities and product sophistication, although it concerns a Colombian facility rather than Italy directly.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>INALUM Signs Key Agreements at Osaka Expo 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103587659/INALUM-Signs-Key-Agreements-at-Osaka-Expo-2025-to-Globalize-Downstream-Aluminum-Strategy-and-Boost-Green-Economy</link><description>INALUM has signed significant agreements at the World Expo 2025 in Osaka to globalize its downstream aluminum strategy and boost the green economy. These agreements aim to enhance aluminum production and distribution capabilities.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Found Energy begins real-world test of zero-carbon reactor</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/aluminium-as-fuel-found-energy-begins-real-world-test-of-zero-carbon-reactor-115952</link><description>Found Energy, a Boston-based startup, is conducting the largest aluminium–water reactor test to convert scrap aluminium into zero-carbon industrial fuel. The 100-kilowatt reactor will be installed at a US tool manufacturing plant to produce heat and hydrogen, aiming to reduce industrial emissions through a circular waste-to-fuel model.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Driving Innovation for a Sustainable Future</title><link>https://www.aluminium-exhibition.com/germany/en-gb/blog/pressemitteilungen/alude2026-showpreparations.html</link><description>ALUMINIUM 2026 trade fair in Düsseldorf will emphasize sustainability with a focus on secondary aluminium for decarbonisation. The event will cover metal processing, recycling, automation, and cross-sector applications, featuring an expanded Sustainability &amp; Recycling Conference to share expert knowledge and best practices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Italian steel factory invests USD 14 mln in training center in Romania</title><link>https://www.romania-insider.com/italian-steel-factory-invests-usd-14-mln-in-training-center-in-romania</link><description>Italian steel company Tenaris invested USD 14 million in a training center for its 1,700 employees in Zalau, Romania. The investment aims to strengthen medium and long-term operations despite global challenges, with support from Romanian government officials and Tenaris leadership.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian has been awarded a tender by Terna S.p.A. and STEG for the construction of a submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia as part of the Elmed Project. The contract could reach a value of around €460 million and involves laying a power cable between Sicily and the Tunisian Cap Bon peninsula at depths up to 800 meters. This project aims to enhance energy security between Europe and Africa and supports the transition to cleaner energy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Will Prysmian's Shift to Recycled Copper Amid Tariffs Impact Its Business?</title><link>https://simplywall.st/stocks/it/capital-goods/bit-pry/prysmian-shares/news/will-prysmians-bitpry-shift-to-recycled-copper-amid-tariffs/</link><description>Prysmian has increased its use of recycled copper in the U.S. due to ongoing trade tensions and tariffs affecting the copper supply chain. This strategic shift aims to mitigate input cost volatility and maintain operational resilience. The move is part of Prysmian's broader efforts to adapt to global copper market disruptions while supporting its competitive position in cable production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian (BIT:PRY): Examining Valuation as Recycled Copper Strategy Advances</title><link>https://simplywall.st/stocks/it/capital-goods/bit-pry/prysmian-shares/news/prysmian-bitpry-examining-valuation-as-recycled-copper-strat</link><description>Prysmian is increasing its use of recycled copper in the U.S. amid trade tensions and tariffs, which complicate copper supply chains. This strategy supports Prysmian's growth in electrification and grid modernization, particularly in the U.S. market where tariffs provide a competitive advantage. However, potential rollback of tariffs could impact profitability and growth assumptions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>NioCorp and IBC Advanced Alloys Successfully Cast Aluminum-Scandium Alloy</title><link>https://www.redchip.com/news/8293747800041119/niocorp-and-ibc-advanced-alloys-successfully-cast-aluminum-scandium-alloy-for-potential-expansion-into-al-sc-alloy-parts</link><description>NioCorp and IBC Advanced Alloys have successfully cast a 0.2% Aluminum-Scandium alloy, marking a potential expansion into Al-Sc alloy parts. This development is part of NioCorp's broader efforts to enhance domestic critical mineral production. NioCorp is hosting an investor webcast to discuss recent milestones and future plans.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>NioCorp to Conduct Live Investor Webcast</title><link>https://www.niocorp.com/niocorp-to-conduct-live-investor-webcast-on-monday-october-27-2025/</link><description>NioCorp is conducting a live investor webcast to update on its Elk Creek Critical Minerals Project and recent corporate milestones. The company has raised significant funding and is working to secure additional financing for project development. The webcast will include a Q&amp;A session with management.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory Rises</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103587839/Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Rises-to-102000-mt-on-Oct-27-2025:-SMM</link><description>According to SMM statistics, domestic aluminum billet inventory in two regions has increased to 102,000 mt. This update reflects recent trends in aluminum stock levels and market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Ministry to hold talks with industry stakeholders on import issues on October 27</title><link>https://manufacturing.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/industry/steel-ministry-to-hold-talks-with-industry-stakeholders-on-import-issues-on-october-27/124737300</link><description>The Ministry of Steel in India will conduct an Open House meeting on October 27, 2025, to discuss import-related issues with industry stakeholders. The meeting aims to address concerns and formulate strategies to stabilize the domestic steel market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel imports fall 29% in H1, but sector still records net forex outflow</title><link>https://indiaseatradenews.com/steel-imports-fall-29-in-h1-but-sector-still-records-net-forex-outflow/</link><description>India's steel imports have decreased by 29% in the first half of the year, yet the sector still experiences a net foreign exchange outflow. This indicates ongoing challenges in the domestic steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China proposes more stringent steel capacity swap plan to curb overcapacity</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/china-proposes-more-stringent-steel-capacity-swap-plan-to-curb-overcapacity/</link><description>China has proposed a more stringent steel capacity swap plan to address overcapacity issues in the industry. This plan follows the pause of a previous program that failed to achieve its goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hebei Songting Steel to Start Blast Furnace Shutdown on Oct 27</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103588781/Hebei-Songting-Steel-to-Start-Blast-Furnace-Shutdown-on-Oct-27</link><description>Hebei Songting Steel is set to begin a blast furnace shutdown for maintenance starting October 27. This shutdown is part of routine maintenance to ensure operational efficiency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Experts urge factories to produce 100% refined steel to cut carbon emissions</title><link>https://www.tbsnews.net/economy/industry/experts-urge-factories-produce-100-refined-steel-cut-carbon-emissions-1270086</link><description>Industry experts are calling for factories to adopt 100% refined steel production as a key measure to reduce carbon emissions. This push aligns with broader efforts to decarbonize the steel sector and promote sustainability in manufacturing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Greece's New Copper-Gold Mine Nears Completion, LME Copper Rose Sharply on Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103587605/Greeces-New-Copper-Gold-Mine-Nears-Completion-LME-Copper-Rose-Sharply-on-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices rose 1.2% to close at $10,947/mt on Friday, with trading volume and open interest increasing. Canadian company Eldorado Gold announced its Skouries copper-gold project in Greece is about 70% complete, with first production expected in early 2026 and commercial production by mid-2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Remain Near Record Highs</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/27/copper-prices-remain-near-record-highs/</link><description>Copper prices are holding near record highs just below $11,000 a tonne, driven by concerns over supply disruptions such as the suspension of Freeport-McMoRan’s Grasberg mine in Indonesia after a fatal mudslide. The metal has rallied about 25% this year, reflecting strong demand and supply-side challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Metals on fire: What's driving the unstoppable rally in copper, aluminium and zinc</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/metals-on-fire-whats-driving-the-unstoppable-rally-in-copper-aluminium-and-zinc/articleshow/124824209.cms</link><description>Copper prices have surged past $10,000 on the LME and are near record highs on India's MCX platform, driven by supply disruptions at major mines, strong demand from infrastructure and green energy sectors, and geopolitical tensions. The rally is supported by factors including accidents at Chile's El Teniente mine, protests in Peru, and a mudslide at Indonesia's Grasberg mine.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper jumps to 16-month high on trade deal optimism</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/metals-copper-jumps-to-16-month-high-on-trade-deal-optimism-158328/</link><description>Copper prices climbed to a 16-month high driven by optimism over a potential U.S.-China trade agreement, reflecting positive market sentiment on easing trade tensions between the two largest economies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to $5.16 USD/Lbs on October 27, 2025, up 1.42% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices increased to $5.16 per pound, up 1.42% from the previous day, with a 6.23% rise over the past month and an 18.92% increase year-over-year. Analysts expect copper to trade at $5.20 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.74 in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Remain Near Record Highs</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/27/copper-prices-remain-near-record-highs/</link><description>Copper prices are holding near record highs, just below $11,000 per tonne, driven by concerns over supply disruptions. A key factor is the suspension of operations at Freeport-McMoRan’s Grasberg mine in Indonesia after a fatal mudslide, impacting the world's second-largest copper mine. The metal's strong rally this year reflects rising global demand and supply-side challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Diablo Resources (ASX:DBO) Confirms Copper Mineralisation Open in All Directions at Phoenix Project</title><link>https://www.marketopen.com.au/diablo-resources-asxdbo-confirms-copper-mineralisation-open-in-all-directions-at-phoenix-project/</link><description>Diablo Resources reported early drilling success at its Phoenix Copper Project in Utah, USA, with significant copper mineralisation confirmed open in all directions and at depth. Maiden drilling returned 10.5 metres at 1.02% copper, including a high-grade interval of 1.5 metres at 3.99% copper. Follow-up drilling is planned for mid-November, targeting further exploration in this recognized copper district.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Copper Smelter Emissions Rule Reversal Explained</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/biden-copper-rule-air-quality-standards-2025/</link><description>The Trump administration reversed Biden-era copper smelter emissions rules, granting a two-year exemption to protect domestic processing. The US processes less than 5% of global copper despite significant mining, relying heavily on foreign smelters, especially in China, which controls about 50% of global copper smelting capacity. This reversal highlights strategic concerns about supply chain security amid rising copper demand driven by clean energy and electric vehicle growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FireFly Announces Major High-Grade Copper and Gold Exploration Breakthrough at Green Bay</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/10/26/3174278/0/en/FireFly-announces-major-high-grade-copper-and-gold-exploration-breakthrough-at-Green-Bay.html</link><description>FireFly Metals reported exceptional drilling results at its Green Bay Copper-Gold Project in Canada, revealing a high-grade mineralised core over at least 800 meters strike length. Recent assays include 43 meters at 7.6% copper equivalent and 15 meters at 16% copper equivalent, indicating significant potential to expand the mineral resource. Ongoing drilling aims to define the full extent of this core for upcoming resource updates.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Miner Sandfire Tracks Ahead of Plan in Strong First Quarter</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/copper-miner-sandfire-tracks-ahead-of-plan-in-strong-first-quarter-2025-10-27</link><description>Sandfire Resources produced 21,800 tonnes of copper-equivalent in the first quarter, representing 23% of its 2026 financial year guidance. This performance reflects planned mining activities and positions the company well for the remainder of the year. The strong start indicates robust operational execution in copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Corruption Probe Underway at Rio Tinto's Mongolian Copper Mine</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/2025102752/corruption-probe-underway-at-rio-tintos-mongolian-copper-mine-update</link><description>An internal investigation into allegations of corruption and unethical conduct is underway at Rio Tinto's Oyu Tolgoi copper mine in Mongolia. The probe involves procurement-related activities and has sought law enforcement cooperation. Oyu Tolgoi is a major copper and gold deposit expected to become the world's fourth-largest copper mine by 2030, critical to Rio Tinto's strategic shift toward copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump Reverses Biden-Era Rules on Copper Smelters</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/trump-reverses-biden-era-rules-on-copper-smelters-2025-10-27</link><description>US President Donald Trump reversed a Biden-era air pollution rule that imposed stricter emissions limits on copper smelters. This regulatory change aims to ease restrictions on domestic copper processing, addressing concerns about supply chain resilience and domestic capacity limitations. The move reflects ongoing tensions between environmental regulations and industrial policy in the copper sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Hellenic Copper Mines Ltd: 2026 Outlook For Large Copper Mines</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/hellenic-copper-mines-ltd-2026-outlook-for-large-copper-mines</link><description>Hellenic Copper Mines Ltd is advancing innovation and sustainability in copper mining through automation, AI-powered resource management, advanced recycling, and digital traceability. The company focuses on energy-efficient operations, enhanced waste management, and compliance with stringent EU environmental standards to boost productivity and minimize environmental impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, Silver &amp; Copper: tech and sustainability trends</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_ca/insights/mining-metals/gold-silver-and-copper-tech-and-sustainability-trends</link><description>Copper companies are addressing supply challenges by adopting digital innovations, AI, satellite technology, and advanced mineral processing to optimize recovery and productivity. Recycling plays a key role, with recycled copper accounting for 32% of global supply in 2023, and companies increasingly collaborating with cleantech firms to enhance sustainable copper supplies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Rise Slightly on October 27 as China-US Economic and Trade Consultations Make Positive Progress</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103588834/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Rise-Slightly-on-October-27-as-China-US-Economic-and-Trade-Consultations-Make-Positive-Progress</link><description>On October 27, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,900 yuan/mt, up 750 yuan/mt from the previous day. Positive progress in China-US economic and trade talks and lower-than-expected US CPI data boosted market sentiment, supporting a slightly higher nickel price with expected sideways movement in the near term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel price rose slightly to $15,334.13 per ton on October 27, 2025, up 0.06% from the previous day. Despite a modest monthly increase, prices remain about 4-5% lower than a year ago. Forecasts suggest nickel may trade around $15,152 by the end of the quarter but could decline to about $14,420 in 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>METALS-Copper jumps to 16-month high on trade deal optimism; nickel rose 0.25%</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/gold-silver-prices-extend-fall-yellow-metal-below-rs-1-23-lakh-what-should-investors-do/articleshow/124839539.cms</link><description>On October 27, nickel prices rose by 0.25% amid broader positive market sentiment driven by optimism over trade deals. This modest increase aligns with gains in other base metals like copper and tin.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SPC's polymetallic Muskox treads the path of giants</title><link>https://mining.com.au/spcs-polymetallic-muskox-treads-the-path-of-giants/</link><description>SPC Nickel has completed a comprehensive field program at the Muskox Project in Nunavut, Canada, including the most thorough modern geophysical survey ever flown over the intrusion. The project shows promising high-grade silver and significant nickel-copper resources, with a 1km trend of high conductivity EM targets identified for potential drilling.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China, ASEAN to upgrade free trade, bring more certainties to world</title><link>https://english.www.gov.cn/news/202510/27/content_WS68fec32dc6d00ca5f9a070ee.html</link><description>A new project covering the full supply chain from nickel mining and processing to battery materials production, manufacturing, and recycling is underway, aiming to strengthen trade and industrial cooperation between China and ASEAN countries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Trump Strikes Strategic Critical Minerals Trade Deals in Southeast Asia</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/critical-minerals-2025-strategic-partnerships-southeast-asia/</link><description>Former President Trump secured critical minerals trade deals in Southeast Asia, focusing on strategic partnerships that include nickel among other critical minerals, to support supply chains for commercial and defense industries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>