<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:17:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 0.81% Lower at $5.0085 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511216592/comex-copper-ends-the-week-081-lower-at-50085-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for November delivery closed the week down 0.81% at $5.0085 per pound, marking a decline in three of the past four weeks. Despite the weekly drop, copper is up 25.65% year-to-date and remains well above its 52-week low.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Jubilee Metals Group reports 65% increase in copper production in first quarter</title><link>https://iol.co.za/business-report/companies/2025-11-22-jubilee-metals-group-reports-65-increase-in-copper-production-in-first-quarter/</link><description>Jubilee Metals Group announced a significant 65% rise in copper production for the first quarter of the 2026 financial year, reflecting strong operational performance and capacity expansion.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Harum Energy Q3 2025 nickel production rises 18.4% Year on Year</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5104917-flash-harum-energy-q3-2025-nickel-production-rises-184-year-on-year</link><description>PT Harum Energy Tbk reported a 18.4% year-on-year increase in nickel pig iron production to 19,249 tonnes in Q3 2025, with sales up 13.11% quarter-on-quarter. The company’s RKEF utilization rate improved to 89% in the first nine months of 2025, and its HPAL project is over 90% complete, with commissioning planned for early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>EV Nickel acquires unpatented mining claim over high-grade Langmuir South and Langmuir #2 nickel zones</title><link>https://www.webdisclosure.com/press-release/ev-nickel-inc-cve-evni-ev-nickel-acquires-unpatented-mining-claim-over-high-grade-langmuir-south-and-langmuir-2-nickel-zones-w2mIvSO5ihM</link><description>EV Nickel Inc. announced the issuance of an unpatented mining claim near Timmins, Ontario, advancing exploration of high-grade nickel mineralization. The company plans diamond drilling pending permit approval expected before the end of 2025, aiming to expand its nickel assets to support North American clean critical mineral supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 0.9 percent - week 48, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-09-percent-week-48-2025-1421295.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending November 22, 2025, was 1.761 million net tons, a 0.9% increase from the previous week. The capacity utilization rate rose to 76.9%, and production is up 9.2% compared to the same week last year. Year-to-date production through November 22, 2025, reached 80.734 million net tons, up 3.3% from last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Weekly Raw Steel Production Report - Week ending November 22, 2025</title><link>https://www.steel.org/industry-data/</link><description>Domestic raw steel production in the U.S. was 1,761,000 net tons with a capability utilization rate of 76.9% for the week ending November 22, 2025. This represents an 8.3% increase compared to the same period last year, indicating a positive production trend despite minor week-over-week fluctuations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit 3-Year High: Is It the Next Key Metal in the Clean Energy Shift?</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-hit-3-year-high-is-it-the-next-key-metal-in-the-clean-energy-shift/</link><description>Aluminum prices have reached a three-year high, driven by strong demand from electric vehicles, solar installations, and grid upgrades. The surge is reshaping supply chains as the metal becomes increasingly important for the transition to a low-carbon economy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Mining Methods 2025: Innovations &amp; Sustainability</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-mining-methods-2025-innovations-sustainability</link><description>The copper mining industry is advancing with innovations such as autonomous equipment, digital transformation, and sustainable extraction methods like in-situ leaching. These technologies are improving efficiency, reducing environmental impact, and supporting responsible resource extraction in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Energy Efficiency in Copper Processing Plants 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/energy-efficiency-in-copper-processing-plants-2025</link><description>In 2025, copper processing plants are achieving up to 30% lower emissions through automation, digitization, and integration of renewable energy. Innovations in thermal recovery and blockchain-based traceability are enhancing both sustainability and supply chain transparency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Daily Inventory of Aluminum Billet in Two Domestic Regions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103637178/</link><description>Aluminum billet inventory in two major domestic regions was reported on November 23, 2025. Prices are expected to move sideways in the 21,200–21,500 yuan/mt range in the near term, with limited downside supported by costs and supply.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Expected to Hover at Highs in Short Term</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103637178/</link><description>Aluminum prices are expected to remain high in the near term, with limited declines in scrap raw material supply. The market continues to respond to supply constraints and strong demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer drops to $2,765.5/t while opening stock climbs to 548,000t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-drops-to-2-765-5-t-while-opening-stock-climbs-to-548-000t-116302</link><description>LME aluminium prices eased on November 21 with cash and three-month contracts declining modestly. Exchange inventories increased, with opening stock rising to 548,000 tonnes. Forward values also weakened amid a slight drop in cash and three-month bids and offers.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price falls to one-month low in wider commodity slump</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-falls-to-one-month-low-in-wider-commodity-slump/</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped as much as 1.6% to $2,526 a ton on the London Metal Exchange, the lowest since November 14, amid a broad commodity pullback. The decline followed data showing record-high Chinese output in November, driven by booming exports and the end of export tax discounts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Manual Processing Profit Narrowed in October, Short-Term Primary Aluminum Imports Expected to Decrease [SMM Analysis]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635112/Manual-Processing-Profit-Narrowed-in-October-Short-Term-Primary-Aluminum-Imports-Expected-to-Decrease-%5BSMM-Analysis%5D</link><description>Profit margins for manual processing of aluminum narrowed in October, with expectations of decreased primary aluminum imports in the short term. Production cuts at an Icelandic smelter and tightening overseas supply have pushed LME aluminum prices higher, while high premiums in Europe and the US may divert supply away from China.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Manual Processing Profit Narrowed in October, Short-Term Primary Aluminum Imports Expected to Decrease [SMM Analysis]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635112/Manual-Processing-Profit-Narrowed-in-October-Short-Term-Primary-Aluminum-Imports-Expected-to-Decrease-%5BSMM-Analysis%5D</link><description>China's primary aluminum imports in October 2025 rose slightly by 0.6% month-on-month and 42.1% year-on-year, while exports decreased 15.2% MoM but increased 54.2% YoY. Production cuts at an Icelandic smelter and expectations of overseas supply tightening pushed LME aluminum prices higher, though SHFE prices lagged, narrowing profit margins for manual processing and likely reducing imports under handbook processing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Limited Commissioning of New Projects Leads to Slow Growth in Aluminum Production in 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635148/limited-commissioning-of-new-projects-leads-to-slow-growth-in-aluminum-production-in-2025-</link><description>China's operating aluminum capacity in 2025 approached the ceiling of compliant capacity with limited new project commissioning, resulting in slow capacity growth. Production cuts due to losses and technological transformation projects resuming contributed to an expected 1.7% year-on-year production growth. Regional capacity increases include resumed production in Sichuan and Guangxi provinces, with overall operating capacity up by 538,000 mt compared to 2024.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer drops to $2,765.5/t while opening stock climbs to 548,000t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-drops-to-2-765-5-t-while-opening-stock-climbs-to-548-000t-116302</link><description>LME aluminum prices eased on November 21, 2025, with the cash bid and offer both dropping by approximately 0.47%. Meanwhile, exchange inventories increased, with opening stock climbing to 548,000 tonnes, indicating a slight softening in market prices amid rising stock levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ITRI Wins Three R&amp;D 100 Awards for Breakthroughs in Regenerative Medicine and Sustainable Technologies</title><link>https://themalaysianreserve.com/2025/11/24/itri-wins-three-rd-100-awards-for-breakthroughs-in-regenerative-medicine-and-sustainable-technologies/</link><description>ITRI has been recognized with three R&amp;D 100 Awards for innovations in regenerative medicine and sustainable technologies, highlighting advancements that could impact aluminum sustainability and industrial processes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Enter Downward Channel as Weakening Costs Keep Stainless Steel Under Pressure</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28192.html</link><description>Nickel prices are trending downward due to weakening costs, which is putting pressure on stainless steel prices. The article highlights ongoing market dynamics affecting stainless steel and related commodities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Stock prices of US' steel industry skyrocket on Nov 24</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/NewsItem/122655</link><description>US steel industry stock prices surged on November 24, driven by acute supply shortages. The article notes strong market reactions to limited steel availability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 24, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/tata-steel-ltd-24-nov-2025-500470</link><description>Tata Steel Ltd shares declined by 0.15% on November 24, trading at ₹167.75 per share. Investors are closely watching the stock amid ongoing market volatility.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US steel shipments lifted by tariffs in Q3</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/us-steel-shipments-lifted-by-tariffs-in-q3/</link><description>US steel producers reported record shipments in Q3 as tariffs reduced imports. The article discusses how trade policies are influencing domestic steel market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ENR November 24, 2025: CONSTRUCTION ECONOMICS</title><link>https://digital.bnpmedia.com/article/CONSTRUCTION+ECONOMICS/5074480/857075/article.html</link><description>Monthly prices for reinforcing bars fell 0.1%, while yearly prices are down 15.1%. The article covers recent trends in construction steel prices and the producer price index for sheet metal.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global steel production ticked higher in October</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/22/global-steel-production-ticked-higher-in-october/</link><description>World crude steel output rose 1% from September to October, reaching 143.3 million metric tons, after four consecutive monthly declines. China's output fell 12% year-on-year, while the rest of the world saw a 1% increase, with daily production at a 22-month low.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Crude Steel Production Declines by 5.9% in October 2025</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/38272/</link><description>Global crude steel production declined 5.9% in October 2025 compared to the same month last year, with Asia and Oceania down 8.2% and Africa up 0.8%. The drop was mainly driven by continued weakness in China.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany increased steel production by 5.1% m/m in October</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Germany's steel production rose 5.1% month-on-month in October 2025, reflecting a regional uptick amid global production declines. The increase highlights ongoing shifts in European steelmaking capacity and output.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Global Steel Industry 2025: At a Pivotal Crossroads</title><link>https://www.steel-technology.com/articles/the-global-steel-industry-2025-at-a-pivotal-crossroads</link><description>The steel industry is undergoing a significant transformation driven by AI, hydrogen-based methods, automation, and sustainability. Green steel production is gaining momentum as demand for low-carbon materials rises, with hydrogen playing a key role in decarbonizing steelmaking processes. Supply chain challenges are also pushing the industry toward tech-driven solutions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Processing Industry Faces Pricing Stress Test</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/24/copper-processing-industry-faces-pricing-stress-test/</link><description>The global copper processing industry is expected to face a significant stress test in pricing mechanisms this week, reflecting ongoing market volatility and supply-demand imbalances. This could impact pricing stability and industry profitability in the near term.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's Grip on Copper Sets Scene for Make-or-Break Supply Talks</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2025/november/china-s-grip-on-copper-sets-scene-for-make-or-break-supply-talks/</link><description>The global copper-processing industry is facing a critical stress test as negotiations intensify amid China's dominance in securing copper concentrate supply and driving down processing fees. Chinese smelters continue to expand, crowding out international competitors and prompting concerns about the viability of the benchmark pricing system.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's Grip on Copper Sets Scene for Make-or-Break Supply Talks</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/chinas-grip-copper-sets-scene-make-or-break-supply-talks</link><description>Geopolitical tensions and China's growing control over copper concentrate supply are putting pressure on the global benchmark pricing mechanism. The expansion of Chinese smelting capacity has led to plummeting processing fees and increased struggles for smelters outside China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Processing Industry Faces Pricing Stress Test</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/24/copper-processing-industry-faces-pricing-stress-test/</link><description>The global copper processing industry is experiencing a major stress test due to China's dominance, constrained metal supplies, and the rapid expansion of processing capacity outpacing mined production. This is raising questions about the sustainability of the current benchmarking structure.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Australian Mining Giant BHP Drops Anglo American Takeover Bid</title><link>https://www.macaubusiness.com/australian-mining-giant-bhp-drops-anglo-american-takeover-bid/</link><description>BHP, a major Australian mining company, has withdrawn its takeover bid for Anglo American, which could impact future copper production and capacity expansion plans in the sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China's Grip on Copper Sets Scene for Make-or-Break Supply Talks</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2025/november/china-s-grip-on-copper-sets-scene-for-make-or-break-supply-talks/</link><description>China's dominant position in copper supply is influencing critical supply talks, with the country deploying digital tools to drive efficiency in copper production. This dynamic is shaping the global copper market amid rising demand and supply challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Enter Downward Channel as Weakening Costs Keep Stainless Steel Under Pressure</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28192.html</link><description>Nickel prices have entered a downward channel due to weakening costs and increased production capacity in China and Indonesia. The oversupply and weak demand are keeping stainless steel prices under pressure, with little room for a near-term rebound in nickel prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices have dropped to 14,532.00 USD/ton, the lowest since April 2025, losing 4.57% over the past four weeks and 8.05% over the past year. The market remains bearish due to persistent oversupply and weak demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in November period I</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103862-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-november-period-i</link><description>Indonesia's Nickel Miners Association (APNI) set the benchmark price for nickel ore at $15,075.33/wmt for the first half of November 2025, a slight decrease from October. Prices for various grades of nickel ore also declined marginally.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 24, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635765/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price was reported at 115,400–120,100 yuan/mt on November 24, with an average price of 117,750 yuan/mt, up 1,050 yuan/mt from the previous day. The market saw a slight rebound amid ongoing oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Rebound Slightly on November 24 as US-Ukraine Talks Make Significant Progress</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103635953/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Rebound-Slightly-on-November-24-as-US-Ukraine-Talks-Make-Significant-Progress</link><description>Nickel prices rebounded slightly on November 24, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 117,750 yuan/mt, up 1,050 yuan/mt from the previous day. The rebound was attributed to progress in US-Ukraine talks, but oversupply remains a concern.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>MMG's deal to buy Anglo American's Brazil nickel assets faces EU regulatory delay</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/mmgs-deal-to-buy-anglo-americans-brazil-nickel-assets-faces-eu-regulatory-delay-2025-11-24</link><description>MMG's acquisition of Anglo American's Brazilian nickel assets is facing delays due to regulatory scrutiny from the European Commission, which is concerned the deal could divert ferronickel supplies away from Europe and negatively impact the European stainless steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in November (Period I)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103862-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-november-period-i</link><description>The Indonesia Nickel Miners Association (APNI) has announced the benchmark prices for nickel ore for the first half of November 2025, providing updated guidance for the domestic market amid ongoing supply and pricing volatility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Ore Port Inventory</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/102492700/</link><description>On November 24, 2025, the national port nickel ore inventory in China increased by 97,000 wet tons, reaching a total of 10.106 million wet tons, reflecting continued high supply levels and inventory buildup.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to $14,549.75 per tonne on November 24, 2025, down 0.48% from the previous day, continuing a downward trend as global supply outpaces demand and inventories remain elevated.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rose to 2,814.85 USD/T on November 24, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices increased to 2,814.85 USD per ton on November 24, 2025, up 0.33% from the previous day. Despite a 2.13% drop over the past month, prices remain 5.87% higher than a year ago, reflecting ongoing volatility in the market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Caps and Closures Market Size, Trends and Regional Data 2025-2035</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/24/3193546/0/en/Aluminum-Caps-and-Closures-Market-Size-Trends-and-Regional-Data-2025-2035.html</link><description>The global aluminum caps and closures market reached USD 9.79 billion in 2025 and is projected to grow to USD 14.60 billion by 2034. The growth is driven by rising demand for product safety, government initiatives like Make in India, and increased focus on sustainable packaging and recycling.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Caps and Closures Market Size, Trends and Regional Data 2025-2035</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/24/3193546/0/en/Aluminum-Caps-and-Closures-Market-Size-Trends-and-Regional-Data-2025-2035.html</link><description>The global aluminum caps and closures market was valued at USD 9.79 billion in 2025 with projections through 2035. This market report provides regional data and trend analysis for the aluminum closures industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Stabilizes on Dovish Fed Bets</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/504350</link><description>Copper prices steadied around $5 per pound, supported by dovish comments from a senior US Federal Reserve official and expectations for a rate cut. Supply concerns were highlighted by Codelco's record premium and Freeport McMoRan's production update.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Alloys Market Trends, Shares, Strategies and Investment Prospects 2025-2030</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251124042696/en/Copper-Alloys-Market-Trends-Shares-Strategies-and-Investment-Prospects-2025-2030---Expansion-of-Aerospace-and-Defense-Sectors-Supports-Demand-for-High-Strength-Fatigue-Resistant-Copper-Alloys---ResearchAndMarkets.com</link><description>The article discusses the latest developments in copper alloy technology, including product and process innovations and emerging technologies shaping the competitive landscape. It highlights how innovation and technology trends are driving growth and sustainability in the copper alloys market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell to a four-year low of $15,235 per ton on the London Metal Exchange, pressured by a weaker outlook from the Federal Reserve despite potential mining quota cuts in Indonesia. Indonesia is considering reducing its nickel ore mining quota sharply from 272 million tons in 2025 to 150 million tons in 2026 to support prices. The metal's decline is also linked to new supply expectations and a slowdown in electric vehicle sales.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Value of EV battery nickel second highest on record, cobalt at 30-month high</title><link>https://www.mining.com/value-of-ev-battery-nickel-second-highest-on-record-cobalt-at-30-month-high/</link><description>Spending on nickel for electric vehicle batteries reached the second highest level on record in the three months ending October 2025, totaling $1.71 billion. Despite recent price slumps, nickel sulphate prices remain elevated, supporting demand in the EV supply chain. Cobalt spending also surged, driven by shifts in battery chemistry and government stockpiling plans.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cuts Rise Again, Aluminum Prices Hover at Highs</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103637113/Expectations-for-US-Fed-Interest-Rate-Cuts-Rise-Again-Aluminum-Prices-Hover-at-Highs-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME aluminum prices opened at $2,802.5/mt and reached an intraday high of $2,817.5/mt on November 25, 2025, closing at $2,813/mt. The market remains in a consolidation phase, with primary aluminum prices showing a narrow-range adjustment trend and downstream demand diverging by alloy type.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Sheet and Plate Market Report: By Key Players, Types</title><link>https://www.openpr.com/news/4286047/aluminum-sheet-and-plate-market-report-by-key-players-types</link><description>The latest report on the Global Aluminum Sheet and Plate Market was released on November 25, 2025, covering manufacturers, regions, types and applications. This market analysis provides insights into current trends and key players in the aluminum sheet and plate sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Stocks of Main Finished Steel Products in China Down 2.5 Percent in Mid-Nov 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/stocksof-mainfinishedsteelproducts-in-china-down-25-percent-in-mid-nov-2025-1421071.htm</link><description>Stocks of main finished steel products in China declined by 2.5 percent in mid-November 2025, indicating tighter supply conditions and potential upward pressure on prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose to 3,108 CNY/T on November 25, 2025, up 0.55% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have increased slightly but remain lower than a year ago.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU appeals WTO ruling in Indonesia steel standoff</title><link>https://www.thejakartapost.com/business/2025/11/25/eu-appeals-wto-ruling-in-indonesia-steel-standoff.html</link><description>The European Union has appealed a World Trade Organization ruling that found errors in its tariff settings on Indonesian stainless steel imports. This move continues the trade dispute between the EU and Indonesia over steel tariffs, impacting international steel trade relations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Codelco to Partner with India's Adani Group, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103637092/Codelco-to-Partner-with-Indias-Adani-Group-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, closing at $10,781.5/mt, up 0.03%. Supply-side arrivals decreased, while state-owned supply replenished normally. Demand weakened after the rebound, and Chinese inventories dropped by 13,900 mt WoW.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to 5.04 USD/lb on November 25, up 1.04% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have fallen 1.88%, but remain 24.33% higher than a year ago. The all-time high was reached in July 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper slips, US rate cut hopes support sentiment</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-slips-us-rate-cut-hopes-support-sentiment/</link><description>Benchmark copper on the LME was down 0.3% at $10,749/mt, but sentiment was supported by hopes for a US rate cut. The price had previously hit a record high of $11,200/mt.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>UBS Forecasts Continued Copper Price Surge</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/25/ubs-forecasts-continued-copper-price-surge/</link><description>UBS has raised its copper price forecasts for 2026, citing tightening supply due to mine disruptions and strong demand from electrification and clean-energy investments. The bank now expects a market deficit of 230,000 tonnes in 2025 and 407,000 tonnes in 2026, with prices projected to reach $13,000 per tonne by December 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Copper Smelters to Face Record Low Fees for 2026</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/chinese-copper-smelters-to-face-record-low-fees-for-2026-2025-11-25</link><description>Chinese copper smelters are expected to accept record low processing fees for 2026 due to ongoing global ore shortages and intense competition for raw materials. This reflects the continued strain on supply chains and the challenges facing new and existing smelting operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Arizona Copper and Gold Ltd. and Core Nickel Corp. Provide Update on Reverse Takeover Transaction and Concurrent Financing</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/story/news/36296817/arizona-copper-and-gold-ltd-and-core-nickel-corp-provide-update-on-reverse-takeover-transaction-and-concurrent-financing</link><description>Arizona Copper and Gold Ltd. and Core Nickel Corp. announced updates on their reverse takeover transaction and concurrent financing, with the closing scheduled for November 25, 2025. The companies expect to issue an aggregate of shares as part of the transaction.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper RRS 2025 — BHP's reserves base provides 27 years of future output</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/market-intelligence/en/news-insights/research/2025/11/copper-rrs-2025-bhps-reserves-base-provides-27-years-of-future-output</link><description>BHP's copper reserves are projected to support 27 years of future output, with innovations expected to produce 410,000 metric tons of copper cathodes over a decade. The article emphasizes the role of technological innovation in sustaining long-term copper supply for the energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Continue to Rebound on November 25</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103638383/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Continue-to-Rebound-on-November-25-Probability-of-Interest-Rate-Cut-in-December-Is-Expected-to-Rise-Significantly</link><description>Nickel prices rebounded on November 25 with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 118,550 yuan/mt, up 800 yuan/mt from the previous day. The rebound was supported by dovish signals from the US Federal Reserve, which increased market expectations for an interest rate cut in December from 40% to 75%. Despite short-term fluctuations, long-term pressure on nickel prices remains, with the SHFE nickel contract projected to trade between 114,000-118,000 yuan/mt.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Major Indonesia Nickel Plant Cuts Output as Waste Piles Up</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/major-indonesia-nickel-plant-cuts-output-as-waste-piles-up/</link><description>A major Chinese-owned nickel plant at Indonesia’s Morawali Industrial Park is reducing production due to its tailings storage nearing capacity, highlighting ongoing waste management challenges in the rapidly expanding nickel sector. The reduction is expected to last at least two weeks while new storage solutions are processed.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Major Indonesia Nickel Plant Cuts Output as Waste Piles Up</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/international/asean/major-indonesia-nickel-plant-cuts-output-waste-piles</link><description>Indonesia’s largest nickel site, Morawali Industrial Park, is experiencing reduced output at a key plant due to full tailings storage, with paperwork for new storage still pending. The situation underscores the environmental and logistical pressures facing Indonesia’s dominant nickel industry.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Announces Bought Deal Private Placement is Oversubscribed and Fully Allocated</title><link>https://themalaysianreserve.com/2025/11/25/canada-nickel-announces-bought-deal-private-placement-is-oversubscribed-and-fully-allocated/</link><description>Canada Nickel Company has announced that its recent private placement offering was oversubscribed and fully allocated, signaling strong investor interest in the company’s nickel projects and expansion plans.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices are expected to hover at highs in the short term</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103639382/</link><description>Aluminum prices are forecasted to remain high in the short term due to ongoing supply constraints and demand factors. Inventory levels and import dynamics in China are key influences on price stability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices are expected to hover at highs in the short term</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103639423/</link><description>According to SMM statistics, aluminum prices are expected to remain high in the short term, influenced by market dynamics including supply constraints and demand factors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Market News: Spain Increases Steel Production by 11.6% in October</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Spain's steel production rose by 11.6% month-over-month in October 2025. Other notable market developments include the US reducing imports of rolled steel by 7.6% in June and Acerinox considering price increases in the US market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Rises to 3,097 CNY/T on November 25, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China rose slightly by 0.19% to 3,097 CNY/T on November 25, 2025. Over the past month, steel prices increased by 0.32%, although they remain 5.78% lower compared to the previous year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Carney expected to announce support measures for steel industry hit by U.S. tariffs</title><link>https://unpublished.ca/news-feed-item/2025-11-26/carney-expected-to-announce-support-measures-for-steel-industry-hit-by-us</link><description>The Canadian federal government plans to limit foreign steel imports and reduce interprovincial rail freight rates to support the domestic steel industry affected by U.S. tariffs. Prime Minister Mark Carney is expected to announce new funding and tighter import limits to help Canadian steel producers fill domestic demand gaps.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Carney expected to announce new supports for steel industry hammered by U.S. tariffs</title><link>https://www.seekyoursounds.com/news/toronto/carney-expected-to-announce-new-supports-for-steel-industry-hammered-by-u-s-tariffs</link><description>The Canadian government aims to cut steel imports from countries without free trade agreements from 50% to 20% of 2024 levels, opening an estimated $854 million in domestic demand. Additionally, freight rates for interprovincial steel shipments may be cut by 50%, with subsidies if rail companies cannot comply, to support the steel sector amid U.S. tariff pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Boston Metal Names Industry Veteran Roy Harvey to Board of Directors</title><link>https://www.macaubusiness.com/boston-metal-names-industry-veteran-roy-harvey-to-board-of-directors/</link><description>Boston Metal, a company innovating in global metals production, announced the appointment of Roy Harvey, an industry veteran, to its board of directors. This move underscores the company's commitment to advancing steel technology innovation and sustainable metals production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 0.76% Higher at $4.9995 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511256179/comex-copper-settles-076-higher-at-49995-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for November delivery rose 0.76% to $4.9995 per pound, marking gains in two of the past three sessions. Despite being down 13.73% from its 52-week high in July, copper is up 25.43% year-to-date, reflecting strong market performance overall.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rises as outflows to US stocks provide support - Markets</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40394268</link><description>Benchmark copper on the London Metal Exchange rose 0.8% to $10,855 per metric ton, supported by outflows to US stocks. The market showed positive momentum amid ongoing supply concerns and steady demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco offers record premiums for 2026 copper sales to China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/commodity/copper/</link><description>Chile's state-owned Codelco proposed record premiums of $335 per ton for copper sales to some buyers, reflecting tightening supply conditions in the global copper market ahead of 2026 negotiations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco's Record Premiums Signal a New Era for Copper Demand and Strategic Investment Opportunities</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/codelco-record-premiums-signal-era-copper-demand-strategic-investment-opportunities-2511/</link><description>Codelco, the world's largest copper producer, faces a 25% output decline due to mine collapse and aging infrastructure, amid surging demand driven by electric vehicles and AI data centers. Record premiums and prices reflect a structural market shift, with forecasts of significant annual deficits through 2026, prompting major investments in mine modernization and safety.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Battery X Metals Announces New Strategic Partnership with Global Top 20 University</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/accesswire/1112296msn/battery-x-metals-announces-new-strategic-partnership-with-global-top-20-university-building-on-preliminary-advancements-in-critical-battery-material-recovery-and-supporting-future-pilot-scale-development-of-proprietary-battery-material-recycling-technology</link><description>Battery X Metals has partnered with a leading university to develop an eco-friendly froth-flotation process for recovering critical battery materials including nickel from end-of-life lithium-ion batteries. This innovation aims to create a circular, resource-efficient supply chain that reduces environmental impact and supports North America's clean energy ecosystem.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesian coastal villages in the dark over nickel pollution</title><link>https://www.eco-business.com/news/indonesian-coastal-villages-in-the-dark-over-nickel-pollution/</link><description>Environmental violations at Indonesia's Morowali Industrial Park highlight ongoing nickel pollution issues affecting local coastal communities. Experts call for stricter sustainability standards to ensure responsible mining practices, warning that failure to improve could reduce global demand for Indonesian nickel.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of producing green hydrogen at its plant in Aosta, Italy. The project aims to reduce carbon emissions by using a 1.008 MW Anion Exchange Membrane electrolyzer to produce 165 tons of hydrogen annually, enough to power one of its 70 furnaces and prevent up to 26 tons of carbon emissions per ton of hydrogen. This initiative is supported by €7.9 million funding from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali SpA Announces Its Commitment to Sustainability with ResponsibleSteel™ Certification</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-25</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has embarked on the path to obtain ResponsibleSteel™ certification, formalizing its commitment to sustainability, environmental protection, and transparency. The company emphasizes that sustainability is integral to its daily operations and aims to create lasting value for employees, customers, and local communities through responsible steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali finalises a 200 million euro share capital increase and the acquisition of Special Melted Products in UK</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/blog</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed a €200 million share capital increase and acquired Special Melted Products in the UK, expanding its portfolio and strengthening its position in the stainless steel and nickel alloy markets. This strategic move supports the company’s growth and vertical integration plans.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Italian expertise fuels Prysmian innovation</title><link>https://www.cabletechnologynews.co.uk/italian-expertise-fuels-prysmian-innovation/</link><description>Prysmian's innovation strategy is strongly driven by its Milan R&amp;D center, with significant investments in Italy totaling €216 million between 2021 and 2024 and plans for an additional €270 million by 2028. The company focuses on high-voltage terrestrial and submarine transmission systems and renewable energy integration, supported by Italian government funding and strategic partnerships.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>BofA Sees Growth Potential for Prysmian from US Tariffs</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/bofa-sees-growth-potential-for-prysmian-from-us-tariffs-ce7d59dddf88f323</link><description>Bank of America projects Prysmian could benefit significantly from US copper tariffs, potentially increasing copper cable prices by 10% and boosting 2026 EBITDA by up to EUR1 billion. This advantage stems from Prysmian's US-based copper cable production after acquiring Encore Wire, with the greatest benefits expected in medium- and low-voltage segments.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Raises Annual Targets After Record Q3 Performance</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/prysmian-raises-annual-targets-after-record-q3-performance/</link><description>Prysmian has raised its full-year 2025 financial guidance following a record third quarter, reflecting strong revenue growth and operational performance. The company continues to capitalize on its global footprint and innovation in cable technologies, reinforcing its market leadership.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Falls Slightly on November 26, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) Steel price fell to 898.05 USD/T on November 26, 2025, down 0.44% from the previous day. Despite the recent dip, HRC Steel prices have risen 4.91% over the past month and are up 28.32% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices and Market Data for Energy Traders and Analysts</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/commodity-insights/en/commodity/metals/ferrous/steel</link><description>S&amp;P Global provides comprehensive and real-time steel market prices, data, and analysis, helping market participants monitor price fluctuations and trends. Their resources include historical and spot prices, forward curves, and detailed market insights to support decision-making in the steel commodity market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News Update - November 26, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides up-to-date prices, news, and analyses for the global iron and steel industry, including futures prices for Turkey, India, Taiwan, China, Europe, and North America as of November 24, 2025. The platform offers comprehensive market transparency and insights.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Future of EU Steel Research - How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://tenova.com/newsroom/upcoming-events/future-eu-steel-research-how-foster-eu-steel-leadership</link><description>This event in Mönchengladbach, Germany, focuses on advancing innovation and sustainability in Europe's steel industry. It highlights the Research Fund for Coal and Steel's role in driving decarbonization, competitiveness, and industrial transformation through breakthroughs in low to zero-emission steelmaking, energy efficiency, and circular economy solutions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Meets Innovation: Emerging Technologies Reshaping the Sector</title><link>https://www.steel-technology.com/articles/steel-meets-innovation-emerging-technologies-reshaping-the-sector</link><description>This article discusses how advances in AI and green steel technologies are transforming the steel industry. It highlights the adoption of smart manufacturing and sustainable production methods to meet growing demand while reducing environmental impact.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Harmony Copper Mine Project Investment Approved, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103639429/Harmony-Copper-Mine-Project-Investment-Approved-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, closing up 0.47% at $10,832.5/mt amid tight supply of high-quality copper and easing geopolitical risks such as potential Russia-Ukraine peace talks. US retail sales data falling short of expectations strengthened market hopes for a Fed interest rate cut, supporting copper prices despite some easing in downstream demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.03 USD/Lbs on November 26, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures climbed above $5 per pound, reaching a near two-week high as investors positioned ahead of a key industry gathering in Shanghai. The global copper-processing sector has faced record low annual treatment and refining charges as metal-processing capacity in China outpaced mined production. Prices were supported by signs of tightening supply, with Chile's Codelco proposing record premiums for 2026 metal sales.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Barrick committed to Pakistan's Reko Diq copper project, says interim CEO</title><link>https://tribune.com.pk/story/2579095/barrick-committed-to-pakistans-reko-diq-copper-project-says-interim-ceo</link><description>Barrick Mining Corp reaffirmed its commitment to the Reko Diq copper mine in Pakistan, one of the world's largest undeveloped deposits. The $7 billion project is expected to produce up to 400,000 tons of copper yearly and is scheduled to start production by the end of 2028.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Doubleview Gold Corp. Achieves a Major Breakthrough in Scandium Recovery from Copper Porphyry Tailings</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/11/26/doubleview-gold-corp-achieves-a-major-breakthrough-in-scandium-recovery-from-copper-porphyry-tailings/</link><description>Doubleview Gold Corp achieved a global first in successfully recovering scandium from copper porphyry flotation tailings with 88% overall recovery to high-purity scandium oxide product. The breakthrough could enable scandium to become a high-margin bonus product alongside a potential world-class copper-gold-cobalt operation at the HAT project.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On November 26, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103640502/</link><description>On November 26, the SMM #1 refined nickel price rose further to an average of 119,850 yuan/mt, up 1,300 yuan/mt from the previous day, indicating continued short-term price recovery amid market fluctuations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price drops 3.7% on Nov 26</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-price-drops-37-on-nov-26/130389</link><description>The London Metal Exchange (LME) nickel price fell by 3.7% on November 26, closing at US$19,897 per ton. This decline reflects ongoing volatility in the nickel market despite recent rebounds in some regions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's Nickel Supply &amp; The Global Price Slump: What the Market Sell-Off Signals for Investors</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/indonesias-nickel-supply-the-global-price-slump-what-the-market-sell-off-signals-for-investors</link><description>Nickel prices have fallen to $14,550 per tonne, near a four-year low, due to Indonesia's refinery expansion flooding the market and causing oversupply. Despite Indonesia's planned quota cuts, market skepticism remains about their impact on tightening supply. LME inventories surged by 90,000 tonnes in 2025, with stainless steel demand weak but EV battery growth providing some long-term support.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Falls to 7-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures in the UK dropped to $14,550 per tonne in November 2025, the lowest since a four-year low in April, due to mounting oversupply largely driven by Indonesia's over-expansion of its nickel sector. Prices have fallen 2.99% over the past month and 6.56% year-over-year, reflecting ample output despite export restrictions implemented since 2020.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Waste constraints hit output at major Indonesia nickel plant</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/waste-constraints-hit-output-at-major-indonesia-nickel-plant</link><description>A major Chinese-owned nickel processing plant in Indonesia's key production hub has reduced output due to waste management constraints. This development adds complexity to the already oversupplied nickel market dominated by Indonesia's refinery expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FPX Nickel secures ECOLOGO certification for sustainable practices</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/fpx-nickel-secures-ecologo-certification-for-sustainable-practices/</link><description>FPX Nickel has achieved UL Solutions ECOLOGO certification, marking a significant milestone in sustainable mineral exploration. This certification reflects the company's commitment to transparency, accountability, and minimizing environmental impacts, making it the first Canadian company outside Quebec to earn this recognition.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>