<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:25:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Steel Market Update</title><link>https://www.crugroup.com/en/communities/newsletters-and-magazines/steel-market-update/</link><description>The Steel Market Update provides the latest pricing, trends, and industry news for flat-rolled steel, including assessments on scrap and futures. It features real-time price tracking, sentiment surveys, inventory levels, and demand analysis for sectors like construction and automotive. Businesses use it to anticipate market shifts.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The TEX Report - January 15, 2026</title><link>https://www.texreport.co.jp/en/daily-reports/3653</link><description>Vietnam's FHS raised domestic HRC prices for March shipments by $7–8. China's 2025 steel exports reached a record 119 million tonnes, with a high monthly average. The daily report covers key steel market developments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A North of 60 copper supply solution</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/15/mining-explorers-2025/a-north-of-60-copper-supply-solution/9433.html</link><description>The article discusses upcoming copper mining projects in the Golden Triangle region, including Galore Creek, KSM, and Schaft Creek, which are poised to significantly boost annual copper production capacity in the area north of 60 degrees latitude.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 refined nickel average price update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103720728/</link><description>On January 15, the SMM #1 refined nickel average price stood at 150,050 yuan/mt, up 3,600 yuan/mt from the previous day, reflecting continued strength in nickel prices amid recent market developments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Surged Sharply on January 15</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103721760/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-surged-sharply-on-january-15-central-bank-conducted-900-billion-yuan-in-outright-</link><description>On January 15, 2026, SMM #1 refined nickel prices rose sharply to an average of 150,050 yuan/mt, up 3,600 yuan/mt from the previous day, amid central bank liquidity measures. The SHFE nickel futures contract gained 3.04%, closing at 145,280 yuan/mt in the morning session. Market dynamics reflect ongoing tension between Indonesian policy expectations and high inventory realities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia may approve nickel ore production quota of around 260 mln tons in 2026, local media says</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/indonesia-may-approve-nickel-ore-production-quota-of-around-260-mln-tons-in-2026-local-media-says/</link><description>Indonesia is considering approving a nickel ore production quota of approximately 260 million tons for 2026. This follows discussions on curbing output to support prices amid global market shifts. The quota aims to balance supply with value maximization strategies.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ontario fast-tracks Crawford nickel project</title><link>https://www.engineeringnews.co.za/article/ontario-fast-tracks-crawford-nickel-project-2026-01-15</link><description>Ontario is accelerating the Crawford nickel project, described as the Western world's largest nickel sulphide mine. The initiative includes building a new nickel processing plant and downstream alloy production to create a fully domestic supply chain. This aims to bolster Canada's critical minerals leadership.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ontario fast-tracks Crawford nickel project</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/ontario-fast-tracks-crawford-nickel-project-2026-01-15</link><description>The Ontario government is prioritizing the Crawford nickel project in 2026 to unlock one of the world's largest nickel deposits. This move is intended to boost the economy and support secure nickel supply chains. It emphasizes full domestic production from mining to processing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Growth Shares: Strategic Investment Opportunity in 2026</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/nickel-industries-growth-shares-2026-investment-opportunity/</link><description>Nickel Industries is highlighted as a strategic investment pick for 2026 growth shares. The article positions the company amid rising nickel market opportunities. It focuses on potential expansion in production capacity.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Major steel and raw material futures prices in China - January 15, 2026</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-prices/steel-prices-market-analyses/longs-and-billet/major-steel-and-raw-material-futures-prices-in-china-january-15-2026-1429717.htm</link><description>Rebar futures at Shanghai Futures Exchange closed at RMB 3,160/mt ($451/mt) on January 15, 2026. Other steel products like HRC listed with weekly changes; iron ore down 0.73%, scrap up 0.88%. Turkish rebar index up 0.17%, reflecting mixed regional trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Coolbrook Named on the 2026 Global Cleantech 100</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20260115771313/en/Coolbrook-Named-on-the-2026-Global-Cleantech-100</link><description>Coolbrook has been recognized on the 2026 Global Cleantech 100 for its RotoDynamic Technology, which replaces fossil fuel burning in heavy industries like iron and steel with electrification. The technology's RotoDynamic Reactor and Heater achieve temperatures up to 1700°C for carbon-free production, potentially cutting 2.4 billion tons of annual CO2 emissions. It supports rapid decarbonization in steel, cement, and chemicals sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto and Amazon Web Services collaborate to bring low-carbon Nuton copper to U.S. data centres</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2026/rio-tinto-and-amazon-web-services-collaborate-to-bring-low-carbon-nuton-copper-to-u-s--data-centres</link><description>Rio Tinto and Amazon Web Services have partnered to deploy Nuton copper technology at U.S. data centers. The technology is projected to use substantially less water and generate lower carbon emissions than conventional concentrator-based copper production methods.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia secures mining quota approval for 2026</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/news/off-the-wire/2026-01-15/vale-indonesia-secures-mining-quota-approval-2026</link><description>Nickel miner PT Vale Indonesia has secured approval for its 2026 mining quota, allowing all operational activities to return to normal. The company did not disclose the specific volume of nickel ore permitted for production this year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Macro factors are mixed, with bullish sentiment slightly cooling in the latter part of the week</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/macro-factors-are-mixed-with-bullish-sentiment-slightly-cooling-in-the-latter-part-of-the-week-aluminium-prices-are-expected-to-fluctuate-at-highs-in-116949</link><description>Mixed macro signals and weak fundamentals persist, but liquidity support keeps aluminum prices elevated. Bullish fund sentiment has cooled slightly after Trump's tariff decision on critical minerals. SHFE aluminum is forecast at RMB 23,800-25,000 per tonne, LME at USD 3,080-3,200 per tonne next week.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Indonesian Mining Restrictions Send Shockwaves Through Global Markets</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hPkZng04cFo</link><description>The nickel market experienced significant volatility in early 2026, with prices climbing $2,200 per ton to $18,650 following Vale's announcement of mining permit delays in Indonesia. Market observers anticipate prices could reach $20,000 per ton during the January-March quarter as Chinese processors face mounting pressure to secure material.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Algoma Steel Shuts Down Cokemaking, Looks to Green Steel Future</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>As Algoma Steel nears completion of its switch to electric arc furnace steelmaking, the Canadian producer has shut down its coke plant. This transition represents a shift toward green steel production methods.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>First Coils Produced at Tata Steel's CSP Plant Following Upgrades by SMS group</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>SMS group completed its upgrade project for Tata Steel Ltd.'s Jamshedpur CSP plant in Jharkhand, India, and the facility has begun rolling its first coils. This upgrade enhances production capacity at the Indian steelmaker.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Restarts Heat Treatment, Finishing Operations</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>Tenaris announced the restart of OCTG heat treatment and finishing operations at its Koppel, Pennsylvania plant. This restart increases production capacity for oil country tubular goods.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Most of copper's rally has happened, Goldman Sachs says. They fear a correction is coming</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/marketwatch/20260115151/most-of-coppers-rally-has-happened-goldman-sachs-says-they-fear-a-correction-is-coming</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts a growing copper surplus and an 18% price drop to $11,000 per ton by end-2026, attributing the recent 23% rally since November largely to speculative inflows rather than fundamentals. High prices are encouraging substitution with aluminum and cooling demand, with global inventories building ahead of Lunar New Year. Peel Hunt echoes this, forecasting a 2026 average of $11,750 despite raising estimates.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Most of copper's rally has happened, Goldman Sachs says. They fear a correction is coming</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/marketwatch/20260115151/most-of-coppers-rally-has-happened-goldman-sachs-says-they-fear-a-correction-is-coming</link><description>Goldman Sachs forecasts a growing copper surplus in 2026, raised to 300,000 metric tons, leading to an 18% price drop to $11,000 per ton by year-end due to high prices cooling demand and boosting scrap supply. The recent 23% rally since November was driven by speculative inflows rather than fundamentals, with EV manufacturers reducing copper use and switching to aluminum. Global inventories are building ahead of restocking.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Rebound</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel futures climbed to around $17,900 per tonne, rebounding from the previous week's sharp pullback as buying momentum returned. Improving demand from Chinese stainless steel mills and EV battery producers is supporting the rebound, while traders adjust speculative positions amid ongoing supply uncertainty.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>TRADE REVIEW: Asian nickel market faces Q1 pressure as oversupply outweighs output cuts</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/011526-trade-review-asian-nickel-market-faces-q1-pressure-as-oversupply-outweighs-output-cuts</link><description>The Asian nickel market anticipates Q1 pressure from oversupply despite output cuts, with Indonesia planning to reduce nickel output in 2026 to support prices and Vale Indonesia halting mining operations on January 2 due to delayed 2026 approvals. Six new HPAL projects could add over 400,000 mt/y of nickel in MHP capacity, though rising sulfur costs may limit impact. S&amp;P Global projects a nickel surplus of 179,000 mt through 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesian Mining Restrictions Send Shockwaves Through Global Nickel Market</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hPkZng04cFo</link><description>Nickel prices climbed $2,200/ton to $18,650 after Vale's mining permit delays in Indonesia, confirming real supply constraints with rises in nickel pig iron and stainless steel prices. Restrictions coincide with weak Q1 output from alternatives like the Philippines, potentially pushing prices to $20,000/ton. Canada Nickel expanded resources at Reid deposit, enhancing Timmins district potential.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>TRADE REVIEW: Asian nickel market faces Q1 pressure as oversupply outweighs output cuts</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/011526-trade-review-asian-nickel-market-faces-q1-pressure-as-oversupply-outweighs-output-cuts</link><description>The Asian nickel market faces oversupply pressure in Q1 2026 despite Indonesia's production controls, with six new HPAL projects potentially adding over 400,000 mt/y of nickel capacity. Automakers are shifting toward lower-cost lithium-iron-phosphate batteries and mid-nickel NMC chemistries, reducing demand for high-nickel battery materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Steel Caucus hears unified call for tougher trade enforcement</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/15/steel-caucus-hears-unified-call-for-tougher-trade-enforcement/</link><description>U.S. Steel highlighted investment momentum with upgrades across multiple facilities and major projects including Big River 2, a new hot strip mill. Industry leaders called for stronger trade laws and melt-and-pour standards to address rising global excess capacity projected to reach 720 million metric tons by 2027.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>This week, the macro cycle rebounded, aluminum | SMM - Metal News</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103141883</link><description>This week, macroeconomic cycles rebounded, leading to unexpected destocking in aluminum inventories. Aluminum prices showed a steady rise as a result. The report highlights positive momentum in the aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>January 16, 2026, Jinshi Futures Morning Report: The Trump Administration</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/67476046/january-16-2026-jinshi-futures-morning-report-the-trump-administration?futusource=news_newspage_recommend</link><description>China Iron and Steel Association reports key steel enterprises produced 19.97 million tons of crude steel in early January, up 21.6% from prior period, estimating national daily output at 2.48 million tons. Mysteel data shows rebar production at 1.903 million tons for week ending January 15, down 0.39%, while apparent demand rose 8.79%. LME base metals mostly declined amid ferrous metals updates.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Business Intelligence Group Honors Axalta with Six BIG Innovation Awards</title><link>https://ir.axalta.com/news/press-releases/detail/678/business-intelligence-group-honors-axalta-with-six-big-innovation-awards</link><description>Axalta received awards for coatings innovations enhancing sustainability in automotive and industrial applications, including electrical steel coatings for efficient electric motors. Technologies like Lumeera 3250 low-bake clearcoat reduce CO2 emissions by at least 20% per vehicle by curing at lower temperatures. Other solutions offer energy savings up to 40%, zero VOCs, and high transfer efficiency for cabinet coatings.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Capstone Copper Achieves Production Guidance</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/16/capstone-copper-achieves-production-guidance/</link><description>Capstone Copper reported record 2025 copper production of 224,764 tonnes, exceeding guidance and up 22% from 2024. Growth was driven by the Mantoverde Development Project and Mantos Blancos debottlenecking, with a record quarterly output of 58,273 tonnes in December. Despite a strike, Mantoverde operates at 75% capacity, and shares surged post-announcement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why Capstone Copper, Catalyst Metals, DroneShield, and Wildcat shares are rising today</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/16/why-capstone-copper-catalyst-metals-droneshield-and-wildcat-shares-are-rising-today/</link><description>Capstone Copper achieved its FY 2025 production guidance with record 224,764 tonnes of copper, up 22% year-over-year due to key project executions. CEO Cashel Meagher highlighted transformational growth from catalysts like Mantoverde. Shares rose 7.5% following the announcement.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Quantum backs Panama's plan to allow stockpile processing at shut copper mine</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/first-quantum-backs-panamas-plan-to-allow-stockpile-processing-at-shut-copper-mine-2026-01-16</link><description>First Quantum Minerals supports Panama's plan to process stockpiles at the shut Cobre Panama copper mine. The company awaits formal approvals to coordinate activities with the government. This could enable some production resumption from existing materials.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Experienced a Significant Correction on January 16</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103723987/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-experienced-a-significant-correction-on-january-16-central-bank-cuts-relending-an</link><description>On January 16, SMM #1 refined nickel prices ranged from 144,700-154,000 yuan/mt, averaging 149,350 yuan/mt, down 700 yuan/mt from the previous day. Spot premiums for Jinchuan #1 refined nickel averaged 6,500 yuan/mt, down 1,500 yuan/mt. The SHFE nickel contract (2602) closed the morning session at 142,540 yuan/mt, down 3.19%, amid central bank rate cuts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] January 16 — Supply side, upstream offers remained at 1,050-1,100 yuan/mtu</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103724001/smm-nickel-market-price-hike-fails-to-boost-demand-cautious-sentiment-persists</link><description>On January 16, upstream offers for nickel remained stable at 1,050-1,100 yuan/mtu, with some iron plants holding firm. A price hike failed to boost demand, as cautious sentiment persists in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>In Case You Missed It - BC Extra Upgrades &amp; Downgrades - 16-01-26</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2026/01/16/in-case-you-missed-it-bc-extra-upgrades-downgrades-16-01-26/</link><description>Canaccord Genuity upgrades Nickel Industries Limited to Buy, raising the target to $1.05 from $0.80 due to higher nickel price forecasts and base metals strength. The broker expects weaker nickel prices to impact EBITDA but sees upside from revised metal price outlooks, including copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel and cobalt out, CO2 in at Turnagain</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/16/news/nickel-and-cobalt-out-co2-in-at-turnagain/9492.html</link><description>The Turnagain nickel-cobalt project is shifting focus from nickel and cobalt production to CO2 sequestration. Details on the operational changes at the site were reported in the latest update.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Quantum Minerals Announces 2025 Preliminary Production and 2026-2028 Guidance</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2026/01/16/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/first-quantum-minerals-announces-2025-preliminary-production-and-2026-2028-guidance/2260062</link><description>First Quantum Minerals released preliminary 2025 production figures and provided guidance for nickel and other metals through 2028. The announcement details expected output capacities in U.S. dollars.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>GT reassesses Finnish nickel-PGM project</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2026/01/16/northern-neighbors/gt-reassesses-finnish-nickel-pgm-project/9490.html</link><description>GT Resources is reassessing its Kaukua nickel-PGM project in Finland by analyzing over 4,600 historic pulps and 500 infill samples to standardize data. The program aims to update resource estimates ahead of potential development.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 3,140.70 USD/T on January 16, 2026, down 0.93% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 8.21%, and are up 17.10% compared to the same time last year. The price reflects trading on a contract for difference tracking the benchmark market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to 3,140.70 USD/T on January 16, 2026, amid tightening supply and production disruptions. China is curbing overcapacity, set to breach its 45 million ton output cap, while new smelters in Indonesia face setbacks. Operations at smelters in Iceland, Mozambique, and Australia are suspended due to high energy costs, equipment failures, bauxite sourcing issues, and geopolitical risks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>AMU: Labor agreement timelines converge in US aluminum</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2026/01/16/labor-contracts-unions-aluminum-2026-trade-prices/</link><description>Multiple collective bargaining agreements at U.S. aluminum producers are expiring or entering negotiations in 2026, potentially impacting operations. This convergence occurs amid trade protections, high aluminum prices, elevated Midwest premiums, and uneven demand. Facilities like Constellium’s Muscle Shoals and Ravenswood are approaching key bargaining phases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel traded flat at around 3,138-3,141 CNY/T on January 16, 2026, marking a slight 0.10% increase from the previous day. Over the past month, prices rose 1.65-1.75%, though they remain 5.68-5.77% lower than a year ago. Steel rebar futures gained on hopes of China stimulus, reaching CNY 3,130 per tonne amid discussions on fiscal measures to boost demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US-based Worthington Steel to acquire Klöckner &amp; Co for $2.4 billion</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Worthington Steel announced plans to acquire Klöckner &amp; Co for $2.4 billion, potentially impacting steel production and distribution capacities. This deal highlights consolidation trends in the global steel sector. Further details on production implications are emerging.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ferrexpo reduced production by 9% y/y in 2025</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Ukrainian producer Ferrexpo reported a 9% year-on-year decline in production for 2025, affecting steel-related output. This reduction comes amid ongoing market challenges. The news was published in the context of recent steel market updates.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Nederland Opens New Production Line for Sustainable Food Packaging</title><link>https://www.tatasteel.com/newsroom/press-releases/india/2026/tata-steel-nederland-opens-new-production-line-for-sustainable-food-packaging/</link><description>Tata Steel Nederland has commissioned a new production line using innovative TCCT (Trivalent Chromium Coating Technology) for more sustainable packaging steel production, complying with future legislation. This patented technology, combined with Protact®, enhances food safety, reduces costs by eliminating extra lacquer layers, and simplifies supply chains. It sets a new European standard for eco-friendly steel packaging.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 1.14% Lower at $5.7885 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601165062/comex-copper-ends-the-week-114-lower-at-57885-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for January delivery fell 6.70 cents per pound, or 1.14%, to $5.7885 over the week, down two of the past three weeks. It declined 15.95 cents or 2.68% on the day, marking the largest one-day drop since January 7, 2026. Year-to-date, it is up 2.82%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper fell to 5.79 USD/Lbs on January 16, down 3.40% from the previous day, amid reports of drops due to China curbing high-frequency trading and retreating from record highs. Over the past month, prices rose 7.88%, and year-over-year up 33.95%. Historically, it reached an all-time high of 6.11 USD/Lbs in January 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper theft ticks up as prices surge</title><link>https://www.foxbusiness.com/video/6387831862112</link><description>Copper thefts are increasing as prices surge, highlighting secondary market impacts of rising copper values. The video discusses trends in theft related to high commodity prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 17,825 USD/T on January 16, 2026, down 4.14% from the previous day, though up 24.09% over the past month. A later update shows prices at 17,566.63 USD/T, down 5.53% daily but up 22.29% monthly and 9.25% year-over-year. This reflects ongoing volatility amid broader market trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Extends Drop Amid Lack of Detail on Indonesia Output Cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-extends-drop-amid-lack-of-detail-on-indonesia-output-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices settled 4.1% lower at $17,155 per ton on the LME, extending declines from a 19-month high due to absent details on Indonesia's output cuts. Three-month futures dropped as much as 5.9% after peaking at $18,800 per ton. The pullback follows a rally driven by supply concerns from the top producer.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Arca &amp; Giga Metals To Explore CDR At Nickel Mine In Canada</title><link>https://carbonherald.com/arca-giga-metals-to-explore-cdr-at-nickel-mine-in-canada/</link><description>Arca Climate Technologies has a 10-year exclusive agreement to assess carbon dioxide removal potential at Giga Metals' Turnagain nickel project using ultramafic waste. The technology accelerates CO2 mineralization, targeting 220 million tonnes of removal, and builds on a decade of collaboration for ESG-enhanced nickel production. This aligns with Canada's critical minerals priorities and demonstrates innovative mining with societal benefits.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper's Bellwether: A Deep-Dive into Freeport-McMoRan (FCX)</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/finterra-2026-1-16-coppers-bellwether-a-deep-dive-into-freeport-mcmoran-fcx</link><description>This article examines Freeport-McMoRan's innovations in copper extraction, particularly its proprietary leaching technology that recovers copper from low-grade waste rock at costs under $1.00/lb, currently producing 300 million pounds annually. The company plans to double this output by 2028, effectively creating a major new mine without traditional environmental or capital costs. It also highlights FCX's newly completed $3.7 billion Manyar Smelter in Indonesia for downstream processing.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 17.01.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel exchanges, showing Shanghai Futures rebar prices flat at 0.00 change on January 16, 2026, for 1-3 month terms. Other futures like Turkey, China, Europe, and North America 1-month terms also held steady as of January 15, 2026. The platform highlights ongoing price monitoring amid global market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper hits one-week low on profit-taking and China demand concerns</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-one-week-low-on-profit-taking-and-china-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices hit a one-week low on Friday due to profit-taking after a rally driven by speculative funds. Physical demand from buyers in China remained muted. This reflects recent market volatility in the commodity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Amazon to be first user of copper made by Rio Tinto venture</title><link>https://www.mining.com/amazon-to-be-first-user-of-copper-made-by-rio-tinto-venture/</link><description>Amazon Web Services will be the first to use copper produced at an Arizona mine using Nuton's bioleaching technology, which uses microorganisms to extract copper from sulfide ores. The technology reduces water usage by up to 80% and carbon emissions by as much as 60% compared to traditional copper production, while achieving recovery rates of up to 85%.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Battery-Grade Nickel Sulphate Prices Rise on January 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103143543/smm-battery-grade-nickel-sulphate-prices-rise-on-january-17</link><description>On January 17, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price reached 26,516 yuan/mt. Quotations for battery-grade nickel sulphate showed an upward trend. This indicates rising prices in nickel derivatives amid recent market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Live Nickel Prices Today</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-prices-today/</link><description>Nickel prices retreated on January 17, 2026, as markets reassessed Indonesia's proposed output cuts. This follows recent volatility in the nickel market. The analysis highlights ongoing price adjustments amid supply uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Squeeze Intensifies as Indonesia Restricts Exports and Canada Accelerates Projects</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-supply-squeeze-intensifies-as-indonesia-restricts-exports-and-canada-accelerates-projects</link><description>Nickel prices surged to $18,650 following Indonesian supply restrictions confirmed by Vale's mining halt. Canada Nickel's Crawford project received Ontario's fast-track approval as a strategic alternative, while the Reid deposit resource increased 46% to 5 million tonnes of contained nickel with superior economics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia's ESDM confirms plan to reduce nickel production to 250-260 million tonnes for 2026</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5110162-flash-indonesias-esdm-confirms-plan-to-reduce-nickel-production-to-250-260-million-tonnes-for-2026</link><description>Indonesia's Ministry of Energy and Mineral Resources confirmed a nickel production target of 250-260 million tonnes for 2026, down from 379 million tonnes in 2025. The quota reduction aims to align with domestic processing capacity and support nickel prices, with global prices surging to $18,000/tonne following the announcement.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Can nickel prices hit $25,000 in 2026?</title><link>https://theoregongroup.substack.com/p/can-nickel-prices-hit-25000-in-2026</link><description>Nickel prices jumped to $16,500–$18,500 per ton in early January 2026, with Indonesia shifting from maximizing supply to maximizing value through production cuts. Only 55% of Indonesia's approved nickel ore production capacity was actually utilized in 2025, suggesting much of the supposed surplus was statistical illusion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Highlights Relevance of Pipestone XL Awaruite Nickel-Cobalt Alloy Discovery to Address U.S. Critical Mineral Supply Chain Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/280485/First-Atlantic-Nickel-Highlights-Relevance-of-Pipestone-XL-Awaruite-NickelCobalt-Alloy-Discovery-to-Address-U.S.-Critical-Mineral-Supply-Chain-Vulnerabilities-Identified-in-January-14-2026-White-House-Proclamation</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel announced preliminary metallurgical testing results for its Pipestone XL project, with magnetic concentrate averaging 1.3% nickel that can be upgraded to approximately 60% through flotation. The project also identified chromium as a potential recoverable mineral, addressing North America's lack of sufficient mined chromium concentrates.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Uranium and copper explode out of the blocks in early 2026</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1jQh6Xy-dX4</link><description>Both uranium and copper prices have exploded upward in the first weeks of 2026 due to positive supply-demand dynamics, with expectations of continued upward movement throughout the year. The video provides a weekly market update on January 17, highlighting strong performances in related ETFs and stocks.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices held flat at $17,806.3/ton over the weekend, consolidating recent volatility</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-prices-today/</link><description>Nickel prices remained stable over the weekend at $17,806.3 per ton as the market consolidated recent volatility. The market continues to monitor supply dynamics and geopolitical factors affecting price movements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Battery Metals: The Strategic Investment Case for 2026</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/battery-metals-the-strategic-investment-case-for-2026</link><description>Global nickel demand is forecast to grow over 7% annually and double to 5-6 million tonnes by 2030, driven by electric vehicle battery production. Canada Nickel's Crawford project and other Western projects are pursuing innovative approaches including carbon sequestration and net-zero nickel production to secure financing in a supply-constrained market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Top Power Press Manufacturers Navigate a Transforming Global Metalforming Market</title><link>https://natlawreview.com/press-releases/top-power-press-manufacturers-navigate-transforming-global-metalforming</link><description>Power press manufacturers are responding to tightening environmental regulations and market demands by developing equipment with improved hydraulic efficiency, reduced energy consumption, and enhanced safety systems. Innovation now focuses on sustainability through energy recovery technologies, digital twins for optimization, and intelligent design principles that reduce operating costs while meeting stricter emissions standards.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>China Aluminum Output at Record, Steel Below 1 Billion Tons</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/china-aluminum-output-at-record-steel-below-1-billion-tons/</link><description>China's aluminum output reached a record high, contrasting with steel production falling below 1 billion tons. Aluminum prices are set to benefit from this supply-demand mismatch.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CICC Expects Aluminum Prices to Continue Hitting New Highs</title><link>https://www.aastocks.com/en/usq/news/comment.aspx?id=NOW.1497023&amp;catg=4</link><description>CICC predicts aluminum prices will keep reaching new highs due to widening supply-demand gaps and supportive global fiscal policies. Low costs are expected to widen profits per ton as prices rise.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China's aluminium output hits record, steel below one billion tonnes</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/chinas-aluminium-output-hits-record-steel-below-one-billion-tonnes</link><description>China's aluminum production rose 2.4% to a record 45 million tonnes in 2025, with December output hitting 3.9 million tonnes. The government maintains a 45-million-tonne capacity cap since 2017 to curb oversupply and emissions, though forecasts predict slight capacity increases. This supports higher aluminum prices amid rising demand and supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China Aluminum Output at Record, Steel Below 1 Billion Tons</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/china-aluminum-output-at-record-steel-below-1-billion-tons/</link><description>China's aluminum output reached a record 45.02 million tons in 2025, up 2.4% from the previous year, marking annual increases throughout the decade. This contrasts with steel production falling below one billion tonnes. The data comes from the national statistics bureau.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China economy stumbles in Q4 with 4.5% growth as aluminum and coal outputs hit record</title><link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/china-economy-stumbles-in-q4-with-4-5-growth/</link><description>China's economy grew 4.5% in Q4 amid record aluminum and coal outputs, highlighting production strength despite slower overall growth. Aluminum production hit new highs, contributing to industrial output. This occurs as the economy faces broader challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Top Power Press Manufacturers Navigate a Transforming Global Metalforming Market</title><link>https://www.einpresswire.com/article/884407979/top-power-press-manufacturers-navigate-a-transforming-global-metalforming-market</link><description>Leading power press manufacturers are adapting to industry shifts by integrating automation, energy efficiency, and digital tools while addressing stricter environmental regulations on emissions and energy use. Innovations include optimized hydraulic systems for reduced oil usage, energy recovery technologies, and safety features like light curtains. These sustainable advancements lower operating costs and support eco-friendly metalforming for applications like automotive and aerospace components.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Steel prices today, January 19th: Global market shows strong divergence, domestic prices remain stable</title><link>https://baonghean.vn/en/gia-thep-hom-nay-191-thi-truong-the-gioi-phan-hoa-manh-gia-trong-nuoc-giu-on-dinh-10320645.html</link><description>Global steel markets exhibit strong divergence on January 19, while domestic prices in Vietnam remain stable. The article highlights varying trends across international regions amid ongoing market dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Aluminum Output at Record, Steel Below 1 Billion Tons</title><link>https://www.energyconnects.com/news/oil/2026/january/china-aluminum-output-at-record-steel-below-1-billion-tons/</link><description>China's steel output is projected to stay below 1 billion tons, contrasting with record aluminum production. This mismatch is expected to support aluminum prices while influencing steel market trends.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Industrial Leads for the Week of January 19, 2026</title><link>https://www.enr.com/articles/62375-industrial-leads-for-the-week-of-january-19-2026</link><description>United States Steel Corp. plans to upgrade the hot strip mill at its Gary Works steel mill in Gary, Indiana. The project involves purchasing equipment to enhance production capacity at the facility.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>From Silver to Copper: How Solar Giants Are Innovating to Cut Costs and Boost Efficiency</title><link>https://now.solar/2026/01/19/from-silver-to-copper-how-solar-giants-are-innovating-to-cut-costs-and-boost-efficiency-investing-news-network/</link><description>Amid a 200% surge in silver prices, solar industry leaders are innovating by shifting to copper as a cost-effective alternative to reduce expenses and improve efficiency. This transition addresses rising material costs in photovoltaic production. The move supports sustainability by leveraging copper's availability for scaling solar technology.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review - Nickel prices adjusted and pulled back on January 19</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103726430/smm-nickel-midday-review-nickel-prices-adjusted-and-pulled-back-on-january-19-while-chinas-gdp-grew-5-yoy-in-2025</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices fell to an average of 145,900 yuan/mt, down 3,450 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. The SHFE nickel futures contract pulled back sharply before rebounding, closing at 142,060 yuan/mt, down 1.6%. The market remains caught between expectations for Indonesian production cuts and the reality of high inventory and weak demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries posts Q4 earnings and lifts outlook</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/19/nickel-industries-posts-q4-earnings-and-lifts-outlook/</link><description>Nickel Industries Ltd reported December quarter adjusted EBITDA of US$35–40 million, impacted by delays in securing an increased RKAB permit for its Hengjaya Mine, leading to sharply reduced ore sales. The HNC HPAL operation achieved record quarterly earnings, and operations resumed in mid-December with strong early 2026 sales of 735,000 wmt of nickel ore by January 17. The company anticipates growth from the upcoming Excelsior Nickel Cobalt project to boost nickel production for electric vehicle batteries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Plunges from Over 2-Year High - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/515604</link><description>Nickel futures dropped to $17,100 per tonne from a two-year high of $18,875 due to reconsidered output cuts by Indonesia, which proposed a 34% reduction in 2026 nickel output amid oversupply concerns and deteriorating ore grades. Expected 2026 ore quotas of 250-260 million tonnes fall below smelter demand and last year's 379 million tonnes. Despite surpluses, demand from electric vehicles offsets weaker stainless steel usage.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries expecting strong 2026</title><link>https://www.miningnews.net/miners/news-analysis/4525811/nickel-industries-expecting-strong-2026</link><description>Nickel Industries missed approximately A$67 million in December quarter earnings due to Indonesian authorities' delay in approving a new sales quota. Despite this, the company reports a strong start to 2026 operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Flags Lower Quarterly EBITDA After RKAB Delay, But Hengjaya Mine Rebounds in Early 2026</title><link>https://www.tipranks.com/news/company-announcements/nickel-industries-flags-lower-quarterly-ebitda-after-rkab-delay-but-hengjaya-mine-rebounds-in-early-2026</link><description>Nickel Industries expects December quarter adjusted EBITDA of US$35–40 million, reduced by RKAB permit delays causing a plunge in Hengjaya Mine ore sales. The mine has rebounded with strong performance in early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The first Energy Release contract in the Aosta Valley is underway: agreement signed between the CVA Group and Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>CVA will construct four new photovoltaic plants in Sicily with over 20 MW capacity, expected to produce 593,600 MWh annually and be fully operational by 2026. This marks the first Energy Release agreement in the Aosta Valley and supports Cogne Acciai Speciali's green energy transition and reduced environmental impact. The partnership strengthens both companies' roles in decarbonization and aligns with the Regional Energy and Environmental Plan (PEAR VDA 2030) and European Green Deal.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italian steelmaker Cogne Acciai Speciali sourcing all energy from renewables</title><link>https://eurometal.net/italian-steelmaker-cogne-acciai-speciali-sourcing-all-energy-from-renewables/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali is now sourcing all power needs in Europe from renewable energy and plans to build a 1-MW electrolyzer and hydroelectric plant by June 2026 at its main Italian site in Aosta. The electrolyzer will produce 210 normal cubic meters of hydrogen per hour, powered by renewable sources, as part of Italy's National Recovery and Resilience Plan funded by the European Union through NextGenerationEU.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali uses 100% renewable electricity in Europe</title><link>https://www.stainless.club/industry-news/read/cogne-acciai-speciali-uses-100-renewable-electricity-in-europe.html</link><description>Since January 2024, all electricity supplied to Cogne Acciai Speciali's European production plants has come from renewable sources. The Italian stainless steel longs producer has completed its transition to environmentally sustainable production across the EU.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has launched a green hydrogen pilot plant as part of the 'Green Hydrogen in Cogne' initiative, marking the first project to replace fossil natural gas with green hydrogen in an industrial heat treatment application.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Capital Flood Reshapes Aluminum's Price Logic: Between Belief and Doubt</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-29819.html</link><description>China's electrolytic aluminum capacity reached 44.83 million tons by end-2025, hitting the regulatory ceiling and accounting for over 57% of global capacity, with output at 44.23 million tons. A production cut at Century Aluminum's Iceland smelter triggered global supply shocks and price surges. China's centralized capacity provides strong supply regulation power in the industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>BHP Upgrades Copper Output Guidance; Raises Cost of Potash Project (2nd Update)</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601194210/bhp-upgrades-copper-output-guidance-raises-cost-of-potash-project-again-2nd-update</link><description>BHP upgraded its fiscal year copper production guidance to 1.9-2.0 million metric tons, supported by strong performance at Escondida mine amid record-high prices from healthy demand and competitor supply disruptions. U.S. copper futures surged to all-time highs, with BHP noting a 29% jump in realized copper prices quarter-over-quarter. CEO highlights resilient Chinese demand and positive 2026 global growth outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>January 20 SMM Cast Aluminum Alloy Morning Comment</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103727784</link><description>Aluminum prices continued to retreat on January 19, with SMM A00 spot aluminum closing at 23,870 yuan/mt, down 160 yuan/mt. The aluminum alloy 2603 futures contract closed at 22,910 yuan/mt, up slightly by 0.09%. Secondary aluminum alloy producers maintained stable offers amid firm costs, low inventory, and bullish expectations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum and copper prices take breather after explosive start to 2026</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-and-copper-prices-take-breather-after-explosive-start-to-2026/</link><description>Aluminum prices steadied at $3,197.50 a ton on the LME, the highest in more than three years, following an explosive start to 2026. Copper wavered around a record, while tin rose after rallying. Investors are assessing the next moves for metals amid recent volatility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China Aluminum Output Hits Record 45.02M Tons in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/china-energy-transition-aluminum-growth-2026/</link><description>China's aluminum production reached a record high of 45.02 million tonnes in 2025, exceeding the government's 45-million-ton cap. This surge highlights ongoing growth amid energy transition efforts. The output milestone underscores China's dominant role in global aluminum supply.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium's unifying approach to net-zero transformation</title><link>https://www.worldclimatefoundation.org/post/climate-nature-and-people-aluminium-s-unifying-approach-to-net-zero-transformation</link><description>The aluminum industry is advancing decarbonization through multiple innovations including ELYSIS zero-carbon smelting technology and CelestiAL solar-powered aluminum production by Emirates Global Aluminium. The sector is implementing a multi-faceted strategy combining clean energy investments with recycling revolution to achieve net-zero goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 937.08 USD/T on January 19, 2026, down 0.20% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 3.20% and are up 34.83% year-over-year. Data was last updated on January 20, 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel prices hiked again amid rising exports</title><link>https://tv.rediff.com/business/steel-prices-hiked-again-amid-rising-exports/367686</link><description>Steel prices in India were hiked again on Friday due to safeguard duties, rising exports, and higher input costs. Some mills increased hot-rolled coil (HRC) prices by 500-750 per tonne. HRC serves as a benchmark for flat steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Latest updates on metals prices worldwide at 0200 GMT, Jan. 20</title><link>https://english.news.cn/20260120/40d7caee401e486c8f030ef3476e9c36/c.html</link><description>At 0200 GMT on Jan. 20, 2026, COMEX copper price stood at 5.82 USD, amid latest global metals updates including gold, iron ore, palladium, and platinum. Reflects current spot pricing in ongoing volatile market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP Boosts Copper Production Outlook for FY26</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/20/bhp-boosts-copper-production-outlook-for-fy26/</link><description>BHP has increased its fiscal year 2026 copper production guidance to between 1.9 and 2.0 million tonnes, driven by record throughput at the Escondida mine and strong asset performance. The company also reported gains in iron ore and coal production amid rising commodity prices. CEO Mike Henry highlighted strong operating momentum and a pathway to 2 million tonnes of copper production in the 2030s.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP lifts copper guidance after record half-year output</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/20/bhp-lifts-copper-guidance-after-record-half-year-output/</link><description>BHP upgraded its FY26 copper production guidance to 1,900–2,000 kt following record half-year output and strong performance at Escondida. Iron ore and coal production also rose, supported by higher prices including copper up 32%. Management emphasized a significant copper growth pipeline targeting around 2 Mt in the 2030s.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP Upgrades Copper Output Guidance; Raises Cost of Potash Project (Again) (2nd Update)</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202601194210/bhp-upgrades-copper-output-guidance-raises-cost-of-potash-project-again-2nd-update</link><description>BHP Group raised its FY26 copper production guidance to 1.9-2.0 million metric tons, fueled by strong Escondida performance amid record-high copper prices. Second-quarter copper output was 490,500 tons, with first-half production flat year-over-year. Iron ore production increased, though prices face pressure from China negotiations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chile delays copper output peak, cuts short-term forecasts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/chile-delays-copper-output-peak-cuts-short-term-forecasts/</link><description>Chile, the world's largest copper producer, delayed its peak annual output goal above 6 million tons by several years and cut forecasts for 2026-2031 due to falling ore grades and mining plan adjustments. Production is expected to stabilize at current levels with gradual recovery toward the period's end. The revision was outlined in a Cochilco report.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On January 20, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103728813/</link><description>On January 20, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 140,900-151,800 yuan/mt, averaging 146,350 yuan/mt, up 450 yuan/mt from the previous day. This indicates a slight upward movement in Chinese refined nickel pricing amid ongoing market fluctuations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tariff Noise, Limited Signal</title><link>https://www.sucdenfinancial.com/en/market-insights/metals-outlook/daily-base-metals-analysis/2026-01-20/</link><description>Base metals, including nickel, recovered some of Friday's weakness on January 20, with expectations of transitioning into a rangebound phase in the near term. Dip-buying persisted, reflecting cautious market sentiment amid tariff discussions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>TECH Project high-grade nickel is primed to fuel the global green transition</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/tech-project-high-grade-nickel-is-primed-to-fuel-the-global-green-transition/32893/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals' TECH Project aims to become a leading source of high-grade, ethically derived nickel for EV batteries and green energy. The project features the DNi Process, an environmentally-friendly extraction method with 98% nitric acid recycling and no tailings dam requirements, positioning it as a carbon-negative production facility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>