<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 05:20:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Surged Sharply to Break Through 130000 yuan/mt on December 30 as the Customs Tariff Commission of the State Council Released the 2026 Tariff Adjustment Plan</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103697607/</link><description>Nickel prices surged sharply on December 30, with SMM #1 refined nickel trading at 128,400-136,700 yuan/mt, averaging 132,550 yuan/mt. The price increase was driven by the Customs Tariff Commission of the State Council releasing the 2026 tariff adjustment plan.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On December 30, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 128,400–136,700 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103697555/</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices on December 30 ranged from 128,400–136,700 yuan/mt with an average price of 132,550 yuan/mt, up 850 yuan/mt from the previous trading session.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>From Glencore trader to Indonesia's nickel king</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/30/from-glencore-trader-to-indonesias-nickel-king</link><description>A former Glencore trader has become the dominant figure in Indonesia's nickel ore trade, handling about a third of the market amid the country's 70% global production share. His stakes span vast mining concessions critical for batteries and EVs. This occurs as Indonesia transitions to influencing nickel prices deliberately.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>ZincFive Raises $30 Million in Oversubscribed Series F Financing</title><link>https://zincfive.com/news/zincfive-raises-30-million-in-oversubscribed-series-f-financing/</link><description>ZincFive secured $30 million in Series F funding to scale production of its patented nickel-zinc battery technology for AI data centers. The company launched its BC 2 AI cabinet, engineered for dynamic AI workloads with zero thermal-runaway risk and 96% recyclability, strengthening its position as a key enabler of sustainable, AI-ready infrastructure.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>From Glencore trader to Indonesia's nickel king</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/30/from-glencore-trader-to-indonesias-nickel-king</link><description>Indonesia controls nearly 70% of global nickel production through technological innovations that transformed low-grade deposits into battery-grade nickel. Key developments include a 2014 ore export ban that shifted the country toward processing and manufacturing, and the adoption of high-pressure acid leaching (HPAL) technology that enabled cost-effective battery-grade nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>US tariff policy affects Japanese steel industry – JISF</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>US tariff policy is impacting the Japanese steel industry, as reported by JISF on December 30, 2025. Other recent notes include 8% growth in Indian steel demand for FY2025/26. The site aggregates steel market news on prices and trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Kutcho Copper Announces Closing of Flow-Through Financing</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/279231/Kutcho-Copper-Announces-Closing-of-FlowThrough-Financing</link><description>Kutcho Copper Corp closed a flow-through financing to fund exploration on its Kutcho copper-zinc property in British Columbia. The proceeds will qualify as Canadian exploration expenses to be incurred by December 31, 2026. This supports the company's development plans for the project amid risks in mineral exploration and mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Soar to Phase Highs on Dec 30, 2025 Driven by Fund Flows and Supply Disruptions</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103698385/Nickel-Prices-Soar-to-Phase-Highs-on-Dec-30-2025-Driven-by-Fund-Flows-and-Supply-Disruptions</link><description>Nickel prices surged significantly on December 30, 2025, with the LME nickel three-month contract reaching $16,700/mt. The single-day increase exceeded 5%, hitting new phase highs driven by fund flows and supply disruptions. This momentum approached previous peaks amid non-ferrous metal market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Electrifying Steel Heat Treatment for Industrial Decarbonisation</title><link>https://highways.today/2025/12/30/electrifying-steel-heat-treatment/</link><description>A South Korean electrified annealing furnace cuts steel heat treatment emissions by over 98%, replacing fossil fuels with electricity for galvanised steel strips. The technology plans AI optimization for various parameters and scalability to other high-temperature industries. It lowers adoption risks while aiding global decarbonization targets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Surged Sharply to Break Through 130,000 yuan/mt on December 30</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103697607/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Surged-Sharply-to-Break-Through-130000-yuanmt-on-December-30-as-the-Customs-Tariff-Commission-of-the-State-Council-Released-the-2026-Tariff-Adjustment-Plan</link><description>Nickel prices surged sharply on December 30, breaking through the 130,000 yuan/mt level as China's Customs Tariff Commission released its 2026 Tariff Adjustment Plan. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 132,200 yuan/mt, up 3.71%, with spot prices averaging 132,550 yuan/mt. Prices are expected to fluctuate between 125,000-135,000 yuan/mt as markets balance expectations of supply contraction from Indonesia's policy tightening against high inventory and weak demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Jump After Top Producer Indonesia Signals 2026 Output Cut</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news/3112-51714-nickel-prices-jump-after-top-producer-indonesia-signals-2026-output-cut</link><description>Indonesia announced plans to cut nickel production in 2026 to balance supply and demand, causing nickel prices to jump to their highest level since March. Spot nickel rose to $16,500 per tonne on Tuesday from $15,800 on Monday, while the three-month LME nickel contract closed up 6.4%. Indonesia's move aims to reduce the surplus it created by expanding its global market share from 31.5% in 2020 to 60.2% in 2024.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>New aluminium projects in Indonesia ramp up, boosting daily average aluminium production outside China</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/new-aluminium-projects-in-indonesia-ramp-up-boosting-daily-average-aluminium-production-outside-china-116757</link><description>Overseas aluminium production increased 2.2% year-over-year in December 2025, with cumulative 2025 production up 2.8% YoY. New Indonesian aluminium projects in ramp-up stage diluted overall operating rates to 87.7%, while energy challenges threaten smelters in Australia (Tomago) and Mozambique (Mozal), with Mozal scheduled for maintenance shutdown around March 15, 2026 due to power supply disagreements.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>New Aluminum Projects in Indonesia Ramp Up, Boosting Daily Average Aluminum Production Outside China</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103699828/New-Aluminum-Projects-in-Indonesia-Ramp-Up-Boosting-Daily-Average-Aluminum-Production-Outside-China</link><description>Overseas aluminum production in December 2025 rose 2.2% year-over-year with an average monthly operating rate of 87.7%, primarily impacted by new Indonesian projects still in commissioning phase. Energy supply agreements remain critical concerns for major smelters, with Tomago securing long-term energy arrangements and Mozal facing shutdown due to power supply negotiations.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel stocks up 2nd straight day, rally up to 5%; SAIL, JSL hit 52-wk highs</title><link>https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/steel-stocks-up-2nd-straight-day-rally-up-to-5-sail-jsl-hit-52-wk-highs-125123100167_1.html</link><description>Share prices of steel companies rallied up to 5% for the second straight day amid government notification of anti-dumping and safeguard duties on flat steel imports for three years. Leading Indian steelmakers hiked domestic HRC and CRC prices by ₹750/tonne on December 30, 2025, to ~₹49,800/ton and ~₹56,400/ton respectively, with further hikes planned for early January 2026. Prices reflect higher raw material costs, moderate inventories, and recovering demand despite prior corrections from May 2025 highs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 31.12.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides daily updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures Rebar terms unchanged on December 30, 2025, and various 1- and 2-month futures for Turkey, China, Europe, and North America as of December 29, 2025. The platform covers indices, prices, and news for rebar, scrap, and iron/steel markets. No specific price changes noted in the latest snapshot.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper drifts higher, but holds below record with investors wary</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-drifts-higher-but-holds-below-record-with-investors-wary/</link><description>Copper prices rose on Tuesday but remained well below recent record highs as investors stayed cautious. The drift higher reflects ongoing market trends amid supply concerns and demand pressures.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Alara Resources Dispatches 32nd Copper Concentrate Shipment</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/31/alara-resources-dispatches-32nd-copper-concentrate-shipment/</link><description>Alara Resources announced the dispatch of its 32nd shipment of copper concentrate from the Al Wash-hi – Majaza copper-gold mine in Oman on December 30, 2025. The shipment totaled 1378.6 WMT of copper concentrate containing approximately 252.6 MT of copper and 5.3 kg of gold. The mine, operated by Alara’s joint venture Al Hadeetha Resources LLC, has maintained consistent production levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 31, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103699678/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price reached 132,700-142,400 yuan/mt on December 31, with an average of 137,550 yuan/mt. This marks an increase of 5,000 yuan/mt from the previous day. The price surge reflects ongoing market volatility in nickel trading.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel hits nine-month high</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/12/31/nickel-hits-nine-month-high</link><description>Nickel prices hit a nine-month high after Indonesia announced plans to cut supply in 2026 to balance demand and boost prices. The country, producing nearly 70% of global nickel for stainless steel and EV batteries, will tighten mining quotas. Despite a weaker year due to battery demand disappointment, Indonesian output remains central to 2026 price outlook.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Surge Reaches Nine-Month High Following Indonesian Cuts</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/nickel-price-surge-2025-policy-intervention/</link><description>Nickel prices surged to a nine-month high following signals of supply cuts from Indonesia. The move aims to address oversupply and support market prices amid global demand trends. This development highlights Indonesia's influence on nickel market dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices jump to multi-month high on Indonesia supply cut signals</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-prices-jump-to-multi-month-high-on-indonesia-supply-cut-signals</link><description>Nickel prices on the LME surged to a multi-month high on Tuesday after Indonesia signaled supply cuts. The announcement triggered sharp gains amid ongoing supply concerns. Prices reflect expectations of tighter quotas to stabilize the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits Nine-month High as Indonesia Plans to Cut Output</title><link>https://klse.i3investor.com/web/blog/detail/ceomorningbrief/2025-12-31-story-h500614173-Nickel_Hits_Nine_month_High_as_Indonesia_Plans_to_Cut_Output</link><description>Nickel prices hit a nine-month high following Indonesia's announcement to cut supply and boost prices. As the top producer, Indonesia's output reduction plans are driving the market surge.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Hits Nine-Month High on Indonesia Cuts</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/nickel-price-surge-2025-policy-intervention/</link><description>Nickel prices surged to a nine-month high following Indonesia's planned output cuts. The policy intervention by the top producer is fueling the price rally.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>GTRI: EU's CBAM effective January 1 likely to force Indian steel exporters to cut prices by 15-22%</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/gtri-eus-cbam-effective-january-1-likely-to-force-indian-steel-exporters-to-cut-prices-by-15-22-1427205.htm</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism enters its payment phase on January 1, 2026, expected to force Indian steel exporters to reduce prices by 15-22%. CBAM's complex compliance requirements will sharply raise costs, potentially pushing smaller exporters out of the EU market entirely.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>GTRI: EU's CBAM effective January 1 likely to force Indian steel exporters to cut prices by 15-22%</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/gtri-eus-cbam-effective-january-1-likely-to-force-indian-steel-exporters-to-cut-prices-by-15-22-1427205.htm</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) takes effect January 1, 2026, expected to force Indian steel exporters to reduce prices by 15-22 percent. The mechanism requires plant-level emissions accounting and independent verification, with compliance costs potentially pushing smaller exporters out of the EU market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hertha Metals to break ground on commercial steel plant in 2026</title><link>https://www.bizjournals.com/houston/news/2025/12/31/hertha-metals-commercial-plant-2026.html</link><description>Hertha Metals will start construction in 2026 on a commercial steel plant producing 30 tonnes daily using innovative clean iron technology. The project creates 60 permanent jobs and 550 construction roles. It advances sustainable steel production amid growing green steel efforts.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Price increase on aluminum effective Jan. 1, 2026</title><link>https://www.pac-clad.com/price-increase-on-aluminum-effective-jan-1-2026/</link><description>Due to rising raw material costs, Petersen is implementing a 10% price adjustment on aluminum sheets, coils, and panels effective for all shipments starting January 1, 2026. Updated pricing will be shared in advance. The company will continue monitoring market conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Price Forecast to Reach $3,000 in 2026: Analysts</title><link>https://www.devere-group.com/aluminium-price-forecast-to-reach-3000-in-2026-analysts/</link><description>Analysts at Bank of America predict aluminum prices will hit $3,000 per ton in 2026 due to a market deficit, following two years of surplus. Factors include Chinese production curbs, US tariffs, and rebounding global demand. Prices recently traded at $2,685 on the LME, up year-to-date.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price forecast for 2026, according to BCA Research</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/commodities-news/aluminum-price-forecast-for-2026-according-to-bca-research-4420841</link><description>BCA Research expects aluminum prices to remain resilient short-term due to constrained Chinese supply and substitution from copper, but forecasts a fade in 2026 amid weakening global manufacturing demand. Chinese production nears its capacity cap, supporting near-term prices. Increased secondary production and overseas expansions may offset pressures later.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>JPMorgan: Aluminum Prices to Near $3000/mt in Q1 2026, But Indonesia's Supply Growth May Offset Rise Later</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103644058/JPMorgan:-Aluminum-Prices-to-Near-3000mt-in-Q1-2026-But-Indonesias-Supply-Growth-May-Offset-Rise-Later</link><description>JPMorgan forecasts aluminum prices approaching $3,000 per mt in Q1 2026, driven by rising copper attractiveness. However, Indonesia's supply growth may offset price rises later. This reflects ongoing market tightness early in the year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: Asean aluminium output to reach 2.7mn t</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2768506-viewpoint-asean-aluminium-output-to-reach-2.7mn-t</link><description>Southeast Asia will add 780,000 t of primary aluminium output in 2026, driven by smelter expansion in Indonesia and new smelters in Vietnam. This expansion contributes to regional output reaching 2.7 million tonnes. The growth reflects increasing investments in the ASEAN aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Year-End Aluminum Ingot Inventory Alert Sounded! Domestic ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103701077</link><description>Domestic aluminum production rose 1.9% YoY and 4.0% MoM in December due to new capacities in Inner Mongolia and Xinjiang, increasing supply pressure on ingot inventories. Casting volumes increased 7.7% MoM, with liquid aluminum proportion expected to drop to 75.1% in January 2026. Inventories are projected to reach around 730,000 mt by end-January, restraining price surges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price forecast for 2026, according to BCA Research</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/commodities-news/aluminum-price-forecast-for-2026-according-to-bca-research-4420841</link><description>Constrained Chinese primary aluminum production near its 45 million metric tonne capacity cap supports near-term prices. However, into 2026, deteriorating global manufacturing and increased secondary production plus overseas expansions will pressure prices downward. Substitution from copper provides current demand tailwind but may weaken with economic slowdown.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Price increase on aluminum effective Jan. 1, 2026</title><link>https://www.pac-clad.com/price-increase-on-aluminum-effective-jan-1-2026/</link><description>Petersen will implement a 10% price adjustment on aluminum sheets, coils, and panels starting January 1, 2026, due to rising raw material costs. Updated pricing will be shared in advance. The company will monitor market conditions for further updates.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Europe's aluminum sector under strain; premiums, smelter ...</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5104276-europes-aluminum-sector-under-strain-premiums-smelter-disruption-and-cbam-tighten-the-market</link><description>Europe's aluminum market faces high premiums reaching USD 335.50/t in December 2025 and projected at USD 327-330/t in 2026, alongside the shutdown of Iceland's Grundartangi smelter removing 213,000 t/yr capacity. The impending CBAM from January 2026 will add USD 100-150/t costs for high-carbon aluminum, tightening supply further.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>COMMODITIES 2026: Mexican aluminum prices poised to rise after ...</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/122425-commodities-2026-mexican-aluminum-prices-poised-to-rise-after-atypical-year-sources-say</link><description>Mexican aluminum prices are expected to rise in 2026 after a stagnant 2025 impacted by US tariffs, with premiums potentially surpassing $400/mt amid rising LME and export demand. Industry sources anticipate a dynamic market with pending projects and strong auto sector demand. Prices climbed back to $330/mt by year-end 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium's unifying approach to net-zero transformation</title><link>https://www.worldclimatefoundation.org/post/climate-nature-and-people-aluminium-s-unifying-approach-to-net-zero-transformation</link><description>The article highlights aluminum's role in sustainable solutions like electric vehicles and solar panels, featuring innovations such as Alcoa and Rio Tinto's ELYSIS zero-carbon smelting technology and EGA's CelestiAL aluminum produced using solar power. These advancements significantly reduce carbon intensity in production and support global decarbonization efforts. The industry is investing in clean energy, recycling, and carbon capture to position aluminum as a key sustainable metal.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Pioneering Sustainability and Innovation</title><link>https://www.lightmetalage.com/news/event-news/aluminium-2026-pioneering-sustainability-and-innovation/</link><description>The ALUMINIUM 2026 trade fair in Düsseldorf, Germany, from October 6–8, will emphasize sustainability, innovation, and the role of secondary aluminum in decarbonization. It will cover advancements in recycling, metal processing, casting, and applications in mobility, construction, and manufacturing. New features include an expanded conference and a Sustainability &amp; Recycling Conference to foster collaboration and showcase cutting-edge technologies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Market trends, policy signals and innovation together suggest a recalibration within the global aluminium downstream industry</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/market-trends-policy-signals-and-innovation-together-suggest-a-recalibration-within-the-global-aluminium-downstream-industry-116723</link><description>The article discusses structural changes in the aluminum industry driven by leadership shifts, policy like the EU's CBAM, market trends, and innovations ahead of 2026. Nagoya University researchers developed new aluminum alloys that maintain strength at high temperatures, are highly recyclable, and suitable for 3D printing, addressing limitations in engines, turbines, and aerospace. These developments enhance competitiveness and sustainability across the value chain.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Accurate steel prices bring clarity to uncertain market</title><link>https://mepsinternational.com/gb/en/news/accurate-steel-prices-bring-clarity-to-uncertain-market</link><description>EU mills are pushing for price increases amid expectations of reduced supply from CBAM implementation, but subdued demand and high inventories from Q4 customs clearance will undermine upward price pressure. The Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism takes effect January 1, 2026, creating uncertainty in European steel markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Brings Back Steel Export Licences From Jan 2026</title><link>https://news.steelbazaar.com/index.php/news/china-brings-back-steel-export-licences-from-jan-2026</link><description>China has introduced an export licensing system for approximately 300 steel product customs codes starting January 1, 2026. The Ministry of Commerce stated the primary purpose is to strengthen monitoring, statistical analysis, and quality tracking of steel exports, requiring firms to submit product quality inspection proof when applying for licenses.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Introduces Stricter Export License Regulations for Steel Products Effective January 2026</title><link>https://www.royalsteelgroup.com/news/china-introduces-stricter-export-license-regulations-for-steel-products-effective-january-2026/</link><description>China's Ministry of Commerce and General Administration of Customs have implemented stricter export license management for steel products, reinstating licensing requirements after a 16-year pause. Exporters must now provide export contracts directly linked to manufacturers and official quality certificates, with non-compliant transactions facing potential customs delays or shipment holds.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Will Korean steelmakers rebound as China's export controls take effect</title><link>https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/business/companies/20260101/will-korean-steelmakers-rebound-as-chinas-export-controls-take-effect</link><description>South Korean steelmakers are cautiously optimistic about potential recovery in 2026 following China's new export licensing system. However, industry analysts remain skeptical about the measure's effectiveness in reducing global steel oversupply, with concerns that Chinese producers may shift toward higher-end markets, intensifying competition.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>India Extends Key Steel Input Import Ban: What This Means for Prices</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/industrial-goodsservices/India-Extends-Key-Steel-Input-Import-Ban-What-This-Means-for-Prices/69555b594342f77179ef39cb</link><description>India has extended import restrictions on low-ash metallurgical coke (less than 18% ash content) until June 30, 2026, effective January 1, 2026. The policy aims to manage domestic supply and may impact raw material costs for the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China will maintain control over steel production and exports in 2026-2030</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/china-will-maintain-control-over-steel-production-and-exports-in-2026-2030/</link><description>China will continue to strictly regulate steel production and prohibit illegal new capacity additions during 2026-2030. This reflects Beijing's ongoing commitment to controlling the steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Technological Innovation Leads the Global Steel Industry into a Low-Carbon New Era</title><link>https://www.sumecmetal.com/news/global-steel-industry-new-era/</link><description>Low-carbon metallurgy technologies, such as Ansteel’s green electricity and green hydrogen fluidized bed hydrogen metallurgy pilot line and CISDI’s hydrogen-based shaft furnace, are driving the steel industry's decarbonization. These innovations achieve near-zero-carbon iron production with high metallization rates and full localization of equipment. They promote green, low-carbon transformation alongside high-end materials and intelligent efficiency.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A Bold Plan: Tata to Transform Green Steel with Nuclear Power</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/a-bold-plan-tata-to-transform-green-steel-with-nuclear-power/</link><description>Tata Steel plans to use 200 small modular reactors (BSRs) for nuclear power to produce green hydrogen, replacing coking coal in steelmaking and slashing carbon emissions. This supports their goals of 40% CO2 reduction by 2030 and full neutrality by 2045, amid upcoming EU CBAM regulations. Their Netherlands plant is already among the world's most efficient.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Gold, silver, and copper prices surge again — here’s the 2026 gold, silver, and copper outlook amid policy risks, supply deficits and structural demand</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/gold-silver-and-copper-prices-surge-again-heres-the-2026-gold-silver-and-copper-outlook-amid-policy-risks-supply-deficits-and-structural-demand/articleshow/126259059.cms</link><description>Copper prices remain strong at around $5.68 per pound, supported by demand from AI infrastructure, data centers, and green energy. Copper ended 2025 near $5.6787 per pound, up 2.59% in the last session and 36% for the year. The outlook for 2026 is bullish due to governments' electrification agendas and rising capital expenditure in AI and clean energy sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to 5.65 USD/Lbs on January 1, 2026, up 0.17% from the previous day, with a 41.61% yearly gain. Despite a year-end pullback to around $5.7 per pound due to profit-taking, it posted its largest annual gain since 2009, driven by supply constraints, energy transition demand, and AI infrastructure. Mine disruptions like Freeport’s Grasberg closure further supported the rally.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper’s unstoppable run! Prices at all-time highs. What’s driving the surge, and will it sustain in 2026?</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/coppers-unstoppable-run-prices-at-all-time-highs-whats-driving-the-surge-and-will-it-sustain-in-2026/articleshow/126229280.cms</link><description>Copper prices have hit record highs due to aggressive policy easing, supply disruptions, tariff-driven stockpiling, and strong demand from electrification and AI infrastructure. Market tightness may persist into early 2026, but analysts anticipate increased volatility from mine recoveries, trade policies, and dollar movements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper set for biggest annual gain since 2009 on supply bets</title><link>https://www.ibj.com/articles/copper-set-for-biggest-annual-gain-since-2009-on-supply-bets</link><description>Copper prices were 1% lower at $12,558.50 a ton on the London Metal Exchange, after hitting a record $12,960 on Monday. The metal is poised for its largest annual gain since 2009, fueled by supply constraints and strong demand expectations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Cathode Rod Weekly Operating Rate Drops Below 50%, Further Decline Expected</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103700365</link><description>The weekly operating rate for copper cathode rod producers fell to 48.83% for the week ending January 1, 2026, down 11.9 percentage points week-over-week. Persistently high copper prices continue to suppress downstream procurement demand, with further declines expected.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Hindustan Copper share price rises 3% in trade on Jan 1: Here's why</title><link>https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/hindustan-copper-share-price-rises-3-in-trade-on-jan-1-here-s-why-126010100188_1.html</link><description>Hindustan Copper's shares rose 3% to an intraday high of ₹534.1 on January 1, 2026, amid buyer demand in early trading. The increase followed the company's announcement that its board advised pursuing an exemption from NSE penalty charges via the Ministry of Mines. The stock traded at ₹525.40, up 1.37%, with a market cap of ₹50,807 crore.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Cathode Rod Weekly Operating Rate Falls Below 50%</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103700365/Copper-Cathode-Rod-Weekly-Operating-Rate-Drops-Below-50-Further-Decline-Expected</link><description>The weekly operating rate for copper cathode rod production has dropped below 50%. Due to the New Year's Day holiday from January 2 to January 8, 2026, the industry's operating rate is expected to decline further. This reflects current production challenges in the sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Road Announces Closing of Second Tranche of Financing</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/6274789</link><description>Copper Road announced the closing of the second tranche of its financing. The news release contains forward-looking information. This development supports the company's ongoing operations in copper-related activities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia nickel smelter forecasts ore demand will reach 350 million tons by 2026</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/12/31/indonesia-nickel-smelter-forecasts-ore-demand-will-reach-350-million-tons-by-2026</link><description>An Indonesian nickel smelter forecasts nickel ore demand to reach 350 million tons by 2026, with imports potentially increasing to 50 million tons as a balancing mechanism. New production capacity is expected online next year amid annual growth of 40-50 million tons. Indonesia plans to reduce mineral production quotas for 2026 to boost prices and revenues.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices surge as Indonesia plans one-third cut in 2026 RKAB quotas</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/analysis/5108592-nickel-prices-surge-as-indonesia-plans-one-third-cut-in-2026-rkab-quotas</link><description>Indonesia's government plans to cut nickel ore mining quotas to 250 million metric tonnes in 2026, down one-third from 379 million tonnes in 2025, sparking market concerns and a surge in nickel prices. Estimated ore consumption is 327 million wmt, creating a potential gap of 77 million wmt, even with up to 25 million tonnes of imports from the Philippines. SHFE nickel futures rose over Yuan 15,000/tonne from December 19-26.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits nine-month high as Indonesia plans to cut output</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-nine-month-high-as-indonesia-plans-to-cut-output/</link><description>Nickel prices hit a nine-month high after Indonesia announced plans to reduce output in 2026 to better match supply with demand and boost prices, as stated by Energy and Mineral Resources Minister Bahlil Lahadalia. The government controls supply via mining quotas (RKABs), with LME nickel rising as much as 4.7% to $16,560 a ton. Indonesian production is central to next year's nickel price outlook.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia nickel smelter group forecasting 2026 ore demand to hit up to 350 million tons</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/indonesia-nickel-smelter-group-forecasting-2026-ore-demand-to-hit-up-to-350-million-tons/</link><description>Indonesia's nickel smelter group forecasts 2026 nickel ore demand to reach up to 350 million tons. This projection aligns with broader industry expectations for increased consumption amid growing production capacities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia navigates nickel market with output cuts, policy shifts</title><link>https://www.spglobal.com/energy/en/news-research/latest-news/metals/122925-indonesia-navigates-nickel-market-with-output-cuts-policy-shifts</link><description>Indonesia plans to cut nickel output in 2026 to support prices and is reversing mining quota policies to regulate supply volatility. These measures aim to stabilize the nickel market amid global demand pressures.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FPX Nickel Joins Mining Association of Canada and UN Global Compact</title><link>https://esgnews.com/fpx-nickel-joins-mining-association-of-canada-and-un-global-compact/</link><description>FPX Nickel has joined the Mining Association of Canada and its Towards Sustainable Mining program, as well as the UN Global Compact, to strengthen its sustainability leadership. These steps align the company with principles on human rights, labor, environment, and anti-corruption while advancing the Baptiste Nickel Project responsibly. The initiatives build on FPX's 2024 Sustainability Report and emphasize stakeholder trust and Indigenous community engagement.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>How 'Phytomining' Could Put the Green in the Green Transition</title><link>https://thetyee.ca/News/2026/01/01/Phytomining-Green-Transition/</link><description>Phytomining uses plants to extract metals like nickel from soil, potentially reducing environmental destruction and human rights abuses associated with traditional mining. This innovative approach could support the green transition by providing a more sustainable method for sourcing critical minerals. The article explores its potential to curb mining impacts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris has acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems for district heating and anti-corrosion coatings in Europe. The acquired business unit has been rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy, enabling anti-corrosion coatings to be applied at Tenaris facilities in Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil. This strategic move aims to reduce delivery times, ensure quality, lower costs, and minimize environmental impact in the offshore market.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris hosts panel on nuclear energy and Italy's boilermaking future</title><link>https://www.tenaris.com/en/news/2025/tenaris-hosts-panel-on-nuclear-energy-and-italy-s-boilermaking-future</link><description>Tenaris hosted a panel discussion titled “Nuclear: the future of the Italian boilermaking industry” last week at Fondazione Dalmine in Italy, partnering with UCC and featuring experts from industry and institutions. The event focused on nuclear energy's role in Europe’s energy transition, Italy’s manufacturing potential, and technologies like small modular reactors. Tenaris’s Italian mill recently obtained accreditation for ASME III standard materials for nuclear facilities, emphasizing quality and safety.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy's Antitrust Authority (AGCM) has initiated an investigation into major low-voltage copper cable manufacturers, including Prysmian Cavi e Sistemi Italia Srl and others, for alleged price-fixing since 2005. Inspections were conducted yesterday at company offices, supported by Guardia di Finanza. Prysmian shares fell 1.26% in response, though analysts view the impact as negligible given the small revenue share from this market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Year-end aluminium ingot inventory alert sounded! Domestic inventory buildup in Q1 2026 a foregone conclusion</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/year-end-aluminium-ingot-inventory-alert-sounded-domestic-inventory-buildup-in-q1-2026-a-foregone-conclusion-116772</link><description>Domestic aluminium production rose 1.9% year-on-year in December due to new capacities in Inner Mongolia and Xinjiang, increasing aluminium ingot supply. Casting volumes grew 7.7% month-on-month, pressuring inventories, with projections of 730,000 tonnes by end-January 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Off-Season, coupled with high aluminium prices, the proportion of liquid aluminium declined in December</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/off-season-coupled-with-high-aluminium-prices-the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminium-declined-in-december-116778</link><description>Entering January 2026, operating aluminium capacity is expected to increase month-on-month with new projects coming online. High prices and off-season demand contributed to declining liquid aluminium proportions in December.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>EU carbon tax from 2026 set to dent India's steel, aluminium exports</title><link>https://www.maritimegateway.com/eu-carbon-tax-from-2026-set-to-dent-indias-steel-aluminium-exports-gtri/</link><description>Starting January 1, 2026, the EU's CBAM will impose payments on carbon-intensive imports, challenging Indian steel and aluminium exports through price reductions of 15-22%. Coal-fired aluminium production faces high carbon costs, impacting competitiveness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ALUMINIUM 2026: Driving Innovation for a Sustainable Future</title><link>https://www.aluminium-exhibition.com/germany/en-gb/blog/pressemitteilungen/alude2026-showpreparations.html</link><description>ALUMINIUM 2026 in Düsseldorf emphasizes sustainability, particularly secondary aluminum for decarbonization, alongside topics like metal processing, primary production, recycling, automation, casting, and surface finishing. It features cross-sector applications in mobility, construction, and manufacturing, with proven formats like themed pavilions and new accents for innovation and networking. Event director Patrick Herman positions it as a driver for collaboration and societal progress in a sustainable aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[CES Innovation Awards® 2026 Honoree] Portable SSD T7 Resurrected</title><link>https://semiconductor.samsung.com/news-events/tech-blog/ces-innovation-awards-2026-honoree-portable-ssd-t7-resurrected/</link><description>Samsung's Portable SSD T7 Resurrected earns a CES Innovation Award 2026 for its enclosure made from 100% recycled aluminum, maximizing sustainable material use. This design innovation addresses environmental challenges while maintaining high performance in a portable SSD. It showcases advancements in recycled materials for consumer electronics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US steel tariffs cause scrap supply glut</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2769786-viewpoint-us-steel-tariffs-cause-scrap-supply-glut</link><description>US ferrous scrap prices are expected to edge up in January due to slower winter supply flows, but long-term steel tariffs will sustain high scrap supply and limit major increases into 2026. US flat and long steel prices have climbed in December, diverging from declining Turkish rebar prices. Domestic HRC prices in India have risen recently amid mill hikes and import duty extensions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Baosteel hikes January 2026 prices due to rising raw material costs, market optimism</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/chinas-baosteel-hikes-january-2026-prices-due-to-rising-raw-material-costs-market-optimism/158231</link><description>China's Baosteel has raised steel prices for January 2026, ending three months of flat pricing amid rising raw material costs and market optimism. Steel demand in China remains weak despite the hike.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU carbon tax from 2026 set to dent India's steel, aluminium exports</title><link>https://www.maritimegateway.com/eu-carbon-tax-from-2026-set-to-dent-indias-steel-aluminium-exports-gtri/</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) starting January 1, 2026, will impose payments on carbon-intensive imports, potentially forcing Indian steel exporters to accept 15-22% price cuts to retain market access. Blast furnace steel faces highest costs, while scrap-based methods are less affected. This comes amid India-EU free trade talks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel demand to grow 8 per cent in FY26 amid price pressures: Icra</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/steel/steel-demand-to-grow-8-per-cent-in-fy26-amid-price-pressures-icra/articleshow/126038567.cms</link><description>Icra forecasts 8% steel demand growth in FY26 despite price pressures, with domestic HRC prices averaging Rs 50,500 per tonne. Operating profit per tonne is also projected amid these trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>2026 Forecast: Steel Price Trends and the "Ripple Effect" on Fastener Costs</title><link>https://www.highfasteners.com/ru/news/detail/2026-forecast-steel-price-trends-and-the-ripple-effect-on-fastener-costs</link><description>Iron ore prices stabilized at $120-$130/ton exiting 2025, with steel mills restocking heavily ahead of 2026. The forecast discusses steel price trends and their impact on fastener costs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Jindal Steel Surges: Expansion Fuels Massive Capacity Hike and Analyst Buy Call</title><link>https://www.whalesbook.com/news/English/industrial-goodsservices/Jindal-Steel-Surges-Expansion-Fuels-Massive-Capacity-Hike-and-Analyst-Buy-Call/69567b214342f77179f63c1a</link><description>Jindal Steel &amp; Power Limited is expanding its Angul facility, commissioning a new blast furnace (BF-II) with 4.6 mtpa capacity, raising iron-making capacity from 10.42 mtpa to 15.02 mtpa and nearly doubling hot metal capacity to 10.65 mtpa. It also added 3 mtpa via BOF-II, increasing total steelmaking capacity to 12.6 mtpa from 9.6 mtpa. Phase II plans include further expansions by March 2027, targeting 17.02 mtpa iron-making and 15.6 mtpa steel-making capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Viewpoint: US steel tariffs cause scrap supply glut</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2769786-viewpoint-us-steel-tariffs-cause-scrap-supply-glut</link><description>US steel tariffs are causing a glut in ferrous scrap supply as North American dealers and exporters flood the domestic market, expected to continue into 2026 amid steady steel production and dampened prices from China. US flat and long steel prices are climbing, while Turkish rebar prices decline, encouraging domestic scrap sales. Scrap prices may edge up in January due to winter supply slowdowns, but tariffs will persist in preventing major increases.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>EU carbon tax from 2026 set to dent India's steel, aluminium exports</title><link>https://www.maritimegateway.com/eu-carbon-tax-from-2026-set-to-dent-indias-steel-aluminium-exports-gtri/</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) transitions to payments from January 1, 2026, challenging Indian steel and aluminium exports with carbon costs passed to suppliers via price cuts of 15-22%. Blast furnace steel and coal-based aluminium face highest impacts; exporters must adapt production for viability amid India-EU FTA talks. India remains a net steel importer, with exports up 32.6% but domestic consumption rising.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel production in 2026 may remain at 7.2 million tons - GMK Center forecast</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/steel-production-in-2026-may-remain-at-7-2-million-tons-gmk-center-forecast/</link><description>Ukraine's steel production is forecasted to stay at 7.2 million tons in 2026, with an optimistic scenario of 7.6 million tons and pessimistic at 6.3-6.6 million tons.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tariffs Pushed CPER Up 39%, Doubling S&amp;P 500 Returns</title><link>https://247wallst.com/investing/2026/01/01/tariffs-pushed-cper-up-39-doubling-sp-500-returns/</link><description>The United States Copper Index Fund (CPER) surged 39% in 2025, driven by a 50% tariff on copper imports effective August 1, more than doubling the S&amp;P 500's returns. Demand from electric vehicles and data centers supports prices, with JPMorgan forecasting $12,500 per metric ton through mid-2026. Future performance depends on tariff persistence and LME inventory levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Capstone Copper Provides Update on Labour Negotiations at Mantoverde Operation</title><link>https://capstonecopper.com/news/capstone-copper-provides-update-on-labour-negotiations-at-mantoverde-operation/</link><description>Union #2 at Capstone Copper's Mantoverde mine in Chile, representing 22% of the workforce, initiated a strike on January 2, 2026, after failed negotiations. Operations will continue at up to 30% of normal production during the strike. The company emphasizes safe reductions and its focus on copper production growth amid labor risks.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia hints at sharp drops in nickel supplies, sending prices higher</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/indonesia-hints-at-sharp-drops-in-nickel-supplies,-sending-prices-higher-48042</link><description>Nickel prices on the London Metal Exchange jumped around 5% to their highest levels in several months following comments from Indonesia’s Minister of Energy and Mineral Resources about reducing nickel production starting in 2026 to rebalance supply and demand. Three-month nickel contracts rose to $16,560 per metric ton, the highest since March. The remarks triggered an immediate market rally.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia stops nickel mining after delay in work plan approval</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/my/node/787843</link><description>Vale Indonesia has halted nickel mining due to a delay in work plan approval. Nickel futures on the London Metal Exchange were 1% higher at US$16,855 a tonne by 11:15am Singapore time. The metal surged more than expected amid ongoing supply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Forecast: Top Trends for Nickel in 2026</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/nickel-price-forecast-top-trends-nickel-2026</link><description>Analyst Manthey predicts nickel prices will remain under pressure throughout 2026 and struggle to hold above US$16,000. This outlook reflects expectations of continued market challenges. Supply and demand dynamics are key factors influencing the forecast.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash]: Nickel &amp; High-Grade NPI Prices Surge, Discount Widens</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103700968/SMM-Nickel-Flash:-Nickel-High-Grade-NPI-Prices-Surge-Discount-Widens</link><description>Nickel prices continued to rise this week, with SMM announcing domestic prices suspended during the New Year holiday and overseas prices resuming on Jan 2. High-grade NPI prices surged, widening the discount. This reflects ongoing bullish trends in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia halts nickel mining on delayed work plan approval</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/vale-indonesia-halts-nickel-mining-delayed-work-plan-approval</link><description>Vale Indonesia has suspended operations at its nickel mines due to a delay in receiving approval for its annual work plan from authorities. The company expects approval soon and states the delay will not impact overall operational sustainability. This occurs amid Indonesia's plans to cut nickel output, contributing to rising nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Indonesia stops nickel mining after delay in work plan approval</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/node/787843</link><description>PT Vale Indonesia has suspended nickel mining operations due to a delay in annual work plan approval from authorities. This halt affects one of Indonesia's largest nickel producers, which is investing in HPAL plants for EV battery materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The High-Risk, High-Reward Case for The Metals Company in 2026</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/high-risk-high-reward-case-metals-company-2026-2601/</link><description>The Metals Company (TMC) pioneers deep-sea mining with technological innovations like autonomous underwater vehicles and remotely operated platforms to extract polymetallic nodules rich in nickel and other battery metals. These advancements reduce costs and enable scaling, supported by partnerships such as Korea Zinc's investment, amid surging demand for clean-energy minerals. However, risks include environmental scrutiny, regulatory challenges, and competition from recycling and urban mining innovations promoting sustainability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel still capped by surplus</title><link>https://think.ing.com/articles/nickel-still-capped-by-surplus/</link><description>Indonesia's nickel supply growth, particularly via HPAL technology converting low-grade laterite ore to battery-grade nickel, will keep the market in surplus through 2026 despite EV demand. Environmental concerns over HPAL's acid use and waste are increasing scrutiny, potentially impacting future approvals and supply. Shifts to LFP batteries, which use less nickel, further cap demand for nickel-intensive chemistries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>BofA Sees Growth Potential for Prysmian from US Tariffs</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/bofa-sees-growth-potential-for-prysmian-from-us-tariffs-ce7d59dddf88f323</link><description>Bank of America projects that US copper tariffs imposed by President Trump could boost Prysmian's 2026 EBITDA by EUR500 million to EUR1 billion, representing up to 30% of estimates. The advantage stems from Prysmian's copper cable production now being almost entirely US-based following the Encore Wire acquisition, with potential 10% price increases in medium and low-voltage segments where imports face 41% average tariffs.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance after reporting third-quarter revenue of EUR5.03 billion, 3% above consensus, driven by strong Renewable Transmission and Power Grids performance. Analysts note the company is likely not yet seeing copper tariff benefits, but expect significant positive impacts in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Off-Season, coupled with high aluminium prices, the proportion of liquid aluminium declined in December</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/off-season-coupled-with-high-aluminium-prices-the-proportion-of-liquid-aluminium-declined-in-december-116778</link><description>High aluminum prices combined with the off-season led to a decline in the proportion of liquid aluminum in December. This reflects broader market trends affecting aluminum usage and supply dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,096 Yuan/MT on January 2, 2026, down 0.32% daily amid soft Chinese demand, with rebar futures maintaining pullbacks from recent highs. Forecasts predict trading at 3014.96 Yuan/MT by quarter-end and 2868.13 in 12 months. Recent news highlights steel rises on improving profitability and pressures from regulatory export concerns.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 931.97 USD/T on January 2, 2026, down 0.32% daily, though up 2.87% monthly and 31.63% yearly. Forecasts expect 949.49 USD/T by quarter-end and 1042.73 in 12 months. Recent updates note rises to 940 USD/T on December 31 amid improving trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMM: Copper Wire &amp; Cable Industry's Jan Operating Rate to Edge Up MoM, Still Below Normal</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103701113/SMM:-Copper-Wire-Cable-Industrys-Jan-Operating-Rate-to-Edge-Up-MoM-Still-Below-Normal</link><description>SMM reports that China's copper wire and cable industry's operating rate for January 2026 is expected to edge up month-over-month but remain below normal levels. Domestic prices are suspended during the New Year holiday, with overseas prices resuming on January 2. This reflects ongoing market adjustments amid high prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM: Copper Wire &amp; Cable Operating Rate Drops Further Amid High Prices, Holidays</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103700497/SMM:-Copper-Wire-Cable-Operating-Rate-Drops-Further-Amid-High-Prices-Holidays</link><description>SMM indicates that the operating rate in China's copper wire and cable sector has dropped further due to high copper prices and holiday effects. This trend highlights supply chain pressures in the industry. Contact details provided for further research reports.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Austral Resources Defies Weather, Exceeds Copper Output Targets</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/01/02/austral-resources-defies-weather-exceeds-copper-output-targets/</link><description>Austral Resources (ASX:AR1) exceeded its Q4 copper production targets with 2,643 tonnes despite extreme weather in Northwest Queensland. December production hit a record 910 tonnes since the 2023 restructure, with no environmental issues and stable processing operations. Access to the Rocklands site is restricted due to flooding, but recovery is expected soon.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Austral Resources Beats Q4 Copper Output Guidance Despite Record Weather</title><link>https://smallcaps.com.au/article/austral-resources-beats-q4-copper-output-guidance-despite-record-weather</link><description>Austral Resources surpassed Q4 copper production guidance of 2,610 tonnes, achieving 2,643 tonnes amid severe wet season weather. December output exceeded 910 tonnes, the highest post-2023 restructure, with Lady Annie and Mt Kelly sites maintaining full capacity. The company advances exploration with a 2026 drill program targeting oxide resources near processing facilities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries partners with Sphere Corp in landmark ENC deal</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/01/02/nickel-industries-partners-with-sphere-corp-in-landmark-enc-deal/</link><description>Nickel Industries announced a strategic partnership with Sphere Corp, valuing its ENC HPAL project at US$2.4 billion, with Sphere acquiring a 10% stake and entering an offtake agreement for nickel cathode. The ENC project targets annual production of 72,000 tonnes of nickel metal upon commissioning, expected in early Q1 2026. This deal marks the first offtake for ENC material into Western markets, targeting aerospace and EV sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries Rockets 8% as SpaceX Supplier Buys Into US$2.4B ENC HPAL Project</title><link>https://stocksdownunder.com/nickel-industries/</link><description>Nickel Industries' shares rose 8% following Sphere Corp's investment in the US$2.4 billion ENC HPAL project. Sphere, a SpaceX supplier, is acquiring a stake, supporting the project's development for nickel production. The deal highlights growing interest in Nickel Industries' capacity expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item></channel></rss>