<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:17:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>December Steel Price Outlook: Macro &amp; Fundamental Drivers</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103643800/december-steel-price-outlook-macrofundamental-drivers-smm-analysis/</link><description>Steel prices have been volatile recently with slight declines in hot metal production but remain high. Inventory is expected to continue declining in December, though destocking pace for sheets and plates will be slow. Macro factors such as domestic policy meetings may support limited price increases despite persistent destocking pressure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron ore edges up as steel price optimism outweighs softer hot metal output</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3X909Y:0-iron-ore-edges-up-as-steel-price-optimism-outweighs-softer-hot-metal-output/</link><description>Iron ore futures rose slightly driven by optimism over stronger steel prices despite softer hot metal output. Chinese steel prices are expected to increase in December due to improved macroeconomic conditions and recovering market fundamentals. Environmental inspections are reducing pig iron production, pressuring raw materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Japan's Steel Sector Needs to Use All Low-Carbon Pathways to Reach Emissions Goal</title><link>https://about.bnef.com/insights/clean-energy/japans-steel-sector-needs-to-use-all-low-carbon-pathways-to-reach-emissions-goal-report/</link><description>Japan's steel sector, responsible for about 13 percent of the country's emissions, must cut emissions from coal-based production to achieve its 2050 net zero goal. Scrap-based electric arc furnaces powered by renewable energy can produce steel at around $720 per ton by 2030, only 18 percent costlier than traditional blast furnace methods but with zero emissions. Japan could lower emissions by maximizing production at existing scrap-EAFs and implementing policies to redirect exported scrap volumes to domestic steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>National hub to cut steel production emissions</title><link>https://www.trailermag.com.au/national-hub-to-cut-steel-production-emissions/</link><description>A national initiative to make steel production greener and more sustainable has launched at Monash University, bringing together researchers and industry partners to develop smarter, low-emission steelmaking processes. The ARC Research Hub for Smart Process Design and Control will use simulation, AI, and industrial testing to transform steelmaking and train future engineers for a low-emission industrial economy.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Japan's Steel Sector Needs to Use All Low-Carbon Pathways to Reach Emissions Goal</title><link>https://about.bnef.com/insights/clean-energy/japans-steel-sector-needs-to-use-all-low-carbon-pathways-to-reach-emissions-goal-report/</link><description>Japan's steel industry must leverage all available low-carbon pathways—including scrap-based electric arc furnaces, hydrogen, and carbon capture—to meet its 2050 net-zero target. BloombergNEF's report highlights that scrap-EAF powered by renewables could be cost-competitive by 2030, while hydrogen and CCS remain more expensive until 2050.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Breakthrough Technology Conference 2025</title><link>https://worldsteel.org/climate-action/breakthrough-technology/</link><description>The second Breakthrough Technology Conference is underway in Singapore, focusing on technologies that can significantly reduce CO2 emissions from steelmaking, such as hydrogen reduction, carbon capture, and reuse. The event highlights the urgency for innovation as the steel industry works to meet global climate goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises to 4-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures rose above $5.2 per pound, reaching their highest level in four months due to tight supply and elevated premiums. Supply constraints include lower output in Chile, planned cuts by Chinese smelters, and a weaker dollar, with markets anticipating a possible Federal Reserve rate cut.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Kamoa-Kakula Mine Copper Smelter to Begin Feeding LME; Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103651428/Kamoa-Kakula-Mine-Copper-Smelter-to-Begin-Feeding-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated significantly, opening at $11,205.5/mt and closing lower at $11,145/mt, down 0.78%. Spot premiums in Shanghai increased, while imported copper prices showed slight increases, reflecting mixed market dynamics amid ongoing supply and demand adjustments.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Retreat Amid China Demand Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/03/copper-prices-retreat-amid-china-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices edged down from recent record highs due to signs of softer demand from China, the world's largest copper consumer. Reduced seasonal demand from Chinese fabricators and a drop in the Yangshan copper premium suggest increased availability of Chinese metal for export, potentially easing global supply tightness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper pulls back from peak; market focus on upcoming Fed rate decision</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3X9033:0-copper-pulls-back-from-peak-market-focus-on-upcoming-fed-rate-decision/</link><description>Copper prices consolidated after pulling back from a record high as markets focused on the upcoming US Federal Reserve interest rate decision. Despite a slight retreat, copper remains near peak levels supported by supply concerns and expectations of a Fed rate cut in December.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper retreats from peak on firmer dollar</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40395487</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange fell 0.4% to $11,207 per metric ton after hitting a recent peak, pressured by a firmer US dollar. The price retreat reflects profit-taking amid ongoing market volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Kamoa-Kakula Mine Copper Smelter to Begin Feeding</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103651428/Kamoa-Kakula-Mine-Copper-Smelter-to-Begin-Feeding-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>The 500,000 mt/year Phase 1 copper smelter at the Kamoa-Kakula mine officially started production on November 21, 2025, and is expected to begin feeding the first batch of copper concentrates before the end of the year. LME copper closed at $11,145/mt, down 0.78%, with the market experiencing considerable fluctuations throughout the trading session.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Retreat Amid China Demand Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/03/copper-prices-retreat-amid-china-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices have edged down from recent record highs as softer demand from China, the world's largest copper consumer, is expected to increase availability of Chinese metal for export and ease global supply pressures. The Yangshan copper premium has fallen to its lowest level since July, signaling reduced appetite for imported metal within the Chinese market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Russia’s Nornickel, one of the world’s largest nickel producers, maintained its 2025 nickel production outlook at 196,000-204,000 metric tons. Nickel production rose 18% in Q3 2025 due to higher volumes of processed raw materials, despite earlier shipment cuts caused by seasonal flooding and equipment replacement challenges.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>United Tractors sets up nickel-processing subsidiary</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/united-tractors-sets-up-nickel-processing-subsidiary</link><description>PT United Tractors Tbk has established a new nickel-focused subsidiary, PT Nusantara Industri Nikel Lestari (NINL), as part of its diversification into nickel processing and services. The subsidiary was approved on December 2, 2025, and will operate in non-ferrous metal manufacturing and trading.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale to hit upper end of 2025 output target, cuts 2026 estimate</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5105914-vale-to-hit-upper-end-of-2025-output-target-cuts-2026-estimate</link><description>Vale expects to reach the upper end of its 2025 nickel output target, alongside copper production targets. However, the company has revised down its production estimates for 2026. The 2025 nickel output target is approximately 175 million tonnes.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mining companies make stunning discovery that could be crucial for sustainable nickel extraction</title><link>https://www.thecooldown.com/green-tech/nickel-mining-improvements-sustainable-practices/</link><description>Allonia and Lundin Mining are testing D-Solve technology at Eagle Mine in Michigan, which uses microbes to selectively dissolve unwanted minerals and increase nickel purity by reducing magnesium impurities by 40% while increasing nickel grade by 18%. This breakthrough could transform mineral mining by decreasing costs and reducing environmental impact while meeting growing global nickel demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal, Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://www.pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coatings in Europe. The acquired business was rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy, enhancing Tenaris's offshore market offerings and enabling coating application at multiple global facilities.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium eases to $2,854/t as Asian 3-month price rises $32/t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-eases-to-2-854-t-as-asian-3-month-price-rises-32-t-116439</link><description>On December 3, 2025, London Metal Exchange (LME) aluminium prices slightly declined to $2,854 per tonne, down about 0.2% from the previous day. However, the 3-month Asian Reference Price increased by $32 per tonne (1.1%) to $2,897 per tonne. LME inventories also saw a small decline in stock and cancelled warrants.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rose to 2,901.50 USD/T on December 3, 2025, up 1.36% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rebounded from a near one-month low to $2,901.50 per tonne on December 3, 2025, up 1.36% from the previous day. The price has risen about 1.05% over the past month and nearly 9.4% year-over-year, supported by macroeconomic tailwinds including expectations of Fed rate cuts and stimulus signals from Beijing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa says high US aluminum prices offset Trump tariff costs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/alcoa-sees-tariff-costs-on-aluminum-shipments-continuing-to-rise/</link><description>Alcoa reported that despite $69 million in additional costs from US tariffs on Canadian aluminum imports, higher domestic aluminum prices have offset these tariff impacts. The US Midwest premium has surged 113% since June, driven by declining inventories and reduced imports, with tariff costs expected to rise further in the current quarter.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Expectations for Interest Rate Cuts Heat Up Combined with Demand Resilience SHFE Aluminum and LME Aluminum Strengthen Simultaneously [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103653664/Expectations-for-Interest-Rate-Cuts-Heat-Up-Combined-with-Demand-Resilience-SHFE-Aluminum-and-LME-Aluminum-Strengthen-Simultaneously-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Aluminum prices strengthened in early December amid expectations for interest rate cuts and resilient demand. Supply constraints and low industry inventory continue to support prices, with limited downside risk and cautious optimism for further gains if demand improves.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China's steel prices set to strengthen in December</title><link>https://www.seaisi.org/details/27592?type=news-rooms</link><description>Chinese steel prices are expected to move upward in December, driven by improved macroeconomic conditions and recovery in market fundamentals. China's national composite steel price ended November at Yuan 3,453/tonne ($488/t), with steelmakers reducing production to support prices. Positive global liquidity and potential Federal Reserve rate cuts are expected to provide additional support for commodity prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Rises to 906 USD/T</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) steel rose to 906 USD/T on December 3, 2025, up 0.55% from the previous day. Over the past month, HRC steel has risen 6.84%, and is up 32.07% compared to the same time last year. The price remains well below its all-time high of 1,945 USD/T reached in September 2021.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Price gap between US HRC, imports shrinks</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/12/03/price-gap-between-us-hrc-imports-shrinks/</link><description>The price gap between US-produced hot-rolled coil and imported steel has narrowed to its lowest level since summer, with US HRC averaging $895/st. After accounting for 50% tariffs and import costs, Asian HRC delivers at approximately $750/st, creating a $145/st premium for domestic steel. The tariff policy implemented by President Trump continues to significantly impact the competitive landscape between domestic and imported steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's steel prices set to strengthen in December</title><link>https://www.seaisi.org/details/27592?type=news-rooms</link><description>Chinese steel prices are expected to rise in December due to an improved macroeconomic environment. Despite production cuts and furnace idling in North China to ease air pollution, steel demand remains resilient, leading to shrinking steel supply and falling inventories across China.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Price gap between US HRC, imports shrinks</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/12/03/price-gap-between-us-hrc-imports-shrinks/</link><description>The price gap between US hot rolled coil (HRC) steel and imported steel has narrowed to its lowest since summer 2025. US domestic HRC remains more expensive than imports from Asia and Europe after tariffs and import costs, but the difference has decreased significantly, influenced by Section 232 tariffs and lead times.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Integrated Steel Plant Joint Venture with JSW Steel in India</title><link>https://www.jfe-steel.co.jp/en/release/2025/12/251203.html</link><description>JFE Steel and JSW Steel's joint venture plans to expand crude steel production at their integrated steelworks in India to 10 million tons by 2030, with potential to increase to 15 million tons. The JV aims to combine JFE's technology with JSW's operational strengths to capture growing Indian steel demand and improve productivity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ArcelorMittal launches new €500 million electric steel production line in France</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/arcelormittal-launches-new-e500-million-electric-steel-production-line-in-france/</link><description>ArcelorMittal has inaugurated a new €500 million electric steel production line in France, capable of producing 155,000 tons of electric steel annually. This facility targets automotive and industrial sectors, supporting the transition to greener steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper reaches record highs on concerns about supply and a weaker dollar</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/12/03/copper-reaches-record-highs-on-concerns-about-supply-and-a-weaker-dollar</link><description>Glencore and Chilean state-owned copper producer Codelco signed a preliminary agreement to collaborate on a new smelter in Antofagasta, Chile, with a processing capacity of about 1.5 million tons per year. Codelco will supply up to 800,000 metric tons of copper concentrate annually for at least ten years. This project aims to increase Chile's smelting capacity, strengthen sovereignty, and improve logistical efficiency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices rise on concerns about supply; Fed rate decision pending</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/12/03/copper-prices-rise-on-concerns-about-supply-fed-rate-decision-pending</link><description>Copper prices surged amid supply concerns and expectations of a Federal Reserve interest rate cut. The partnership between Codelco and Glencore to build a smelter in Chile was highlighted, with the smelter expected to process 1.5 million tons per year and improve Chile's copper smelting capabilities, which currently represent only 6% of global capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Smashes Records as Supply Fears Intensify Amidst LME Withdrawal Surge</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-12-3-copper-smashes-records-as-supply-fears-intensify-amidst-lme-withdrawal-surge</link><description>Copper futures surged over 2.6% on the London Metal Exchange due to supply fears amid accelerating electrification and decarbonization demands. The industry faces challenges like declining ore grades and ESG pressures, making innovation in mining technology and recycling critical to sustaining supply and supporting the green economy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices rose slightly on December 3</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103652643</link><description>Nickel prices increased slightly on December 3, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 120,000 yuan/mt, up 100 yuan/mt from the previous day. Despite short-term fluctuations, nickel prices face long-term pressure amid expectations of a US Fed interest rate cut and subdued manufacturing data. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract fluctuated between 114,000-118,000 yuan/mt.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris remains profitable in 2025</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/tenaris-steel-oil-gas-market-earnings-q3-2025/</link><description>Tenaris reported a $37 million profit in Q3 2025, a 15.6% increase from the previous quarter but a 22.9% decrease compared to Q3 2024. Sales in North American oil and gas tubular products remained steady, despite some tariff increases on steel imports affecting costs and margins. The company expects sales to stay close to Q3 levels but anticipates margin pressure from higher tariffs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris reduced pipe sales to 2.95 million tons in January-September</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/tenaris-reduced-pipe-sales-to-2-95-million-tons-in-january-september/</link><description>Tenaris sold 2.95 million tons of pipe products in the first nine months of 2025, marking a 2% decrease compared to the same period in 2024. This reduction reflects a slight decline in overall sales volumes amid challenging market conditions.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Soar</title><link>https://www.interactivebrokers.com/campus/traders-insight/securities/macro/chart-advisor-aluminum-prices-soar/</link><description>Aluminum prices reached their highest levels in three years, trading around USD 2,880–2,920 per ton, driven by production constraints in China and supply limits. The recent rally suggests a structural supply deficit beginning to materialize, with forecasts indicating potential further upside if prices hold above USD 2,800.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Hits 15-week High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices rose to $906 per ton, marking a 15-week high and a 6.84% increase over the past month. The price is also up 32.07% compared to the same period last year, reflecting a positive trend in the benchmark steel market despite recent volatility.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Northern Sun Energy and PowerFlex Announce Solar + Storage Behind-the-Meter Project for Prysmian Manufacturing</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/northern-sun-energy-and-powerflex-announce-solar--storage-behind-the-meter-project-for-prysmian-manufacturing-302631434.html</link><description>Northern Sun Energy and PowerFlex are developing a 7.5 MWp solar array with 1MW battery storage to power Prysmian's cable manufacturing plant in Du Quoin, Illinois. The facility produces copper medium voltage cables used in renewable energy, and the project will generate 50% of the plant's energy needs, reducing grid reliance and enhancing sustainability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Drops 335 mt WoW to 55,300 mt on Dec 4</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103654915/SMM-Flash-News:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Drops-335-mt-WoW-to-55300-mt-on-Dec-4</link><description>Domestic secondary aluminum ingot inventories in China dropped by 335 metric tons week-over-week to 55,300 metric tons as of December 4, 2025. Prices are expected to fluctuate narrowly at high levels in the short term, with market attention on improvements in aluminum scrap supply.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Domestic Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventory Drops 335 mt WoW to 55,300 mt on Dec 4</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103654915/SMM-Flash-News:-Domestic-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Drops-335-mt-WoW-to-55300-mt-on-Dec-4</link><description>Domestic secondary aluminum ingot inventory in China dropped by 335 metric tons week-on-week to 55,300 metric tons on December 4, 2025. The decline reflects ongoing tight supply conditions and continued demand resilience in the aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Japan's JFE to buy 50% in Bhushan's steel business</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/japans-jfe-to-buy-50-in-bhushans-steel-business/articleshow/125755779.cms</link><description>Japan's JFE Steel plans to acquire a 50% stake in Bhushan Power &amp; Steel, aiming to increase JSW Kalinga's steel production capacity to 10 million tons. The deal, expected to conclude by mid-2026, supports expansion plans leveraging existing land and aims to boost production and profitability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fortescue and TISCO join forces on green ironmaking technology trial</title><link>https://www.fortescue.com/articles/fortescue-and-tisco-join-forces-on-green-ironmaking-technology-trial</link><description>Fortescue Metals Group and Taiyuan Iron and Steel (TISCO) have partnered to trial green ironmaking technology, aiming to reduce carbon emissions in steel production. This collaboration reflects growing industry efforts to develop sustainable steelmaking processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Record High on LME Surge</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/04/copper-hits-record-high-on-lme-surge/</link><description>Copper prices surged to a new record high, driven by a surge in requests to withdraw metal from London Metal Exchange warehouses, mainly fueled by demand in Asia. Prices exceeded $11,400 per tonne, surpassing previous peaks and highlighting ongoing supply tightness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Record High on Supply Concerns and Weaker Dollar</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-hits-record-high-on-supply-concerns-and-weaker-dollar/</link><description>Copper prices advanced to a record high, rising 0.7% to $14,895, supported by supply concerns and a weaker US dollar. The market remains tight, with ongoing worries about global supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US November ADP Employment Unexpectedly Declines, LME Copper Surges Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103653621/US-November-ADP-Employment-Unexpectedly-Declines-LME-Copper-Surges-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices surged overnight, closing at $11,448.5 per tonne, up 2.72%, amid a surprise decline in US ADP employment and comments from Treasury Secretary Yellen on interest rate cuts. Glencore's downward revision of copper production forecasts further intensified supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Sets New Record in London</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-sets-new-record-in-london/</link><description>Copper futures on the LME jumped as much as 2.6% to over $11,400 per tonne, setting a new record amid a spike in warehouse withdrawals and concerns of a global supply squeeze. Traders are ramping up shipments to American ports as US futures surge.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Unreleased SMM Metal Production Data for October 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103599376/Unreleased-SMM-Metal-Production-Data-for-October-2025</link><description>China's copper cathode production in October 2025 decreased by 29,400 metric tons month-on-month (2.62%) but increased 9.63% year-on-year, with a cumulative increase of 11.96% for the year. The decline was mainly due to maintenance at eight smelters affecting 2.2 million mt of smelting capacity. Production is expected to slightly decrease in November but may recover somewhat in December despite high copper prices limiting output incentives.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell 1.8% to $15,235 per ton on the LME, reaching a four-year low due to a weak outlook from the Federal Reserve despite potential mining quota cuts in Indonesia. Indonesia is considering reducing nickel ore mining quotas sharply from 272 million tons in 2025 to 150 million tons in 2026 to support prices. The metal has declined about 8% this year, pressured by new supply and slowing electric vehicle sales.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Outlook for the Nickel Industry in the 15th Five-Year Plan Period</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-28500.html</link><description>The global nickel market is experiencing structural oversupply driven by increased low-cost secondary nickel supply from Indonesia and weak downstream demand, especially in stainless steel. The industry is shifting focus from scale to high-quality development emphasizing technology, cost efficiency, and sustainability. Nickel prices on December 4 were benchmarked at 120,433.33 RMB/ton, slightly up from earlier in the month.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On December 4, the SMM #1 refined nickel price stood at 117,700–123,100 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103654760/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on December 4 averaged 120,400 yuan/mt, rising 400 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects a modest price recovery amid ongoing market volatility and supply-demand imbalances in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 14,873 USD/T on December 4, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices declined 0.18% to $14,873 per tonne on December 4, 2025, continuing a downward trend with prices down 0.95% over the past month and 6.82% year-over-year. The Indonesian government announced new rules restricting nickel refining permits to refiners producing intermediate products, as markets reassess the magnitude of global oversupply.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 refined nickel price update</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103654760/</link><description>On December 4, the SMM #1 refined nickel price stood at 117,700–123,100 yuan/mt, with an average price of 120,400 yuan/mt, up 400 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects modest daily gains in the Chinese refined nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Proposal for global minerals deal meets opposition as China looks away</title><link>https://www.climatechangenews.com/2025/12/04/proposal-for-global-minerals-deal-meets-opposition-as-china-looks-away/</link><description>A proposal for a global minerals deal is facing opposition as China distances itself from the initiative. The article discusses geopolitical tensions surrounding critical minerals negotiations, with Saudi Arabia, Iran, and Russia also involved in the discussions.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium holds steady at USD 2,854/t and alumina platts stays flat at USD 313.5/t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-holds-steady-at-usd-2-854-t-and-alumina-platts-stays-flat-at-usd-313-5-t-116453</link><description>On December 4, 2025, the London Metal Exchange (LME) aluminium price remained steady at USD 2,854 per tonne with no change from the previous day’s close. The 3-month bid and offer prices rose slightly, while inventory levels showed a decline in opening stock and cancelled warrants but stable live warrants.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit 3-Year High: Is It the Next Key Metal in the Clean Energy Shift?</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-hit-3-year-high-is-it-the-next-key-metal-in-the-clean-energy-shift/</link><description>Aluminum prices surged to a three-year high near USD 2,800 per tonne, driven by rising demand from electric vehicles, solar, and grid upgrades. Supply concerns include China's production caps, environmental regulations, and geopolitical risks affecting bauxite imports from Guinea.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Weekly Survey: Aluminum Processing Industry Strained by Off-Season and High Aluminum Prices with Structural Divergence Persisting</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103655695/smm-weekly-survey-aluminum-processing-industry-strained-by-off-season-and-high-aluminum-prices-with-structural-divergence-persisting-</link><description>The operating rate of domestic aluminum downstream processing enterprises fell slightly due to high aluminum prices suppressing spot order transactions. Primary aluminum alloy production remained stable, but demand was cautious with structural divergence across sectors. Export orders show promise, but domestic operations remain constrained by price fluctuations and weak year-end stockpiling.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Metalysis Begins Commercial Production of High Scandium Loading Aluminium Scandium Alloy Powder</title><link>https://smttoday.com/2025/12/04/metalysis-begins-commercial-production-of-high-scandium-loading-aluminium-scandium-al%E2%82%83sc-alloy-powder/</link><description>Metalysis has started commercial production of high-purity aluminium scandium alloy powder, addressing critical needs in semiconductor, aerospace, and defense sectors. The company is scaling production from Gen 2 units to larger Gen 3 and Gen 4 units to meet growing market demand, driven by Western supply chain diversification away from China.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Tracking the Impact of U.S. Tariffs on Five Targeted Canadian Industries</title><link>https://www.rbc.com/en/economics/canadian-analysis/featured-analysis/insights/tracking-the-impact-of-u-s-tariffs-on-five-targeted-canadian-industries/</link><description>Despite 25% U.S. tariffs on Canadian aluminum imports, Canadian aluminum production only declined modestly by 2% through September 2025, with employment in aluminum manufacturing increasing by 5%. High global demand and prices have helped offset production drops, while the U.S. has limited capacity to replace Canadian aluminum imports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>NioCorp Acquires Scandium Alloy Assets to Support Potential First Ever Vertically Integrated U.S. Scandium Mine-to-Markets Supply Chain</title><link>https://www.niocorp.com/niocorp-acquires-scandium-alloy-assets-to-support-potential-first-ever-vertically-integrated-u-s-scandium-mine-to-markets-supply-chain/</link><description>NioCorp completed the acquisition of FEA Materials' assets and IP to produce aluminum-scandium master alloy in the U.S., aiming to establish a vertically integrated scandium supply chain. This move supports growing market demand in defense and commercial sectors and complements NioCorp's Elk Creek Project for critical minerals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China's Total Aluminum Production Flat WoW but Up 3% YoY</title><link>http://www.aastocks.com/en/mobile/news.aspx?newsid=NOW.1488705&amp;newstype=61&amp;newssource=AAFN</link><description>China's aluminum production from November 27 to December 3 was 856,000 metric tons, unchanged week-over-week but increased 3% year-over-year. This reflects steady output amid market conditions, according to Citi research.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>[SMM Analysis] Analysis of Steel Price Trends in December</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103643800</link><description>Steel prices have shown a volatile trend recently with slight declines in hot metal production but high levels overall. Inventory is expected to continue declining in December, though destocking for sheets and plates remains slow. Macro expectations around domestic policy meetings may provide limited upside for steel prices, but persistent destocking pressure and weak sales could constrain price increases.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel to restart second blast furnace in Granite City</title><link>https://www.stlpr.org/economy-business/2025-12-04/u-s-steel-restart-second-blast-furnace-granite-city-works</link><description>U.S. Steel announced it will restart its second blast furnace at Granite City Works, aiming to hire 400 new workers. This move reverses previous idling decisions and is seen as a positive development for the facility amid ongoing ownership changes and investment plans excluding Granite City.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The President of the Treasury Board will highlight measures to protect and transform Canada's steel and lumber industries</title><link>https://www.canada.ca/en/treasury-board-secretariat/news/2025/12/the-president-of-the-treasury-board-will-highlight-measures-to-protect-and-transform-canadas-steel-and-lumber-industries.html</link><description>The Canadian government announced upcoming measures to support and transform the steel and lumber industries, with an event scheduled at Brannon Steel to highlight these initiatives aimed at protecting the sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel fined for leaking oil into Monongahela River</title><link>https://triblive.com/business/u-s-steel-fined-for-leaking-oil-into-monongahela-river/</link><description>U.S. Steel was fined $135,000 and required to implement stronger pollution controls after environmental regulators found the company leaked oil into the Monongahela River at its West Mifflin facility.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Hydrogen-Based Ironmaking Technology: Green Steel Guide</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/hydrogen-based-ironmaking-technology-2025-decarbonisation/</link><description>Hydrogen-based ironmaking technology offers a revolutionary method to cut steel production emissions by 95% through clean chemical reduction processes. This innovation could transform global steel production by enabling decarbonisation, supported by renewable energy, advanced electrolyser technologies, AI-driven process control, and material science advances.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AI Startup Deep.Meta Pushes UK Steel Toward Lower Emissions</title><link>https://esgnews.com/ai-startup-deep-meta-pushes-uk-steel-toward-lower-emissions/</link><description>Deep.Meta's AI-driven simulations have achieved nearly a 10% emissions reduction at Spartan UK, the country's only steel plate producer. The company is advancing its Deep.Optimiser PhyX system with government support, aiming to optimize steel production processes, reduce energy use, and support net zero goals across global steel markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Surge Drives 34% Rally Amid Supply Constraints</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-price-rally-2025-record-surge-demand-supply/</link><description>Copper prices have surged 34% year-to-date in 2025, reaching US$5.33 per pound, a four-month high driven by supply constraints, energy transition demand, and disruptions in Chile and Chinese smelters. The rally accelerated in the final quarter with a 13% gain since late August and a 5% jump in the first week of December, with forecasts suggesting prices could reach $16,000 per tonne under favorable conditions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits All-Time Highs! Scrap Prices Surge Heading Into December 2025</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N_Bbz3_wyiU</link><description>Copper futures have broken all-time price records due to speculative buying and algorithm-driven trades, despite weak mill demand in major markets. The rapid price increase of about 5% in days is driven primarily by investor flows and thin inventories, raising volatility concerns for scrappers and recyclers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price won't stay above $11,000 for long, says Goldman</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-wont-stay-above-11000-for-long-says-goldman/</link><description>Goldman Sachs cautions that copper’s recent rally above $11,000 per ton is unlikely to be sustained as current fundamentals show adequate supply despite market optimism. They highlight that the rally is driven by expectations of future tightness rather than present demand, with a global surplus expected until at least 2029 and potential demand slump in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper hits record high after Citi lifts price outlook</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3XB02W:0-copper-hits-record-high-after-citi-lifts-price-outlook/</link><description>Copper reached a record high following Citi's upgraded price outlook, fueled by supply concerns and optimistic market sentiment. The rally reflects ongoing worries about supply disruptions amid strong demand expectations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Surge Amid Bullish Outlook and Supply Concerns</title><link>https://www.gurufocus.com/news/3235236/copper-prices-surge-amid-bullish-outlook-and-supply-concerns</link><description>Copper prices surged 1.2% to $11,581.50 per ton, surpassing earlier highs this week. Analysts from Citigroup predict continued strength driven by supply concerns and a bullish market outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto's Nuton Technology: A Game-Changer in Low-Carbon Copper Production</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/rio-tinto-nuton-technology-game-changer-carbon-copper-production-2512/</link><description>Rio Tinto's Nuton bioleaching technology significantly reduces carbon emissions and water use by 60-80% compared to traditional copper production methods. It produces 99.99% pure copper at mine sites with a carbon footprint far below global averages, supporting the growing demand for sustainable copper in renewable energy and electric vehicles.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gunnison Copper Announces That Rio Tinto's Nuton Technology Produces First Copper</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/276917/Gunnison-Copper-Announces-That-Rio-Tintos-Nuton-Technology-Produces-First-Copper</link><description>After over 30 years of R&amp;D, Rio Tinto's Nuton bioleaching technology produced its first copper cathode at Gunnison Copper's Johnson Camp mine. The technology achieves up to 80% less water usage and 60% lower carbon emissions than conventional methods, aiming to produce copper with the lowest carbon footprint in the U.S.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto's Nuton tech makes first-ever copper cathode at Gunnison mine</title><link>https://www.mining.com/rio-tintos-nuton-tech-makes-first-ever-copper-cathode-at-gunnison-mine/</link><description>Nuton's proprietary bioleaching technology produced the first copper cathode at Gunnison Copper's Johnson Camp mine, demonstrating cleaner, faster, and more efficient copper production at industrial scale. The technology reduces water use by up to 80% and carbon emissions by up to 60%, while shortening supply chains by producing copper cathode directly at the mine.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Vale–Glencore Sudbury Venture Aims to Unlock 880,000-Ton Copper Volume for North America</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/vale-glencore-sudbury-venture-aims-to-unlock-880000-ton-copper-volume-for-north-america/</link><description>Vale and Glencore plan to deepen and extend an existing mine shaft in Canada's Sudbury Basin to unlock about 880,000 metric tons of copper over 21 years. This brownfield approach reduces environmental impacts and capital expenses, supporting North America's critical minerals supply for clean energy technologies and the global low-carbon transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>High cash flow enables dividend uplift: Aurubis confirms sustainable growth strategy</title><link>https://www.aurubis.com/en/media/press-releases/press-releases-2025/high-cash-flow-enables-dividend-uplift-aurubis-confirms-sustainable-growth-strategy</link><description>Aurubis started production of phase one of its Richmond project in the US, the first secondary smelter for complex multimetal recycling in North America. The plant will process around 180,000 tons of complex recycling materials annually once phase two is completed, contributing to sustainable copper supply and reducing reliance on imports in the US market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel Expands Phase 2X Drilling at Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project</title><link>https://investingnews.com/first-atlantic-nickel-expands-phase-2x-drilling-at-pipestone-xl-nickel-alloy-project-four-additional-holes-targeting-1-4-kilometer-strike-length-and-850-meter-width-at-rpm-zone/</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel is expanding its Phase 2X drilling program at the Pipestone XL project, targeting a 1.4-kilometer strike length and 850-meter width at the RPM zone. The project aims to provide a secure, low-energy, and environmentally sustainable nickel supply chain for North America by bypassing traditional smelting and roasting processes. Updates on recovery and concentrate products for nickel, chromium, and cobalt are expected in early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>US Minerals Projects Seek 'Industrial Vision' from Washington to Compete with China</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/us-minerals-projects-seek-industrial-vision-from-washington-to-compete-with-china/</link><description>Executives from US minerals companies are urging the government to develop a comprehensive industrial plan to build a critical minerals supply chain including nickel. They advocate for pressuring Indonesia to limit nickel production, which currently accounts for about 60% of global supply and has depressed prices. The goal is to support domestic nickel refining capacity, such as Westwin Elements' planned refinery in Oklahoma, and stabilize nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale Foresees Higher Iron Ore, Copper &amp; Nickel Production Next Year</title><link>https://www.industrialinfo.com/news/article.jsp?newsitemID=350106</link><description>Vale projects a 10% increase in nickel production for the upcoming year, alongside modest increases in iron ore and copper output. This forecast reflects the company's plans to expand its mining operations and meet growing demand for nickel in various industries.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>TECH Project high-grade nickel is primed to fuel the global green transition</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/tech-project-high-grade-nickel-is-primed-to-fuel-the-global-green-transition/32893/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals’ TECH Project aims to become the world’s premier source of high-grade, ethically derived nickel to support the green transition. The project uses an environmentally-friendly DNi Process with over 98% nitric acid recycling and no tailings dam requirements, promising a carbon-negative, sustainable nickel production for EV batteries and energy storage industries.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industry News, Views and Commentary - Chronickels</title><link>https://nickelinstitute.org/en/blog/</link><description>NOVONIX’s patented all-dry, zero-waste cathode synthesis technology is expected to reduce costs and environmental impact in nickel-based cathode production. The article discusses nickel’s sustainability potential across its value chain, emphasizing the importance of responsible mining, manufacturing, and recycling to support the expanding electric vehicle battery market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>China Built Indonesia's Nickel Boom: Market Analysis</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/indonesia-nickel-strategy-geopolitical-2025-china/</link><description>China controls about 75% of Indonesia’s nickel operations, crucial for EV battery supply chains. The article highlights shifts in battery chemistry preferences, supply chain diversification away from China, and the growing importance of sustainable nickel production methods as key factors shaping the global nickel market and energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Carrascal Nickel Corporation Strengthens Its Position as a Responsible Mining Leader in APAC Through Sustainability and Community-Focused Initiatives</title><link>https://vietnamnews.vn/media-outreach/1731104/carrascal-nickel-corporation-strengthens-its-position-as-a-responsible-mining-leader-in-apac-through-sustainability-and-community-focused-initiatives.html</link><description>Carrascal Nickel Corporation, a Philippine mining company, emphasizes responsible mining, environmental sustainability, and community partnership in its nickel and iron ore operations. The company is reinforcing its commitment to sustainable practices in the Asia-Pacific region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Climate-friendly metals can come from deep-sea ores</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-climate-friendly-metals-deep-sea.html</link><description>A new process using hydrogen reduction to extract nickel, cobalt, and copper from deep-sea ores significantly reduces CO2 emissions by over 90% compared to carbon-based methods. This innovative approach requires less energy and fewer steps, offering a more sustainable alternative for sourcing critical metals needed for batteries and clean technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Reports 7% Drop in Quarterly Net Sales Amid Weakness in Europe and Brazil</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-reports-7-drop-in-quarterly-net-sales-amid-weakness-in-europe-and-brazil-ce7c5fdcd18af421</link><description>Italian steel pipe manufacturer Tenaris posted a 7% decline in net sales for the second quarter of 2025, mainly due to lower deliveries in Europe and Brazil. The report highlights challenges in the European market impacting the company's performance.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME Aluminium Holds Steady at USD 2,854/t and Alumina Platts Stays Flat at USD 313.5/t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-holds-steady-at-usd-2-854-t-and-alumina-platts-stays-flat-at-usd-313-5-t-116453</link><description>LME aluminium prices remained steady at around USD 2,854 per tonne on December 4, with minor fluctuations in 3-month bids and offers. Alumina prices also stayed flat at USD 313.5 per tonne. Inventory levels saw slight decreases, indicating stable market conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking decarbonisation</title><link>https://www.bhp.com/news/bhp-insights/2025/12/steelmaking-decarbonisation</link><description>BHP highlights the ongoing challenge of decarbonising steel production as demand rises globally. The company supports multiple technology pathways, including carbon capture and renewable energy, to achieve near zero emissions steel production, despite project delays due to high costs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World's First General Design Approval (GDA) for Developed Steel and Post-Weld Heat Treatment (PWHT) Exemption based on ECA for Low-pressure LCO2 Tanks</title><link>https://www.mhi.com/news/251205.html</link><description>Mitsubishi Shipbuilding and Nippon Steel received the world's first General Design Approval for a new high-strength steel that allows exemption from post-weld heat treatment in large low-pressure LCO2 tanks. This innovation is expected to reduce costs and improve productivity in steel manufacturing for CO2 transport.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AI Startup Leads UK Steel Towards Net Zero</title><link>https://www.azom.com/news.aspx?newsID=65086</link><description>Deep.Meta, a UK manufacturing startup, demonstrated it can reduce steel production emissions by nearly 10% at Spartan UK's steel plant, advancing efforts toward net zero emissions in the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steelmaking decarbonisation - BHP</title><link>https://www.bhp.com/news/bhp-insights/2025/12/steelmaking-decarbonisation</link><description>BHP is supporting multiple technology pathways to reduce greenhouse gas emissions in steelmaking, including carbon capture and renewable energy integration. The company aims to help the industry achieve a 30% reduction in emissions intensity relative to conventional blast furnace steelmaking, with widespread adoption expected after 2030.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World's First General Design Approval (GDA) for Developed Steel and Post-Weld Heat Treatment (PWHT) Exemption based on ECA for Low-pressure LCO2 Tanks</title><link>https://www.mhi.com/news/251205.html</link><description>Mitsubishi Shipbuilding and Nippon Steel have achieved the world's first General Design Approval for a new steel and manufacturing process exempting post-weld heat treatment for large low-pressure liquid CO2 tanks. This breakthrough enhances economic viability and productivity while supporting carbon neutrality goals through advanced steel solutions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Alumbrera mine is expected to commence production in 2028</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103655842/The-Alumbrera-mine-is-expected-to-commence-production-in-2028-Overnight-LME-copper-fluctuated-and-closed-lower-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>The Alumbrera mine is slated to start production in 2028. Kamoa-Kakula set copper production targets of 380,000 to 420,000 mt for 2026 and 500,000 to 540,000 mt for 2027, maintaining a medium-term target of 550,000 mt. The Kamoa-Kakula copper smelter began operations on December 1, 2025, with copper sales in 2026 expected to exceed production due to inventory reductions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Glencore eyes $2.4b copper push</title><link>https://australianminingreview.com.au/news/glencore-eyes-2-4b-copper-push/</link><description>Glencore announced plans to increase copper output to about 1 million tonnes by 2029 and 1.6 million tonnes by 2035, up from 850,000–875,000 tonnes in 2025. The company plans a $2.4 billion capital investment for a project expected to yield 880,000 tonnes of copper over 21 years, with a final investment decision expected in the first half of 2027. This expansion is driven by rising copper prices and demand from electric vehicles and data centers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price won't stay above $11,000 for long, says Goldman</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-wont-stay-above-11000-for-long-says-goldman/</link><description>Goldman Sachs analysts predict that despite recent supply disruptions tightening copper availability, global demand growth has softened, and they do not foresee a global copper shortage until at least 2029. Copper prices recently hit a record high due to supply concerns and US-bound shipments ahead of potential tariffs, but demand weakness, especially in China, may limit price sustainability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP becomes global copper barometer</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/05/bhp-becomes-global-copper-barometer/</link><description>BHP shares rose over 3% amid signs of a tentative rebound in Chinese copper demand, with Chinese producers increasing operating rates in November. Despite high copper prices causing some substitution with aluminum, BHP remains a key indicator of global copper activity, producing over two million tonnes in FY25 and contributing nearly 45% of group EBITDA. The company’s valuation is closely tied to Chinese market movements and copper demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Adani, Hindalco seek Peru copper assets as demand surges</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/metals-mining/adani-hindalco-seek-peru-copper-assets-as-demand-surges/articleshow/125780821.cms</link><description>India's copper imports rose 4% to 1.2 million metric tons in the fiscal year ending March 2025, with demand expected to climb to 3-3.3 million tons. In response, Indian companies Adani and Hindalco are seeking copper assets in Peru to secure supply amid surging demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On December 5, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103656760/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 117,400 and 122,700 yuan per metric ton on December 5, with an average price of 120,050 yuan/mt, marking a decrease of 350 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Flash] SMM December 5: Domestic high-grade NPI ex-factory price observed</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103657371/</link><description>According to SMM, the domestic high-grade nickel pig iron (NPI) ex-factory price was recently observed at 910-920 yuan per nickel unit on December 5, reflecting current market conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>USGS Director Champions Domestic Mining</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/12/05/news/usgs-director-champions-domestic-mining/9388.html</link><description>The US Geological Survey director emphasized the importance of domestic mining to meet the growing demand for critical minerals including nickel. Expanding mining capacity is essential to support the generation and transmission infrastructure needed for energy and technology sectors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, northern Italy, marking a significant step towards sustainable steel production. This initiative aligns with the company's ongoing commitment to innovation and environmental responsibility in the steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>