<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:16:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aluminium Prices Are On The Rise As US Premium At Record High</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZdDnECeL4Zs</link><description>Aluminum prices are up 13% in 2025, with the US premium hitting record highs. China reiterated its commitment to preventing overcapacity in metal production, supporting global price increases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa Says High US Aluminum Prices Offset Trump Tariff Costs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/alcoa-sees-tariff-costs-on-aluminum-shipments-continuing-to-rise/</link><description>Alcoa reported that higher US aluminum prices have offset the increased costs from Trump’s tariffs on Canadian aluminum. The company expects further tariff-related costs but sees domestic price strength helping to mitigate the impact.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Hits Three-Year High as US-China Truce Boosts Market Confidence</title><link>https://www.channelchek.com/news-channel/aluminum-hits-three-year-high-as-us-china-truce-boosts-market-confidence</link><description>Aluminum prices surged to their highest level since May 2022, driven by supply constraints in China and renewed optimism following a tentative US-China trade truce. The rally reflects the market’s sensitivity to geopolitical developments and production policies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Premium for Aluminum in the US Spot Market Has Hit a Record High</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103615477/</link><description>The US spot market aluminum premium reached a record high, with buyers paying $4,792 per ton. The surge is attributed to high import tariffs and tight supply conditions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rod Production Cut Wave Hits - Nearly 800,000 MT of Capacity Undergoes Concentrated Maintenance Shutdowns in November</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103617727/aluminum-rod-production-cut-wave-hits-nearly-800000-mt-of-capacity-undergoes-concentrated-maintenance-shutdowns-in-november-smm-analysis</link><description>China's aluminum rod production declined to 381,000 mt in October 2025, with operating rates falling to 53.56%. Production cuts affecting nearly 792,000 mt of capacity emerged in November across multiple regions, with Inner Mongolia leading reductions at 252,000 mt, representing approximately 10% of total sample capacity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>European Aluminum Premium Soars to Nine-Month High of $324 Per Tonne Amid Supply Disruptions and CBAM Anticipation</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-11-12-european-aluminum-premium-soars-to-nine-month-high-of-324tonne-amid-supply-disruptions-and-cbam-anticipation</link><description>The European aluminum duty-paid premium reached $324 per metric ton in November 2025, marking a nine-month high driven by supply disruptions including the Grundartangi smelter outage in Iceland and front-loading of imports ahead of CBAM implementation. European downstream manufacturers in automotive, construction, and packaging sectors face significantly increased input costs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>European Aluminum Duty-Paid Premium Hits $324 Per Ton</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/european-aluminum-premium-2025-dynamics/</link><description>The European aluminum duty-paid premium currently stands at $324 per metric ton, with a peak of $330 reached on November 3, the highest level since late January. The Grundartangi smelter in Iceland experienced a critical electrical equipment failure in late October, reducing production capacity by approximately two-thirds or 213,000 tons annually.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium Prices Are On The Rise As US Premium At Record High</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZdDnECeL4Zs</link><description>Aluminum prices have risen 13% in 2025 with LME prices near three-year highs, driven by supply concerns and China's reiteration of preventing overcapacity in metal production. Reports suggest the aluminum market faces a deficit for the current year and potentially 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SS Breaks Downward Through 12,500 yuan/mt, Stainless Steel Spot Trading Weak with Insufficient Market Confidence</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Finished-Steel</link><description>Stainless steel futures broke below 12,500 yuan/mt, reaching an intraday low of 12,460 yuan/mt, driven by further declines in SHFE nickel and weak stainless steel fundamentals. The SS2601 contract was quoted at 12,560 yuan/mt, down 5 yuan/mt from the previous trading day, with market sentiment turning bearish.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel fell to 3,038 CNY/T on November 12, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices declined to 3,038 CNY/T, down 0.16% from the previous day. Over the past month, steel prices have fallen 0.69%, and are down 7.09% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel fell to 844.05 USD/T on November 12, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot-Rolled Coil (HRC) steel fell to 844.05 USD/T, down 0.93% from the previous day. Over the past month, HRC steel prices have risen 3.69%, and are up 23.22% compared to the same time last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>European carbon prices exceeded €80/t in November</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>European carbon prices surpassed the €80 per ton threshold in November, reflecting market conditions affecting steel production costs in the region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Flat Steel Market Size to Hit USD 1,157.84 Billion by 2034</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/12/3186658/0/en/Flat-Steel-Market-Size-to-Hit-USD-1-157-84-Billion-by-2034.html</link><description>The global flat steel market is projected to grow from USD 724.33 billion in 2025 to USD 1,157.84 billion by 2034. Major developments include AM/NS India's capacity expansion with a new 7 MTPA integrated flat steel mill in Andhra Pradesh, and the industry's significant transition toward low-carbon steel production through electric arc furnaces and hydrogen-based technologies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/copper-cables-antitrust-launches-investigation-into-alleged-cartel-prysmian-and-nexans-stock-market-drops/</link><description>The Italian Antitrust Authority has opened an investigation into major low voltage copper cable manufacturers in Italy, including Prysmian, for alleged price fixing since 2005. Inspections were conducted at company offices and distributors, impacting Prysmian's stock price negatively. Analysts believe the investigation will have a negligible impact on Prysmian due to the small market share of low voltage copper cables in its revenue.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium price dips slightly to USD 2,878.55/t amid mixed market signals</title><link>https://www.balajialuminium.com/aluminium-price-dips-slightly-to-usd-2878-55-t-amid-mixed-market-signals-12-november-2025/</link><description>Aluminum futures were quoted at around USD 2,878.55 per ton on November 12, 2025, marking a slight daily drop of 0.15%. The market remains volatile with mixed signals, but prices are still near recent highs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SSAB gains SEA funds for steel mill</title><link>https://www.globaltrailermag.com/ssab-gains-sea-funds-for-steel-mill/</link><description>SSAB has received approximately €28.67 million in funding from the Swedish Energy Agency to complete processes at its €4.5 billion electrified steel mill in Luleå, Sweden. The funding will support the development of technical solutions for electrification and energy efficiency in finishing processes, replacing natural gas and propane usage. The project is expected to reduce SSAB's carbon dioxide emissions by approximately 90 percent.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Firms Up as China Tackles Overcapacity</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel/news/496605</link><description>Steel rebar futures climbed to around CNY 3,100 per ton following China's announcement of new measures to curb steelmaking capacity in key regions. Beijing proposed a stricter capacity swap plan that would prohibit adding new steel capacity in key areas to rebalance supply and demand and improve profit margins.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Oman Poised to Lead Global Green Steel Revolution: IEEFA Report</title><link>https://solarquarters.com/2025/11/13/oman-poised-to-lead-global-green-steel-revolution-ieefa-report/</link><description>An IEEFA report highlights Oman's potential to become a leader in green steel production, leveraging its integrated steelmaking supply chain and renewable energy resources. The report emphasizes that transitioning from gas-based direct reduced iron production to green hydrogen is essential for Oman to capture the green premium in global markets.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Iron Process Revolutionising Zero-Carbon Steel Manufacturing</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/green-iron-technology-zero-carbon-2025/</link><description>Green iron technology uses clean electricity and hydrogen gas instead of coal and natural gas to convert iron ore into high-grade steel products. The process can reduce steelmaking emissions by over 90% compared to traditional methods while maintaining cost competitiveness. Market projections suggest 15-25% of global steel production could convert to green iron processes by 2035, with potential capacity reaching 50-100 million tonnes annually.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Taseko Florence Copper Production: Arizona ISCR Mining 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/florence-copper-mining-difference-2025/</link><description>Taseko Florence Copper has achieved major construction milestones in 2025, with the solvent extraction and electrowinning plant substantially completed in September and wellfield operations commencing in mid-October. The project is now ramping up production using in-situ recovery technology, with a phased approach to ensure sustainability and efficiency.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Taseko Reports Stronger Copper Output, Nears First Production at Florence Copper 2025</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/taseko-reports-stronger-copper-output-nears-first-production-at-florence-copper-2025-11-13</link><description>Taseko's Gibraltar mine saw increased copper production, reaching 27.6 million pounds, including 895,000 pounds of cathode, as mining moved into higher-grade areas. The company is nearing first production at its Florence Copper project, marking a significant milestone for the company.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Taseko Announces Improved Third Quarter Financial and Operational Results</title><link>https://tasekomines.com/investors/news/taseko-announces-improved-third-quarter-financial-and-operational-results</link><description>Taseko reported improved copper production for the third quarter, with expectations for 2025 output between 100 and 105 million pounds. The company anticipates further increases in copper head grades and recoveries in the fourth quarter.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>DPM Metals Announces Preliminary Third Quarter Production Results</title><link>https://dpmmetals.com/news-media/news-releases/dpm-metals-announces-preliminary-third-quarter-pro-11525/</link><description>DPM Metals reported increased gold and copper production in the third quarter, with both mines on track to meet 2025 guidance. The company highlighted the integration of the Vareš asset and its growth potential for copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Asia Q3 profit jumps to P3.09B on higher ore prices, exports</title><link>https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2025/11/13/711926/nickel-asia-q3-profit-jumps-to-p3-09b-on-higher-ore-prices-exports/</link><description>Nickel Asia Corp. reported a more than twofold increase in attributable net income for Q3, reaching P3.09 billion, driven by higher nickel ore prices and strong export performance. The company's operating mines sold 13.89 million WMT of nickel ore in the first nine months, with exports of saprolite and limonite ore totaling 8.32 million WMT at an average price of $37.52 per WMT, marking a 51.66% increase in export prices. The company expects nickel ore price tightness to persist as Indonesia enforces stricter policies on production permits.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 15,025.25 USD/T on November 13, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 15,025.25 USD/T on November 13, 2025, down 0.13% from the previous day, with prices down 0.53% over the past month and 4.50% compared to the same time last year. Nickel futures in the UK fell to $15,000 per tonne in November, trading at the lower end of their narrow range since June and significantly underperforming other base metals amid views of an oversupplied market. The decline is attributed to ample output from Indonesia's over-expanded nickel sector following the country's ore export ban in 2020.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Asia Q3 profit jumps to P3.09B on higher ore prices, exports</title><link>https://www.bworldonline.com/corporate/2025/11/13/711926/nickel-asia-q3-profit-jumps-to-p3-09b-on-higher-ore-prices-exports/</link><description>Nickel Asia Corporation (NAC) reported a 10.95% increase in share price following a Q3 profit of P3.09 billion, driven by higher nickel ore prices and exports. The company sold 13.89 million WMT of nickel ore in the first nine months, with export prices rising 51.66% amid tight supply due to stricter Indonesian production permit policies. NAC is also diversifying into copper and gold through its joint venture and expanding renewable energy projects.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>On November 13, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103618599/</link><description>The Shanghai Metals Market (SMM) reported that the #1 refined nickel price ranged from 118,600 to 122,700 yuan per metric ton on November 13, with an average price of 120,650 yuan/mt, marking a slight increase of 200 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel mine, hydroelectric project to be added to major projects list</title><link>https://energynow.ca/2025/11/nickel-mine-hydroelectric-project-to-be-added-to-major-projects-list/</link><description>Canada plans to add the Crawford Nickel Project in Ontario and a hydroelectric project in Nunavut to its major projects list, highlighting the growing importance of nickel mining and renewable energy infrastructure in the country.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alcoa says high US aluminum prices offset Trump tariff costs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/alcoa-sees-tariff-costs-on-aluminum-shipments-continuing-to-rise/</link><description>Alcoa reported that US tariffs on Canadian aluminum increased costs by $69 million compared to the previous quarter, but higher domestic aluminum prices have more than offset these tariff costs. The company expects tariff-related costs to rise further by $50 million in the current quarter, reflecting declining inventory and imports, while shipments from Canada to the US are returning to normal.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Linktour's 'Can-to-Car' Aluminum Tech Sets New Standard</title><link>https://www.openpr.com/news/4269924/linktour-s-can-to-car-aluminum-tech-sets-new-standard</link><description>Linktour has developed a proprietary WQAL Registered technology that uses post-consumer aluminum to minimize waste and energy consumption, significantly reducing the carbon footprint in vehicle manufacturing. Their all-aluminum monocoque body reduces vehicle weight by 45% compared to steel, enhancing performance and energy efficiency while promoting sustainability in EV production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>IEEFA: Oman a Frontrunner in the Green Steel Transition</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>A report from the Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis (IEEFA) indicates that Oman is positioned to become a global leader in the green iron and steel industry. The country is making significant progress in the transition toward sustainable steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel to Build DRI Plant on Big River Steel Works Campus</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>United States Steel Corporation confirmed plans to construct a direct reduced iron (DRI) plant on the Big River Steel Works campus in Osceola, Arkansas. This investment represents a significant step toward cleaner steel production methods.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel holds steady as U.S. government shutdown ends amid persistent market caution</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-holds-steady-as-us-government-shutdown-ends-amid-persistent-market-caution/157756</link><description>LME nickel prices remained steady following the end of the U.S. government shutdown, but market caution persists amid uncertain economic conditions. The cautious sentiment continues to influence nickel trading dynamics.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia limits new nickel permits to add value to production</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/indonesia-limits-new-nickel-permits-to-add-value-to-production/</link><description>Indonesia, the world's largest nickel producer, has stopped approving new permits for nickel plants producing certain intermediate products without plans for further processing. This move aims to push the industry up the value chain and address oversupply, potentially causing delays or cancellations of new projects. The regulation affects plants finishing after 2027 and emphasizes investment in downstream processing for electric vehicle battery materials.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Fathom Nickel expands Gochager Lake footprint</title><link>https://mining.com.au/fathom-nickel-expands-gochager-lake-footprint/</link><description>Fathom Nickel is advancing exploration at its Gochager Lake Project in Saskatchewan, Canada, aiming to establish a significant nickel district. Recent soil geochemistry and portable x-ray fluorescence results indicate expanding scale, with further assay results expected soon. Winter conditions favor upcoming drilling activities supported by infrastructure development like ice roads.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Homeland Nickel Enters Agreement with USA Company, Amplifying Exposure to Strategic Holdings</title><link>https://investingnews.com/homeland-nickel-enters-agreement-with-usa-company-amplifying-exposure-to-strategic-holdings/</link><description>Homeland Nickel Inc. announced the formation of Patriot Nickel Corp, a U.S.-based company aimed at building domestic nickel supply in Southern Oregon. Homeland will option key nickel properties to Patriot and receive a 20% equity stake, enhancing shareholder value and aligning with the 'America First' trend in critical mineral supply. The partnership is expected to facilitate regulatory progress and investor interest in the U.S. nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italian Expertise Fuels Prysmian Innovation</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/italian-expertise-fuels-prysmian-innovation</link><description>Prysmian is advancing its R&amp;D activities in Italy with over €5.5 million funding from Italian authorities for projects focused on high-voltage terrestrial and submarine transmission systems and renewable energy integration. The company is also involved in national initiatives like the Green New Deal and the RESTART Extended Partnership to drive innovation in energy and telecommunications.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum's Tug-of-War: Localized Weakness Meets Global Bullishness Amidst Shifting Market Dynamics</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-11-13-aluminums-tug-of-war-localized-weakness-meets-global-bullishness-amidst-shifting-market-dynamics</link><description>Despite localized industrial weakness and inventory concerns, aluminum prices showed a robust upward trend, trading around $2,881.15 per ton with a 4.92% increase over the past month. The market is driven by tightening supply, strong demand from growth industries, and China's production policies, creating a complex but bullish environment.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum's Tug-of-War: Localized Weakness Meets Global Bullishness Amidst Shifting Market Dynamics</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-11-13-aluminums-tug-of-war-localized-weakness-meets-global-bullishness-amidst-shifting-market-dynamics</link><description>The aluminum market shows a complex dynamic with localized industrial weakness in sectors and regions, but overall bullish sentiment driven by global supply constraints and strong demand from key growth industries. Despite weak manufacturing PMIs in the US and China, inventory destocking and stabilizing Chinese stocks indicate tightening physical supply, supporting price surges and investor confidence.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>NLMK USA Raises Prices for Hot-Rolled and Cold-Rolled Steel by $50/t</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/nlmk-usa-raises-prices-for-hot-rolled-and-cold-rolled-steel-by-50-t/</link><description>According to Kallanish, spot prices for HRC in the US rose to a new range of $830-865 per short ton on November 13, 2025. NLMK USA announced price increases for both hot-rolled and cold-rolled steel products.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron Ore Futures Plummet Amidst China's Faltering Steel Demand</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2025-11-13-iron-ore-futures-plummet-amidst-chinas-faltering-steel-demand-sending-ripples-across-global-markets</link><description>Iron ore futures have dropped significantly due to weak steel demand in China, pushing contracts to multi-month lows and signaling a structural shift in the global steel market. Chinese steel mills are cutting production to manage losses amid oversupply concerns, while environmental restrictions and a property sector downturn further constrain output. Globally, trade tensions are rising as regions like Europe plan to reduce tariff-free steel imports to protect domestic producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Can Tata Steel make Vande Bharat's wheels? MD says a business case is a must</title><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/can-tata-steel-make-vande-bharat-s-wheels-md-says-a-business-case-is-a-must-13675906.html</link><description>Tata Steel's Managing Director highlighted the company's capability to produce strategic steel products like railway wheels but emphasized that economic viability is a key challenge. The company plans to increase production capacity for wheels to meet Indian Railways' projected demand of 200,000 wheels by 2026, with a new plant phase expected to start by FY27. Tata Steel also produces specialized steels for automotive and hydrogen transfer applications.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Electric Secures $200M Bridge Loan for Arizona Copper Mine</title><link>https://www.mining.com/ivanhoe-electric-secures-200m-bridge-loan-for-arizona-copper-mine/</link><description>Ivanhoe Electric secured a $200 million bridge loan for its Santa Cruz copper project in Arizona, which is designed to produce 72,000 tonnes of pure copper cathodes annually. The project is expected to begin copper cathode production in late 2028 with an estimated after-tax NPV of $1.4 billion.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Energy Minister Tim Hodgson highlights Canada Nickel's Crawford mine</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2nbgGz0_GzA</link><description>Canada Nickel's Crawford mine in Ontario is being fast-tracked for approval as a major project, with a projected lifespan of over 40 years and potential to become one of the top 10 nickel producers globally. The project emphasizes low carbon emissions and plans expansions to produce other metals and develop nickel refining and stainless steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Inert Anode Aluminium Technology: Revolutionary Breakthrough</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/aluminium-production-inert-anode-technology-2025/</link><description>Rio Tinto has successfully implemented a 450 kiloampere inert anode cell at its Alma smelter in Quebec, eliminating direct CO₂ emissions from aluminium production. This technology is a key part of Rio Tinto's decarbonisation strategy and is being scaled with a demonstration plant under construction at the Arvida smelter, promising a transformative impact on sustainable aluminium production.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>ELYSIS Hits Milestone: First Inert Anode Aluminum Cell</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/elysis-hits-milestone-first-inert-anode-1569913/</link><description>ELYSIS has started up a 450 kiloampere inert anode cell at Rio Tinto's Alma smelter, marking the first commercial-scale use of this technology that produces aluminium without direct carbon emissions. This breakthrough supports large-scale low-carbon aluminium production and is central to Rio Tinto's long-term decarbonization plans, with a demonstration plant underway at Arvida.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ball, Unilever show green aluminium can work</title><link>https://minesandmoney.com/news/industry/ball-unilever-show-green-aluminium-can-work</link><description>Ball and Unilever are using aluminium produced with Alcoa's ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology, which employs inert anode technology to eliminate greenhouse gas emissions. This collaboration combines low-carbon primary aluminium with high recycled content, representing a significant advancement in sustainable aluminium packaging and supply chain innovation.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Manufacturer unveils innovative product that could transform future brake calipers</title><link>https://www.thecooldown.com/green-tech/brembo-brake-calipers-recycled-aluminum/</link><description>Brembo has launched brake calipers made from 100% recycled aluminum, reducing lifecycle carbon emissions by 70%. After five years of R&amp;D, this innovation demonstrates that high-performance automotive components can be produced sustainably without compromising quality, marking a significant step in the industry's sustainability efforts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Revolutionizing Industries: The Rising Impact of Lightweight Metal Tubing</title><link>https://techbullion.com/revolutionizing-industries-the-rising-impact-of-lightweight-metal-tubing/</link><description>Lightweight aluminum-based metal tubing is driving industrial transformation by offering high strength-to-weight ratios that improve efficiency and sustainability in automotive, aerospace, and construction sectors. Innovations in low-carbon manufacturing and closed-loop recycling are enhancing environmental performance, supporting global sustainability goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Major step forward for emissions-free aluminium smelting</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/major-step-forward-for-emissions-free-aluminium-smelting-2025-11-14</link><description>ELYSIS is advancing aluminium production by replacing carbon anodes with inert materials that generate oxygen instead of greenhouse gases. This technology aims to revolutionize the industry by enabling emissions-free smelting, contributing significantly to global decarbonization efforts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Turkey billet prices increased in the second half of October, affecting imports and domestic supplies</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>In Turkey, billet prices rose in late October, impacting both domestic supplies and imports from Russia. However, Russian companies face limited price increases due to weak demand outside Turkey, and Turkish steel producers have struggled to raise rebar prices, limiting further cost increases for scrap and semi-finished products.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>NDRC: China's steel prices to rally in November</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103780-ndrc-chinas-steel-prices-to-rally-in-november</link><description>China's steel prices are expected to rebound in November amid cautious optimism among market participants. Recent reports indicate a rangebound rebar market with some softening, but overall bullish sentiment is supported by macroeconomic signals and capacity adjustments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>American rebar producers have raised prices by $60/t</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>American rebar producers have increased prices by $60 per ton, reflecting ongoing cost pressures and market dynamics. This price adjustment is part of broader trends in steel production and consumption observed globally.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Proposal to amend publication deadline for Germany, Italy steel scrap price assessments</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/proposal-to-amend-publication-deadline-for-germany-italy-steel-scrap-price-assessments/</link><description>Fastmarkets proposed changing the publication deadline for Germany and Italy domestic steel scrap price assessments from the second Friday to the final Friday of each month. This amendment aims to ensure all key market participants have finalized monthly prices before assessments are published.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices, Charts, Analysis &amp; Forecast</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Copper</link><description>Copper prices showed slight fluctuations with the LMEselect Copper 3 Month price at around $10,859/mt on November 14, 2025. Downstream procurement remains weak, but spot discounts for SHFE copper are unlikely to widen as delivery dates approach, keeping transactions near parity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper retreats on weak China data, US caution</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3WQ03C:0-copper-retreats-on-weak-china-data-us-caution/</link><description>Copper prices retreated after a four-session winning streak due to weak economic data from China raising demand concerns, alongside cautious investor sentiment in the US. This pullback reflects ongoing sensitivity of copper prices to global economic indicators.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Grasberg Mine Suspension Creates Major Copper Production Crisis</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/grasberg-underground-catastrophe-copper-supply-2025/</link><description>The Grasberg mine suspension has caused a significant disruption in copper production, with Freeport McMoRan reporting a 13.2% decline in Q3 2025 output compared to Q3 2024. The suspension could reduce 2025 copper production by approximately 262,000 metric tons, a 35% decrease from original forecasts, driving copper prices to 15-month highs of $10,485 per metric ton due to tightened supply.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>DPM Metals Reports Record Third Quarter 2025 Financial Results</title><link>https://dpmmetals.com/news-media/news-releases/dpm-metals-reports-record-third-quarter-2025-finan-11656/</link><description>DPM Metals reported strong copper production of 7.8 million pounds in Q3 2025, a 6% increase over Q3 2024, driven by higher ore volumes and copper grades. However, copper production for the first nine months of 2025 was 8% lower than 2024 due to lower grades and recoveries, consistent with the mine plan.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>American Pacific Announces Sale of Palmer Copper-Zinc VMS Project to Vizsla Copper</title><link>https://americanpacificmining.com/news-releases-2025/american-pacific-announces-sale-of-palmer-copper-zinc-vms-project-to-vizsla-copper/</link><description>American Pacific Mining sold its Palmer Copper-Zinc VMS Project to Vizsla Copper for $15 million in equity plus up to $15 million in milestone payments. The project is seen as a critical metals opportunity in Alaska, with Vizsla Copper planning to advance exploration and development in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Vizsla Copper to buy Palmer VMS project</title><link>https://www.miningnewsnorth.com/story/2025/11/14/news-nuggets/vizsla-copper-to-buy-palmer-vms-project/9359.html</link><description>Vizsla Copper announced the acquisition of the Palmer VMS project, a significant copper-zinc deposit in Alaska. The acquisition is expected to enhance Vizsla's portfolio of critical mineral assets and support year-round exploration activities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Tivan Ltd News Today, Nov 14: Gold and Copper Discoveries Boost Timor</title><link>https://meyka.com/blog/tivan-ltd-news-today-nov-14-gold-and-copper-discoveries-boost-timor-1411/</link><description>Tivan Ltd announced significant gold and copper discoveries in Timor-Leste, marking an important development for the region's mining sector. These discoveries could enhance future copper production potential in the area.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fell sharply on November 14 as concerns over the US Fed's hawkish stance triggered cautious market sentiment</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103621463/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fell-sharply-on-November-14-as-concerns-over-the-US-Feds-hawkish-stance-triggered-cautious-market-sentiment</link><description>On November 14, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 119,600 yuan/mt, down 1,050 yuan/mt from the previous day. The decline was driven by market caution due to the US Federal Reserve's hawkish stance and uncertainty from divergent Fed officials' views on interest rates, pressuring nickel prices to remain weak in the near term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Indonesia releases benchmark prices for nickel ore in November Period I</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5103862-flash-indonesia-releases-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore-in-november-period-i</link><description>The Indonesia Nickel Miners Association announced benchmark prices for nickel ore for the first half of November 2025, with the reference price set at $15,075.33/wmt, down 0.44% from late October. Prices for various nickel grades also saw slight decreases compared to the previous period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/base-metals-investing/nickel-investing/nickel-forecast/</link><description>Nickel prices were volatile in the first half of 2025 but stabilized in Q3 amid ongoing oversupply concerns driven mainly by rapid production growth in Indonesia. Despite rising consumption, structural oversupply pressured prices, with a forecast of temporary price support due to seasonal output declines in the Philippines from October to early 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 14, the price range for SMM #1 refined nickel was</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103621443/</link><description>The price range for SMM #1 refined nickel on November 14, 2025, was between 117,400 and 121,800 yuan per metric ton, averaging 119,600 yuan/mt, marking a decrease of 1,050 yuan/mt. This reflects current market pricing trends for refined nickel in China.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's Top Cable Maker Sees US Copper Tariff as Opportunity</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/worlds-top-cable-maker-sees-us-copper-tariff-as-opportunity/</link><description>Prysmian, the world's largest copper cable maker, views the US copper tariff as an opportunity to strengthen its local supply chain and competitive position. The company benefits from sourcing copper domestically and is in close contact with US authorities regarding the tariff implementation.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell slightly to $2,853.35 per ton on November 14, 2025, down 0.90% from the previous day, but remain up over 7% year-over-year. Prices recently eased from a three-year high amid soft manufacturing PMIs in the US and China, though supply concerns keep prices elevated.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Rose to 3,053 CNY/T on November 14, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose to 3,053 CNY/T on November 14, 2025, up 0.16% from the previous day. Over the past month, steel prices have increased 1.63%, though they remain 3.93% lower than a year ago. Historically, steel reached an all-time high of 6,198 CNY/T in May 2021.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Fell to 853.02 USD/T on November 14, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel declined to 853.02 USD/T on November 14, 2025, down 0.23% from the previous day. Over the past month, HRC Steel prices have risen 4.92%, and are up 23.45% compared to the same time last year. HRC Steel recently hit a 15-week high of 857.00 USD/T on November 13.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Steel Markets Show Mixed Price Movements in Second Week of November 2025</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/37868/</link><description>Global steel markets displayed mixed price movements during the second week of November 2025, with some steel products recording increases while others declined. The varied performance reflects ongoing market volatility across different regions and product types.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>COP30 Evening Summary – November 14</title><link>https://cop30.br/en/news-about-cop30/cop30-evening-summary-november-14</link><description>Day 5 of COP30 highlighted major advances in steel technology and sustainability, including the adoption of the Belém Declaration on Global Green Industrialization and new interoperability agreements among global steel standards covering 70% of world production. These agreements aim to create a global market for near-zero and low-emissions steel, with independent verification and common carbon intensity data. Maersk also announced plans for 41 methanol-enabled vessels and large-scale green methanol offtake agreements starting in 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US Steel outlines $14B domestic investment plan with Nippon Steel</title><link>https://www.manufacturingdive.com/news/us-steel-outlines-14b-investment-nippon-steel-Q2-earnings-2025/804863/</link><description>U.S. Steel, backed by Nippon Steel, unveiled a $14 billion investment plan focused on domestic manufacturing, R&amp;D, and product innovation through 2028. The plan includes facility upgrades, new direct reduced iron and electric arc furnace projects, and aims to protect and create over 100,000 jobs. The partnership also targets $2.5 billion in annual synergy benefits by 2030 through operational efficiencies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper fell to 5.04 USD/Lbs on November 14, 2025, down 0.21% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices hovered near two-week highs above $5 per pound due to improved demand outlook after the US government shutdown ended. However, prices fell slightly amid reduced bets on a Federal Reserve rate cut and weak trade data from China, including a 1.1% fall in October exports and slowing import growth. Speculation about China's potential stricter controls on copper smelting projects could support prices in the future.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 2.26% Higher at $5.0495 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511148867/comex-copper-ends-the-week-226-higher-at-50495-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for November delivery gained 11.15 cents per pound, or 2.26%, closing at $5.0495 this week, reflecting a positive weekly performance in copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Fed Expectations Weigh on Gold</title><link>https://www.admis.com/fed-expectations-weigh-on-gold/</link><description>Copper prices moved lower in line with broader risk-off sentiment as markets reduced bets on a December Federal Reserve rate cut. Weak economic data from China, including slow factory output and retail sales growth, weighed on demand. On the supply side, copper production showed mixed results with increases in Peru and BHP’s Escondida mine but declines at Codelco and Collahuasi, supporting near-term copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Key facts: Rio Tinto shares dip on copper price drop; signs wind deal</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/tradingview:75a8fb3a909bf:0-key-facts-rio-tinto-shares-dip-on-copper-price-drop-signs-wind-deal-partners-in-tamarack-project/</link><description>Rio Tinto shares dipped following a drop in copper prices but the company signed a 15-year power purchase agreement for 78.5 MW of wind energy to power its Kennecott copper operations in Utah, signaling a commitment to sustainable mining practices amid market fluctuations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>AI Boom Pushes Copper Toward a Supply Crunch, BNEF Warns</title><link>https://www.mining.com/video/ai-boom-pushes-copper-toward-a-supply-crunch-bnef-warns/</link><description>A new BloombergNEF report highlights that the rapid expansion of AI data centers is significantly increasing copper demand, potentially adding 400,000 tonnes annually. Combined with ongoing energy transition projects and fragile mine supply, this could push copper prices to $13,500 per tonne by 2028, raising concerns about a looming supply crunch.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Green Transition Ignites Demand While Supply Scarcity Fuels Volatility</title><link>http://business.times-online.com/times-online/article/marketminute-2025-11-14-coppers-crucible-green-transition-ignites-demand-while-supply-scarcity-fuels-volatility</link><description>Recent market trends show that the global energy transition is driving strong copper demand, while supply constraints are causing price volatility. The article emphasizes the need for accelerated investment in sustainable mining, recycling, and innovative technologies to meet future demand and secure ethical supply chains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices fell sharply on November 14, as concerns over the US Fed's hawkish stance triggered cautious market sentiment</title><link>https://m.netdania.com/news/%5BSMM%20Nickel%20Midday%20Review%5D%20Nickel%20prices%20fell%20sharply%20on%20November%2014,%20as%20concerns%20over%20the%20US%20Fed's%20hawkish%20stance%20triggered%20cautious%20market%20sentiment.%20%7C%20SMM/Buzz%20FX/%7Bna:%5B%7Bt:%5B%22BUZZ_FX_GF%22%5D%7D%5D,hf:0%7D/tcnews/1dee7009fe486533b21694a605d8213917eb49e2@%7B%22Syms%22:%5B%5D,%22Inf%22:%7B%22PBL%22:%22Shanghai%20Metals%20Market%22%7D%7D/1763093721</link><description>Nickel prices dropped sharply on November 14 amid concerns about the US Federal Reserve's hawkish monetary policy, which led to cautious sentiment in the market. The decline reflects broader macroeconomic worries affecting commodity prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 14,880 USD/T on November 14, down 0.53% from the previous day, with a 1.78% decline over the past month. The market remains oversupplied, especially due to increased output from Indonesia, and prices are significantly lower than last year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Lifezone Metals raises US$15 million to advance work on Kabanga nickel project</title><link>https://africanminingmarket.com/lifezone-metals-raises-usd15-million-to-advance-work-on-kabanga-nickel-project/24219/</link><description>Lifezone Metals has launched a $15 million direct share offering to fund advancement of its Kabanga nickel project in Tanzania, aiming to develop one of the world's largest undeveloped high-grade nickel sulfide deposits.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali launches pilot phase of green hydrogen project</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-pilot-phase-of-green-hydrogen-project-1410354.htm</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has started the pilot phase of its green hydrogen production project at its plant in Aosta, Italy. The project uses a 1.008 MW Anion Exchange Membrane electrolyzer to produce 165 tons of green hydrogen annually, aiming to reduce carbon emissions and power one of its 70 furnaces entirely. This initiative is supported by €7.9 million funding from Italy’s National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italy's Cogne Acciai Speciali launches green hydrogen pilot plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has commenced operations at a green hydrogen pilot plant in Aosta, northern Italy, as part of its efforts to reduce fossil fuel use in steel production. This pilot plant is a key step in the company’s sustainability strategy to cut carbon emissions in its manufacturing processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali SpA Announces Its Commitment to Sustainability with ResponsibleSteel™ Certification</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-25</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has embarked on the ResponsibleSteel™ certification process for its Aosta site, formalizing its commitment to sustainable steel production. The certification reflects the company’s dedication to environmental responsibility, transparency, and social challenges in the steel industry, aiming to create lasting value for employees, customers, and communities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris remains profitable in 2025</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/tenaris-steel-oil-gas-market-earnings-q3-2025/</link><description>Tenaris reported a $37 million profit in Q3 2025, a 15.6% increase from the previous quarter but a 22.9% decrease compared to Q3 2024. Sales in North American oil and gas tubular products remained steady despite some reductions in drilling activity, with margins affected by recent tariff increases on steel imports.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S.A. Reports Shareholder Update on Ownership Stake and Planned Share Sales</title><link>https://www.quiverquant.com/news/Tenaris+S.A.+Reports+Shareholder+Update+on+Ownership+Stake+and+Planned+Share+Sales</link><description>Tenaris's controlling shareholders plan to sell some shares while maintaining at least a 67% ownership stake, in response to the company's ongoing share repurchase program. The timing and amount of sales will depend on market conditions, with no current plans to reduce ownership below 67%.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Announces 2025 Third Quarter Results</title><link>https://www.otcmarkets.com/stock/TS/news/Tenaris-Announces-2025-Third-Quarter-Results?e&amp;id=3342563</link><description>Tenaris released its financial and operational results for the third quarter of 2025, highlighting steady sales and profitability despite market challenges. The report reflects the company's resilience in the steel and energy sectors amid tariff impacts and fluctuating drilling activity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S A : Weekly Report (November 10, 2025 - November 14, 2025)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/tenaris-s-a-weekly-report-november-10-2025-a-november-14-2025-on-the-ce7d5fd2d18cf42d</link><description>As of November 14, 2025, Tenaris held 33,065,400 ordinary shares in treasury, representing 3.08% of its total issued share capital. This report provides an update on the company's shareholding and treasury stock status during the week.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Inert Anode Aluminum Production: Carbon-Free Future</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/inert-anode-aluminum-production-2025-environmental-breakthrough/</link><description>Inert anode technology is revolutionizing aluminum production by enabling carbon-free processes that could eliminate 400-700 million tonnes of CO₂ emissions annually if widely adopted by 2040-2045. Recent milestones include a commercial-scale 450-kiloampere cell startup at Rio Tinto's Alma smelter. The technology also offers productivity improvements, higher purity aluminum, and integration with renewable energy for near-zero lifecycle emissions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ball is making investments to increase its production capacity in India</title><link>https://www.apnnews.com/ball-is-making-investments-to-increase-its-production-capacity-in-india/</link><description>Ball Corporation is investing to expand its aluminum production capacity in India, aiming to meet growing demand and strengthen its market position. This move reflects broader industry trends of capacity growth in emerging markets to support global aluminum consumption.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Inert Anode Aluminum Production: Carbon-Free Future</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/inert-anode-aluminum-production-2025-environmental-breakthrough/</link><description>Inert anode aluminum production technology eliminates 95% of CO2 emissions while boosting manufacturing efficiency by up to 5% above conventional methods. If the technology achieves 50% market penetration by 2040, it could eliminate 400-500 million tonnes of direct process emissions globally.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Emissions-Free Aluminium Smelting Breakthrough Achieved</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/elysis-technology-industrial-smelting-innovation-2025/</link><description>ELYSIS inert anode technology, developed through a partnership between Alcoa Corporation and Rio Tinto, eliminates CO2 emissions in aluminum smelting while generating oxygen instead. The 450 kA commercial-scale cell represents a revolutionary transformation in industrial smelting with applications across automotive, aerospace, and construction sectors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>At COP30: Can-to-Can Recycling Delivers 18% Higher Efficiency and Major Climate Benefits for Aluminium Beverage Cans</title><link>https://international-aluminium.org/at-cop30-can-to-can-recycling-delivers-18-higher-efficiency-and-major-climate-benefits-for-aluminium-beverage-cans/</link><description>Research by Innoval Technology demonstrates that can-to-can recycling increases melt recovery rates by 18% and cuts energy use and greenhouse gas emissions by 15% compared to mixed-alloy recycling. Expanding Deposit Return Systems across the EU and UK by 2030 could deliver an additional 50% reduction in greenhouse gas emissions for aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China October crude steel output slides on weather-led restrictions, lower margins</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/china-october-crude-steel-output-slides-on-weather-led-restrictions-lower-margins/</link><description>China's crude steel production in October declined due to weather-related production restrictions and reduced profit margins. These factors contributed to a slowdown in steel output, reflecting ongoing challenges in the Chinese steel industry amid environmental and economic pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Central Yunnan Nonferrous Metals Achieves 200,000 mt Copper Anode Production Milestone</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103047390/Central-Yunnan-Nonferrous-Metals-Achieves-200000-mt-Copper-Anode-Production-Milestone</link><description>Central Yunnan Nonferrous Metals exceeded 200,000 metric tons of copper anode production for the first time, marking a significant production milestone. This achievement represents a major accomplishment in the company's copper refining operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper: Wired for the Future</title><link>https://sprott.com/insights/copper-wired-for-the-future/</link><description>Copper is central to the clean energy transition, with demand projected to reach 61% of global energy use by 2040. The article discusses the supply and demand imbalance, the importance of investment in sustainable mining, and the role of M&amp;A activity in securing future copper supplies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Ore Concentrate &amp; Gold Copper Concentrate 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-ore-concentrate-gold-copper-concentrate-2025</link><description>Technological innovations in copper concentrate processing are driving sustainability, with closed-loop water systems, reduced emissions, and improved tailings management. Satellite technology and digital solutions are also enhancing efficiency and transparency in mining operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Live Nickel Price per Metric Ton in USD</title><link>https://goldpricez.com/us/nickel</link><description>The live nickel price per metric ton in USD is updated continuously, reflecting global market movements. Prices are influenced by EV battery demand, stainless steel output, and supply from Indonesia and the Philippines.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 15 Nov 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/11/15/the-market-in-numbers-15-nov-2025/</link><description>Nickel prices showed a slight decline on November 15, with a 0.06% drop, continuing a trend of weakness over the past week and month. The broader market remains cautious amid ongoing oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>