<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 05:45:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A new way to make steel could reduce America's reliance on imports</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2026/new-way-make-steel-could-reduce-americas-reliance-imports-0213</link><description>Hertha Metals is advancing a novel single-step steelmaking process using natural gas and electricity on molten iron oxide, operating a 1-tonne-per-day pilot plant near Houston since late 2024. The company plans to build a 10,000-ton-per-year plant this year, reaching full capacity by end-2027, also producing high-purity iron for magnets to onshore critical materials. This innovation aims to outcompete traditional methods and integrate with existing U.S. steel infrastructure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A new way to make steel could reduce America's reliance on imports</title><link>https://news.mit.edu/2026/new-way-make-steel-could-reduce-americas-reliance-imports-0213</link><description>Hertha Metals has developed a new steel production system using natural gas and electricity that reduces iron ore to molten steel in a single step, eliminating the need for coking and sintering plants. The process uses 30 percent less energy and is 25 percent more cost-competitive than conventional American steel mills while reducing emissions. The company is scaling from its current 1-tonne-per-day pilot plant to a 10,000-ton-per-year facility expected to reach full capacity by end of 2027.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Border States Commodity Update: February 2026</title><link>https://tedmag.com/border-states-commodity-update-february-2026/</link><description>Major copper miners reported strong 2025 fourth-quarter production results. Rio Tinto achieved an 11% increase in copper production, exceeding 800,000 metric tons, driven by the Oyu Tolgoi mine in Mongolia with a 5% year-over-year rise in Q4 output. Freeport-McMoRan posted better-than-expected results despite a production decline at Indonesia’s Grasberg mine due to a natural disaster, expecting 85% recovery by mid-2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Wants to Further U.S. Copper Investment Amid Tariffs</title><link>https://www.industrialinfo.com/iirenergy/industry-news/article/rio-tinto-wants-to-further-us-copper-investment-amid-tariffs--343839</link><description>Rio Tinto is advancing the Resolution copper mine project in the U.S., potentially producing up to 500,000 tons of copper concentrate annually from 43.2 million tons of ore over 40 years, with permitting estimated for completion by February 13, 2026. The company is also investing in Bingham Canyon mine expansions, including a $1.5 billion Phase II project to extend life to 2032 and add 1 million tons of refined copper, plus a $500 million North Rim Skarn development for additional capacity by end-2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Sulphate Daily Review - February 13: Trading Sluggish Before the Holiday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/en/newscontent/103771216-SMM-Nickel-Sulphate-Daily-Review-February-13-Trading-Sluggish-Before-the-Holiday-Nickel-Salt-Prices-Remain-Stable</link><description>Battery-grade nickel sulphate prices remained stable at 31,635 yuan/mt on February 13, with trading activity slowing ahead of the Lunar New Year holiday. Market activity is expected to remain subdued during the holiday period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale reports $3.8 billion loss in Q4 due to nickel asset impairment</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/vale-reports-38-billion-loss-in-q4-due-to-nickel-asset-impairment-93CH-4504294</link><description>Mining giant Vale reported a $3.8 billion fourth-quarter loss, primarily driven by a $3.5 billion impairment on its nickel assets in Canada due to expectations of lower nickel prices. The impairment reflects broader concerns about the nickel market outlook.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale posts $3.8bn loss on nickel impairment; analysts welcome core profit</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/vale-posts-3-8bn-loss-on-nickel-impairment-analysts-welcome-core-profit-2026-02-13</link><description>Vale recorded a $3.5 billion impairment on nickel assets in its Base Metals division, contributing to a $3.8 billion quarterly loss that significantly exceeded analyst expectations of a $2.7 billion profit. The impairment reflects declining nickel price forecasts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>World's biggest nickel mine in Indonesia told to cut output</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/international/asean/worlds-biggest-nickel-mine-indonesia-told-cut-output</link><description>PT Weda Bay Nickel, the world's largest nickel mine, has been ordered to reduce its 2026 production quota to 12 million tonnes of ore, down from 42 million tonnes in 2025—a 71% reduction. This cut is part of Indonesia's broader strategy to restrict nickel supply, as the country produces approximately 65% of global nickel.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's Weda Bay Nickel facing quota cut by 70%, causing nickel prices to surge</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/indonesias-weda-bay-nickel-facing-quota-cut-by-70-causing-nickel-prices-to-surge/159215</link><description>The Indonesian government has drastically cut the production quota for PT Weda Bay Nickel to 12 million tonnes, triggering significant price movements in global nickel markets. The reduction reflects Indonesia's effort to tighten supply and support prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia risks oversupply in Class 2 nickel: Expert</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-risks-oversupply-in-class-2-nickel-expert</link><description>An expert analysis suggests that Indonesia's plan to sharply reduce its nickel ore production quota may paradoxically create oversupply risks in Class 2 nickel markets. The article discusses potential market implications of the production cuts.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Trump signals rollback on 50% steel and aluminum tariffs – what it means for solar</title><link>https://pv-magazine-usa.com/2026/02/13/trump-signals-rollback-on-50-steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-what-it-means-for-solar/</link><description>The Trump administration is preparing to scale back up to 50% tariffs on imported steel and aluminum to address an affordability crisis. This could significantly lower costs for the US solar industry, where aluminum frames now represent 14% of solar panel manufacturing costs. The rollback may ease Balance of System costs for utility-scale and residential solar projects.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Metals retreat on reports Trump may soften aluminium tariffs</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/business/2026/02/13/metals-retreat-on-reports-trump-may-soften-aluminium-tariffs</link><description>Metals prices retreated on the London Metal Exchange after reports that Trump may soften aluminum tariffs. The benchmark three-month aluminum contract slipped more than 2.5% to $2,965.75 a tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump signals rollback on 50% steel and aluminum tariffs: What it means for solar</title><link>https://pv-magazine-usa.com/2026/02/13/trump-signals-rollback-on-50-steel-and-aluminum-tariffs-what-it-means-for-solar/</link><description>The Trump administration is reportedly preparing to scale back up to 50% tariffs on imported steel and aluminum to address affordability concerns. The shift toward 'targeted' metal duties could significantly impact the solar supply chain, where aluminum frames have become the costliest component in panel production at 14% of manufacturing costs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Construction steel prices: Yining (Feb 13, 2026 19:05)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/daily-prices/6913922-construction-steel-prices-yining</link><description>Mysteel reports construction steel prices in Yining, China, collected on February 13, 2026, including round bar and other products with 13% VAT. Similar daily price updates were issued for other regions like Kuitun, Kumul, Urumchi, and Zhuhai on February 14. These reflect ongoing market monitoring amid rangebound expectations for February.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper scrap prices: Baoding (Feb 13, 2026 17:40)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/daily-prices/6913632-copper-scrap-prices-baoding</link><description>Mysteel reports copper scrap prices in Baoding, China, including grades like brass (Cu:98%), low-voltage cable (Cu≥99.5%), and others with low, high, and mid prices in Yuan/tonne including 13% VAT. Prices were updated as of February 13, 2026, 17:40, reflecting regional market activity. Similar updates available for other Chinese cities like Foshan and Shanghai on February 14.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 16,995 USD/T on February 13, 2026</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell 1.48% to $16,995 per tonne on February 13, declining 9.53% over the past month despite remaining 9.96% higher than a year ago.[1] Nickel futures had surged to $17,900 per tonne earlier in February following Indonesia's announcement of production quota cuts to 270 million tonnes for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tariffs: The Pedal Keeps Hitting the Metal | February 2026</title><link>https://shapirometals.com/blog/tariffs-the-pedal-keeps-hitting-the-metal--february-2026</link><description>Since Trump's 50% tariff on aluminum in June, Midwest premiums and prices have risen monthly, with premiums from $0.40s to $1.04 and LME up $600 per tonne. A potential 25% tariff on imports from partners like Canada could add $0.35-0.37 per lb to US premiums. 2026 LME aluminum forecasts average around $3,250 per forecasts from analysts.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Taylor's Scrapyard and Metal Recycling Reports Steel Prices Continue Upward Trend in Early 2026</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/abnewswire-2026-2-13-taylors-scrapyard-and-metal-recycling-reports-steel-prices-continue-upward-trend-in-early-2026</link><description>Taylor's Scrapyard reports continued steel price rises in early 2026, building on January gains into February, following seasonal trends of strengthening demand from mills and manufacturing. This upward momentum creates opportunities for scrap metal sellers as consumption increases in construction and industrial sectors. The company offers metal recycling and demolition services in Georgia.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Construction steel prices: Tangshan (Feb 13, 2026 18:15)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/daily-prices/6913792-construction-steel-prices-tangshan</link><description>Mysteel reports construction steel prices in Tangshan, China, as collected by on-ground teams. This update provides the latest snapshot of regional pricing amid ongoing market fluctuations. Specific price details reflect current trading levels on February 13.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>ArcelorMittal sees 2% rise in steel sales</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/steel/arcelormittal-sees-2-rise-in-steel-sales/articleshow/127948574.cms</link><description>ArcelorMittal projects a 2% increase in global steel demand for 2026 (excluding China), with production and shipments expected to grow across all regions. European mills are anticipated to benefit from trade protections including the Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) and new tariff rate quota mechanisms.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Steadies as Lunar New Year Nears</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to 5.80 USD/Lbs on February 13, 2026, up 0.30% from the previous day. Despite a 4.17% decline over the past month, copper remains 25.48% higher than a year ago. The price movement reflects support from ongoing supply disruptions and robust global demand, though near-term weakness is expected as economic activity in China slows ahead of Lunar New Year holidays.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Today</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-prices-today/</link><description>Nickel prices plummeted on February 13, 2026, entering a correction phase after a recent speculative rally. The market reflects updated intraday data during active trading hours.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminium prices drop to one-week low on report Trump may ease tariffs</title><link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/aluminium-prices-drop-to-one-week-low-on-report-trump-may-ease-tariffs-126021301395_1.html</link><description>Benchmark three-month aluminium on the London Metal Exchange fell 1.9% to $3,040.50/t after reports that the US may trim some tariffs. The decline reflects macro-driven risk-off sentiment, profit-taking, and reduced physical demand ahead of the Chinese Lunar New Year break.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump plans to ease some steel, aluminum tariffs</title><link>https://finance-commerce.com/2026/02/trump-scale-back-steel-aluminum-tariffs/</link><description>Donald Trump plans to scale back select steel and aluminum tariffs amid price concerns. The announcement caused shares of major producers like Alcoa and Century Aluminum to decline significantly, while benchmark aluminum prices on the LME fell to one-week lows.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Wheel steel prices: China's major cities (Feb 13, 2026 16:18)</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/daily-prices/6912611-wheel-steel-prices-chinas-major-cities</link><description>Mysteel reports wheel steel prices across China's major cities as of February 13, 2026, at 16:18. Note that no news updates will occur from February 16-23 due to Chinese New Year. This provides the latest available pricing data within the timeframe.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ryerson and Olympic Steel Announce Successful Closing of Merger</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ryerson-and-olympic-steel-announce-successful-closing-of-merger-302688031.html</link><description>Ryerson and Olympic Steel have completed their merger, forming the second-largest North American metals service center with expected $120 million in annual synergies by early 2028 through procurement, efficiency, and optimization. The combined entity enhances processing capabilities, geographic expansion, and asset utilization to improve service amid a manufacturing demand upcycle.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel and aluminum tariffs, Trump reconsiders: Prysmian sinks, Tenaris rises on the Milan Stock Exchange</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/dazi-acciaio-e-alluminio-trump-ci-ripensa-prysmian-affonda-tenaris-sale-a-piazza-affari-cosa-sta-succedendo/</link><description>Tenaris's stock rose on the Milan Stock Exchange following reports that Trump may reconsider steel and aluminum tariffs. The company continues strategic operations, including a contract worth up to €550 million with Enedis to supply electrical structures for modernizing France's electrical grid over seven years with options for three additional years.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Agrees Framework Agreement With Enedis To Modernise The French Power Grid</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-agrees-framework-agreement-with-enedis-to-modernise-the-french-power-grid</link><description>Prysmian signed a €550 million contract with Enedis to supply the full range of medium-voltage cables over seven years (2026-2032). The agreement includes the use of recycled materials such as over 12% recycled aluminum and over 30% recycled copper, aligning with both companies' sustainability and circular economy goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Signs EUR500 Million Deal for French Power Grid</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/prysmian-signs-eur500-million-deal-for-french-power-grid-ce7e5ddadb8cf623</link><description>Prysmian announced a seven-year agreement with Enedis valued at €500 million to become the sole supplier for medium-voltage cables. The partnership aims to enhance circular economy practices and reduce carbon emissions through the use of renewable energy sources and recycled materials in cable production.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Falls on Likely US Tariff Slash</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/aluminum-falls-on-likely-us-tariff-slash/</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK fell to $3,050 per tonne, continuing the pullback from a three-year high. The decline follows reports of a likely US tariff reduction on aluminum imports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>February 14: Aluminum Prices Strong While Downstream Orders Remain Weak; Aluminum Billet Processing Fees in Three Regions Remain Flat Compared to Yesterday - Daily Review of Spot Aluminum Billets</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103177818-february-14-aluminum-prices-strong-while-downstream-orders-remain-weak-aluminum-billet-processing-fees-in-three-regions-remain-flat-compared-to-yesterday-daily-review-of-spot-aluminum-billets</link><description>Aluminum prices remained strong on February 14 despite weak downstream orders. Aluminum billet processing fees in three regions stayed flat compared to the previous day.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price rises as looming smelter closure adds to supply strains</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-rises-as-looming-smelter-closure-adds-to-supply-strains/</link><description>South32 Ltd. is proceeding with plans to mothball its Mozal smelter in Mozambique next month, a major supplier to the European market. The closure adds to growing supply constraints as Chinese smelters near government-imposed production capacity caps and 50% US tariffs have caused imports to slump, with aluminum prices rallying 17% last year and 5.5% so far in 2026.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bessent discusses possible narrowing of steel, aluminum tariffs</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2026-02-14/business/industry/Bessent-discusses-possible-narrowing-of-steel-aluminum-tariffs/2524445</link><description>Treasury Secretary Bessent commented on reports of potential tariff rollbacks, stating that any changes would likely involve clarification on incidental objects rather than broad scaling back. The Trump administration has imposed 50% tariffs on steel and aluminum imports, with discussions ongoing about possible modifications.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bessent discusses possible narrowing of steel, aluminum tariffs</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2026-02-14/business/industry/Bessent-discusses-possible-narrowing-of-steel-aluminum-tariffs/2524445</link><description>U.S. Treasury Secretary Bessent discussed the Trump administration's potential plan to scale back 50 percent tariffs on steel and aluminum imports to address rising affordability issues. Officials believe the tariffs are hurting consumers by raising prices for goods including pie tins and food-and-drink cans.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump plans to roll back some tariffs on steel, aluminium goods</title><link>https://www.thenews.pk/print/1398950-trump-plans-to-roll-back-some-tariffs-on-steel-aluminium-goods-ft-reports</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump plans to scale back some tariffs on steel and aluminum goods, according to Financial Times reporting. The move comes as Commerce Department and trade officials believe the tariffs are hurting consumers, with shares of major steelmakers declining following the announcement.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bessent discusses possible narrowing of steel, aluminum tariffs</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2026-02-14/business/industry/Bessent-discusses-possible-narrowing-of-steel-aluminum-tariffs/2524445</link><description>US Treasury Secretary Bessent discussed potential narrowing of 50% tariffs on steel and aluminum imports and derivatives like appliances in a CNBC interview. The Trump administration imposed these tariffs, but changes may clarify incidental items ahead of midterm elections. He noted it would be the president's decision after consulting the US Trade Rep.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Prices Inched Lower in February</title><link>http://news.metal.com/newscontent/102143337-Nickel-Futures-Prices-Inched-Lower-in-February</link><description>Nickel prices declined in February amid macroeconomic headwinds including higher-than-expected CPI (6.4%) and PPI (6%) data, along with hawkish Federal Reserve commentary raising interest rate concerns. The LME announced on February 23 that Asian nickel trading would resume on March 20, which also contributed to price declines.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Philippine nickel sales to Indonesia to jump after Jakarta curbs</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/philippine-nickel-sales-to-indonesia-to-jump-after-jakarta-curbs/</link><description>Philippine nickel ore shipments to Indonesia could double to 30 million tons in 2026 following Indonesia's production cuts. Philippine miners see this as an opportunity to fill the supply gap created by Indonesia's domestic output reduction, though expansion may be limited by aging mines and slow approval processes.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum pulls back after a one-week low following market digests reporting Trump may ease tariffs</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/02/14/aluminum-pulls-back-after-a-oneweek-low-following-market-digests-reporting-trump-may-ease-tariffs</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to their lowest level in a week on Friday after reports that the U.S. may slash some import tariffs. The benchmark three-month aluminum on the LME lost as much as 2.7% but reduced losses to 0.9% by end of trading at $3,074/t.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum pulls back after a one-week low following market digests reporting Trump may ease tariffs</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2026/02/14/aluminum-pulls-back-after-a-oneweek-low-following-market-digests-reporting-trump-may-ease-tariffs</link><description>Aluminum prices fell to a one-week low on Friday, dropping as much as 2.7% to $3,074 per metric ton on the LME after reports of potential U.S. tariff reductions. The metal had peaked due to supply concerns but pulled back amid tariff speculation. Alcoa and Century Aluminum shares declined alongside steelmakers.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>EU steelmakers demand electricity price cut to safeguard the bloc's competitiveness</title><link>https://eurometal.net/eu-steelmakers-demand-electricity-price-cut-to-safeguard-the-blocs-competitiveness/</link><description>European steelmakers are urging the EU to reduce electricity prices to around €50/MWh to protect the bloc's steel industry competitiveness. The demand addresses high energy costs impacting production viability amid global challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel, a Russian nickel producer, will shift some of its nickel production to a copper plant for repairs</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2026/02/14/nornickel-a-russian-nickel-producer-will-shift-some-of-its-nickel-production-to-a-copper-plant-for-repairs</link><description>Nornickel plans to maintain 2026 nickel production at 193,000-203,000 metric tonnes by shifting some output to a copper facility during a 270-day smelting furnace upgrade at Nadezhda Metallurgical Plant in 2027. This unconventional approach offsets half the plant's capacity loss. The company is preparing production lines for pilot tests this year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Trump to Roll Back Some Tariffs on Steel, Aluminum</title><link>https://english.aawsat.com/business/5240698-trump-roll-back-some-tariffs-steel-aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices sank to a one-week low after reports that Trump may trim import tariffs, with LME's three-month contract slipping over 1.18% to $3,063.50 a ton and Shanghai's most-active contract falling 1.76% to 23,195 yuan a ton. Trading slowed in China ahead of the Lunar New Year break from February 15 to 24. Copper prices also tumbled amid these pressures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump Moves to Roll Back Metal &amp; Aluminum Tariffs as Affordability Pressures Mount</title><link>https://www.agbull.com/trump-moves-to-roll-back-metal-aluminum-tariffs-as-affordability-pressures-mount/</link><description>The Trump administration plans targeted easing of metal tariffs ahead of 2026 midterms to address affordability for voters and manufacturers. This follows earlier bolstering from Iran tensions but recent drops on deal prospects, weakening demand, and supply growth per IEA forecasts. Prices show slowing downside amid persistent oversupply concerns.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminium drops on report Trump may ease tariffs</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40407256/aluminium-drops-on-report-trump-may-ease-tariffs</link><description>Aluminium prices fell to a one-week low on reports of potential US tariff trims, with other industrial metals also declining. Trading volumes were low ahead of holidays, contributing to the price drop.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump to Roll Back Some Tariffs on Steel, Aluminum</title><link>https://english.aawsat.com/business/5240698-trump-roll-back-some-tariffs-steel-aluminum</link><description>US President Trump plans to scale back some steel and aluminum tariffs due to concerns over rising consumer prices for goods like cans and pie tins. Aluminum prices dropped to a one-week low following the report, with trading slowed in China due to Lunar New Year closure. The administration will exempt certain items and pursue targeted security probes instead of broad expansions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose to 3,056 CNY/T on February 13, 2026, up 0.53% from the previous day, though down 2.80% over the past month and 4.68% year-over-year. Recent news highlights steel rebar futures falling to a one-month low around CNY 3,070/ton on February 9 due to mills trimming production ahead of Lunar New Year. Earlier in February, prices pulled back from five-month highs amid declining industrial metals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Mid-February 2026 Steel Pipe Market: Navigating the Final Stretch of the Holiday Hiatus</title><link>https://www.sanonpipe.com/news/mid-february-2026-steel-pipe-market-navigating-the-final-stretch-of-the-holiday-hiatus/</link><description>Steel pipe production remains idle but is expected to resume in a staggered manner from the week of February 23rd onwards, with full stable output anticipated by early March. The supply chain is preparing for reactivation, with initial post-holiday lead times potentially extending to 50-65 days as manufacturers clear significant order backlogs from before the holiday shutdown.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>Italy's Antitrust Authority has initiated an investigation into major low-voltage copper cable manufacturers, including Prysmian Cavi e Sistemi Italia Srl, for alleged price-fixing since 2005. Inspections were conducted yesterday at company offices, distributors, and the National Federation of Electrical Material Wholesalers, supported by Guardia di Finanza. Prysmian shares dropped 1.26% in response, though analysts view the impact as negligible given the small market share.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Steel industry faces challenges amid domestic focus shift</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/steel-industry-faces-challenges-amid-domestic-focus-shift-2026-2-16/98479</link><description>Vietnamese steel companies are shifting focus to the domestic market due to weakening export demand and trade barriers, leading to intense competition and compressed profit margins. Companies like Nam Kim Steel are expanding production capacity with new plants such as the Phú Mỹ Steel plant set to start in Q1 2026, but simultaneous expansions by competitors like VNSteel and Dong A Steel risk oversupply. Analysts highlight challenges in achieving supply-demand balance and rising operating costs impacting profitability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Why copper and nickel prices are moving today: key market drivers - Feb 15, 2026</title><link>https://naturalresourcestocks.net/why-copper-and-nickel-prices-are-moving-today-key-market-drivers-feb-15-2026/</link><description>Copper prices rose to $5.80/lb (+0.30%) as of the latest update on Feb 13, 2026, driven by supply tightness, electrification demand, stockpiling, policy risks, supply disruptions, and China demand signals. The market remains sensitive to inventory flows and tariff uncertainties. Nickel prices fell to $16,995/tonne (-1.48%) amid Indonesia supply issues.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why copper and nickel prices are moving today: key market drivers - Feb 15, 2026</title><link>https://naturalresourcestocks.net/why-copper-and-nickel-prices-are-moving-today-key-market-drivers-feb-15-2026/</link><description>Nickel prices are modestly lower at $16,995/tonne as of the February 13 close, amid choppy trading balancing Indonesia-driven supply headlines against oversupply concerns. The market remains sensitive to stainless steel demand and global growth expectations. Copper holds near elevated levels, but nickel faces demand-cycle uncertainty.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Why copper and nickel prices are moving today: key market drivers - Feb 15, 2026</title><link>https://naturalresourcestocks.net/why-copper-and-nickel-prices-are-moving-today-key-market-drivers-feb-15-2026/</link><description>Nickel prices reacted to Indonesia ordering Weda Bay, the world's biggest nickel mine complex, to cut its 2026 ore quota. As of February 13 close, nickel stood at $16,995/ton amid supply management headlines. This contributes to broader market movements influenced by Indonesian supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer price drops 3.88% to $2,996/t; opening stock slips 0.41%</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-price-drops-3-88-to-2-996-t-opening-stock-slips-0-41-117289</link><description>LME aluminium prices recorded a sharp decline on February 13, with cash bid prices falling to $2,995/t from $3,116.5/t (3.90% decline). The price drop is attributed to stock market declines, profit-taking, position squaring, strong US labour data, and reduced China demand before Lunar New Year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>White House denies reports of steel, aluminum tariff rollback</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/white-house-denies-reports-of-steel-aluminum-tariff-rollback/</link><description>The White House pushed back against recent reports suggesting a potential rollback of the 50% steel and aluminum tariffs. White House trade advisor Peter Navarro stated there was no basis for reports that the administration planned to reduce these tariffs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>White House denies reports of steel, aluminum tariff rollback</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/white-house-denies-reports-of-steel-aluminum-tariff-rollback/</link><description>The White House denied reports suggesting a potential rollback of the 50% steel and aluminum tariffs. This statement addresses market speculation impacting commodity prices and related stocks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Cans Recycling Services Market Projected to Reach</title><link>https://www.openpr.com/news/4391273/aluminum-cans-recycling-services-market-projected-to-reach</link><description>Rising primary aluminum costs are making recycled aluminum economically attractive, as recycling consumes 95% less energy than primary production. Technological advancements including AI-powered sorting systems and advanced metallurgical analysis are expanding market opportunities, with Asia-Pacific capturing 35% of incremental growth and mandatory recycling targets driving $4.8 billion in infrastructure investment.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Brazil to Host Latin America's First Exclusive Metal Packaging Congress</title><link>https://whattheythink.com/news/129261-brazil-host-latin-americas-first-exclusive-metal-packaging-congress/</link><description>Brazil is hosting Latin America's first exclusive metal packaging congress. Limited details are available from the press release provided.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel fell to 965.04 USD/T on February 16, 2026, down 0.72% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 2.89%, with a yearly increase of 26.56%. The data was last updated on February 15, 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>February 16, 2026 Scrap &amp; Used Car Market Update</title><link>https://603autosalvage.com/market-review/february-16-2026-scrap-used-car-market-update/</link><description>Ferrous scrap shows modest improvement, with shredded steel trading in the $290-$315 per ton range. Mills are returning from the holiday with restocked order books. This indicates positive trends in the scrap steel market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 16.02.2026</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides real-time updates on global iron and steel prices, including Shanghai Futures rebar terms as of February 13, 2026. Various futures contracts for regions like China, Turkey, Europe, and North America are listed. The platform offers analyses and comments on the industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>White House denies reports of steel, aluminum tariff rollback</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/white-house-denies-reports-of-steel-aluminum-tariff-rollback/</link><description>The White House has denied recent reports suggesting a potential rollback of the 50% tariffs on steel and aluminum. This stance maintains current trade protections amid ongoing commodity market discussions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Pricing</title><link>https://internationalwire.com/copper-pricing/</link><description>International Wire reports the copper base price at $8.4000 effective February 16, 2026, for Omega - Camden. Additional indices include COMEX copper monthly average at $5.88100 and LME copper cash settlement at $5.9370 for January 2026. This provides a current pricing snapshot amid ongoing market trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global copper exchange stocks top 1Mt for first time in two decades</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/global-copper-exchange-stocks-top-1mt-for-first-time-in-two-decades-2026-02-16</link><description>Copper stocks on the world's three biggest metal exchanges exceeded one-million metric tons for the first time in more than two decades. This buildup signals shifting market dynamics potentially impacting prices and supply trends.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global copper exchange stocks top 1Mt for first time in two decades</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/global-copper-exchange-stocks-top-1mt-for-first-time-in-two-decades-2026-02-16</link><description>Copper stocks on the world's three biggest metal exchanges have exceeded one-million metric tons for the first time in more than two decades. This buildup indicates shifting supply dynamics amid recent market pressures. The increase highlights potential easing of immediate tightness despite ongoing production challenges.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Monday Report - 16 February 2026</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2026/02/16/the-monday-report-16-february-2026/</link><description>Spot nickel prices fell 5.10% to $7.63/lb in the latest futures update. The report covers broader metals market movements, including gains in gold and silver amid expectations for UK CPI data. Energy futures show minor declines in crude oil prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper Values Retreat to $5.9 Per Pound as Chinese Industrial Engine Idles for Lunar New Year</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/wral/article/marketminute-2026-2-16-copper-values-retreat-to-59-per-pound-as-chinese-industrial-engine-idles-for-lunar-new-year</link><description>Copper futures settled near $5.90 per pound due to a seasonal slowdown in China during Lunar New Year starting February 17, 2026, leading to reduced industrial activity and inventory buildup. This follows volatility with peaks near $6.50 in late January. Post-holiday recovery in March could see range-bound trading between $5.75 and $6.10, with potential rallies if stimulus boosts demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>BHP Earnings Feb. 17: 62C Dividend Seen, Copper Guide Raised</title><link>https://www.ebc.com/forex/bhp-earnings-feb-17-62c-dividend-seen-copper-guide-raised</link><description>BHP has lifted its FY26 copper production guidance to 1,900–2,000 kt ahead of its half-year results on February 17, 2026. The company highlights strong copper performance and resilience in China's commodity demand. This guidance uplift supports valuation and dividend confidence amid favorable prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Norilsk Nickel will be the first in the world to launch a unique tunneling complex in the Arctic</title><link>https://www.akm.ru/eng/press/norilsk-nickel-will-be-the-first-in-the-world-to-launch-a-unique-tunneling-complex-in-the-arctic/</link><description>Norilsk Nickel plans to test its unique 700-ton Norda mechanized tunneling complex at the Taimyrsky mine in Q2 2026, targeting 150,000 tons of ore production that year from the Severnaya-4 deposit. The equipment promises record penetration speeds and improved safety. All specialists are trained, and assembly is underway.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>U.S., Nippon Steel to reline Gary Works blast furnace this year</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/u.s.-nippon-steel-to-reline-gary-works-blast-furnace-this-year-2026-2-17/98490</link><description>U.S. Steel and Nippon Steel plan to reline blast furnace #14 at Gary Works starting May 2026, costing $350 million and lasting 100 days until August, ensuring no supply interruptions. The company will invest $900 million in 2026, followed by $800 million in 2027 and $1.1 billion in 2028. Local activists oppose the project over environmental concerns, advocating for greener steelmaking.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S., Nippon Steel to reline Gary Works blast furnace this year</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/u.s.-nippon-steel-to-reline-gary-works-blast-furnace-this-year-2026-2-17/98490</link><description>U.S. Steel and Nippon Steel plan to reline blast furnace #14 at the Gary Works facility later this year as part of a $900 million investment in 2026, followed by further investments in 2027 and 2028. The project aims to implement high-productivity, energy-efficient technologies to reduce CO2 emissions intensity. This follows board approval in December 2025 for the $350 million reline of the facility's largest blast furnace.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP Boosts Profit Amid Copper Surge</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2026/02/17/bhp-boosts-profit-amid-copper-surge/</link><description>BHP reported a 28% profit surge to US$5.64 billion in the first half, driven by increased copper earnings and strong margins, allowing it to raise full-year 2026 copper production guidance to 1.9-2 million tonnes. Output from the Escondida mine and other Chilean operations contributed to this revision. The company declared an interim dividend of US73¢ per share, up from the previous year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper becomes BHP's biggest earnings driver</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/copper-becomes-bhps-biggest-earnings-driver-2026-02-17</link><description>BHP has increased its group copper production guidance for the 2026 financial year to between 1.9-million and 2.0-million tonnes. Copper has become the company's largest earnings driver.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Becomes BHP's Top Earnings Driver in 2026</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-bhps-biggest-earnings-driver-2026/</link><description>Copper has become BHP's largest earnings driver by 2026, boosting earnings with high margins.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>What's Behind the Copper Hype? A Fireside Conversation with BHP Americas President Brandon Craig</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/whats-behind-copper-hype-fireside-conversation-bhp-americas-president-brandon-craig</link><description>CSIS hosts a discussion on copper market trends, including tightening supply, declining ore grades, and geopolitical risks affecting energy, data centers, and defense technologies. BHP Americas President Brandon Craig joins to explore U.S. strategies for copper security, investment, and innovation in the value chain. The event underscores copper's role in technological leadership and economic resilience.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel price jumps as Indonesia’s top mine cuts output</title><link>https://www.mining.com/nickel-price-jumps-as-indonesias-top-mine-cuts-output/</link><description>LME nickel prices rose 2% to $17,835/tonne after Indonesia slashed PT Weda Bay Nickel's 2026 ore quota to 12 million tonnes from 42 million in 2025, extending a 20% rally. Total national quotas are set at 260-270 million tonnes, down from 379 million in 2025, tightening global supply. Eramet plans to request a quota revision.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Defy Tariff Rollback Rumors as 'Project Vault' and Carbon Levies Reshape Global Supply</title><link>http://markets.chroniclejournal.com/chroniclejournal/article/marketminute-2026-2-17-aluminum-prices-defy-tariff-rollback-rumors-as-project-vault-and-carbon-levies-reshape-global-supply</link><description>Aluminum prices hold above $3,100 per tonne despite rumors of US tariff rollbacks, driven by structural supply deficits and the US government's Project Vault initiative launched on February 2 with $10 billion for essential minerals. The US Midwest Premium hit a record $560 per tonne, with LME stocks near historic lows under 300,000 tonnes. Market focus shifts to government buying and off-take agreements amid physical scarcity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Defy Tariff Rollback Rumors as 'Project Vault' and Carbon Levies Reshape Global Supply</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2026-2-17-aluminum-prices-defy-tariff-rollback-rumors-as-project-vault-and-carbon-levies-reshape-global-supply</link><description>The global aluminum market is being driven by the U.S. government's $12 billion 'Project Vault' initiative to build a Strategic Critical Minerals Reserve, which is supporting prices despite tariff rollback speculation. Critically low domestic inventories and the EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism are reshaping valuations more than trade policy, with the Midwest Premium reaching a record $560 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>U.S. Raw Steel Production Climbs 5.6% Year Over Year in Mid-February 2026</title><link>https://www.scrapmonster.com/news/steel/u.s.-raw-steel-production-climbs-5.6-year-over-year-in-mid-february-2026-2026-2-17/98497</link><description>U.S. domestic raw steel production reached 1.8 million net tons in the week ending February 14, 2026, with mills operating at 77.8% capability utilization. This represents a 5.6% increase compared to the same week in 2025, and year-to-date production through February 14 is up 4.0% to 11.357 million net tons. The Southern district led regional output with 826,000 net tons.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metals market alert: Why copper price is falling today after stockpiles hit 20-year high</title><link>https://economictimes.com/news/international/us/metals-market-alert-why-copper-price-is-falling-today-after-stockpiles-hit-20-year-high-and-aluminum-slips-amid-tariff-uncertainty/articleshow/128470990.cms</link><description>Copper prices fell as much as 0.8% below $12,800 a ton as LME inventories hit a 20-year high, with global stocks exceeding 1 million tons across major exchanges. In China, near-record prices cooled demand, leading to rebuilding inventories amid caution over U.S. tariffs. Aluminum and other metals also slipped as markets awaited tariff clarity.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer eases to $3,014/t as opening stocks drop 0.42% to 477,550t on February 17</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-eases-to-3-014-t-as-opening-stocks-drop-0-42-to-477-550t-on-february-17-117318</link><description>LME aluminium cash prices declined 0.77% to $3,014 per tonne on February 17, with opening stocks dropping 0.42% to 477,550 tonnes and cancelled warrants rising sharply. The three-month Asian Reference Price stood at $3,035 per tonne, while LME alumina Platts price was $306.93 per tonne. This reflects ongoing inventory adjustments amid market pressures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices fall after report of curbs to tariffs</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/commodities-news/aluminum-prices-fall-after-report-of-curbs-to-tariffs-4504666</link><description>Aluminum prices in London slipped 1.7% to $3,045 per tonne following reports that the Trump administration plans to curb tariffs on some metal products to address surging consumer prices. The White House is reviewing affected products for exemptions and considering a targeted national security probe instead of broad expansions. Prices are down nearly 2% for the week but up 2% year-to-date.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price drops as Trump moves to narrow levies on metal products</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-drops-as-trump-moves-to-narrow-levies-on-metal-products/</link><description>Aluminum prices fell up to 2.7% on the LME as traders reacted to reports of President Trump planning to narrow the scope of import tariffs on aluminum and steel due to consumer impacts. The metal settled 0.7% lower at $3,077.50 per tonne, with ample near-term supplies indicated by expanding price discounts between contracts. Treasury Secretary downplayed any major rollback.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer eases to $3,014/t as opening stocks drop 0.42% to 477,550t on February 17</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-eases-to-3-014-t-as-opening-stocks-drop-0-42-to-477-550t-on-february-17-117318</link><description>LME aluminum prices declined 0.77% on February 17, with cash offer prices falling to $3,014 per tonne. Warehouse stocks decreased slightly while cancelled warrants surged 23.66%, indicating shifting market dynamics in inventory management.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Conscious Choice―Shaping Mobility's Future Through Recycled Aluminum</title><link>https://www.shm-afeela.com/en/news/2026-02-18/</link><description>AFEELA is incorporating high-purity, high-strength recycled aluminum into vehicle body panels and motor mounts through collaboration with Honda and suppliers. This approach ensures safety and performance via meticulous scrap selection, refining, and quality assurance. The initiative sets standards for sustainable mobility by integrating recycled materials into structural components.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Jindal Steel Ltd. Hits New 52-Week High of Rs.1230 on 18 Feb 2026</title><link>https://www.marketsmojo.com/news/stocks-in-action/jindal-steel-ltd-hits-new-52-week-high-of-rs1230-on-18-feb-2026-3845717</link><description>Jindal Steel Ltd. reached a new 52-week and all-time high of Rs.1230, reflecting a strong rally in the ferrous metals sector with 44.44% one-year appreciation. The stock trades above all major moving averages, indicating a well-established uptrend despite slight daily lag versus the sector. Its Mojo Grade is Hold, upgraded from Sell in November 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SGH Steel Dynamics Makes A$15B BlueScope Takeover Bid</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/cross-border-steel-consolidation-2026-global-markets-trends/</link><description>SGH Steel Dynamics has made a A$15 billion takeover offer for BlueScope, representing significant consolidation activity in the global steel market. This cross-border deal reflects ongoing industry consolidation trends in 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Conscious Choice―Shaping Mobility's Future Through Recycled Materials</title><link>https://www.shm-afeela.com/en/news/2026-02-18/</link><description>Sony Honda Mobility's AFEELA vehicle incorporates recycled steel and aluminum into structural components including body panels, motor mounts, and load-bearing parts. The company has developed an integrated system for material sourcing and quality assurance that enables recycled materials to meet performance standards comparable to virgin materials, setting new standards for sustainable vehicle development.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Teck Announces 2025 Production and Sales Update and Reaffirms Outlook</title><link>https://www.teck.com/news/news-releases/2026/teck-announces-2025-production-and-sales-update-and-reaffirms-outlook</link><description>Teck reports 2025 annual copper production of 453,500 tonnes, meeting guidance, with strong Q4 performance across assets including 55,400 tonnes from Quebrada Blanca. Copper sales in Q4 were lower than production due to inventory buildup from weather delays. The company reaffirms 2026 copper production guidance for Antamina at 95,000–105,000 tonnes with no changes to other 2026–2028 guidance.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why a tighter Copper Market puts Southern Hemisphere Mining front and centre – Investor Stream First Look</title><link>https://www.shmining.com.au/2026/02/why-a-tighter-copper-market-puts-southern-hemisphere-mining-front-and-centre-investor-stream-first-look/</link><description>The article discusses how a tightening copper market positions Southern Hemisphere Mining prominently for investors. It highlights recent drilling results summary from the Llahuin project as featured in a video. This comes amid broader market dynamics emphasizing copper supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME Nickel Futures Drop 0.93% on February 18</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103183599-LME-Nickel-Futures-Drop-093-on-February-18</link><description>On February 18, London Metal Exchange (LME) nickel futures prices fell by 0.93%. This decline reflects recent market volatility influenced by Indonesian supply dynamics and global demand trends. The drop adds to ongoing price swings in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries lifts 2026 quota, driving stronger outlook and margins</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/02/18/nickel-industries-lifts-2026-quota-driving-stronger-outlook-and-margins/</link><description>Nickel Industries received a 60% increase in its 2026 RKAB nickel ore sales quota to 14.3 million wet metric tonnes, boosting production capacity and margins. January 2026 saw Adjusted EBITDA of about US$50 million, driven by higher nickel prices and improved NPI margins up 150% to US$2,800/t. The quota supports stable supply for RKEF and HPAL operations amid positive market trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>3-Month Nickel Commodity Price Falls Toward US$16,875/Ton (Tuesday, February 17, 2026)</title><link>https://databoks.katadata.co.id/en/market/statistics/fb73cc493c80e11/3month-nickel-commodity-price-falls-toward-us16875ton-tuesday-february-17-2026</link><description>The 3-month nickel commodity price declined to around US$16,875 per ton as of February 17, 2026. This drop signals short-term bearish pressure in the nickel market. It follows broader trends of volatility tied to supply and demand factors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel prices recover to $18000 as market confidence stabilizes</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-prices-recover-to-18000-as-market-confidence-stabilizes/159259</link><description>LME nickel prices rebounded to US$18,000 per ton, stabilizing market confidence after an earlier sharp drop. This recovery provides relief to the stainless steel sector, which relies heavily on nickel. It reflects improving sentiment amid supply constraints and demand recovery.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries lifts 2026 quota, driving stronger outlook and margins</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2026/02/18/nickel-industries-lifts-2026-quota-driving-stronger-outlook-and-margins/</link><description>Nickel Industries received a 60% increase in its 2026 RKAB nickel ore sales quota to 14.3 million wet metric tonnes, up from 9.0 million wmt. The company reported January 2026 Adjusted EBITDA from Operations of approximately US$50 million, with significantly improved margins across its nickel pig iron and HPAL operations.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries secures 60% increase in 2026 ore sales quota</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-secures-60-increase-in-2026-ore-sales-quota</link><description>Nickel miner and processor Nickel Industries Ltd announced a 60% increase in its 2026 ore sales quota. This development reflects the company's strengthened position following Indonesia's updated production quotas for the year.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia tightens control on nickel as US and China scramble for critical minerals</title><link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/world/2026/Feb/18/indonesia-tightens-control-on-nickel-as-us-and-china-scramble-for-critical-minerals</link><description>Indonesia, which controls approximately 60% of global nickel supply as of 2024, is implementing stricter regulatory controls on nickel mining and processing. The crackdown includes seizures of mining operations and significant fines, though analysts note that nickel's strategic importance may be declining as Chinese EV manufacturers shift to battery chemistries requiring less nickel.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal</title><link>https://pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired isOplus's oil and gas division for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coatings. The business unit was rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy and will apply anti-corrosion coatings to line pipes at Tenaris facilities across Italy, Mexico, Argentina, and Brazil.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Tenaris to Launch TenarisShawcor White Jacket™ Coating at the Hydrogen World Expo</title><link>https://www.hydrogen-worldexpo.com/industry-news/tenaris-launch-tenarisshawcor-white-jacket-coating-hydrogen-ccus-technology-world-expo</link><description>Tenaris unveiled TenarisShawcor White Jacket™, an advanced coating solution developed at its Villamarzana, Italy facility for severe onshore and underground pipeline applications. The coating is suitable for hydrogen and carbon capture transportation pipelines, offering enhanced resistance to material embrittlement.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Acciaierie d'Italia to start preferential negotiations with Azerbaijani consortium on acquisition of former Ilva plants</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/acciaierie-ditalia-to-start-preferential-negotiations-with-azerbaijani-consortium-on-acquisition-of-former-ilva-plants-1384557.htm</link><description>Extraordinary commissioners of Acciaierie d’Italia and ILVA in extraordinary administration have requested authorization from Italy’s Ministry of Enterprises and Made in Italy to begin preferential negotiations with an Azerbaijani consortium (Baku Steel Company CJSC and Azerbaijan Investment Company OJSC) for the sale of the former Ilva steel plants.[8] Ten proposals had been received by the January 10 deadline, and the chosen consortium was selected based on criteria including financial stability, industrial sustainability, and expected benefits for employment and local communities.[8]</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>