<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:17:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingots Inventory Remains Flat WoW on Dec 1 – SMM Stats Show</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646973/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventory-Remains-Flat-WoW-on-Dec-1-SMM-Stats-Show</link><description>On December 1, 2025, the inventory of aluminum ingots in major domestic consumption areas in China was recorded at 596,000 metric tons, remaining flat week-on-week. Domestic aluminum production in November 2025 increased 1.47% year-on-year but decreased 2.82% month-on-month.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM: Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory in Two Regions Remains Flat at 83,500 mt on Dec 1, 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103647181/SMM:-Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Remains-Flat-at-83500-mt-on-Dec-1-2025</link><description>On December 1, 2025, domestic aluminum billet inventory in two major regions stood at 83,500 metric tons, unchanged from the previous week. Production data for November 2025 showed a year-on-year increase of 1.47% but a month-on-month decrease of 2.82%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum – Price – Chart – Historical Data – News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to 2,873.60 USD/tonne on November 28, 2025, up 1.42% from the previous period. The market continues to face supply pressures due to China’s output cap and production disruptions in Iceland and Australia.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Macro Sentiment Dominates; Marginal Improvement in Fundamentals – Aluminum Prices Expected to Fluctuate at Highs in Short Term [SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103647032/Macro-Sentiment-Dominates-Marginal-Improvement-in-Fundamentals-Aluminum-Prices-Expected-to-Fluctuate-at-Highs-in-Short-Term-%5BSMM-Aluminum-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Aluminum prices fluctuated upward in early December, supported by year-end demand and high raw material costs. Inventory levels remained stable, while production in China saw a slight year-on-year increase but a month-on-month decline.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Constellium SE to Showcase Innovations in Aluminum Products at the 2025 Paris Air Show</title><link>https://www.quiverquant.com/news/Constellium+SE+to+Showcase+Innovations+in+Aluminum+Products+at+the+2025+Paris+Air+Show</link><description>Constellium SE will present innovative aluminum products emphasizing sustainability and performance, including its first aluminum ingot made from end-of-life aircraft in collaboration with TARMAC Aerosave and Airbus. The company highlights advancements in sustainable aviation and next-generation wing technologies, promoting a circular economy in aerospace.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>IAI Reports Progress In Greenhouse Gas Reduction Initiative</title><link>https://international-aluminium.org/iai-reports-progress-in-greenhouse-gas-reduction-initiative/</link><description>The International Aluminium Institute announced progress in its greenhouse gas reduction initiative, with 80% of members setting long-term net-zero targets and many aiming for a 50% reduction in emissions by 2030. The industry is investing in technologies like inert anode technology, carbon capture, and renewable energy to achieve decarbonization goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ball, Unilever show green aluminium can work</title><link>https://miningbeacon.com/industry/ball-unilever-show-green-aluminium-can-work</link><description>Ball and Unilever demonstrated the use of green aluminum combining 50% ELYSIS low-carbon primary aluminum and 50% post-consumer recycled content for aerosol cans. The ELYSIS process, developed by Alcoa and Rio Tinto, eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions from smelting using inert anode technology, marking a significant step in decarbonizing aluminum packaging.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The Net Zero Innovation Hub for Data Centers and Phinergy Sign Strategic Collaboration to Validate Clean Aluminum-Air Generator (AAG) for Energy Resilience in Large-Scale Data Centers</title><link>https://www.netzerodatacenters.com/hub-and-phinergy-sign-strategic-collaboration-to-validate-clean-aluminum-air-generator-aag-for-energy-resilience-in-large-scale-data-centers</link><description>The Net Zero Innovation Hub and Phinergy partnered to validate aluminum-air generator technology that produces clean, zero-emission electricity from aluminum for data centers. This recyclable energy vector offers high energy density and grid resilience, supporting the transition to net-zero operations in cloud and AI-driven data centers.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vice trade minister expresses regret over Canada's stronger steel safeguard plan</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-12-01/business/economy/Vice-trade-minister-expresses-regret-over-Canadas-stronger-steel-safeguard-plan/2466844</link><description>South Korea's Vice Trade Minister Park Jung-sung expressed regret over Canada's announcement of stronger steel safeguard measures, which reduce tariff rate quotas for steel imports from countries with free trade agreements, including Korea. The measures, effective December 26, 2025, may burden Korea's steel industry amid global oversupply and trade protectionism, potentially affecting Korean investments in Canada.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Fire Occurs at Nippon Steel's Hokkaido Plant; No One Injured</title><link>https://www.nippon.com/en/news/yjj2025120100215/</link><description>A fire occurred at Nippon Steel Corp.'s North Nippon Works in Muroran, Hokkaido, Japan, early Monday morning after an explosion at a hot-air stove. The fire was brought under control around 8 a.m., and no injuries were confirmed, though the company suspended blast furnace operations to ensure safety and is assessing potential damage to other facilities.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vice trade minister expresses regret over Canada's stronger steel safeguard plan</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-12-01/business/economy/Vice-trade-minister-expresses-regret-over-Canadas-stronger-steel-safeguard-plan/2466844</link><description>South Korea's Vice Trade Minister Park Jung-sung expressed concern over Canada's new steel safeguard measures announced this week, which will reduce tariff rate quotas for Korean steel imports starting December 26. The measures include a 25 percent tariff on steel derivative imports and represent additional trade protectionism affecting Korea's already struggling steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Arab Steel Summit 2025: MENA steel demand yet to reflect record project activity</title><link>https://metalexpert.com/en/latestissue?select=MK_WSNPLUS&amp;issue=3996</link><description>The Arab Steel Summit 2025 highlighted a disconnect between record project activity in the Middle East and North Africa region and actual steel demand levels. The report suggests ongoing challenges in converting project announcements into sustained demand for regional steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cut in December Rise, LME Copper Surged Significantly</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646957/Expectations-for-US-Fed-Interest-Rate-Cut-in-December-Rise-LME-Copper-Surged-Significantly-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper closed at $11,175.5/mt with a 2.25% gain, driven by expectations of a US Federal Reserve interest rate cut in December and concerns about tight copper supply following Chile's 7% YoY production decline in October. The US dollar came under pressure as markets priced in dovish Fed policy, providing support for copper prices amid long-term contract negotiations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper rose to 5.23 USD/Lbs on December 1, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices reached 5.23 USD/Lbs, up 0.89% from the previous day and 27.74% year-over-year, as US futures tested their highest level in four months amid supply concerns. Mine disruptions from major producers including Freeport-McMoRan's Grasberg mine in Indonesia and production slowdowns in Chile and Peru have driven sellers to raise prices, while markets price in an 85% probability of a 25 basis point Fed rate cut in December.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold prices rise modestly, silver and copper hit record highs</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/59218/gold-prices-rise-modestly-silver-and-copper-hit-record-highs</link><description>Copper reached record highs alongside silver as precious and industrial metals rallied on December 1, 2025, reflecting broader market strength driven by supply constraints and monetary policy expectations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper sets record high as top Chinese smelters plan to cut output</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3X701R:0-copper-sets-record-high-as-top-chinese-smelters-plan-to-cut-output/</link><description>Copper prices reached new record highs as major Chinese copper smelters agreed to cut production by over 10% in 2026 to address negative processing fees. Chile's Codelco, the world's largest copper producer, also raised copper premiums significantly, influencing market dynamics and contributing to the price surge.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cut in December Rise, LME Copper Surged Significantly Last Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646957/Expectations-for-US-Fed-Interest-Rate-Cut-in-December-Rise-LME-Copper-Surged-Significantly-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices rose sharply last Friday, closing at $11,175.5/mt, supported by expectations of a US Federal Reserve interest rate cut in December and a weaker US dollar. Chile's copper production fell 7% year-on-year in October, intensifying concerns about tight supply and supporting bullish copper prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Asia Market Quick Take – December 1, 2025</title><link>https://www.home.saxo/en-sg/content/articles/macro/asia-market-quick-take--december-1-2025-01122025</link><description>Copper prices surged to record levels amid concerns over global operational disruptions in mining and smelting. LME copper futures hit a record $11,210.50 per tonne, driven by supply tightness and bullish market sentiment following meetings of miners, smelters, and traders in Shanghai.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper hits record high as global supply concerns intensify</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/copper-hits-record-high-as-global-supply-concerns-intensify</link><description>Copper prices surged to a record high on the London Metal Exchange due to intensifying global supply concerns. The market is reacting to production cuts and supply disruptions, pushing prices to unprecedented levels.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Announces Leadership Appointments</title><link>https://www.ivanhoemines.com/news-stories/news-release/ivanhoe-mines-announces-leadership-appointments/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced leadership appointments as it prepares to issue copper production guidance for its Kamoa-Kakula project for 2026 and 2027. The company is advancing multiple copper projects in Southern Africa, including expansions and new developments aimed at increasing copper output.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Australian Gold and Copper Unveils High-Grade Drilling Results at Achilles Project</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/stocks/gold/australian-gold-and-copper-unveils-high-grade-drilling-results-at-achilles-project</link><description>Australian Gold and Copper reported high-grade drilling results at its Achilles copper project, indicating promising potential for copper resource expansion. The results support ongoing exploration and development efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Larvotto eyes Blockade copper mine opportunity</title><link>https://industryqld.com.au/larvotto-eyes-blockade-copper-mine-opportunity/</link><description>Larvotto Resources secured an option to acquire the Blockade copper mine, previously mined for high-grade copper in the 1980s. This move reflects Larvotto's strategy to expand its copper production capacity through acquisition and development of existing assets.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Monday Report - 01 December 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/12/01/the-monday-report-01-december-2025/</link><description>Nickel prices showed a slight increase, with the London Metal Exchange nickel price rising by 0.36% to $6.65 per pound. The report highlights a positive trend for base metals including nickel, amid expectations of a Federal Reserve rate cut in December and ongoing commodity market movements.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On December 1, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103648236/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 119,750 yuan per metric ton on December 1, up 250 yuan from the previous day, indicating a slight upward movement in refined nickel prices in the Chinese market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM High-Grade NPI] Price Trends Diverge, Outlook Bleak for Next Week</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103646634/SMM-High-Grade-NPI:-Price-Trends-Diverge-Outlook-Bleak-for-Next-Week</link><description>High-grade nickel pig iron (NPI) prices are expected to remain weak in the coming week, with refined nickel prices projected to decline again. The report reflects a cautious market sentiment amid ongoing price pressures in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>EcoPro completes Hungary cathode plant, leverages Indonesian nickel</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/ecopro-completes-hungary-cathode-plant-leverages-indonesian-nickel</link><description>South Korea's EcoPro has completed construction of its first European cathode plant in Debrecen, Hungary. The facility will leverage Indonesian nickel supplies for battery material production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Eagle Mine and Allonnia: Nickel Purification Breakthrough 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/eagle-mine-nickel-production-2025-d-solve-technology/</link><description>Eagle Mine and Allonnia have developed the D-Solve technology that reduces nickel impurities by 40% and increases concentrate grade by 18%. This biological innovation enhances nickel recovery from low-grade ores while reducing environmental impact, supporting sustainability and economic goals in nickel mining for clean energy applications.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali obtains ResponsibleSteel™ certification</title><link>https://www.responsiblesteel.org/issued-certificates-and-ongoing-audits</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali S.p.A has received the ResponsibleSteel™ Core Site Certification, reflecting its commitment to sustainability and responsible steel production. This certification aligns with the company's ongoing efforts to reduce environmental impact and promote transparency in its operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium climbs to $2,860/t, up 1.2%; alumina Platts slips 1.6%</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-climbs-to-2-860-t-up-1-2-alumina-platts-slips-1-6-116403</link><description>LME aluminium prices rose by 1.2% to $2,860 per tonne on December 1, driven by declines in stocks and cancelled warrants. Meanwhile, alumina Platts prices weakened by 1.6%, reflecting shifts in the alumina market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Dry Season Looms: Rising Power Costs to Drive December Aluminum Weighted Average Cost Higher</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103648904/dry-season-looms-rising-power-costs-to-drive-december-aluminum-weighted-average-cost-higher</link><description>China's domestic aluminum production costs are expected to rise in December 2025 due to increased electricity costs amid the dry season and rising prices for prebaked anodes and fluoride salt. Domestic operating aluminum capacity reached 44.23 million metric tons by the end of November 2025, with all operating capacity profitable in November despite cost increases. The average tax-inclusive full cost for aluminum production in December is forecasted to be around 16,100-16,500 yuan/mt.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Commentary: Don't Let China Capture Yet Another Strategic US Market in Secondary Aluminum Production</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/dont-let-china-capture-yet-anotehr-strategic-us-market-in-secondary-aluminum-production/</link><description>China, having dominated primary aluminum production through state investment and subsidized energy, is now targeting global aluminum recycling markets. The US risks losing its growing aluminum recycling sector to China, which has eased scrap import rules and increased buying power for used beverage cans. The article urges the US to strengthen scrap export controls and invest in recycling infrastructure to prevent repeating past losses in the aluminum industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>U.S. Risks Losing Aluminum Recycling to China, Warns Industry</title><link>https://www.indexbox.io/blog/us-aluminum-industry-warns-of-ceding-recycling-market-to-china/</link><description>The US aluminum industry warns that China is poised to dominate the global aluminum recycling market, following its previous dominance in primary aluminum production. China's 14th five-year plan includes controlling recycled aluminum, supported by relaxed scrap import rules and competitive pricing. The US faces challenges including low recycling rates and export controls, while Europe plans to restrict aluminum scrap exports to counter China's strategy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>S&amp;P Global Energy Celebrates Ten-year Anniversary of Platts Benchmark Steel Rebar and Scrap Assessments as Settlement Basis for London Metals Exchange</title><link>https://press.spglobal.com/2025-12-01-S-P-Global-Energy-Celebrates-Ten-year-Anniversary-of-Platts-Benchmark-Steel-Rebar-and-Scrap-Assessments-as-Settlement-Basis-for-London-Metals-Exchange</link><description>S&amp;P Global Energy commemorated the 10-year anniversary of Platts steel scrap and rebar price benchmarks becoming settlement references for London Metals Exchange futures contracts. The benchmarks track the landed value of steel scrap feedstock in Turkey and the export value of finished steel rebar products, with record trading volumes observed in 2024.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Thyssenkrupp to reduce steel production, cut or outsource 11,000 jobs</title><link>https://economictimes.com/us/business/thyssenkrupp-to-reduce-steel-production-cut-or-outsource-11000-jobs/articleshow/125697230.cms</link><description>German steel producer Thyssenkrupp announced it would cut or outsource approximately 11,000 jobs and reduce steel production capacity. This restructuring reflects the company's strategic shift in response to market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper price begins to rise– Forecast today – 1-12-2025</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/copper-analysis/copper-price-begins-to-rise%E2%80%93-forecast-today-%E2%80%93-1-12-2025-123070</link><description>Copper prices are rising with a bullish trend confirmed after surpassing $5.2000, supported by stochastic positivity and forming extra support at $4.9500. The forecast targets $5.3200 and potentially $5.5000, with the expected trading range between $5.0600 and $5.3200.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 0.65% Higher at $5.2190 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512015836/comex-copper-settles-065-higher-at-52190-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper settled at $5.2190, up 0.65%, marking its highest settlement since late October and continuing a four-session winning streak. Prices remain up over 30% from their 2025 low but are still below the July record high.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Hits Four-Month High on Tight Supply</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/506270</link><description>Copper futures rose above $5.2 per pound, reaching a four-month high due to tight supply, lower output in Chile, planned Chinese smelter cuts, and a weaker dollar. Prices have increased around 13% on the LME since August amid ongoing shortages.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese smelters cut production, copper prices hit new record</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/59228/chinese-smelters-cut-production-copper-prices-hit-new-record</link><description>LME three-month benchmark copper hit a record at $11,294.5 per tonne, driven by Chinese smelter production cuts and strong global demand. Prices remain elevated amid ongoing supply constraints.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Announces Africa's Largest and Greenest Copper Smelter Has Commenced Heat-Up</title><link>https://www.ivanhoemines.com/news-stories/news-release/ivanhoe-mines-announces-africas-largest-and-greenest-copper-smelter-has-commenced-heat-up/</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines has started the heat-up process for Africa's largest and greenest copper smelter at Kamoa-Kakula, with the first feed of concentrate expected by year-end. The company will issue 2026 and 2027 copper production guidance this week, signaling a major expansion in capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Chinese Smelters Cut Production, Copper Prices Hit New Record</title><link>https://www.idnfinancials.com/news/59228/chinese-smelters-cut-production-copper-prices-hit-new-record</link><description>Major Chinese smelters have agreed to cut copper production in 2026, contributing to copper prices hitting a new record. The production cuts, combined with strong global demand, are tightening supply and pushing prices higher.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Renforth Collaborates with CTRI to assess sustainability opportunities at Victoria nickel polymetallic open pit deposit</title><link>https://www.thenewswire.com/press-releases/1AJ6FPYW2-renforth-collaborates-with-ctri-to-assess-sustainability-opportunities-at-victoria-nickel-polymetallic-open-pit-deposit.html</link><description>Renforth is partnering with CTRI to investigate green extraction technologies at the Victoria nickel project in Ontario, including green heap leaching with CO2 sequestration, organic leaching alternatives, and bioleaching processes. The company is also exploring nickel bioaccumulating plants as exploration tools and investigating carbonation of ultramafics for environmental and economic benefits.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The New Gold Rush: Battery Metals Powering the Green Revolution</title><link>http://markets.chroniclejournal.com/chroniclejournal/article/marketminute-2025-12-1-the-new-gold-rush-battery-metals-powering-the-green-revolution</link><description>The article examines the surging demand for battery metals including nickel, driven by electric vehicle expansion and renewable energy storage needs. It highlights how nickel producers are positioning themselves to supply high-purity nickel for EV batteries as part of the global energy transition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada's Algoma Steel to Cut 1,000 Jobs Amid US Tariffs</title><link>https://www.ttnews.com/articles/canada-algoma-steel-layoffs</link><description>Canadian steelmaker Algoma Steel Group Inc. announced it will lay off 1,000 workers and close its blast furnace and coke operations in Sault Ste. Marie due to US tariffs. The company reported a 13 percent sales drop and C$89.7 million in third quarter tariff costs, with the US steel market becoming largely closed to Canadian producers. Algoma plans to transition fully to electric-arc furnace production by early 2026, with layoffs taking effect on March 23.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>South32 completes sale of nickel refinery to CoreX Holding</title><link>https://global.morningstar.com/en-gb/news/alliance-news/1764588445593270500/in-brief-south32-completes-sale-of-nickel-refinery-to-corex-holding</link><description>South32 has completed the sale of its nickel refinery to CoreX Holding, marking a significant transaction in the nickel processing sector. The sale aligns with South32's strategic portfolio adjustments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM: Domestic Aluminum Billet Inventory in Two Regions Stays Flat at 83,500 mt on Dec 2, 2025</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103649257/SMM:-Domestic-Aluminum-Billet-Inventory-in-Two-Regions-Stays-Flat-at-83500-mt-on-Dec-2-2025</link><description>China's aluminum billet inventory in two key domestic regions remained stable at 83,500 metric tons as of December 2. The average full cost for aluminum production in China increased by 1.1% month-over-month in November 2025, reflecting cost pressures in the industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Futures Gain Amid Supply Constraints and Production Caps</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,892.55 per ton on December 1, 2025, driven by supply constraints including China's cap on aluminum production at 45 million tons annually and setbacks in new smelter projects in Indonesia due to energy costs and regulatory issues. Additional supply pressures come from disruptions such as equipment failure at Iceland’s Grundartangi smelter and Alcoa's planned closure of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nippon Steel to shortlist two or three states for new U.S. plant</title><link>https://www.japantimes.co.jp/business/2025/12/02/companies/nippon-steel-interview-us-plant/</link><description>Japan's largest steel producer Nippon Steel will shortlist two or three U.S. states for construction of a major new plant and make a final decision on its location in early 2027. The plant, to be run by U.S. Steel subsidiary, will have 3 million tons of annual capacity and require stable, competitively-priced power supply. The decision on shortlisted states is expected around the end of summer 2026.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>LME Three-Month Copper Hits Record High, SHFE Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103649216/LME-Three-Month-Copper-Hits-Record-High-SHFE-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME three-month copper hit a record high of $11,334/mt, closing at $11,232.5/mt, driven by tight supply, mine production cuts, and strong energy transition demand. The weakening US dollar also supported prices, though downstream demand was dampened by the surge.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper eases from peak as market keeps focus on supply risks</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3X802F:0-copper-eases-from-peak-as-market-keeps-focus-on-supply-risks/</link><description>Copper prices eased slightly from record highs as investors remain focused on supply risks, including planned Chinese smelter output cuts and Codelco's premium hikes. The market expects tight refined copper supply, with the US dollar weakening amid expectations of a Fed rate cut.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco offers US clients copper at record premiums above $500 per ton over LME prices</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/codelco-offers-us-clients-copper-at-record-premiums-above-500-per-ton-over-lme-prices/</link><description>Chile's Codelco is offering US clients copper at record premiums above $500 per ton over LME prices, reflecting tight supply and strong demand. This move highlights ongoing concerns about global copper availability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME Three-Month Copper Hits Record High, SHFE Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103649216/LME-Three-Month-Copper-Hits-Record-High-SHFE-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices reached a record high of $11,334/mt overnight, closing at $11,232.5/mt, driven by tight supply, mine production cuts, and strong demand from the global energy transition. Chinese copper inventories dropped by 14,500 mt week-on-week, and secondary copper prices also rose significantly.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to a four-month high above $5.2 per pound, supported by supply constraints from mine disruptions in Chile, Indonesia, and Peru, as well as planned cuts by Chinese smelters. The price increase reflects ongoing concerns about global copper supply and strong demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Larvotto eyes Mt Isa copper revival</title><link>https://www.australianresourcesandinvestment.com.au/2025/12/02/larvotto-eyes-mt-isa-copper-revival/</link><description>Larvotto Resources is advancing its copper ambitions at Mt Isa by acquiring the historic Blockade mine and launching a new drilling program. The company aims to unlock near-term copper production and transform the project into a credible development opportunity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Two critical commodities: 12 Days of Christmas</title><link>https://mining.com.au/two-critical-commodities-12-days-of-christmas/</link><description>Nickel prices have stabilized after a turbulent 2025 marked by supply disruptions from Indonesia and global mine shutdowns. Nickel futures hovered around US$14,676 per tonne recently, with consumption rising steadily, driven mainly by stainless steel demand linked to global GDP growth, especially in China. LME nickel stockpiles have increased through 2025, indicating a market regaining composure after earlier price declines.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>On December 2, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was ...</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103650436/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price on December 2 ranged between 117,200 and 122,600 yuan per metric ton, with an average price of 119,900 yuan/mt, showing a slight increase of 150 yuan/mt from the previous day. This reflects a minor upward movement in nickel prices in the Chinese market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices fluctuated rangebound on December 2 amid US manufacturing data</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103650437/</link><description>Nickel prices remained rangebound on December 2, influenced by the US November ISM Manufacturing PMI of 48.2, which indicated a contraction in manufacturing activity. LME nickel prices showed limited movement amid this economic data, reflecting cautious market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME Nickel Official Prices</title><link>https://www.lme.com/en/metals/non-ferrous/lme-nickel</link><description>The official LME nickel prices on December 2, 2025, were around US$14,655 to US$14,660 per tonne, consistent with recent price stability observed in the nickel market. This price level aligns with the broader trend of nickel prices hovering near US$15,000 per tonne throughout 2025.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Edison Energia, Prysmian in 150MW Italy Solar PV PPA</title><link>https://www.pv-tech.org/edison-energia-prysmian-in-150mw-italy-solar-pv-ppa/</link><description>Italian energy company Edison Energia has signed a multi-year power purchase agreement with Prysmian to supply around 25% of Prysmian's annual electricity consumption in Italy from a 150MWp solar PV plant in Viterbo province. The deal represents Prysmian's commitment to securing long-term renewable energy supply and stable energy costs as part of its sourcing strategy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian has been awarded a tender by Terna and STEG to construct a submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia under the Elmed Project, with a potential contract value of around €460 million. The power line will run between Sicily and Tunisia's Cap Bon peninsula at depths up to 800 meters, creating an energy bridge between Europe and Africa.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Market Navigates Volatility as China's Output Concerns Meet Mixed Industrial Demand</title><link>https://www.financialcontent.com/article/marketminute-2025-12-2-aluminum-market-navigates-volatility-as-chinas-output-concerns-meet-mixed-industrial-demand</link><description>Global aluminum prices are experiencing significant volatility due to concerns about China's production capacity and mixed signals from global industrial demand. Despite a recent price drop to $2,862.40 per tonne, supply constraints from China support prices, while forecasts suggest potential dips early in 2026 but a generally firm-to-rising price environment.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price falls to one-month low in wider commodity slump</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-falls-to-one-month-low-in-wider-commodity-slump/</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped to a one-month low of $2,526 per ton on the London Metal Exchange amid a broader commodity slump and anticipation of the Federal Reserve's interest rate decision. Despite short-term declines, longer-term trends remain bullish due to expected production slowdowns in China and rising input costs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME cash aluminium slips 0.03% to $2,858/t as futures extend gains</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-cash-aluminium-slips-0-03-to-2-858-t-as-futures-extend-gains-116418</link><description>The London Metal Exchange cash aluminum price slightly declined by 0.03% to $2,858 per tonne, while futures prices extended gains. This minor slip reflects ongoing market fluctuations amid broader base metals volatility.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum prices surged to their highest level since May 2022</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103602122/Aluminum-Prices-Soar-to-17-Month-High-on-Base-Metals-Rally-Eased-US-China-Trade-Tensions</link><description>Aluminum prices rose 0.9% to $2,909.50 per ton on the London Metal Exchange, marking the highest level since May 2022. The rally is supported by a base metals market upswing and eased US-China trade tensions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Market Navigates Volatility as China's Output Concerns Meet Mixed Industrial Demand</title><link>https://www.financialcontent.com/article/marketminute-2025-12-2-aluminum-market-navigates-volatility-as-chinas-output-concerns-meet-mixed-industrial-demand</link><description>China's aluminum production is nearing its annual capacity cap of 45 million tons, limiting growth to about 2% in 2025 and 0.7% in 2026. This constraint, combined with global environmental regulations and supply chain challenges such as potential sanctions on Russian aluminum, is creating a supply squeeze amid rising demand from green energy sectors like electric vehicles and solar energy.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Novelis Wins German Ecodesign Award for Recycled Aluminium Automotive Sheet</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/novelis-wins-german-ecodesign-award-for-recycled-aluminium-automotive-sheet-302630683.html</link><description>Novelis received the German Ecodesign Award for its innovative aluminum alloy made with 100% recycled end-of-life automotive scrap. The alloy, Novelis Advanz™ 6F – e170RC, contains at least 75% recycled content and is commercially available for exterior automotive applications. This achievement demonstrates the feasibility of true car-to-car aluminum recycling, significantly reducing CO2 emissions and advancing circular economy goals in the automotive industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Market Navigates Volatility as China's Output Concerns Meet Mixed Industrial Demand</title><link>https://www.financialcontent.com/article/marketminute-2025-12-2-aluminum-market-navigates-volatility-as-chinas-output-concerns-meet-mixed-industrial-demand</link><description>The aluminum industry is experiencing volatility driven by China's production limits and mixed demand signals. A key trend is the growing adoption of green aluminum production, emphasizing renewable energy sources and advanced recycling technologies. Certification schemes like the Aluminium Stewardship Initiative are pushing the industry toward lower carbon footprints, while innovation, supply chain resilience, and regionalization are becoming critical for sustainable growth.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel prices hit five-year low; weak trend likely to persist in near term</title><link>https://economictimes.com/industry/indl-goods/svs/steel/steel-prices-hit-five-year-low-weak-trend-likely-to-persist-in-near-term-bigmint/articleshow/124776337.cms</link><description>Domestic steel prices in India have fallen to a five-year low amid rising imports and weak demand. High inventories and seasonal weakness are expected to keep prices subdued in the near term, with potential production cuts if prices correct further. The government is discussing import issues to support domestic steel competitiveness.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Final Thoughts - Steel Market Update</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/12/02/final-thoughts-1896/</link><description>Steel price hikes that began in November are continuing into December, with US producers like Nucor and Canadian mills raising prices due to low imports, lower inventories, and longer lead times. However, the price spread between hot-rolled and galvanized steel remains narrow, limiting converter margins.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>American steel producers are gradually raising prices for rolled products</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/american-steel-producers-are-gradually-raising-prices-for-rolled-products/</link><description>US steel producers have increased prices for rolled steel products, with #4 rebar prices rising to $870-910 per short ton. This reflects ongoing price increases in the US market amid supply constraints and demand dynamics.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Mitsui to Invest in EVERSTEEL – Developer and Supplier of AI-based Steel Scrap Analysis Systems</title><link>https://www.mitsui.com/jp/en/topics/2025/1252509_14859.html</link><description>Mitsui is investing in EVERSTEEL to advance AI-based steel scrap analysis systems, supporting decarbonization by improving scrap quality control and streamlining feedstock procurement. The collaboration aims to enhance the competitiveness and sustainability of the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 1.11% Lower at $5.1610 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202512026224/comex-copper-settles-111-lower-at-51610-data-talk</link><description>Front month Comex copper for December delivery fell 1.11% to $5.1610 per pound, snapping a four-session winning streak. Despite the decline, copper remains up nearly 30% year-to-date, reflecting strong gains since its 52-week low earlier in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices hit new record high</title><link>https://www.brusselstimes.com/business/1863278/copper-prices-hit-new-record-high</link><description>Copper prices reached a new record high driven by a tense market with supply chain challenges and uncertainty over US tariffs. Prices rose on London and New York futures markets amid growing demand and large shipments to the US, as traders await clarity on import duties.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Amerigo's Minera Valle Central Receives Prestigious 2025 Circular Awards in Chile</title><link>https://investingnews.com/amerigo-s-minera-valle-central-receives-prestigious-2025-circular-awards-in-chile/</link><description>Amerigo Resources' Minera Valle Central (MVC) received a 2025 Circular Award for its Energy and Environmental Liabilities Transformation project, which recovers copper and molybdenum from tailings while improving energy efficiency. The project converts environmental liabilities into valuable assets by using tailings as production input, reducing energy consumption, emissions, and natural resource use through state-of-the-art technology and circular economy principles.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Descent: A Stronger Dollar and Faltering Demand Drag Down the Red Metal</title><link>http://markets.chroniclejournal.com/chroniclejournal/article/marketminute-2025-12-2-coppers-descent-a-stronger-dollar-and-faltering-demand-drag-down-the-red-metal</link><description>The article discusses copper market challenges as of December 2, 2025, including price pressures from a stronger dollar and faltering demand, while highlighting opportunities in renewable energy infrastructure and the need for strategic adaptations. It emphasizes that copper mining companies must accelerate exploration and embrace new extraction technologies alongside sustainable practices, while consumers should invest in recycling technologies and supply chain optimization.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fluctuated rangebound amid macro pressures</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103650444</link><description>Nickel prices showed short-term fluctuations with lingering long-term pressure. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract settled slightly up at around 117,790 yuan/mt, with spot prices averaging 119,900 yuan/mt. Market sentiment is influenced by a weaker US manufacturing PMI and expectations of a US Fed interest rate cut in December.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia's Nickel Supply &amp; The Global Price Slump - What the Market Sell-Off Signals for Investors</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/indonesias-nickel-supply-the-global-price-slump-what-the-market-sell-off-signals-for-investors</link><description>Nickel prices have fallen near a four-year low around $14,550 per tonne due to oversupply from Indonesia's refinery expansion, despite announced quota cuts. LME inventories surged by 90,000 tonnes in 2025, reinforcing market skepticism about effective supply tightening. While electric vehicle demand supports long-term nickel use, current oversupply dominates near-term price weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price rebounds above $14,900 on weak US dollar expectations</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-price-rebounds-above-14900-on-weak-us-dollar-expectations/158101</link><description>Nickel prices on the London Metal Exchange closed at $14,928 per ton, rising by $99 and continuing a weekly increase after three months of declines. The rebound is attributed to expectations of a weaker US dollar, although supply concerns remain.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Ironic Metals secures funding to decarbonise iron and nickel production</title><link>https://www.engineerlive.com/content/ironic-metals-secures-funding-decarbonise-iron-and-nickel-production</link><description>Ironic Metals has secured funding to advance decarbonization efforts in iron and nickel production. The company is working on technologies to reduce carbon emissions in the production of these critical metals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Lifts 2025 Outlook After Q3 Beat on Strong Transmission Growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance after reporting third-quarter revenue of €5.03 billion, exceeding expectations due to strong growth in Renewable Transmission and Power Grids segments. The company highlighted a stable high-voltage backlog of about €16 billion and noted that copper tariffs could benefit them more in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Raises Annual Targets After Record Q3 Performance</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/prysmian-raises-annual-targets-after-record-q3-performance/</link><description>Following a historically strong third quarter, Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance. The company’s growth is supported by increased demand in transmission and power grids, with ongoing investments in copper cable production and electrification projects.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices fell slightly on December 2, 2025, but futures are up over 10% for the year due to supply decreases. China's production cap of 45 million tons and setbacks in new smelter projects in Indonesia, along with disruptions like equipment failure at Iceland’s Grundartangi smelter, are tightening supply. Alcoa announced closure of its Kwinana alumina refinery due to deteriorating ore grades.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever Partner to Launch the First Use of ELYSIS Carbon-Free Smelting Technology in Consumer Personal and Home Care Packaging</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251105083984/en/Alcoa-Ball-and-Unilever-Partner-to-Launch-the-First-Use-of-ELYSIS-Carbon-Free-Smelting-Technology-in-Consumer-Personal-and-Home-Care-Packaging</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever have collaborated to introduce aluminum produced using ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology in consumer packaging. This technology eliminates direct greenhouse gas emissions by generating oxygen instead of CO2 during smelting. The new aerosol can combines 50% ELYSIS primary aluminum with 50% recycled content, representing one of the lowest-carbon packaging solutions available and showcasing cross-industry collaboration for sustainability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>December Steel Price Outlook: Macro &amp; Fundamental Drivers</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103643800/december-steel-price-outlook-macrofundamental-drivers-smm-analysis/</link><description>Steel prices have been volatile recently with slight declines in hot metal production but remain high. Inventory is expected to continue declining in December, though destocking pace for sheets and plates will be slow. Macro factors such as domestic policy meetings may support limited price increases despite persistent destocking pressure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron ore edges up as steel price optimism outweighs softer hot metal output</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3X909Y:0-iron-ore-edges-up-as-steel-price-optimism-outweighs-softer-hot-metal-output/</link><description>Iron ore futures rose slightly driven by optimism over stronger steel prices despite softer hot metal output. Chinese steel prices are expected to increase in December due to improved macroeconomic conditions and recovering market fundamentals. Environmental inspections are reducing pig iron production, pressuring raw materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Japan's Steel Sector Needs to Use All Low-Carbon Pathways to Reach Emissions Goal</title><link>https://about.bnef.com/insights/clean-energy/japans-steel-sector-needs-to-use-all-low-carbon-pathways-to-reach-emissions-goal-report/</link><description>Japan's steel sector, responsible for about 13 percent of the country's emissions, must cut emissions from coal-based production to achieve its 2050 net zero goal. Scrap-based electric arc furnaces powered by renewable energy can produce steel at around $720 per ton by 2030, only 18 percent costlier than traditional blast furnace methods but with zero emissions. Japan could lower emissions by maximizing production at existing scrap-EAFs and implementing policies to redirect exported scrap volumes to domestic steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>National hub to cut steel production emissions</title><link>https://www.trailermag.com.au/national-hub-to-cut-steel-production-emissions/</link><description>A national initiative to make steel production greener and more sustainable has launched at Monash University, bringing together researchers and industry partners to develop smarter, low-emission steelmaking processes. The ARC Research Hub for Smart Process Design and Control will use simulation, AI, and industrial testing to transform steelmaking and train future engineers for a low-emission industrial economy.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Japan's Steel Sector Needs to Use All Low-Carbon Pathways to Reach Emissions Goal</title><link>https://about.bnef.com/insights/clean-energy/japans-steel-sector-needs-to-use-all-low-carbon-pathways-to-reach-emissions-goal-report/</link><description>Japan's steel industry must leverage all available low-carbon pathways—including scrap-based electric arc furnaces, hydrogen, and carbon capture—to meet its 2050 net-zero target. BloombergNEF's report highlights that scrap-EAF powered by renewables could be cost-competitive by 2030, while hydrogen and CCS remain more expensive until 2050.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Breakthrough Technology Conference 2025</title><link>https://worldsteel.org/climate-action/breakthrough-technology/</link><description>The second Breakthrough Technology Conference is underway in Singapore, focusing on technologies that can significantly reduce CO2 emissions from steelmaking, such as hydrogen reduction, carbon capture, and reuse. The event highlights the urgency for innovation as the steel industry works to meet global climate goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises to 4-Month High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures rose above $5.2 per pound, reaching their highest level in four months due to tight supply and elevated premiums. Supply constraints include lower output in Chile, planned cuts by Chinese smelters, and a weaker dollar, with markets anticipating a possible Federal Reserve rate cut.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Kamoa-Kakula Mine Copper Smelter to Begin Feeding LME; Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103651428/Kamoa-Kakula-Mine-Copper-Smelter-to-Begin-Feeding-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated significantly, opening at $11,205.5/mt and closing lower at $11,145/mt, down 0.78%. Spot premiums in Shanghai increased, while imported copper prices showed slight increases, reflecting mixed market dynamics amid ongoing supply and demand adjustments.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Retreat Amid China Demand Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/03/copper-prices-retreat-amid-china-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices edged down from recent record highs due to signs of softer demand from China, the world's largest copper consumer. Reduced seasonal demand from Chinese fabricators and a drop in the Yangshan copper premium suggest increased availability of Chinese metal for export, potentially easing global supply tightness.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper pulls back from peak; market focus on upcoming Fed rate decision</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L1N3X9033:0-copper-pulls-back-from-peak-market-focus-on-upcoming-fed-rate-decision/</link><description>Copper prices consolidated after pulling back from a record high as markets focused on the upcoming US Federal Reserve interest rate decision. Despite a slight retreat, copper remains near peak levels supported by supply concerns and expectations of a Fed rate cut in December.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper retreats from peak on firmer dollar</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40395487</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange fell 0.4% to $11,207 per metric ton after hitting a recent peak, pressured by a firmer US dollar. The price retreat reflects profit-taking amid ongoing market volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Kamoa-Kakula Mine Copper Smelter to Begin Feeding</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103651428/Kamoa-Kakula-Mine-Copper-Smelter-to-Begin-Feeding-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>The 500,000 mt/year Phase 1 copper smelter at the Kamoa-Kakula mine officially started production on November 21, 2025, and is expected to begin feeding the first batch of copper concentrates before the end of the year. LME copper closed at $11,145/mt, down 0.78%, with the market experiencing considerable fluctuations throughout the trading session.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Retreat Amid China Demand Concerns</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/12/03/copper-prices-retreat-amid-china-demand-concerns/</link><description>Copper prices have edged down from recent record highs as softer demand from China, the world's largest copper consumer, is expected to increase availability of Chinese metal for export and ease global supply pressures. The Yangshan copper premium has fallen to its lowest level since July, signaling reduced appetite for imported metal within the Chinese market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Russia’s Nornickel, one of the world’s largest nickel producers, maintained its 2025 nickel production outlook at 196,000-204,000 metric tons. Nickel production rose 18% in Q3 2025 due to higher volumes of processed raw materials, despite earlier shipment cuts caused by seasonal flooding and equipment replacement challenges.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>United Tractors sets up nickel-processing subsidiary</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/united-tractors-sets-up-nickel-processing-subsidiary</link><description>PT United Tractors Tbk has established a new nickel-focused subsidiary, PT Nusantara Industri Nikel Lestari (NINL), as part of its diversification into nickel processing and services. The subsidiary was approved on December 2, 2025, and will operate in non-ferrous metal manufacturing and trading.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale to hit upper end of 2025 output target, cuts 2026 estimate</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5105914-vale-to-hit-upper-end-of-2025-output-target-cuts-2026-estimate</link><description>Vale expects to reach the upper end of its 2025 nickel output target, alongside copper production targets. However, the company has revised down its production estimates for 2026. The 2025 nickel output target is approximately 175 million tonnes.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mining companies make stunning discovery that could be crucial for sustainable nickel extraction</title><link>https://www.thecooldown.com/green-tech/nickel-mining-improvements-sustainable-practices/</link><description>Allonia and Lundin Mining are testing D-Solve technology at Eagle Mine in Michigan, which uses microbes to selectively dissolve unwanted minerals and increase nickel purity by reducing magnesium impurities by 40% while increasing nickel grade by 18%. This breakthrough could transform mineral mining by decreasing costs and reducing environmental impact while meeting growing global nickel demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal, Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://www.pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, gaining ownership of pre-insulated pipeline systems and anti-corrosion coatings in Europe. The acquired business was rebranded as Tenaris Coating Italy, enhancing Tenaris's offshore market offerings and enabling coating application at multiple global facilities.</description><category>general</category></item></channel></rss>