<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 05:17:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Investors Amass Record Bull Bets on Aluminium Supply Shortage</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/fund-positioning-market-transformation-2025/</link><description>Record investment surges in aluminum reflect structural supply shortages amplified by US tariffs and EU sanctions on Russian aluminum. The US Midwest premium hit $1,938 per ton, 67% above the LME price, indicating tight supply and depleted inventories ahead of tariff hikes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,856.95 per tonne on November 7, 2025, supported by demand in electrification sectors and supply disruptions including a potline suspension at Iceland's Grundartangi smelter and Alcoa's shutdown of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia. China maintains a production cap of 45 million tons annually, limiting supply growth amid rising energy costs and regulatory risks.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global bauxite upswing triggers exports, expansions and collaborations across the aluminium ecosystem</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/global-bauxite-upswing-triggers-new-expansions-and-collaborations-across-the-aluminium-ecosystem-heres-whats-unfolding-116130</link><description>The global increase in bauxite demand is driving new exports, expansions, and collaborations within the aluminum industry. This upswing is fostering advancements in aluminum casthouse technology and supporting sustainable growth across the aluminum ecosystem worldwide.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,029 CNY/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.33% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have declined 2.13%, and are down 6.22% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts suggest steel will trade at 3,039.40 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,904.76 in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Hits 7-week Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices fell to 15,020 USD/ton on November 7, 2025, marking the lowest level since September and a 2.40% decline over the past month. The market is expected to trade at 14,887.32 USD/ton by the end of the quarter, with further declines projected over the next 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Market Shows Recovery Signs Amid Policy Support &amp; Trade Tensions</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-market-shows-recovery-signs-amid-policy-support-trade-tensions</link><description>Nickel prices have moved into the upper half of the $15,000-$15,800 per ton range, suggesting a potential recovery as battery supply chains may be entering a restocking cycle. Policy support and trade tensions, including US tariffs on Chinese graphite and deals with Indonesia, are influencing the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Live Nickel Price</title><link>https://www.kitco.com/price/base-metals/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices are currently at 15,089.99 USD/ton, down slightly from the previous day. The market remains volatile, with prices fluctuating within a narrow range.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME Nickel Official Prices</title><link>https://www.lme.com/en/metals/non-ferrous/lme-nickel</link><description>The official LME nickel price for November 9, 2025, is 14,830.00 USD/ton (bid) and 14,840.00 USD/ton (offer), reflecting a continued downward trend in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC steel prices traded flat at 847 USD/T on November 7, 2025, but have risen 4.18% over the past month and 19.80% year-on-year. Forecasts suggest prices will reach 858.87 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 930.60 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals Report (11.09.2025): Financing Critical Minerals 2.0 Through Government Equity and Private Capital</title><link>https://investornews.com/critical-minerals-rare-earths/critical-minerals-report-11-09-2025-financing-critical-minerals-2-0-through-government-equity-and-private-capital/</link><description>Copper prices have reached a record $11,200 per tonne, reflecting tight supply conditions driven by demand from electric vehicles and power grids. The report highlights supply chain concerns, including Glencore's potential closure of its Horne copper smelter in Quebec, Canada's largest copper metal operation, due to environmental upgrade requirements.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices rose to $2,856.95/t on November 7, up 0.45% from the previous day. The price has increased 3.55% over the past month and is up 8.63% year-on-year. Futures are expected to trade at $2,879.83/t by the end of the quarter.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Hits 627,000 mt on Nov 10, Up 5,000 mt WoW from Last Thu</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611375/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Hits-627000-mt-on-Nov-10-Up-5000-mt-WoW-from-Last-Thu</link><description>Domestic aluminum ingot social inventory in China reached 627,000 mt on November 10, up 5,000 mt week-on-week. LME aluminum is projected to trade between $2,830-$2,930/mt in the coming week.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever pioneer carbon-free aluminum manufacturing for consumer packaging</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-pioneer-carbon-free-aluminum-manufacturing-for-consumer-packaging/</link><description>Alcoa, in partnership with Ball Corporation and Unilever, announced the first use of ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology for consumer packaging, eliminating direct greenhouse gas emissions by producing oxygen instead of CO2. This initiative represents a significant step toward low-carbon aluminum products and highlights cross-sector collaboration ahead of COP30 climate discussions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Hits 627,000 mt on Nov 10, Up 5,000 mt WoW from Last Thu</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611375/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Hits-627000-mt-on-Nov-10-Up-5000-mt-WoW-from-Last-Thu</link><description>Social inventory of domestic aluminum ingots in China reached 627,000 metric tons as of November 10, 2025, increasing by 5,000 metric tons week-over-week. Market expectations for SHFE aluminum prices range between 21,300-21,900 yuan/mt, while LME aluminum is projected between $2,830-$2,930/mt next week.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Asian steel market seen under pressure in Q4 amid weak demand, trade barriers</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/asian-steel-market-seen-under-pressure-in-q4-amid-weak-demand-trade-barriers/</link><description>The Asian steel market is under pressure in Q4 2025 due to weak demand and rising trade barriers, according to a recent S&amp;P Global Commodity Insights report.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>WA to source green steel from local manufacturers for gov't projects</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/wa-to-source-green-steel-from-local-manufacturers-for-govt-projects/</link><description>The Western Australian Government has launched an initiative to use locally made green steel in major government projects, supporting job creation and local manufacturing. The program encourages the use of sustainable building materials and introduces a new procurement approach favoring local green steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Steel?</title><link>https://fremantleshippingnews.com.au/2025/11/10/green-steel/</link><description>Fortescue has initiated a green iron pilot project at Christmas Creek in the Pilbara, with first production scheduled for 2025. This marks a significant step in Australia's efforts to develop green steel production capacity.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Participation in the Development of Critical Minerals and Rare Earths Feedstock Production Project in Australia</title><link>https://www.marubeni.com/en/news/2025/info/00037.html</link><description>Marubeni Corporation announced its participation in a critical minerals and rare earths feedstock production project in Australia, supporting the development of essential materials for advanced manufacturing, including steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>WA to source green steel from local manufacturers for gov't projects</title><link>https://www.australianmanufacturing.com.au/wa-to-source-green-steel-from-local-manufacturers-for-govt-projects/</link><description>The Western Australian Government announced an initiative to prioritize locally made green steel for major government infrastructure projects, supporting the state's manufacturing sector and sustainability goals. The program includes a new procurement approach favoring green steel and aims to create jobs while advancing decarbonization in construction materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Consumer Confidence Falls to a Low Level, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611345/US-Consumer-Confidence-Falls-to-a-Low-Level-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper futures opened at $10,743.5/mt on Friday night, fluctuated during the session, and closed slightly higher at $10,695/mt with a 0.07% increase. The SHFE copper contract closed marginally lower at 85,920 yuan/mt. Vedanta Resources announced the establishment of CopperTech Metals Inc. in the US to meet copper resource security needs amid rising demand driven by data centers, power grids, and defense technology.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price holds loss as equity rout, strong dollar weigh on metals</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-holds-loss-as-equity-rout-strong-dollar-weigh-on-metals/</link><description>Copper prices traded near $10,650 per ton on the LME after a four-day losing streak, pressured by a stronger US dollar and global equity market declines. The recent rally cooled following a record high last month amid optimism over a US-China trade deal and supply disruptions. Chinese buyers were seen purchasing dips, and a key African port for copper trade reopened, easing supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminium rises with copper as US govt shutdown nears end</title><link>http://www.theedgemarkets.com/node/778947</link><description>Copper prices rose alongside aluminium on November 10, boosted by improving risk appetite as the US government shutdown neared resolution. This positive market sentiment contributed to gains in base metals including copper.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Rise Amid Uncertainty Over U.S. Tariffs</title><link>https://www.gurufocus.com/news/3197726/copper-prices-rise-amid-uncertainty-over-us-tariffs</link><description>Copper prices have risen amid uncertainty over potential changes to U.S. tariffs, with indications from the U.S. President about reconsidering copper tariffs. This could tighten global copper supply outside the United States, influencing market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US Consumer Confidence Falls to a Low Level, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103611345/US-Consumer-Confidence-Falls-to-a-Low-Level-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper prices fluctuated and closed lower on Friday, ending at $10,695/mt with a 0.07% increase, while SHFE copper also saw a slight decline. Trading volumes and open interest remained robust, reflecting ongoing market activity. The meeting also noted Vedanta's spin-off of Konkola Copper Mines into US-based CopperTech Metals Inc.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Critical Minerals List: 2025 Strategic Addition</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/critical-minerals-strategic-value-copper-demand-2025/</link><description>The US officially added copper to its critical minerals list in November 2025, highlighting its strategic importance. The article discusses global copper production concentration, with Chile leading, and notes China's dominance in refining capacity, which creates supply chain vulnerabilities. Infrastructure and workforce limitations in the US are also highlighted.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Bullish Outlook: China's Industrial Resilience and Global Supply Constraints Drive Growth</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/copper-bullish-outlook-china-industrial-resilience-global-supply-constraints-drive-growth-2511/</link><description>China's industrial output surged in Q3 2025, boosting copper demand, especially from high-tech manufacturing and NEV production. The article forecasts a 150,000 metric ton deficit in 2026 and a 40% rise in global demand by 2040, underscoring the need for supply-side solutions. Copper's role in decarbonization and digitalization is emphasized.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper and Potassic alteration above main Southern Porphyry Target at Llahuin</title><link>https://www.shmining.com.au/2025/11/copper-and-potassic-alteration-above-main-southern-porphyry-target-at-llahuin/</link><description>Exploration drilling at the Llahuin project has advanced to 1,198.9m downhole, with copper and potassic alteration identified above the main Southern Porphyry Target. The results indicate potential for further copper discoveries in the region.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>USGS officially adds copper, silver to critical minerals list</title><link>https://www.mining.com/us-officially-adds-copper-silver-to-critical-minerals-list/</link><description>The US Geological Survey has officially added copper and silver to the critical minerals list, emphasizing their importance to the US economy and national security. The update will inform policy decisions on trade, investment, and mine permitting, reflecting growing concerns over supply chain security.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Hits 4-Year Low as Gloom Offsets Potential Indonesia Cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell to their lowest level in four years, driven by a lackluster outlook from the Federal Reserve and concerns over a stronger US dollar. Despite Indonesia considering sharp mining quota cuts, the market remains oversupplied and sentiment is weak.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices were in the doldrums on ...</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103607793</link><description>Nickel prices remained weak on November 10, 2025, with little movement as market participants awaited further developments. The US dollar index continued to influence price trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Breakthrough Tech Yields 99% Pure Nickel, Cobalt</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/breakthrough-tech-yields-99-pure-nickel-cobalt-1566990/</link><description>A new electrochemical process has been developed to recover nickel and cobalt with over 97% nickel recovery and 99% purity from battery leachates. This technology minimizes chemical usage and enables sustainable recycling with high metal purity and recovery rates, potentially impacting nickel supply chains.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Reason for Today's Sharp Aluminum Price Hike (November 10, 2025)</title><link>https://vmrf.vn/en/the-reason-for-todays-sharp-aluminum-price-hike-november-10-2025-1784</link><description>Aluminum prices rose sharply by about 0.7-1.2% reaching $2,856-$2,860 per ton due to global alumina and bauxite supply shortages caused by disruptions in Guinea and Brazil. Production cuts in China and Australia, combined with increased demand from green industries and economic stimulus, are driving a global deficit and pushing prices higher.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Surge Amid U.S. Government Reopening Hopes</title><link>https://www.gurufocus.com/news/3198766/aluminum-prices-surge-amid-us-government-reopening-hopes</link><description>Aluminum prices on the London Metal Exchange surged 1.7% to $2,895 per ton driven by optimism over a potential U.S. government reopening. The market remains strong due to Chinese capacity curbs and resilient demand, with analysts predicting a market deficit of 1.8 million tons this year despite high producer margins potentially limiting further price rises.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum rises on the outlook of reopening the US government</title><link>https://www.economies.com/commodities/steel-news/aluminum-rises-on-the-outlook-of-reopening-the-us-government-47712</link><description>Aluminum prices rose 1.7% to $2,895 per ton on the London Metal Exchange, supported by optimism about a U.S. government reopening. Production cuts in China and sustained global demand contribute to a supply deficit of around 1.8 million tons this year, though high producer margins may cap further price increases.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Premium Reaches Record High in the US Due to Tariffs and Global Squeeze</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/11/10/aluminum-premium-reaches-record-high-in-the-us-due-to-tariffs-and-global-squeeze</link><description>Record-high aluminum premiums in the US are driven by steep import tariffs and a global supply shortage. The physical market is experiencing tight conditions, with limited supply and increased demand pushing premiums to unprecedented levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Premiums for Aluminum in U.S. Reach Record Highs</title><link>https://globalnews.ca/video/11519806/premiums-for-aluminum-in-u-s-reach-record-highs</link><description>US aluminum premiums have hit record highs due to import tariffs and a global supply squeeze. The situation is impacting the physical market, with producers and consumers facing increased costs and limited availability.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Aluminium Expands Low-Carbon Portfolio with Launch of Restora Production at BALCO</title><link>https://thecsruniverse.com/articles/vedanta-aluminium-expands-low-carbon-portfolio-with-launch-of-restora-production-at-balco</link><description>Vedanta Aluminium has expanded its low-carbon product portfolio by launching Restora production at BALCO, reflecting ongoing efforts to enhance ecological restoration and community stewardship through sustainable aluminum manufacturing practices.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Raw Steel Production Is Up 1.0 Percent - Week 46, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-10-percent-week-46-2025-1418884.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production rose 1.0% for the week ending November 8, 2025, reaching 1.758 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.7%. This marks a 9.1% increase compared to the same period last year, reflecting continued growth in the sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Holds November Pullback</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel/news/500255</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China fell to CNY 3,040 per tonne due to lower demand and increased trade protectionism. Exports from China dropped 12.5% year-on-year in October, and the construction PMI hit a record low, signaling ongoing sector contraction.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices in the Second Week of November 2025</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/37868/</link><description>Global steel markets showed mixed price movements in the second week of November 2025, with some products increasing and others declining. The report highlights regional differences in price trends and market sentiment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices Down As Ship Recycling Slows</title><link>https://www.marinelink.com/news/steel-prices-down-ship-recycling-slows-532241</link><description>Global steel prices are falling as ship recycling activity slows, particularly in South Asia. Prices in Pakistan and India have dropped below USD 400/LDT, with weak demand and limited supply contributing to the downturn.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AISI: Weekly raw steel production ticks up</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/10/aisi-weekly-raw-steel-production-ticks-up/</link><description>US mills produced an estimated 1,758,000 short tons of raw steel in the week ending November 8, 2025, up 1.0% from the previous week. The mill capability utilization rate was 76.7% last week, up from 76.0% the week prior and 9.1% higher than the same week a year earlier. Year-to-date production now stands at 77,228,000 short tons, 3.1% higher than the same period in 2024.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises as Risk Appetite Improves</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/500503</link><description>Copper futures climbed back above $5 per pound on Monday, reaching a one-week high as risk appetite strengthened amid optimism that the US government shutdown may soon end. The red metal also benefited from a weaker dollar and the Trump administration's addition of copper to its list of critical materials for the US economy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Surge Copper Highlights Strengthening Policy Environment for Critical Minerals Development in Canada</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/10/3184388/0/en/Surge-Copper-Highlights-Strengthening-Policy-Environment-for-Critical-Minerals-Development-in-Canada.html</link><description>Surge Copper welcomes measures in Budget 2025 that support critical minerals development in Canada, with the Berg Project positioned to benefit from infrastructure initiatives and federal-provincial support. The project features a large-scale copper and molybdenum resource with low-carbon, hydro-powered design aligned with national priorities for responsible resource development.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aqua Metals partners with Westwin to strengthen US nickel supply chain</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aqua-metals-partners-with-westwin-to-strengthen-us-nickel-supply-chain/</link><description>Aqua Metals signed a non-binding letter of intent with Westwin Elements to supply up to 1,000 metric tons of recycled nickel carbonate annually starting in 2027. This partnership aims to build one of the first fully domestic recycled nickel supply chains in the US, reducing reliance on imports and supporting clean energy systems. The deal is valued at around $12 million annually based on current nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aqua Metals and Westwin Elements Sign LOI for U.S.-Produced Nickel Carbonate Supply</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/10/3184463/36806/en/Aqua-Metals-and-Westwin-Elements-Sign-LOI-for-U-S-Produced-Nickel-Carbonate-Supply.html</link><description>Aqua Metals announced a non-binding Letter of Intent with Westwin Elements to supply up to 1,000 metric tons of recycled battery-grade nickel carbonate annually starting in 2027. The agreement follows successful qualification of Aqua Metals' nickel carbonate product and aims to establish one of the first domestic sources of nickel carbonate to support US industrial and battery manufacturing needs.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aqua Metals Westwin Partnership Creates US Nickel Supply</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/aqua-metals-westwin-nickel-supply-2025/</link><description>Aqua Metals and Westwin have partnered to create America's first integrated nickel battery recycling supply chain, aiming to produce 500 to 1,000 metric tons of recycled nickel carbonate annually by 2027. This closed-loop system converts battery waste into new battery production feedstock, enhancing US nickel supply security amid growing electric vehicle adoption and reducing dependence on foreign imports.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aqua Metals and Westwin Elements Sign LOI for U.S.-Produced Nickel Carbonate Supply</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/10/3184463/36806/en/Aqua-Metals-and-Westwin-Elements-Sign-LOI-for-U-S-Produced-Nickel-Carbonate-Supply.html</link><description>Aqua Metals and Westwin Elements have signed a letter of intent to create one of the first domestic sources of battery-grade nickel carbonate in the U.S., using advanced recycling technologies. The collaboration aims to strengthen the circular supply chain for critical minerals and reduce dependence on imports, supporting sustainable and secure domestic manufacturing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Recycling Technology Achieves 99% Purity of Nickel and Cobalt</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-recycling-technology-purity-nickel-cobalt.html</link><description>A research team affiliated with UNIST has developed a new recycling technology that recovers over 95% of nickel and cobalt from waste batteries, achieving up to 99% purity. This eco-friendly method could significantly reduce the environmental impact of battery production and support the circular economy.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>New Recycling Tech Recovers Nearly Pure Nickel and Cobalt from Old Batteries</title><link>https://interestingengineering.com/energy/recycling-nickel-cobalt-ev-batteries</link><description>Researchers have unveiled an innovative recycling technology that extracts 99% pure nickel and cobalt from spent electric vehicle batteries. The breakthrough could help meet the growing demand for sustainable battery materials and reduce reliance on virgin mining.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum premium reaches record high in the US due to tariffs and global squeeze</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/11/10/aluminum-premium-reaches-record-high-in-the-us-due-to-tariffs-and-global-squeeze</link><description>The premium for aluminum in the U.S. spot market has reached record highs due to combined effects of tariffs and global supply constraints. A U.S. buyer on the spot market will pay $4,792 per ton when the aluminum price is $2,850, reflecting the significant tariff impact on domestic pricing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Premiums for aluminum in U.S. reach record highs</title><link>https://globalnews.ca/video/11519806/premiums-for-aluminum-in-u-s-reach-record-highs</link><description>The U.S. physical market for aluminum has experienced record-high premiums driven by steep import tariffs and a shortage of supplies. This represents a significant shift in the domestic aluminum market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum premium reaches record high in the US due to tariffs and global squeeze</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mining/2025/11/10/aluminum-premium-reaches-record-high-in-the-us-due-to-tariffs-and-global-squeeze</link><description>Record-high aluminum premiums in the U.S. are attributed to steep import tariffs combined with a global shortage of supplies. The tight market conditions reflect both domestic trade policy and international supply constraints.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ball Corporation launches 'Aluminum Assists'—a season-long fan tournament to drive green action at Ball Arena with the Denver Nuggets and Colorado Avalanche</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/ball-corporation-launches-aluminum-assists-a-season-long-fan-tournament-to-drive-green-action-at-ball-arena-with-the-denver-nuggets-and-colorado-avala-116150</link><description>Ball Corporation announced a season-long sustainability challenge engaging fans of the Denver Nuggets and Colorado Avalanche to take green actions and choose aluminum packaging. Fans compete in a tournament-style competition to complete verified sustainability challenges like recycling and ridesharing, with opportunities to win exclusive prizes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>COP30: Unilever, Ball and Alcoa unveil 'first' carbon-free aluminum aerosol can</title><link>https://www.packaginginsights.com/news/carbon-free-aluminum-aerosol-can.html</link><description>Unilever, Ball, and Alcoa unveiled the world's first consumer personal and home care packaging using ELYSIS carbon-free aluminum smelting technology. The collaboration demonstrates how companies across the value chain can accelerate low-carbon innovation and deliver tangible sustainability benefits.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever pilot 'carbon-free' smelting technology in personal and home care packaging</title><link>https://packagingeurope.com/news/alcoa-ball-and-unilever-pilot-carbon-free-smelting-technology-in-personal-and-home-care-packaging/13602.article</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever are piloting ELYSIS carbon-free smelting technology in personal and home care packaging applications. The ELYSIS process uses inert anode technology to eliminate greenhouse gas emissions from aluminum smelting, producing oxygen instead of CO2.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>USGS adds copper: American Pacific sees projects boost</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/usgs-adds-copper-american-pacific-sees-projects-boost/</link><description>Copper was added to the U.S. Geological Survey's 2025 critical minerals list under the Trump administration's expanded definition of essential minerals. This designation aims to strengthen domestic supply chains and counter reliance on foreign sources, providing tailwinds for American Pacific Mining's copper-gold projects in Montana and Alaska.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>EU CBAM Adjustments Transform Aluminium Pricing Markets</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/eu-carbon-border-adjustment-aluminium-markets-2025/</link><description>The European Union's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM), effective January 1, 2026, will impose carbon-based pricing on aluminum imports, reshaping global aluminum trade by linking prices to environmental compliance. This new regulatory framework introduces certificate costs based on embedded carbon emissions, significantly impacting international aluminum market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Eases from 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/499462</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK fell to $2,850 per tonne from a three-year high amid soft manufacturing PMIs in the US and China, though supply concerns kept prices 12% higher year-to-date. China's annual aluminum output cap of 45 million tons is expected to be breached next year, and smelters face challenges expanding in Indonesia due to energy costs and regulations. Issues at key smelters, including Iceland's Grundartangi and Alcoa's Kwinana refinery, also pressured supply.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>EU CBAM Adjustments Transform Aluminium Pricing Markets</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/eu-carbon-border-adjustment-aluminium-markets-2025/</link><description>The EU's Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) is reshaping global aluminum pricing, favoring regions with low-carbon production like Norway, Iceland, Canada, and Brazil. High-carbon producers in China, India, and Russia face increased costs and competitive disadvantages, prompting shifts in production and investment toward cleaner technologies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 11, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-11-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd shares rose 0.10% to ₹1,181.20 on November 11, 2025. The update reflects current market sentiment and minor gains in the company's stock price.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is up 1.0 percent - week 46, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-up-10-percent-week-46-2025-1418884.htm</link><description>According to the American Iron and Steel Institute (AISI), US domestic raw steel production for the week ending November 8, 2025, was 1.758 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.7%. Year-to-date adjusted production through November 8, 2025, was 77.228 million net tons at a capacity utilization rate of 77.0%, representing a 3.1% increase from the same period last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vale gearing up to meet Indian demand as China steel output stagnates</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/vale-gearing-up-to-meet-indian-demand-as-china-steel-output-stagnates-ceo-says-2025-11-11</link><description>Brazilian miner Vale is preparing to meet rising iron ore demand from India, which could double its steel production by the end of the decade. This shift reflects changing global steel dynamics as China's steel output stagnates.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>South Korea confronts global steel barriers as US, EU and Canada tighten rules</title><link>https://koreapro.org/2025/11/south-korea-confronts-global-steel-barriers-as-us-eu-and-canada-tighten-rules/</link><description>South Korea's trade ministry held a joint public-private meeting to assess the impact of global protectionist measures targeting steel, including US Section 232 tariffs and Tariff Rate Quota systems in the EU and Canada. The ministry announced a Steel Industry Advancement Plan that includes stronger domestic safeguards and financial support for affected producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Grasberg Accident Investigation Concludes, LME Copper Surged Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103613614/Grasberg-Accident-Investigation-Concludes-LME-Copper-Surged-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>LME copper settled at $10,874.5/mt, up 1.68%, after opening at $10,820/mt and reaching a high of $10,903/mt. Freeport Indonesia completed its investigation into the slurry leakage incident at Grasberg copper-gold mine, with the Big Gossan and Deep Mill Level Zone mines resuming operations at the end of October.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices drop on Fed policy uncertainty and Codelco supply</title><link>https://www.miningreporters.com/noticia/news/2025/11/copper-price-falls-fed-policy-codelco-supply</link><description>Copper prices extended losses on Tuesday, falling as much as 2.4% to around $10,855 per tonne on the LME, pressured by renewed uncertainty over US interest rates and easing supply concerns from Chilean miner Codelco. The US dollar reached its highest level since May, further weighing on metals that had surged in anticipation of a US-China trade truce.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper climbs on US shutdown deal, supply tightness</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L4N3WN05Z:0-copper-climbs-on-us-shutdown-deal-supply-tightness/</link><description>Copper prices climbed on Tuesday as a potential resolution to the US federal government shutdown lifted market sentiment, with the three-month copper contract up 0.24% at $10,822 per ton. Fresh production data showing reduced output at Chile's Codelco reinforced expectations of tighter supply next year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>3 ASX copper shares soaring amid 28% surge in commodity price this year</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/11/11/3-asx-copper-shares-soaring-amid-28-surge-in-commodity-price-this-year/</link><description>ASX copper shares are benefiting from a 28% surge in the commodity price this year to US$5.08 per pound on Tuesday, driven by higher demand amid the global energy transition. Copper has been supported by its designation as a critical material for the US economy and national security, as well as a weaker US dollar.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>ARENA commits $25.3 million to continue SunDrive's copper solar cell breakthrough</title><link>https://arena.gov.au/news/arena-commits-25-3-million-to-continue-sundrives-copper-solar-cell-breakthrough/</link><description>Australia’s ARENA has committed $25.3 million to advance SunDrive’s copper metallisation technology for solar cells, aiming to provide a silver-free alternative amid rising silver prices. This investment supports scaling up production of copper-based solar technology, contributing to clean energy innovation.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Collapse Forces Market Repricing as Oversupply Weak Demand Challenge Producers</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-price-collapse-forces-market-repricing-as-oversupply-weak-demand-challenge-producers</link><description>The nickel market is undergoing severe structural adjustment with prices collapsing to around US$15,000 per tonne in mid-2025 due to oversupply and weak demand. Macroeconomic factors such as US dollar strength and tariffs on imports from major producers like Indonesia and Russia are adding complexity, driving supply chain realignment and creating distinct pricing mechanisms based on source jurisdiction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On November 11, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 119,400-123,200 yuan/mt</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103614036/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 119,400 to 123,200 yuan per metric ton on November 11, with an average price of 121,300 yuan/mt, marking a slight increase of 100 yuan/mt from the previous day.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Sulphate Daily Review] November 11 Nickel Salt Prices Slightly Declined</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103614820/%5BSMM-Nickel-Sulphate-Daily-Review%5D-November-11-Nickel-Salt-Prices-Slightly-Declined</link><description>On November 11, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price was 28,285 yuan/mt, with a slight decline in the quotation range for battery-grade nickel sulphate.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price hikes slightly on Nov 11, remaining stable</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/NewsItem/130109</link><description>The international nickel price remained stable on November 11, with the three-month futures price on the London Metal Exchange (LME) slightly rising, reflecting a steady market condition.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries targets US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-targets-us-1-billion-ebitda-by-2026</link><description>Australia-listed nickel miner and processor Nickel Industries Limited aims to achieve US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026, signaling strong growth ambitions amid current market conditions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Industries targets US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-industries-targets-us-1-billion-ebitda-by-2026</link><description>Nickel Industries aims to achieve US$1 billion EBITDA by 2026, reflecting growth ambitions in the nickel sector. The company is expanding production capacity amid strong demand for nickel, particularly for battery and stainless steel applications.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris S.A. Announces Share Buyback Reaching 5.01% of Voting Rights</title><link>https://www.barchart.com/story/news/29731024/tenaris-sa-announces-share-buyback-reaching-501-of-voting-rights</link><description>Tenaris announced that the company is expected to report earnings on November 11, 2025, before market open. This earnings report serves as a clear catalyst for traders and investors.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>US flat steel pricing recovers previous weekly dip with steady November scrap, HRC futures rally</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-prices/steel-prices-market-analyses/flats-and-slab/us-flat-steel-pricing-recovers-previous-weekly-dip-with-steady-november-scrap-hrc-futures-rally-1418865.htm</link><description>US flat steel prices rebounded after a recent dip, supported by bullish November scrap pricing and steel futures. Market movements show cautious outlooks with mixed price changes in various regions, including stable or slightly down ex-China HRC prices and shifts in Turkey's import HRC segment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMU Price Ranges: Sheet and plate products inch higher</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/11/smu-price-ranges-sheet-and-plate-products-inch-higher/</link><description>Sheet and plate steel prices increased by $5-15 per short ton, reaching multi-month highs. Hot-rolled coil prices rose for the fifth consecutive week to $830/st, cold rolled steel prices hit the highest average since July, and galvanized and plate prices also saw notable gains amid cautious buyer sentiment.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Why copper is 'a ticking time bomb for explosive price action'</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/marketwatch/2025111191/why-copper-is-a-ticking-time-bomb-for-explosive-price-action</link><description>Copper prices have dropped approximately 15% from record highs achieved less than four months ago, though tariff uncertainty continues to impact the market. The real growth driver for copper demand is AI data centers, which are expected to consume 6.7% to 12% of total U.S. electricity by 2028, compared to 4.4% in 2023. Global copper markets are likely to remain dislocated until final tariff decisions are made, which will limit downside pressure on prices.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Why copper is 'a ticking time bomb for explosive price action'</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/marketwatch/2025111191/why-copper-is-a-ticking-time-bomb-for-explosive-price-action</link><description>The global copper market may face a 30% supply shortfall by 2035 due to mining challenges and rising demand, especially from AI data centers. Despite recent price drops, tariffs and supply-demand imbalances keep copper prices supported, with market dislocations expected until tariff decisions are finalized.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Japan’s JX, partners to merge Mitsubishi’s refined copper unit into Pan Pacific</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/japans-jx-partners-to-merge-mitsubishi-materials-refined-copper-unit-into-pan-pacific/</link><description>Japan’s JX Advanced Metals and partners plan to integrate Mitsubishi Materials’ copper concentrates procurement and refined copper sales into Pan Pacific Copper to boost profitability amid deteriorating conditions in copper concentrate procurement and smelting margins. JX may cut copper production by tens of thousands of tons in fiscal 2025 and reduce smelting capacity by March.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper's Historic 2025 Rally: A Global Economy in the Red Metal's Grip</title><link>https://markets.financialcontent.com/stocks/article/marketminute-2025-11-11-coppers-historic-2025-rally-a-global-economy-in-the-red-metals-grip</link><description>The STOXX Global Copper Miners index surged 55% in 2025, driven by heightened earnings expectations and green transition demand. The article discusses strategic pivots needed across mining, manufacturing, and recycling sectors, with the recycling industry presenting significant opportunities for expanded capacity and technological advancements in secondary copper recovery.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>$25.3 million finance to advance SunDrive copper solar cell technology</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/2025/11/11/25-3-million-finance-to-advance-sundrive-copper-solar-cell-technology/</link><description>The Australian Renewable Energy Agency committed an additional $25.3 million to SunDrive to scale up its copper metallisation technology for solar cells. The innovation replaces expensive silver with more abundant and cheaper copper while achieving higher cell and module efficiencies, supporting global decarbonisation efforts.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Project boosts ethically responsible exploration of critical raw materials</title><link>https://phys.org/news/2025-11-boosts-ethically-responsible-exploration-critical.html</link><description>The VECTOR project, coordinated by the Helmholtz Institute Freiberg, developed efficient and low-impact exploration methods for critical raw materials including copper across Europe. The research integrates geosciences with data and social sciences to enable responsible supply of raw materials while addressing environmental and social concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review: Nickel Prices Dropped Slightly on November 11</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103614704/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-dropped-slightly-on-November-11-as-a-US-Fed-governor-suggested-continuing-to-cut-interest-rates-in-December</link><description>On November 11, the SMM #1 refined nickel price was 119,400–123,000 yuan/mt, averaging 121,300 yuan/mt, up 100 yuan/mt from the previous trading day. The slight increase came amid expectations of continued interest rate cuts by the US Fed.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Greenland grants 30-year permit to EU-backed Molybdenum mine involving Cogne Acciai Speciali</title><link>https://www.mining.com/greenland-grants-30-year-permit-to-eu-backed-molybdenum-mine/</link><description>Greenland Resources secured a 30-year permit for the Malmbjerg molybdenum project, supported by the EU and involving Cogne Acciai Speciali through off-take agreements. The mine will supply critical molybdenum used to strengthen steel, benefiting sectors like aerospace and energy.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Glencore Cuts Century Aluminum Stake in $276M Deal</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/glencore-divestment-century-aluminum-2025/</link><description>Glencore has reduced its shareholding in Century Aluminum through a $276 million strategic block trade, with implications for U.S. domestic aluminum production capacity and supply chain resilience. The transaction highlights evolving ownership structures in the critical domestic aluminum sector.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel prices rises 0.6–2.5 pct in October 2025</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025-11-12:newsml_BER4Brcjs:0-steel-prices-rises-0-6-2-5-pct-in-october-2025-dosm-screen/</link><description>The unit price index of steel increased by 0.6 to 2.5 percent in October 2025 compared to September 2025, indicating a general upward trend in steel prices during that period.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Surging Copper Price Drives Historic 2025 Rally</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-prices-2025-supply-demand-record/</link><description>Copper prices have climbed to record levels of US$11,200 per tonne on the London Metal Exchange in 2025, with a recent pullback to approximately US$10,800 per tonne. JPMorgan Chase forecasts copper reaching US$12,000 per tonne in Q1 2026, representing approximately 11% additional upside, driven by widening global supply deficits and accelerating energy transition infrastructure investment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Surging copper price shines light on BHP shares and 3 other ASX 200 mining stocks</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/11/12/surging-copper-price-shines-light-on-bhp-shares-and-3-other-asx-200-mining-stocks/</link><description>Copper has risen 27% since the start of 2025, reaching record highs of US$11,200 per tonne before pulling back to US$10,800 per tonne. JPMorgan Chase's head of base and precious metals research predicts copper will reach US$12,000 per tonne in Q1 2026, which could benefit ASX 200 mining stocks with significant copper exposure like BHP Group.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Commodities Lift as US Dollar Weakens</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/12/commodities-lift-as-us-dollar-weakens/</link><description>Copper prices gained support from a weaker US dollar and improved market risk appetite following expectations that the US government shutdown would conclude. The premium on US to LME copper has climbed back to approximately US$1,000 per tonne, driven by expectations that the Commerce Department will decide next year on phased tariffs of 15% increasing to 30% on refined copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price falls on Fed uncertainty, Codelco supply relief</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-falls-on-fed-uncertainty-codelco-supply-relief/</link><description>Copper prices dropped as much as 2.4% amid broader declines in base metals, with three-month copper trading at roughly US$10,855 per tonne by 1 p.m. ET. The decline was driven by Federal Reserve uncertainty and supply relief from Codelco.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Star Copper dives into unlocking Copper Creek's potential</title><link>https://mining.com.au/star-copper-dives-into-unlocking-copper-creeks-potential/</link><description>Star Copper's 2025 exploration campaign in British Columbia has advanced the Copper Creek target towards identifying a large-scale porphyry copper deposit. The company has completed soil sampling, mapping, and started first-pass drilling to validate their structural-geochemical model, aiming to extend drilling in 2026.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 Refined Nickel Price on November 12</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103617049/</link><description>On November 12, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged from 118,400 to 122,500 yuan/mt, with an average of 120,450 yuan/mt, down 850 yuan/mt from the previous day. The price decline reflects ongoing market adjustments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/492981</link><description>Nickel futures dropped to 15,078.00 USD/ton, the lowest level since September 2025, as oversupply from Indonesia continues to pressure prices. LME inventories have reached record highs, with Chinese-origin nickel now making up 65% of stocks.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>PE eyes BHP's Nickel West as China tightens rare earth grip</title><link>https://www.marketsgroup.org/news/pe-eyes-bhps-nickel-west-as-china-tightens-rare-earth-grip</link><description>China's tightening control over rare earth exports has renewed global interest in nickel, especially in Australia. BHP's Nickel West, running at a loss, is up for sale with private equity and local miners showing interest. Japanese firms have also acquired stakes in Australian nickel projects aiming for competitive production costs.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel ore stockpiles rise as smelters cut output, import from Philippines</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/nickel-ore-stockpiles-rise-as-smelters-cut-output-import-from-philippines</link><description>Indonesia's nickel ore stockpiles are increasing as domestic smelters reduce production and boost imports from the Philippines. This shift reflects adjustments in supply amid changing production dynamics in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Cables and Systems to close Schuylkill Haven facility</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/PlvOdwvbSh4</link><description>Prysmian Cables and Systems announced the closure of its Schuylkill Haven facility, which will affect 150 employees.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian shares rise as Italian cable maker seen as winner amid US copper tariffs</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/prysmian-shares-rise-as-italian-cable-maker-seen-as-winner-amid-us-copper-tariffs-4127785</link><description>Prysmian shares rose as much as 4% on expectations that the world's largest cable maker's large US business could benefit from US tariffs on copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>