<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 05:17:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SMM Exclusive: Overview of Metal Production in September 2025 and Forecast for October</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103560133/SMM-Exclusive:-Overview-of-Metal-Production-in-September-2025-and-Forecast-for-October</link><description>China's copper cathode production in September 2025 decreased by 4.31% month-on-month due to increased smelter maintenance and tight copper anode supply, despite a year-on-year increase of 11.62%. Production is expected to decline further in October and November as maintenance continues and supply constraints persist, with operating rates dropping especially for large smelters.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Update: Q2 2025 in Review</title><link>https://investingnews.com/daily/resource-investing/base-metals-investing/copper-investing/copper-forecast/</link><description>Copper prices were volatile in Q2 2025 but remained elevated overall, influenced by tariffs, global economic uncertainty, and trade tensions. The market may have entered a supply deficit due to disruptions such as the shutdown at Ivanhoe-Zijin Kakula-Kamoa mine in the DRC, with production guidance lowered significantly, highlighting tight copper supply against growing demand from structural growth sectors like AI data centers and energy transition.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Mining companies make stunning discovery that could be crucial for sustainable nickel production</title><link>https://www.thecooldown.com/green-tech/nickel-mining-improvements-sustainable-practices/</link><description>Eagle Mine is piloting D-Solve technology to increase nickel purity by reducing magnesium impurities by 40%, which could extend mine life and improve process efficiencies. This innovation reduces waste and energy use in nickel mining, supporting lower production costs and advancing clean energy transition goals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Italy awards Prysmian $539mn contract for Tunisia-Europe power cable</title><link>https://energynews.pro/en/italy-awards-prysmian-539mn-contract-for-tunisia-europe-power-cable/</link><description>Italy has awarded Prysmian a contract worth $539 million to build a submarine power cable connecting Italy and Tunisia as part of the Elmed Project. The cable will run from the Partanna substation in Sicily to the Mlaabi substation in Tunisia, supporting cleaner energy integration between the two countries.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Cables: Antitrust Launches Investigation into Alleged Cartel Involving Prysmian and Others</title><link>https://www.firstonline.info/en/cavi-in-rame-antitrust-avvia-indagine-su-presunto-cartello-prysmian-e-nexans-in-calo-in-borsa/</link><description>The Italian Antitrust Authority has launched an investigation into alleged anti-competitive practices among major low voltage copper cable manufacturers in Italy, including Prysmian. The probe focuses on coordinated pricing and sales conditions dating back to 2005, with inspections conducted at company offices and distributors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Stabilizes as Supply Risks Persist</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures steadied above $4.90 per pound amid ongoing supply risks, with output disruptions in Chile and Indonesia tightening global production. The market also reacted to expectations of additional US Federal Reserve rate cuts and persistent deflationary pressures in China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Rises on US Rate Cut Bets</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper futures climbed back above $5 per pound as dovish remarks from the Fed reinforced expectations for more US rate cuts, improving the global demand outlook. Supply concerns remain elevated due to recent output disruptions in major producing countries.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Fall as Trade Tensions and the US Government Shutdown Weigh</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/10/16/copper-prices-fall-as-trade-tensions-and-the-us-government-shutdown-weigh</link><description>Copper prices dipped slightly as U.S.-China trade tensions and the ongoing U.S. government shutdown dampened market sentiment, though a weaker dollar provided some support. Concerns about Chinese demand growth persist, with some traders reducing positions amid expectations of softer GDP data from China.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>What Ford Stands to Lose From Its Aluminum Shortage, Production Disruptions</title><link>https://www.freep.com/story/money/cars/ford/2025/10/16/ford-aluminum-shortage-production/86710068007/</link><description>Ford is facing aluminum supply shortages due to a fire at a Novelis plant, impacting production at its Kentucky and Dearborn facilities. The shortage threatens to disrupt manufacturing of key models like the F-150 and Super Duty pickups, with potential layoffs and financial impacts. Tariffs on imported aluminum complicate sourcing alternatives.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Secondary Aluminum Ingot Inventories in Key Cities Drop on Oct 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103573342/%E3%80%90SMM-Flash-News%E3%80%91Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Inventories-in-Key-Cities-Drop-on-Oct-17</link><description>Secondary aluminum enterprises maintained flat quotations amid a wait-and-see market stance. The SMM ADC12 price held steady at 21,050 yuan/mt, while inventories of secondary aluminum ingots in key Chinese cities declined, indicating tightening supply conditions in the secondary aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Japan Q4 aluminium talks drag out in effort to bridge gap, say sources</title><link>https://sundayguardianlive.com/world/japan-q4-aluminium-talks-drag-out-in-effort-to-bridge-gap-say-sources-156356/</link><description>Quarterly pricing talks between Japanese aluminium buyers and global producers have extended unusually long due to a wide gap in price expectations amid sluggish demand and high inventories. Japanese aluminium stocks rose slightly, while producers hold out for higher premiums influenced by rising prices in the US and Europe.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Consultation opens for $2 billion green aluminium production credit</title><link>https://www.pv-magazine-australia.com/press-releases/consultation-opens-for-2-billion-green-aluminium-production-credit/</link><description>The Australian government has opened consultation on a $2 billion Green Aluminium Production Credit aimed at decarbonizing aluminium smelters by promoting production using renewable energy. The initiative supports Australia's ambition to lead in low-carbon aluminium production, which is critical for the energy transition and reducing greenhouse gas emissions from this energy-intensive industry.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Extrusion Market CAGR to be at 5.2% from 2025 to 2029</title><link>https://www.einpresswire.com/article/858599334/aluminum-extrusion-market-cagr-to-be-at-5-2-from-2025-to-2029-115-59-billion-industry-revenue-by-2029</link><description>The aluminum extrusion market is projected to grow robustly to $115.59 billion by 2029, driven by government support, urbanization, and increased demand in automotive and packaging sectors. Growth is also fueled by trends in green building construction, where aluminum's sustainability and recyclability are highly valued.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Market to Reach USD $243.04 Billion by 2029 at 6.4% CAGR</title><link>https://www.brusselsnewsnetwork.com/article/858596581-aluminum-market-to-reach-usd-243-04-billion-by-2029-at-6-4-cagr</link><description>The global aluminum market is expected to grow to $243.04 billion by 2029, with a CAGR of 6.4%, driven by advances in recycling, electric vehicle demand, construction, and aerospace sectors. Innovations such as 3D printing and new aluminum alloys, along with increased use in packaging and renewable energy projects, are key growth factors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Jinshi Futures Morning Update - October 17, 2025</title><link>https://news.futunn.com/en/post/63406043/jinshi-futures-morning-update-october-17-2025-friday</link><description>The update discusses various market trends, including ferrosilicon prices from Hebei Steel, which were set at RMB 5,660/ton for October, down RMB 140/ton. However, it does not specifically focus on steel prices. Precious metals have seen significant volatility, with gold and silver hitting record highs.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Tata Steel Share Price Live Updates</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/stocks/stock-liveblog/tata-steel-stock-price-today-live-17-oct-2025/liveblog/124618753.cms</link><description>Tata Steel's share price closed at Rs 173.24 in the previous trading session and is experiencing a slight gain today. The update focuses on stock market dynamics rather than steel prices specifically.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-17-oct-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's stock price increased by 0.29%, reaching ₹1,173.10 per share. This update is about stock performance rather than steel market trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Taiwan's Tung Ho Steel Keeps H-Beam Prices Flat</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/taiwans-tung-ho-steel-keeps-h-beam-prices-flat-for-second-half-of-oct/157289</link><description>Tung Ho Steel has maintained stable H-beam prices for the second half of October, continuing a trend of price stability throughout most of 2025. This decision reflects a consistent approach to pricing in the Taiwanese market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Update</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel prices rose to $815/ton on October 16, 2025, marking a slight increase from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen by 0.25%, and are up 15.60% year-over-year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>India's Steel Giants Risk Locking in 12 Billion Tonnes of CO₂</title><link>https://carbontracker.org/indias-steel-giants-risk-locking-in-12-billion-tonnes-of-co%E2%82%82/</link><description>India's major steel companies are planning significant capacity expansions, which could hinder the country's climate goals and expose them to EU carbon tariffs. The expansion relies heavily on traditional blast furnace technology due to the high cost of low-carbon alternatives. This poses a risk to achieving India's net-zero targets by 2070.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Jindal Stainless Doubles Slag Capacity to Boost Circular Production</title><link>https://www.constructionworld.in/steel-news/jindal-stainless-doubles-slag-capacity-to-boost-circular-production/80241</link><description>Jindal Stainless, India's largest stainless steel producer, has doubled its slag processing capacity to enhance circular production. This move aims to improve sustainability and efficiency in its operations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Miners Plunge Amid US-China Tensions</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/10/17/copper-miners-plunge-amid-us-china-tensions/</link><description>Shares in Australian copper mining companies fell significantly due to a drop in copper prices driven by escalating US-China tensions. Concerns about reduced demand from China, a major copper consumer, have pressured prices and impacted copper producers' market valuations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Market Trends: Volatility and Supply Pressures Shape 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/copper-market-trends-2025-demand-growth/</link><description>Copper prices are forecasted to remain elevated through 2026 due to structural supply-demand imbalances and rising demand from the energy transition. Price scenarios range from $9,000 to $15,000 per tonne depending on supply disruptions and demand growth, with risks including economic slowdowns and trade tensions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price rebounds as traders see $12,000 within reach after rally</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-rebounds-as-traders-see-12000-within-reach-after-rally/</link><description>Copper prices have rebounded recently, with traders optimistic about reaching $12,000 per tonne following a strong rally. This reflects bullish sentiment amid ongoing supply constraints and demand from energy transition sectors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Japan, the West, and South Korea Report Continued Decline in TC/RC; LME Copper Slightly Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103573294/Japan-the-West-and-South-Korea-Report-Continued-Decline-in-TCRC-LME-Copper-Slightly-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Copper futures on the LME showed slight gains after fluctuating overnight, closing at $10,620/mt. Japan, Spain, and South Korea warned that the sharp decline in copper concentrate treatment and refining charges threatens the mining and smelting industry chain, potentially forcing some smelters to scale back or exit.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 0.28% Lower at $4.9580 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510167118/comex-copper-settles-028-lower-at-49580-data-talk</link><description>Comex copper prices declined by 0.28% to $4.9580 per pound, marking a third consecutive session of losses and the largest three-day decline since October 10, 2025. Despite recent drops, copper remains up over 24% from its 52-week low earlier this year.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper slips as US govt shutdown, trade tensions weigh - Markets</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40387843</link><description>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange fell 0.7% to $10,566 per metric ton amid concerns over a US government shutdown and ongoing trade tensions. These factors contribute to market uncertainty despite tight supply conditions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Daily Nickel price, Lme Comex Shfe Price of Nickel live | SMM</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Nickel</link><description>The latest SMM spot price for #1 Nickel is USD 15,000.3–15,335.02 per metric ton, with an average of USD 15,167.66, up 25.85 from the previous day. Nickel briquettes and JinChuan Nickel also saw slight increases, while Indonesian refined nickel prices dropped by USD 260 per tonne.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel Prices Maintain Fluctuating Trend on October 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103574518/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Maintain-Fluctuating-Trend-on-October-17-US-and-Russian-Presidents-Hold-Phone-Conversation-After-Nearly-Two-Months</link><description>SMM #1 refined nickel prices in China ranged from 121,000 to 123,700 yuan per metric ton, averaging 122,350 yuan, up 200 yuan from the previous day. The market continues to experience fluctuations amid ongoing global economic and political developments.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME WEEK: Nickel market could stay in oversupply until 2030</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/lme-week-nickel-market-could-stay-in-oversupply-until-2030-macquarie/</link><description>According to Macquarie, the global nickel market is expected to remain in surplus until 2030, indicating prolonged oversupply conditions. This outlook aligns with recent projections of continued excess production relative to demand in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel touts $70B GDP boost from Timmins mine project</title><link>https://www.northernontariobusiness.com/industry-news/mining/canada-nickel-touts-70b-gdp-boost-from-timmins-mine-project-11350020</link><description>Canada Nickel highlights that its proposed Crawford open-pit nickel mine near Timmins is expected to generate over $70 billion in GDP benefits. This project represents a significant investment in nickel production capacity in Canada, contributing to economic growth and mining sector expansion.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Asia faces P7 million penalty as Mindoro geothermal deal ends</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/business/2025/10/17/2480334/nickel-asia-faces-p7-million-penalty-mindoro-geothermal-deal-ends</link><description>Nickel Asia Corporation is facing a penalty of 7 million Philippine pesos following the conclusion of its geothermal deal in Mindoro. The company disclosed this development to the Philippine Stock Exchange, reflecting operational and contractual changes impacting its business.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>PT Vale and PAMA Officially Launch Nickel Mining Project in Kolaka</title><link>https://www.djakarta-miningclub.com/news/pt-vale-and-pama-officially-launch-nickel-mining-project-in-kolaka</link><description>PT Vale and PAMA have officially launched a new nickel mining project in Kolaka, Indonesia. This development marks an expansion of nickel production capacity in the region, supporting Indonesia's position as a major nickel producer.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Falls Slightly After Recent Rally, But Up Over Past Month and Year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped to $2,774.55 per tonne on October 17, 2025, down 0.88% from the previous day, but remain up 2.89% over the past month and 6.06% year-on-year. The market outlook suggests prices could reach $2,784.44 per tonne by the end of the quarter and $2,907.92 in 12 months, reflecting ongoing bullish sentiment amid tight supply and strong demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Aluminum Morning Meeting Summary: Bullish Trend Intact, But Volume Divergence Signals Caution</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>Domestic and international macro environments remain favorable, supporting aluminum prices. Technical indicators show a bullish trend, but lower-than-average trading volume suggests potential for a correction. Resistance is seen at 21,150–21,250 yuan/mt, with support at 20,850–20,950 yuan/mt.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME Explores Sustainable Metal Premia as Aluminum Demand Grows</title><link>https://www.lme.com/en/metals/non-ferrous/lme-aluminium</link><description>The LME is considering the introduction of price premia for sustainable metals, including aluminum, as part of efforts to meet rising demand for low-carbon materials. Aluminum remains a key metal for global industries due to its recyclability and strength-to-weight ratio, with the LME Official Price serving as the global benchmark.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Golden Triangle builds on Steel Dynamics growth with new Kloeckner aluminum plant</title><link>https://www.newsfromthestates.com/article/golden-triangle-builds-steel-dynamics-growth-new-kloeckner-aluminum-plant</link><description>The Golden Triangle is expanding its industrial capacity with a new Kloeckner aluminum plant, building on the growth of Steel Dynamics. This development aims to enhance regional economic and industrial activities.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LIXIL Standardizes Low-Carbon PremiAL Across Its Product Line</title><link>https://newsroom.lixil.com/2025091701</link><description>LIXIL Corporation is standardizing the use of PremiAL, its recycled low-carbon aluminum that reduces CO₂ emissions by approximately 50%, across its product line at no extra cost starting October 2025. This initiative leverages nearly 30 years of aluminum recycling expertise to significantly lower embodied carbon in building materials, supporting the decarbonization of the construction industry in Japan.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel Price Update and Forecast</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>Hot Rolled Coil (HRC) steel prices decreased to $789/tonne, the lowest since February 2025, down 0.48% from the previous day. Prices have fallen 2.40% over the past month but remain 15.05% higher than a year ago. Analysts expect prices to rise to $831/tonne by the end of the quarter and $894/tonne within 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMU Survey: Current Sentiment Sinks to Lowest Level Since May 2020</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/17/smu-survey-current-sentiment-sinks-to-lowest-level-since-may-2020/</link><description>Steel buyers report steady to slightly higher prices but weak demand and slow inventories. U.S. domestic sheet prices remain rangebound amid supply tightness and weak demand, with scrap prices falling in October. Tariffs continue to cloud market outlook as the industry heads into the final quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SMU flat-rolled market survey results now available</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/17/smu-flat-rolled-market-survey-results-now-available-18/</link><description>Steel mill lead times have decreased across most sheet and plate products in the US, according to the latest SMU survey. Current steel buyer sentiment has dropped to its lowest level since May 2020, reflecting weak demand and rangebound domestic prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper rose to $4.96 per pound on October 17, 2025, up 0.33% from the previous day, with a 9.32% increase over the past month and a 13.92% rise year-over-year. Trading Economics forecasts copper to trade at $4.93 per pound by the end of the quarter and $5.40 in 12 months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Ends the Week 1.71% Higher at $4.9315 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202510176093/comex-copper-ends-the-week-171-higher-at-49315-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for October delivery gained 1.71% this week to $4.9315 per pound, despite a recent four-session losing streak and a 3.31% drop over the last four sessions. Copper remains up 23.72% from its 52-week low but is down 14.9% from its 2025 high.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Pulled Back This Week Due to Fundamental Pressure</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575414/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-pulled-back-this-week-due-to-fundamental-pressure-and-inventory-levels-increased-further</link><description>Nickel prices have retreated due to fundamental pressures and increased inventory levels. The most-traded SHFE nickel contract closed at 121,160 yuan/mt, down 1.89% week-over-week. LME nickel prices also fell to $15,140/mt, showing synchronized weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alaska Energy Metals Provides Corporate Update On Nikolai Nickel Project, Alaska And Announces Amendment To Restricted Share Plan And Grants Of Stock Options And Restricted Share Units</title><link>https://www.webdisclosure.com/press-release/alaska-energy-metals-provides-corporate-update-on-nikolai-nickel-project-alaska-and-announces-amendment-to-restricted-share-plan-and-grants-of-stock-options-and-restricted-share-units-0QbQl3fiVKg</link><description>Alaska Energy Metals reports that first-pass metallurgical testing at the Eureka deposit of the Nikolai nickel project is nearing completion, with results expected in November 2025. The company is also advancing an internal options study and pursuing US government grant funding, with a Preliminary Economic Assessment planned for 2026.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,774.55 USD/T on October 17, 2025, down 0.88% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices dropped slightly to $2,774.55 per tonne on October 17, 2025, down 0.88% from the previous day. Despite this dip, prices have risen 2.89% over the past month and are up 6.06% compared to the same time last year. Aluminum futures recently hit a three-year high amid tight supply and bullish demand expectations, with forecasts suggesting prices could reach $2,805.80 per tonne by the end of the quarter.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price heads for longest winning streak in a year</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-heads-for-longest-winning-streak-in-a-year-before-fed/</link><description>Aluminum prices climbed for a seventh consecutive session ahead of the Federal Reserve's anticipated interest rate decision, reaching the highest levels since March 2025. The metal's gains are supported by expectations of monetary easing, which tends to weaken the dollar and boost industrial metals. Additionally, increased withdrawals from inventories have raised concerns about supply tightness.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CRU: Soft Demand Weighs on Sheet Imports into the US</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/10/17/cru-soft-demand-weighs-on-sheet-imports-into-the-us/</link><description>Brazilian slab export prices remained stable in October amid competition from low-priced Asian offers, with export volumes slightly down month-over-month but up year-over-year. An incident at ArcelorMittal Mexico impacted slab production, potentially increasing reliance on imported slabs to offset shortfalls.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash bid hits $2,789/t; stocks down to 491,225t</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-bid-hits-2-789-t-stocks-down-to-491-225t-115885</link><description>LME aluminium prices edged higher on October 17, with the cash bid at $2,789 per tonne and warehouse stocks declining slightly by 0.83% to 491,225 tonnes. The three-month and forward contract prices also increased, reflecting modest gains across the market despite a small drop in inventories. The LME alumina Platts price remained steady at $318.91 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices and Market Trends - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China rose slightly to 3,044 CNY per ton on October 17, 2025, marking a 0.03% increase from the previous day. However, steel prices have fallen 1.07% over the past month and are down 6.34% compared to the same period last year, with forecasts suggesting a slight increase by the end of the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>First Africa-Europe Power Bridge Moves Ahead As Contract Awarded For Submarine Cable</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news/0110-49154-first-africa-europe-power-bridge-moves-ahead-as-contract-awarded-for-submarine-cable</link><description>Prysmian has won a €460 million contract to build a 220-km high-voltage submarine power cable connecting Sicily, Italy, to Tunisia. The cable will carry 600 MW and is part of the Tunisia-Italy interconnection project (ELMED), supporting cleaner energy and energy security between Europe and Africa.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian wins 460 million euros power cable deal connecting Italy to Tunisia</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/prysmian-wins-460-mln-euros-power-cable-deal-connecting-italy-to-tunisia-ce7d58d3d08af02d</link><description>Prysmian secured a contract worth around €460 million to build a submarine power cable from the Partanna substation in Sicily to the Mlaabi substation in Tunisia. The project is part of the Elmed Project and aims to enhance energy interconnection and support the transition to cleaner energy.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>LME WEEK: US aluminum price rise spurs deliveries from Canada</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/lme-week-us-aluminum-price-rise-spurs-deliveries-from-canada/</link><description>The rise in US aluminum prices has led to an increase in deliveries from Canada, though not yet at full pace. The Midwest premium has hit a record high, effectively pricing in the 50% tariff. This has also influenced European duty-paid aluminum premiums, which have jumped significantly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Trump's tariffs spur US aluminum industry to boost recycling</title><link>https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/clean-aluminum/trump-tariffs-spur-metal-recycling</link><description>President Trump's tariffs have prompted the US aluminum industry to increase recycling efforts. This shift is part of broader trends in the US aluminum market, which has seen changes in inventories and production strategies.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Chart and Historical Data</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose slightly to 3,044 CNY/tonne on October 17, 2025, up 0.03% from the previous day. However, steel prices have fallen 1.07% over the past month and are down 6.34% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect steel to trade around 3,047 CNY/tonne by the end of the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices in China rose slightly to 3,044 CNY/T on October 17, 2025, up 0.03% from the previous day, but are down 1.07% over the past month and 6.34% year-over-year. Trading Economics forecasts steel to trade at 3047.39 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter, with a further decline expected over the next 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BHP's Copper Boom: Sustainable Mining to Meet Soaring Global Demand</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/bhps-copper-boom-sustainable-mining-to-meet-soaring-global-demand/</link><description>BHP is investing in sustainable mining practices to meet the growing demand for copper, driven by electric vehicles, renewable energy, and data centers. The company aims to support a lower-carbon future with strong operations and clean energy goals. Recycled copper will also play a significant role in meeting rising demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Anaconda Copper Mine 2025: Innovations &amp; Sustainability</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/anaconda-copper-mine-2025-innovations-sustainability</link><description>The Anaconda Copper Mine is embracing innovations like AI, digital monitoring, and eco-rehabilitation to meet sustainability and economic goals. The mine serves as a model for responsible resource extraction, balancing environmental stewardship with community resilience. Advances in technology are crucial for the future of mining.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Gold, Silver &amp; Copper: Tech and Sustainability Trends</title><link>https://www.ey.com/en_ca/insights/mining-metals/gold-silver-and-copper-tech-and-sustainability-trends</link><description>Copper companies are leveraging digital innovations and sustainability practices to address supply gaps. Technologies like AI and satellite imaging are being used to enhance exploration and production. Recycling and circular economy principles are also key strategies to ensure long-term value and reduce environmental impact.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Glut Persists but African Mining Ambitions Remain Strong</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/1410-49523-nickel-glut-persists-but-african-mining-ambitions-remain-strong</link><description>The global nickel market is expected to remain oversupplied in 2026, with a projected surplus of 261,000 tons. Despite weak prices, African mining projects continue to advance. Nickel prices have fallen significantly since 2022.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Copper slips on US credit fears</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40388118</link><description>Copper slid to a one-week low, tracking a fall in global financial stocks as signs of credit stress at US regional banks weighed on market sentiment. The decline reflected broader concerns about credit quality in the US financial sector.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper price back on track for weekly gain as Trump calms trade angst</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/copper-price-back-on-track-for-weekly-gain-as-trump-calms-trade-angst/</link><description>Copper pared declines after US President Donald Trump eased fears of a trade war with China, boosting demand prospects for the metal. The wiring metal is on pace for a 0.5% weekly gain, having touched $11,000 a ton the previous week—the highest intraday level since May 2024—on supply concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 15,110 USD/T on October 17, 2025, down 0.79% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices decreased to $15,110 per tonne on October 17, 2025, marking a 0.79% drop from the previous day and a 1.47% decline over the past month. The price is down 11.02% compared to the same time last year, with expectations for further decline over the next 12 months.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>RMI Introduces New Sustainable Aluminum Finance Framework to Propel Industry Decarbonization</title><link>https://esgnews.com/rmi-introduces-new-sustainable-aluminum-finance-framework-to-propel-industry-decarbonization/</link><description>RMI has introduced a Sustainable Aluminum Finance Framework to help banks align financing with decarbonization goals. Aluminum is crucial for electric vehicles and renewable energy infrastructure, and decarbonizing the sector requires switching to clean power sources and increasing recycling rates.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Price Chart and Market Trends</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices rose slightly to 3,044 CNY/ton on October 17, 2025, up 0.03% from the previous day. However, steel prices have fallen 1.07% over the past month and are down 6.34% compared to last year. Forecasts expect prices to trade around 3,008.71 CNY/ton by the end of the quarter.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Global Copper Demand Projected to Outpace Supply by Over 500,000 Tonnes In 2025</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/global-copper-demand-projected-to-outpace-supply-by-over-500-000-tonnes-in-2025--driving-upward-price-pressure-302563846.html</link><description>Copper demand is expected to exceed supply by over 500,000 tonnes in 2025, leading to upward price pressure. The metal is crucial for infrastructure development, renewable energy initiatives, and agricultural modernization. Persistent supply constraints and geopolitical challenges are contributing factors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>LME nickel price maintains upward trend on Oct 19</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lme-nickel-price-maintains-upward-trend-on-oct-19/121795</link><description>The three-month futures price of nickel on the London Metal Exchange (LME) rose by US$32/ton on October 19, closing at US$15,684/ton, indicating a short-term upward trend in nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>On October 19th, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulfate index price was 32113/ton</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/102425401/</link><description>The battery-grade nickel sulfate index price dropped by 121 yuan/ton on October 19 compared to the previous working day, reflecting a slight decrease in prices for battery-grade nickel products.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Enhances Energy Performance and Reduces Environmental Impact</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA to enhance energy performance and reduce environmental impact. This agreement supports the company's decarbonization efforts and aligns with regional sustainability goals. It also benefits CVA by stabilizing energy sale prices and providing economic incentives.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Italian Steelmaker Cogne Acciai Speciali Sourcing All Energy from Renewables</title><link>https://eurometal.net/italian-steelmaker-cogne-acciai-speciali-sourcing-all-energy-from-renewables/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali now sources all its energy from renewable sources in Europe. The company plans to build a hydroelectric plant and an electrolyzer at its Aosta site to produce green hydrogen. This project is part of Italy's National Recovery and Resilience Plan.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali Launches Green Hydrogen Pilot Plant</title><link>https://yieh.com/en/News/italys-cogne-acciai-speciali-launches-green-hydrogen-pilot-plant/156769</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has launched a pilot plant in Aosta, Italy, to produce green hydrogen. This initiative is part of the company's efforts to transition towards cleaner energy sources. The project is supported by the European Union through NextGenerationEU.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Awarded The Italy-Tunisia Interconnection</title><link>https://www.prysmian.com/en/media/press-releases/prysmian-awarded-the-italy-tunisia-interconnection</link><description>Prysmian has been awarded a contract for the construction of a submarine power interconnection between Italy and Tunisia under the Elmed Project. The project aims to create an energy bridge between Europe and Africa, enhancing energy security. The contract could reach a value of around €460 million.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Secures €460m Contract For Italy–Tunisia Subsea Power Link</title><link>https://www.wireworld.com/wirenews/prysmian-secures-460m-contract-for-italytunisia-subsea-power-link.html</link><description>Prysmian has secured a contract to build a submarine power cable connecting Italy and Tunisia. The project is valued at approximately €460 million. It will enhance energy connectivity between Europe and Africa.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Green Steel &amp; Renewable Energy: Revolutionizing the Industry</title><link>https://www.allthingssupplychain.com/green-steel-renewable-energy-revolutionizing-the-industry/</link><description>Green steel production powered by renewable energy, especially green hydrogen, is transforming the steel industry by significantly reducing CO2 emissions. This innovation replaces coal in steelmaking with green hydrogen produced via electrolysis using renewable sources like wind and solar, offering a sustainable pathway for the global steel supply chain.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Global Steel Industry 2025: At a Pivotal Crossroads</title><link>https://www.steel-technology.com/articles/the-global-steel-industry-2025-at-a-pivotal-crossroads</link><description>The steel industry is undergoing major changes with AI integration, automation, and sustainability driving new production methods. Green steel production is gaining momentum as demand for low-carbon materials rises, with companies adopting sustainable steelmaking to meet zero-emission goals and attract investors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises Toward 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/490733</link><description>Aluminum futures rose toward $2,730 per tonne in October, reaching the highest level in three years amid expectations of lower supply. Chinese authorities have cut their annual output growth target for base metals to 1.5% for 2025 and 2026, down from 5%, and Alcoa announced the shutdown of its Kwinana alumina refinery in Australia due to deteriorating bauxite grades. Physical aluminum demand increased, causing primary aluminum stocks to drop by 55,000 tonnes in September before rebounding slightly.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Drops on Oct 20</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575945/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Drops-on-Oct-20</link><description>Social inventory of aluminum ingots in major domestic consumption areas dropped to 625,000 metric tons as of October 20, indicating tightening supply conditions in the domestic market. This decline in inventory aligns with broader trends of reduced aluminum availability amid strong demand.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Weekly Recap: Aluminium's low-carbon revolution in action</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/weekly-recap-aluminiums-low-carbon-revolution-in-action-115796</link><description>The global aluminum industry is rapidly transforming with a focus on sustainability, including the adoption of renewable energy, advanced recycling technologies, and innovative production methods. Highlights include RUSAL’s new electrochemical technology for high-purity recycling, Taural India’s emission-reducing initiatives, and Egypt’s Dandara Solar Energy project to cut Egyptalum’s emissions by 30%.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Stainless Mills Hold Prices Pre-Contracting</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/10/20/nickel-prices-flat-mills-hold-prices/</link><description>U.S. stainless steel prices remained flat with mills maintaining base price increases from summer, showing no further hikes or price erosion despite weak demand. Market survey indicates stable demand for 60% of respondents, with no significant oversupply or undersupply evidenced by steady mill lead times.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Coal and Steel Production Shrink Again as Demand Slumps</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-20/china-s-coal-and-steel-production-shrink-again-as-demand-slumps</link><description>China's steel production fell for the fifth consecutive month in September to its lowest level since December 2023, driven by weaker demand and government efforts to curb excessive output. Coal production also declined year-on-year due to inspections and flooding, while steel output dropped 4.6% in September amid rising feedstock costs and subdued demand.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Q2: Strong volumes boost profit, brokers maintain cautious stance</title><link>https://www.business-standard.com/markets/news/jsw-steel-q2-strong-volumes-boost-profit-brokers-maintain-cautious-stance-125102000132_1.html</link><description>JSW Steel reported a 269.7% year-on-year jump in consolidated net profit to ₹1,623 crore in Q2FY26, driven by higher sales volumes despite lower realisations. The company achieved record crude steel production of 7.90 million tonnes, with domestic sales up 14% year-on-year and exports surging 89%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's Coal and Steel Production Shrink Again as Demand Slumps</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-20/china-s-coal-and-steel-production-shrink-again-as-demand-slumps</link><description>China's coal and steel output declined in September due to weak demand and government efforts to curb excessive production. Steelmaking output dropped for the fifth consecutive month to its lowest since December 2023.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Climbs on Easing Trade Tensions, China's Economic Outlook</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-20/copper-climbs-on-easing-trade-tensions-china-s-economic-outlook</link><description>Copper prices rose more than 1% as US President Donald Trump sought to ease trade tensions with China and Beijing signaled confidence in meeting its economic growth targets. The improved sentiment around risk assets, including commodities, followed signs of reduced US-China confrontation ahead of expected trade talks later this month.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Codelco Plans to Raise Copper Premiums in Europe, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575818/Codelco-Plans-to-Raise-Copper-Premiums-in-Europe-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Chile's Codelco plans to increase copper premiums for European customers to a record $345/mt in 2026, reflecting tight global supply and rising energy costs. Meanwhile, LME copper futures saw significant intraday volatility but closed slightly lower, while SHFE copper edged up modestly amid active trading.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Commodity Radar: Copper prices cool off after Monday's sharp rally – time to buy on dips for 16% potential gains, says Religare expert</title><link>https://economictimes.com/markets/commodities/news/commodity-radar-copper-prices-cool-off-after-mondays-sharp-rally-time-to-buy-on-dips-for-16-potential-gains-says-religare-expert/articleshow/124548572.cms</link><description>Copper prices fell sharply on Tuesday following a strong rally the previous day, as investors took profits. Despite the pullback, analysts highlight ongoing supply disruptions, falling exchange inventories, and strong demand from green energy and EVs as factors supporting a bullish long-term outlook for copper.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>This ASX All Ords copper stock has almost tripled investors' money in 2025. Here's why it could keep charging higher</title><link>https://www.fool.com.au/2025/10/20/this-asx-all-ords-copper-stock-has-almost-tripled-investors-money-in-2025-heres-why-it-could-keep-charging-higher/</link><description>Aeris Resources Ltd shares have significantly increased in value due to rising copper prices and strategic positioning in the defence sector. Copper is crucial for both green energy transitions and defence applications, contributing to its demand growth. The company's operational performance and market trends suggest potential for further growth.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>TRADE REVIEW: Copper concentrate TC/RCs to be pressured in Q4 by restocking demand from smelters</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/trade-review-copper-concentrate-tc-rcs-to-be-pressured-in-q4-by-restocking-demand-from-smelters/</link><description>Copper concentrate treatment and refining charges are expected to face pressure in Q4 due to restocking demand from smelters preparing for 2026 production. This demand could impact the pricing dynamics of copper concentrates in the Asian market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ero Copper (TSX:ERO) Boost Operations Growth Listed TSX Smallcap Index</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/ca/stocks/metal-and-mining/ero-copper-tsxero-boost-operations-growth-listed-tsx-smallcap-index</link><description>Ero Copper has exceeded quarterly earnings expectations, reflecting operational efficiency. The company's Tucumã Operation has begun commercial production, contributing to increased operational capacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia releases October (Period I) benchmark prices for nickel ore</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5100101-flash-indonesia-releases-october-period-i-benchmark-prices-for-nickel-ore</link><description>The Indonesia Nickel Miners Association announced domestic benchmark prices for nickel ore for the first half of October 2025, with prices increasing slightly from September. Prices for nickel ore grades from 1.6% to 2.0% Ni content rose by $0.18 to $0.28 per wet metric ton compared to the previous period.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices edged down slightly on October 20 as China and the US agreed to hold a new round of trade consultations</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103576549/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-down-slightly-on-October-20-as-China-and-the-US-agreed-to-hold-a-new-round-of-trade-consultations-as-soon-as-possible</link><description>On October 20, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 122,100 yuan/mt, down 250 yuan/mt from the previous day. The slight price decline coincided with news of upcoming trade talks between China and the US, which may influence market sentiment.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel prices pulled back this week due to fundamental pressure and inventory levels increased further</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103575414/%5BSMM-Analysis%5D-Nickel-prices-pulled-back-this-week-due-to-fundamental-pressure-and-inventory-levels-increased-further</link><description>Nickel prices declined under pressure from fundamentals with the SHFE nickel contract closing down 1.89% week-on-week at 121,160 yuan/mt. Inventory levels increased, creating a stalemate between cost support and inventory pressure. LME nickel prices also showed weakness, settling at $15,140/mt, down 0.53% week-on-week.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Stainless Mills Hold Prices Pre-Contracting</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/10/20/nickel-prices-flat-mills-hold-prices/</link><description>Nickel prices have remained range-bound through September and October with some upward drift from summer lows. Despite this, downside risks persist due to funds shifting to net short positions and global economic headwinds. Stainless steel buyers may benefit from potential nickel price declines affecting surcharges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Poised to Exit $15K Range as Seasonal Supply Constraints Hit Market</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-prices-poised-to-exit-15k-range-as-seasonal-supply-constraints-hit-market</link><description>Nickel prices have been range-bound between $15,000 and $15,800 per ton since April 2025, but seasonal supply constraints and regulatory crackdowns in Indonesia are creating conditions for potential price increases. Growing electric vehicle demand and government support in Canada add to positive market fundamentals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Stainless Mills Hold Prices Pre-Contracting - MetalMiner</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/10/20/nickel-prices-flat-mills-hold-prices/</link><description>Nickel prices remain flat amid ample supply and a strong U.S. dollar, with little indication of a demand turnaround in the short term. Stainless steel buyers may benefit from potential declines in nickel surcharges, although global economic headwinds persist.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Sumitomo-Mitsubishi partnership underpins Kalgoorlie Nickel Project development</title><link>https://mining.com.au/sumitomo-mitsubishi-partnership-underpins-kalgoorlie-nickel-project-development/</link><description>The partnership between Sumitomo Metal Mining and Mitsubishi Corporation is driving the development of the Kalgoorlie Nickel Project (KNP) with a fully funded $98.5 million Definitive Feasibility Study. The collaboration strengthens the project's path to market and supports long-term nickel-cobalt supply security.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Kalgoorlie Nickel Project Secures Three-Year Major Status Extension</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/news/kalgoorlie-nickel-project-2025-critical-minerals-renewal/</link><description>The Kalgoorlie Nickel Project benefits from a three-year major status extension, leveraging laterite deposits with improved processing technologies for better recovery and sustainability. The joint venture between Ardea Resources, Sumitomo Metal Mining, and Mitsubishi Corporation combines Australian expertise with Japanese technology and market access to strengthen nickel production capacity.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices edged down slightly on October 20</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103576549/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-edged-down-slightly-on-October-20-as-China-and-the-US-agreed-to-hold-a-new-round-of-trade-consultations-as-soon-as-possible</link><description>Nickel prices in China edged down slightly amid ongoing trade negotiations between China and the U.S. The SHFE nickel contract showed consolidation with prices expected to remain subdued due to weak fundamentals and external uncertainties.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Vale scraps plans to build Quebec nickel sulphate facility</title><link>https://www.mining.com/vale-scraps-plans-to-build-quebec-nickel-sulphate-facility/</link><description>Vale has cancelled its C$325 million nickel sulphate plant project in Quebec after General Motors delayed its Ultium Cam battery expansion. The facility would have been North America's first fully domestic nickel sulphate plant, critical for lithium-ion battery production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali and CVA Agreement for Decarbonization</title><link>https://www.cogne.com/en/post/press-release-24</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with CVA to enhance energy performance and reduce environmental impact. The agreement supports CVA's leadership in decarbonization and provides stable revenue flows for CVA through the Energy Release scheme. It aligns with Cogne's strategic goals for sustainability.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Cogne finalizes Mannesmann tubes acquisition to expand stainless footprint</title><link>https://eurometal.net/cogne-finalizes-mannesmann-tubes-acquisition-to-expand-stainless-footprint/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes from Salzgitter for EUR 135 million, expanding its presence in the seamless tubes and stainless steel nickel alloy pipes market. The acquisition integrates Mannesmann's operations in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, enhancing Cogne's competitiveness in aerospace, automotive, and energy sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>