<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:14:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fell sharply on November 5 once again approaching the 119,000 yuan/mt mark</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103605685/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fell-sharply-on-November-5-once-again-approaching-the-119000-yuanmt-mark</link><description>On November 5, SMM #1 refined nickel prices in China dropped to a range of 119,400–122,500 yuan/mt, with the average down 850 yuan/mt from the previous day. The decline was attributed to a stronger US dollar and internal Fed disagreements, while spot premiums for domestic brands showed mixed trends.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Watchdog seeks tighter regulations on nickel mining</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/business/2025/11/05/2484839/watchdog-seeks-tighter-regulations-nickel-mining</link><description>Climate Rights International released a report titled 'Broken Promises,' calling for stricter regulations on nickel mining due to environmental and social concerns. The report highlights ongoing issues with mining practices and their impacts on local communities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Eases from 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum/news/499462</link><description>Aluminum prices eased from their recent three-year high, falling to $2,862 per tonne on November 4, 2025, amid a rebound in the dollar and uncertain demand. Despite the dip, prices remain up 7.63% compared to the same period last year.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>LME aluminium cash offer slips to USD 2,838.5/t as market steadies</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/lme-aluminium-cash-offer-slips-to-usd-2-838-5-t-as-market-steadies-for-next-move-116095</link><description>The LME aluminium 3-month Asian Reference Price slipped by USD 9 per tonne to USD 2,850 on November 5, 2025, as the market steadied after recent volatility. The price movement reflects a period of consolidation ahead of the next market move.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel prices fell to 841.98 USD/T on November 5, 2025, down 0.71% from the previous day. Over the past month, prices have risen 5.38%, and are up 19.55% compared to the same time last year. The forecast expects HRC Steel to trade at 864.45 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 934.57 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Prices Decline on Fed Uncertainty and Supply Relief</title><link>https://www.indexbox.io/blog/copper-prices-decline-on-fed-uncertainty-and-supply-relief/</link><description>Copper prices dropped as much as 2.4% amid uncertainty over US Federal Reserve monetary policy and easing concerns about global supply. The US dollar strengthened to its highest since May, pressuring metals. Despite a rally earlier in the year due to supply disruptions, expectations of increased output from major producers like Chile's Codelco are easing supply tensions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Decline Driven by Dollar Strength and Supply Shifts</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/copper-price-decline-2025-demand-supply-currency-dynamics/</link><description>Copper prices have experienced a sustained decline due to a stronger US dollar, demand uncertainties, and evolving supply conditions. The correction follows a period of strength driven by infrastructure optimism and supply disruptions, highlighting copper's sensitivity to global economic sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Firm Dollar, Worries About Demand in China Weigh on Copper</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/firm-dollar-worries-about-demand-in-china-weigh-on-copper/</link><description>Copper is expected to trade in a $10,000 to $11,000 range in the near term as a strong US dollar and concerns about Chinese demand weigh on prices. Risk sentiment deterioration and macroeconomic factors continue to influence market dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>DRC: Kamoa-Kakula Copper Mine to Get 50 MW from Inga II in November</title><link>https://www.ecofinagency.com/news-industry/0511-50137-drc-kamoa-kakula-copper-mine-to-get-50-mw-from-inga-ii-in-november</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced that its Kamoa-Kakula copper complex in the DRC will begin receiving 50 MW of power from the Inga II hydroelectric dam this November, with further increases planned as grid upgrades progress. This marks a key step in securing stable energy supply for one of the world's largest copper producers.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Critical Minerals for a Sustainable Transition Report</title><link>https://www.sydney.edu.au/sydney-environment-institute/news-analysis/news/2025/11/05/-critical-minerals-for-a-sustainable-transition-report-.html</link><description>This report examines how critical minerals like nickel are essential for the renewable energy transition but also pose environmental, social, and governance challenges. It emphasizes balancing energy security with ecosystem and community protection, advocating for equitable benefit sharing and ecological limits in mineral extraction.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Cogne Acciai Speciali acquisition by Mannesmann Stainless Tubes is complete</title><link>https://stainless-steel-world.net/cogne-acciai-speciali-acquisition-by-mannesmann-stainless-tubes-is-complete/</link><description>Cogne Acciai Speciali has completed the acquisition of Mannesmann Stainless Tubes GmbH from Salzgitter AG, expanding its production of seamless stainless steel and nickel alloy tubes. The acquisition includes facilities in Germany, France, Italy, and the US, and will strengthen Cogne’s market presence globally. The acquired company will be renamed DMV to emphasize excellence and entrepreneurship.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Lundin Mining Reports Third Quarter 2025 Results and Increases Full-Year Copper Production Guidance and Lowers Cost Guidance</title><link>https://lundinmining.com/news/lundin-mining-reports-third-quarter-2025-results-a-123218/</link><description>Lundin Mining reported strong Q3 2025 results with copper production exceeding earlier quarters. The company increased its full-year copper production guidance by 11,500 tonnes to a midpoint of 328,000 tonnes and lowered its consolidated copper cash cost guidance to $1.85 to $2.00 per pound, reflecting improved operational performance, especially at Caserones and Chapada.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Commission opens in-depth investigation into the proposed acquisition of Anglo American's nickel business by MMG</title><link>https://europeansting.com/2025/11/05/commission-opens-in-depth-investigation-into-the-proposed-acquisition-of-anglo-americans-nickel-business-by-mmg/</link><description>The European Commission has launched an in-depth investigation into MMG's proposed acquisition of Anglo American's nickel business, citing concerns that MMG could divert ferronickel supply away from European markets. This could increase costs and reduce quality for European stainless steel producers, impacting the critical nickel supply chain in Europe.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fell sharply on November 5</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103605685/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-fell-sharply-on-November-5-once-again-approaching-the-119000-yuanmt-mark</link><description>Nickel prices on the SHFE fell sharply on November 5, approaching 119,000 yuan/mt before a slight rebound. The US dollar index rose to a three-month high, impacting nickel prices, while China's central bank conducted significant liquidity operations to maintain banking system stability.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Domestic Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Dips Slightly to 622,000 mt on Nov 6</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103606812/Domestic-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-Slightly-to-622000-mt-on-Nov-6</link><description>Social inventory of aluminum ingots in China dipped slightly to 622,000 metric tons on November 6, 2025. Prices closed above most short-term moving averages despite a pullback from intraday highs.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Backing in Bell Bay Aluminium</title><link>https://www.premier.tas.gov.au/latest-news/2025/november/backing-in-bell-bay-aluminium</link><description>The Tasmanian government has secured a 12-month power agreement to ensure the immediate future of Bell Bay Aluminium, preserving 550 jobs and $700 million in annual economic activity. The agreement allows time for further negotiations with Rio Tinto and the federal government on a long-term plan for the smelter, which is highlighted as one of Australia's greenest due to its hydroelectric power sourcing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Bell Bay Aluminium Deal: Tasmanian Gov 12-Month Agreement</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/tasmanian-government-bell-bay-aluminium-deal-2025/</link><description>Tasmania's government has reached a 12-month emergency deal for Bell Bay Aluminium, safeguarding jobs and the smelter's economic impact. The article compares Bell Bay's 190,000-tonne annual capacity and 94% hydroelectric energy profile favorably against mainland Australian smelters, emphasizing its low-carbon, premium market positioning amid national energy transition challenges.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Secondary Aluminium: Powering India's Green Growth, Circular Economy, and Global Competitiveness</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/secondary-aluminium-powering-indias-green-growth-circular-economy-and-global-competitiveness-116096</link><description>A press release highlights the growing role of secondary (recycled) aluminium in India's green growth strategy and circular economy. It underscores how recycled aluminium is enhancing India's global competitiveness in the metals sector, though specific production or capacity figures are not provided.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Russel Metals Announces 2025 Third Quarter Results</title><link>https://www.mining.com/press-release?id=690bd77a36ca8728810b704e</link><description>Steel prices increased substantially in early 2025 due to U.S. tariffs, but margins moderated in the third quarter as higher inventory costs impacted profitability. The company expects fourth quarter margins to remain consistent with the end of the third quarter, with seasonal reductions in shipments.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Products Market Expanding With $523.49 Billion at 3.8% CAGR by 2029</title><link>https://www.einpresswire.com/article/864489154/steel-products-market-expanding-with-523-49-billion-at-3-8-cagr-by-2029</link><description>The steel products market is projected to grow from $437.06 billion in 2024 to $450.21 billion in 2025, with a CAGR of 3.0%. Growth is expected to continue, reaching $523.49 billion by 2029, driven by infrastructure development, automotive industry demand, and technological advances.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel Prices in the First Week of November 2025</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/37765/</link><description>Steel coil prices showed overall stability in the first week of November 2025, with wire rod prices at $555–565 per ton FOB Turkey and hot-rolled flat steel at $455–460 per ton. The market remains steady with little fluctuation in regional pricing.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nucor Increases Hot-Rolled Coil Prices for Second Week</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/germany-convenes-steel-summit-in-light-of-ongoing-crisis-in-the-sector/</link><description>Nucor raised its hot-rolled coil prices to $890 per ton in early November 2025, marking the second consecutive weekly increase. This signals market stabilization and could influence broader price trends in the U.S. steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany Convenes Steel Summit in Light of Ongoing Crisis in the Sector</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/germany-convenes-steel-summit-in-light-of-ongoing-crisis-in-the-sector/</link><description>Germany held a steel summit on November 6, 2025, to address the ongoing crisis in the sector. Government and business leaders discussed support measures for the struggling steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nippon Steel US Market Challenges: $15B Acquisition Losses</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/nippon-steel-us-market-challenges-2025/</link><description>Nippon Steel reported a 356.8 billion yen loss amid challenging US market conditions, excluding American operations from guidance. The steel industry faces a perfect storm of demand weakness and structural changes, with declining construction activity, shifts in automotive steel requirements due to electric vehicles, and energy sector preferences for alternative materials.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Pipe and Steel Industrial Fabricators Announces Second Expansion in Two Years to Further Strengthen Louisiana’s Industrial Manufacturing Base</title><link>https://www.opportunitylouisiana.gov/news/pipe-and-steel-industrial-fabricators-announces-second-expansion-in-two-years-to-further-strengthen-louisianas-industrial-manufacturing-base</link><description>Pipe and Steel Industrial Fabricators is investing $5.1 million to expand its steel processing and fabrication facility in Livingston Parish, Louisiana, increasing beam-cutting capacity and creating 56 new jobs. The expansion aims to enhance efficiency, safety, and production capacity, supporting growth in Louisiana’s manufacturing sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Baosteel has reduced its steel production targets</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/baosteel-has-reduced-its-steel-production-targets/</link><description>Baosteel has lowered its steel production targets despite a 10.9% increase in production to 5.17 million tons in the first nine months of 2025. The company is likely to exceed the stated target for the year but is adjusting goals in response to market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Germany convenes steel summit in light of ongoing crisis in the sector</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/germany-convenes-steel-summit-in-light-of-ongoing-crisis-in-the-sector/</link><description>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz has invited government and business leaders to a steel summit on November 6 to discuss support measures for the struggling steel industry amid ongoing crises. The summit aims to find solutions for energy costs, overcapacity, and industry sustainability.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World Steel Association: Climate Change and Steel Production</title><link>https://worldsteel.org</link><description>The World Steel Association released a policy paper on November 6, 2025, outlining pathways to reduce CO2 emissions and promote sustainable practices in steel production. The association emphasizes transparent data disclosure, resource efficiency, and a commitment to a low-carbon future.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper Just Set a Record. The Market's Already Having Second Thoughts</title><link>https://m.fastbull.com/news-detail/copper-just-set-a-record-the-markets-already-news_4200_0_2025_4_4963_3/4200_GC2511</link><description>Copper prices recently hit a record high but declined 2.6% to $10,897/mt amid concerns that supply shortfalls may be offset by scrap exports and increased mine supply from marginal producers. Analysts from Goldman Sachs suggest copper prices may remain within the $10,000 to $11,000 range without a sustained breakout higher.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Pumpkin Hollow Copper Mine Production Resumption Receives Support, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Higher Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103606685/Pumpkin-Hollow-Copper-Mine-Production-Resumption-Receives-Support-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Higher-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Kinterra Capital and Southwest Critical Materials LLC received a non-binding letter of interest from the U.S. Export-Import Bank for up to $220 million to support the restart of the Pumpkin Hollow copper mine, with $180 million earmarked for underground operations and $20 million for technical work on the southern open-pit project. Meanwhile, LME copper futures closed higher at $10,733/mt, up 0.79%, amid active trading.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Kenadyr Provides Operational Update on the Adelita Copper-Gold-Silver Project and Status Update of Reactivation Transaction</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/KNDYF/kenadyr-provides-operational-update-on-the-adelita-copper-gold-wir6mh8avw4r.html</link><description>Kenadyr announced that Phase 1 exploration at the Adelita Copper-Gold-Silver Project in Mexico will begin in November 2025, including drilling and geophysical surveys, as the project prepares for reactivation under new ownership. The project is fully permitted, with final transaction approvals pending.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices were in the doldrums on November 6</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103607793/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-were-in-the-doldrums-on-November-6-as-the-US-ADP-employment-figure-for-October-increased-by-42000-exceeding-market-expectations</link><description>On November 6, the SMM #1 refined nickel price ranged between 118,900 and 122,100 yuan per metric ton, averaging 120,500 yuan/mt, which is down 450 yuan/mt from the previous day. The price decline reflects ongoing weakness in the nickel market amid broader economic factors.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME's nickel price goes up on Nov 6</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/ru/NewsItem/144578</link><description>Nickel futures prices at the London Metal Exchange increased by over $200 per ton on November 6, closing at $18,445 per ton. The nickel spot price also saw gains, indicating some short-term upward movement despite broader market weakness.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>LME's nickel prices slightly increase on Nov 6</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/lmes-nickel-prices-slightly-increase-on-nov-6/151128</link><description>Nickel futures prices on the London Metal Exchange slightly increased by $4 per ton, closing at $16,127 per ton on November 6. This modest rise contrasts with other reports of price declines, suggesting some volatility in nickel pricing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Midday Review</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103608007/</link><description>Nickel prices remained weak on November 6, 2025, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 120,500 yuan/mt, down 450 yuan/mt from the previous day. The market sentiment was subdued following stronger-than-expected US employment data.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>BofA Sees Growth Potential for Prysmian from US Tariffs</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/bofa-sees-growth-potential-for-prysmian-from-us-tariffs-ce7d59dddf88f323</link><description>Bank of America estimates Prysmian could raise copper cable prices by 10% due to US tariffs, potentially increasing 2026 EBITDA by up to EUR1 billion. Prysmian's copper cable production is largely US-based after acquiring Encore Wire, benefiting from tariffs on imports, especially in medium- and low-voltage segments.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Prysmian lifts 2025 outlook after Q3 beat on strong transmission growth</title><link>https://www.investing.com/news/earnings/prysmian-lifts-2025-outlook-after-q3-beat-on-strong-transmission-growth-4317981</link><description>Prysmian raised its full-year 2025 guidance after reporting Q3 revenue of €5.03 billion, beating expectations. Growth was driven by strong performance in Renewable Transmission and Power Grids units, with a stable high-voltage backlog of about €16 billion supporting future prospects.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Aluminum price hits three-year high as US-China truce buoys outlook</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-price-hits-three-year-high-as-us-china-truce-buoys-outlook/</link><description>Aluminum futures on the London Metal Exchange reached $2,902 a metric ton, the highest since May 2022, supported by China's production caps and easing US-China trade tensions. Despite positive demand outlooks, risks remain due to slowing momentum in China's economy, with recent manufacturing surveys showing declines.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel and petrochemical restructuring</title><link>https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/opinion/editorial/20251106/ed-steel-and-petrochemical-restructuring</link><description>South Korea's steel industry is facing a severe downturn due to oversupply, weak domestic demand, and global protectionism. The government has introduced a Steel Industry Advancement Plan aimed at reducing production capacity for rebar and other general-purpose steel products, alongside limited financial aid to export-oriented firms. However, critics warn that without stronger measures to offset losses or ease cost pressures, the plan may fail to achieve meaningful reform.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SKF Presents a Novel Bearing Steel Designed to Enable the Next Generation of Aeroengine Technology</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2025/11/06/skf-presents-a-novel-bearing-steel-designed-to-enable-the-next-generation-of-aeroengine-technology/</link><description>SKF has introduced a new bearing steel that accelerates development cycles and supports future sustainability goals in the aerospace industry. This innovation is expected to enhance performance and durability in next-generation aeroengines.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices rose to 4.99 USD/lb on November 6, up 0.39% from the previous day, but have declined 1.28% over the past month. Despite recent volatility, copper remains 13.07% higher than a year ago, with forecasts predicting further increases in the coming months.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper prices drop on Fed policy uncertainty and Codelco supply</title><link>https://www.miningreporters.com/noticia/news/2025/11/copper-price-falls-fed-policy-codelco-supply</link><description>Copper prices fell on renewed uncertainty about US interest rates and easing supply concerns after positive production signals from Chilean miner Codelco. LME copper dropped as much as 2.4% to around $10,855 per tonne, while COMEX prices hovered near $5.013 per pound.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Indonesia limits new nickel permits to add value to production</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/indonesia-limits-new-nickel-permits-to-add-value-to-production/</link><description>Indonesia has stopped approving new permits for nickel plants producing intermediate products like nickel pig iron and mixed hydroxide precipitate unless they plan further processing. This move aims to push the world's largest nickel producer further up the value chain and address oversupply issues. The regulation may delay or cancel projects finishing after 2027, impacting the nickel industry's growth trajectory in Indonesia.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel to Attend North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference 2025</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/06/3182419/0/en/First-Atlantic-Nickel-to-Attend-North-American-Stainless-Special-Alloys-Conference-2025-Highlighting-Pipestone-XL-Nickel-Alloy-Project-s-Smelter-Free-Processing-and-Chromium-Byprod.html</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel announced its participation in the North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference to showcase its Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project. The project features a unique nickel-iron-cobalt alloy mineral that allows smelter-free processing, reducing energy use and environmental impact. This discovery in Newfoundland addresses critical supply chain vulnerabilities for nickel, cobalt, and chromium in North America.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Caraga faces environmental damage from nickel mining</title><link>https://www.bulatlat.com/2025/11/06/caraga-faces-environmental-damage-from-nickel-mining/</link><description>The Caraga region is experiencing environmental damage due to nickel mining activities. The report highlights concerns over ecological degradation and the impact on local communities. This situation underscores the environmental challenges associated with nickel production in mining regions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Canada Nickel Zero-Carbon Industrial Cluster Hub</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/zero-carbon-industrial-cluster-canada-nickel-2025/</link><description>Canada Nickel Company is pioneering a zero-carbon industrial cluster in Ontario that transforms mining waste into hydrogen, fertilizer, and carbon storage products. This innovative approach integrates carbon sequestration technology with mining operations to create a carbon-negative industrial ecosystem, enhancing project economics and supporting regional decarbonization goals.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel to Attend North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference 2025</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/06/3182419/0/en/First-Atlantic-Nickel-to-Attend-North-American-Stainless-Special-Alloys-Conference-2025-Highlighting-Pipestone-XL-Nickel-Alloy-Project-s-Smelter-Free-Processing-and-Chromium-Byprod.html</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel will showcase its Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project, which features a smelter-free processing method using awaruite, a nickel-iron-cobalt alloy mineral. This technology reduces energy use and environmental impact by eliminating overseas smelting, supporting a resilient North American critical minerals supply chain for nickel, cobalt, and chromium.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Australian battery system technology to be assessed for SSN-AUKUS nuclear-powered submarines</title><link>https://www.baesystems.com/en/article/australian-battery-system-technology-to-be-assessed-for-ssn-aukus-design</link><description>Australian nickel zinc battery technology developed by PMB Defence Engineering is set for assessment to integrate into the SSN-AUKUS nuclear-powered submarine program. This innovation highlights the strategic role of nickel-based battery systems in advanced defense applications, emphasizing sustainability and performance.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian Could Be a Relative Winner From Trump's Copper Tariff</title><link>https://m.fastbull.com/news-detail/prysmian-could-be-a-relative-winner-from-trumps-news_8600_0_2025_3_929_3/8600_NAT.GAS</link><description>Citi analysts suggest Prysmian may benefit from President Trump's proposed 50% tariff on copper due to its vertically integrated US copper operations, including sourcing from a Freeport mine and a copper rod mill in Texas. This gives Prysmian a competitive edge over smaller players, potentially driving share price gains.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SHFE Aluminum Hits New Yearly High in Night Session, Aluminum Prices Continue to Fluctuate at Highs</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Aluminum</link><description>SHFE aluminum prices reached a new yearly high during the night session, with prices expected to trade between 21,300-21,900 yuan/mt next week. Despite environmental restrictions impacting production, supply changes are expected to be small, while demand may weaken next month. Inventory pressure is rising as the peak season ends, but overall macro sentiment remains optimistic with aluminum prices fluctuating at high levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Macro sentiment is strong at home and abroad, and aluminium prices continue to fluctuate at highs</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/macro-sentiment-strong-at-home-and-abroad-aluminium-prices-continue-to-fluctuate-at-highs-116109</link><description>Domestic aluminum production in China increased by 1.13% year-over-year in October 2025, with aluminum ingot inventory slightly rising to 622,000 tonnes. Despite limited fundamental drivers, optimistic macroeconomic conditions both domestically and internationally support aluminum prices fluctuating at high levels. SHFE aluminum is expected to trade between 21,300-21,900 yuan per tonne, while LME aluminum is forecasted between USD 2,830-2,930 per tonne.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever Partner to Launch the First Use of ELYSIS Carbon-Free Smelting Technology in Consumer Packaging</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251105083984/en/Alcoa-Ball-and-Unilever-Partner-to-Launch-the-First-Use-of-ELYSIS-Carbon-Free-Smelting-Technology-in-Consumer-Personal-and-Home-Care-Packaging</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever have collaborated to introduce ELYSIS carbon-free aluminum smelting technology in consumer personal and home care packaging. This partnership aims to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and promote sustainable aluminum production, aligning with global decarbonization goals and growing consumer demand for low-carbon products.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball and Unilever Partner to Launch the First Use of ELYSIS Carbon-Free Smelting Technology in Consumer Personal and Home Care Packaging</title><link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251105083984/en/Alcoa-Ball-and-Unilever-Partner-to-Launch-the-First-Use-of-ELYSIS-Carbon-Free-Smelting-Technology-in-Consumer-Personal-and-Home-Care-Packaging</link><description>Alcoa, Ball Corporation, and Unilever have collaborated to launch the first consumer packaging using ELYSIS carbon-free aluminum smelting technology, marking a significant step toward decarbonizing the aluminum sector. This innovation combines higher recycled content with low-carbon primary aluminum, showcasing cross-industry collaboration for sustainable manufacturing.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever Pioneer Carbon-Free Aluminum in Consumer Packaging</title><link>https://marketchameleon.com/articles/b/2025/11/6/alcoa-ball-unilever-elysis-carbon-free-aluminum-packaging</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever have introduced the world’s first consumer personal and home care packaging made with ELYSIS carbon-free aluminum, leveraging inert anode technology to eliminate greenhouse gas emissions from smelting. The project highlights how supply chain collaboration can accelerate low-carbon innovation and support global climate goals.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Europe heavy steel plate prices buoyed by CBAM cost pressures</title><link>https://eurometal.net/europe-heavy-steel-plate-prices-buoyed-by-cbam-cost-pressures-strong-slab-offers-lack-of-imports/</link><description>Domestic heavy steel plate prices in Europe remained strong in the week ending November 6, supported by the EU's impending Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) cost pressures. The market is also influenced by strong slab offers and a lack of imports, which are sustaining price levels.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Europe heavy steel plate prices buoyed by CBAM cost pressures and strong slab offers</title><link>https://eurometal.net/europe-heavy-steel-plate-prices-buoyed-by-cbam-cost-pressures-strong-slab-offers-lack-of-imports/</link><description>Domestic heavy steel plate prices in Europe remained strong due to the EU's upcoming Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) and limited imports. Cost pressures and robust slab offers have supported price levels in the European steel plate market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Vedanta Resources Launches CopperTech Metals to Bolster U.S. Copper Security and Advance Technology and Infrastructure Transformation</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/business-wire/20251106537189/vedanta-resources-launches-coppertech-metals-to-bolster-us-copper-security-and-advance-technology-and-infrastructure-transformation</link><description>Vedanta Resources launched CopperTech Metals, a U.S.-domiciled company focused on expanding copper production from the Konkola Copper Mines in Zambia. The company plans to increase production from 140,000 tonnes in FY26 to 300,000 tonnes by 2031, with ambitions to reach 500,000 tonnes annually, leveraging advanced mining and AI-driven technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>CopperTech Metals Launch: High-Grade Mining Investment</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/coppertech-metals-launch-2025-strategic-vision/</link><description>CopperTech Metals launched with a focus on high-grade copper mining assets in Zambia, boasting ore grades of 2.9–3.3% copper, significantly above global averages. The company emphasizes integrated operations and advanced technology to maximize efficiency and profitability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Dixie Gold Inc. Readies for a Tightening Copper Environment with the Soo East Copper Project</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/273408/Dixie-Gold-Inc.-Readies-for-a-Tightening-Copper-Environment-with-the-Soo-East-Copper-Project-Divests-Interest-in-Preston-JV</link><description>Dixie Gold Inc. has acquired the Soo East Copper Project in Ontario, comprising 137 mining claims over approximately 3,013 hectares. This acquisition follows recent high-grade copper discoveries nearby and positions the company to capitalize on tightening copper supply conditions. The project aims to leverage exploration advances to meet growing copper demand sustainably.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Surging: Bull Run Amid Supply Crunches</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2024/11/27/aluminum-prices-to-surge/</link><description>Global aluminum prices have surged to a five-month high, reaching around $2,710 a tonne on November 7, 2025, driven by economic growth, supply concerns, and the impact of China's production caps. Supply constraints are exacerbated by halted bauxite exports from Guinea and reduced output from Australia and Jamaica, causing inventories to drop to their lowest since 2015.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>CBA CEO signals Brazilian aluminum export shift</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/cba-ceo-signals-brazilian-aluminium-export-shift/</link><description>Brazilian aluminum producer CBA is shifting its product mix toward ingots to meet demand and redirecting volumes from U.S. to European customers amid tariff-driven market changes. Despite increased competition and tariffs, CBA maintains a competitive advantage with low-carbon products and strong client relationships, while U.S. Midwest aluminum premiums hit historic highs due to inventory depletion.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Price Difference Between Steel Coil and Steel Screw Contracts</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103028892</link><description>On November 7, the price gap between the main contract for steel coil and steel screw was 154 yuan/ton, down 10 yuan/ton from the previous day. This reflects ongoing volatility and narrowing margins in the Chinese steel futures market.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China Steel Glut Threatens Japan Trading Houses in 2025</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/china-steel-export-surge-2025-market-disruption/</link><description>China's record steel exports in 2025, exceeding 100 million tons annually, are causing market disruption and financial pressure on Japan's major trading houses. The oversupply is driven by weak domestic demand and unchanged production capacity, leading to aggressive export strategies.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metallus Announces Third-Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/metallus-announces-third-quarter-2025-results-302607495.html</link><description>Metallus reports Q3 2025 results and provides an outlook for Q4, noting lower expected shipments and adjusted EBITDA due to seasonality and supply chain issues. The company anticipates a slight increase in base prices for bar and tube products, with extended lead times into early 2026.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>150 Small Steel Mills in India Halt Production Due to Low Prices</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/150-small-steel-mills-in-india-have-suspended-operations-due-to-low-steel-prices/</link><description>Approximately 150 small steel mills in India have suspended operations because of excessively low steel prices, highlighting the financial strain on smaller producers amid challenging market conditions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 07, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-07-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd's share price rose by 0.15% to ₹1,155.70, reflecting positive market sentiment despite broader industry challenges. The update provides real-time insight into investor confidence in one of India's largest steel producers.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Trump expands critical minerals list to copper, met coal, uranium</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-11-07/national/politics/Trump-expands-critical-minerals-list-to-copper-met-coal-uranium/2438979</link><description>The Trump administration added 10 minerals, including metallurgical coal used for steel production, to the U.S. critical minerals list to boost domestic mining and reduce reliance on imports from China. This expansion supports federal investments and incentives to secure materials vital for defense, manufacturing, and clean energy, aiming to strengthen U.S. supply chains against global disruptions.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Metallus Announces Third-Quarter 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/metallus-announces-third-quarter-2025-results-302607495.html</link><description>Metallus reported its Q3 2025 financial results and highlighted a new long-term supply agreement for vacuum arc remelt (VAR) steel, securing a stable, high-quality steel source to support growth in aerospace and defense markets. The company is targeting $250 million in annual aerospace and defense sales by mid-2026 and continues labor negotiations with the United Steelworkers union.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>A billion lessons for green iron in Australia</title><link>https://ieefa.org/articles/billion-lessons-green-iron-australia</link><description>Australia is investing $1 billion in developing a green iron industry, aiming to learn from the experiences of Europe and the US in transitioning to sustainable steel production. The initiative reflects growing global interest in decarbonizing steel manufacturing to meet environmental goals.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Composite Metal Foam Could Lead to Safer Hazmat Transportation</title><link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-composite-metal-foam-safer-hazmat.html</link><description>A new study reveals that composite metal foam (CMF) can withstand extreme forces, making it a promising material for safer transportation of hazardous materials. This innovation could significantly improve safety standards in the steel and transportation sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Trump expands critical minerals list to copper, met coal, uranium</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2025-11-07/national/politics/Trump-expands-critical-minerals-list-to-copper-met-coal-uranium/2438979</link><description>The U.S. administration expanded its critical minerals list to include copper, metallurgical coal, and uranium, emphasizing copper's importance for electric vehicles, power grids, and data centers. This move aims to boost domestic mining, reduce reliance on imports from China, and guide federal investments and incentives to secure supply chains for defense and clean energy technologies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Update: Q3 2025 in Review</title><link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/nickel-price-update-q3-2025-review</link><description>Nickel prices were volatile in the first half of 2025 but stabilized in Q3 amid ongoing oversupply concerns driven mainly by rapid production growth in Indonesia. Despite rising demand, the market remains structurally oversupplied, with LME nickel stockpiles increasing significantly through the third quarter. The end of the US EV tax credit on September 30 may also impact future nickel demand in the electric vehicle sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Falling Stainless Prices Drag Suppliers</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2024/11/07/steel-nickel-prices-drag-suppliers/</link><description>Chinese primary nickel prices fell 7.06% to $15,940 per metric ton, while Indian prices dropped 8.54%, reflecting a bearish trend in nickel following a decline in stainless steel prices. The stainless steel market remains weak due to contraction in the U.S. manufacturing sector, with major producers reporting year-over-year sales declines, further pressuring nickel demand and prices.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Futures Fall to Over 1-Month Low</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel/news/492981</link><description>Nickel futures dropped below $15,100 per tonne, the lowest level in over a month, due to continued oversupply from Indonesia. Indonesian production has flooded global supply chains, pushing LME inventories to a record high of 308,000 tons. In response, Indonesia has tightened production quotas and mining permit regulations to stabilize prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Stellantis terminates Alliance Nickel offtake deal</title><link>https://www.miningweekly.com/article/stellantis-terminates-alliance-nickel-offtake-deal-2025-11-07</link><description>Stellantis has ended its nickel offtake agreement with Alliance due to falling nickel prices and tighter financing conditions, which have delayed project progress. The termination reflects the challenging market environment for nickel amid price declines and financial constraints.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>First Atlantic Nickel to Attend North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference 2025</title><link>https://investingnews.com/first-atlantic-nickel-to-attend-north-american-stainless-special-alloys-conference-2025-highlighting-pipestone-xl-nickel-alloy-project-s-smelter-free-processing-and-chromium-byproduct-potential-for-no/</link><description>First Atlantic Nickel announced its participation in the North American Stainless &amp; Special Alloys Conference, highlighting its Pipestone XL Nickel Alloy Project. The project features a unique nickel-iron-cobalt alloy mineral, awaruite, which allows for smelter-free processing and supports a resilient domestic supply chain amid ongoing nickel market volatility and oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Alliance Nickel's Offtake Agreement with Stellantis to be Renegotiated</title><link>https://www.sharecafe.com.au/2025/11/07/alliance-nickels-offtake-agreement-with-stellantis-to-be-renegotiated/</link><description>Alliance Nickel announced that Stellantis has provided notice of termination for their binding offtake agreement effective December 3, 2025, due to missed contractual milestones amid challenging nickel market conditions. Stellantis remains interested in renegotiating terms aligned with the revised project timeline and market environment. Alliance Nickel is also exploring strategic alternatives including a potential SPAC transaction for a Nasdaq listing.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Indonesia tightens nickel smelter licensing, limits new projects</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/indonesia-tightens-nickel-smelter-licensing-limits-new-projects</link><description>The Indonesian government has officially restricted new investment permits for nickel smelters by tightening licensing requirements. This policy aims to push the nickel industry towards higher value-added processing and control the rapid expansion of smelting capacity. The move is expected to impact new projects and investment decisions in Indonesia's nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Rises to Over 3-Year High Amid Tight Supply and China's Production Cap</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK rose to $2,915 per tonne, the highest in over three years, driven by tight supply and China's commitment to preventing overcapacity with an annual output cap of 45 million tons. Prices rose 0.45% to $2,856.95 USD/T on November 7, 2025, with forecasts expecting prices to reach $2,918.78 USD/T by the end of the quarter and $3,053.09 in 12 months.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US aluminum scrap trade faces 2025 shake-up amid tariffs and global demand</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5101605-us-aluminum-scrap-trade-faces-2025-shake-up-amid-tariffs-and-global-demand</link><description>The US aluminum scrap trade experienced significant changes in early 2025 due to new import tariffs and shifting global demand. Imports of aluminum scrap rose 31% in the first half of 2025 compared to the previous year, despite a 25% import tariff implemented in March. This tariff led recyclers to increasingly rely on domestic scrap recovery rather than foreign imports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Pioneering Sustainable Practices Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever Lead with Carbon-Free Smelting Technology</title><link>https://csimarket.com/news/pioneering-sustainable-practices-alcoa-ball-and-unilever-lead-with-carbon-free-smelting-technology2025-11-07140104</link><description>Alcoa, Ball, and Unilever are leading the way in sustainable aluminum technology by deploying ELYSIS carbon-free smelting for consumer packaging. This initiative demonstrates how material innovation and industry collaboration can drive tangible sustainability benefits and reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel prices fall slightly amid ongoing market adjustments</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel prices fell to 3,034 CNY/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.16% from the previous day. Over the past month, steel prices have declined by 1.97% and are down 6.07% compared to the same time last year. The price is expected to trade at 3,039.40 Yuan/MT by the end of the quarter and 2,904.76 Yuan/MT in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>HRC Steel prices show modest decline but remain up year-on-year</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/hrc-steel</link><description>HRC Steel traded flat at 847 USD/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.35% from the previous day. Despite the slight daily drop, prices have risen 3.82% over the past month and are up 19.39% compared to the same time last year. Forecasts expect HRC Steel to reach 864.45 USD/T by the end of the quarter and 934.57 USD/T in 12 months.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Klöckner sharpens US focus as Americas segment delivers strong Q3</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/07/klockner-sharpens-us-focus-as-americas-segment-delivers-strong-q3/</link><description>Klöckner Metals Americas reported robust earnings in Q3 2025 despite softer steel prices, with shipments up 2.8% year-on-year. The company is selling eight US distribution sites to focus more on higher-value-added metal processing, aiming to reduce exposure to volatile commodity markets and increase service center business to 87% of sales.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>U.S. Steel posts strong Q3 as Nippon centers it in global growth strategy</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/07/u-s-steel-posts-strong-q3-as-nippon-centers-it-in-global-growth-strategy/</link><description>U.S. Steel reported a 15% increase in net sales to $4.43 billion in Q3 2025, driven by strong performance in its Mini Mill and Tubular segments. Despite higher costs and weaker European demand reducing net income by 16% year over year to $100 million, the Mini Mill segment saw an 86% sales increase and improved margins due to higher prices and contributions from Big River Steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Iron ore logs weekly loss on soft steel demand, production cuts in China</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/iron-ore-logs-weekly-loss-on-soft-steel-demand-production-cuts-in-china/</link><description>Blast furnace production cuts in North China, a major steelmaking region, have led to a decline in steel output, contributing to a weekly loss in iron ore prices. The reduced steel demand and production adjustments reflect ongoing challenges in the Chinese steel sector.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China will promote value-added steel production</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/china-will-promote-value-added-steel-production/</link><description>China's annual steel production is expected to fall below 1 billion tons for the first time in six years by the end of 2025, driven by declining demand. The country plans to focus on promoting value-added steel production to adapt to changing market conditions and improve product quality.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>USWC's Rare November Bulk Scrap Cargo Sale to Turkey</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/scrap-metal-trade-anomaly-2025-rare-cargo-turkey/</link><description>The U.S. West Coast (USWC) sold a rare bulk scrap cargo to Turkey amid disruptions in Asian scrap markets, creating a unique arbitrage opportunity. Turkey remains a major scrap importer with strong demand for premium scrap grades, benefiting from geographic advantages and electric arc furnace technology adoption.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Falls on Fed Policy, Codelco Supply</title><link>https://www.miningreporters.com/noticia/news/2025/11/copper-price-falls-fed-policy-codelco-supply</link><description>Copper extended losses as renewed uncertainty over US interest rates and positive production signals from Chile's Codelco eased supply fears, with LME three-month copper around $10,855/tonne and COMEX near $5.013/lb. The US dollar's strength and mixed signals from Fed officials further pressured prices, though copper remains up over 20% in 2025.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Set for Weekly Drop</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper/news/500126</link><description>Copper futures steadied around $4.95/lb but were set for a weekly loss amid a global risk-off mood, weak Chinese trade data, and speculation about Beijing curbing copper refining overcapacity. Concerns over AI valuations and a prolonged US government shutdown added to the cautious market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 15020 USD/T on November 7, 2025, down 0.23% from the previous day</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices decreased to 15,020 USD per tonne on November 7, 2025, marking a 0.23% drop from the previous day. Over the past month, nickel prices fell by 2.40%, and are down 8.01% compared to the same time last year, reflecting ongoing oversupply concerns and muted momentum in the market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The world nickel market in 2025 – a growing surplus in an uncertain global landscape</title><link>https://stainless-steel-world.net/the-world-nickel-market-in-2025-a-growing-surplus-in-an-uncertain-global-landscape/</link><description>Global primary nickel production is projected to grow by 5.9% in 2025, contributing to a growing surplus amid record-high EV sales and rising stainless steel production. LME and SHFE nickel inventories have been rising steadily, surpassing 230,000 tonnes in early 2025, reflecting ongoing oversupply despite geopolitical uncertainties.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Supply Woes: Innovations Steering a Sustainable EV Future</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-supply-woes-innovations-steering-a-sustainable-ev-future-aemc/</link><description>This article discusses the critical role of nickel in battery technology for electric vehicles (EVs) and highlights innovations such as low-nickel or nickel-free battery chemistries, advanced battery recycling, and smaller battery sizes to ensure sustainability. It also emphasizes financial incentives and policies like the U.S. Inflation Reduction Act and the EU’s Battery Fund to boost domestic battery production and mining capacities.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Greening nickel extraction requires institutional and financial support</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-01811-8</link><description>The article highlights the environmental challenges of nickel mining, particularly the greenhouse gas emissions from clearing carbon-rich forests. It stresses the need for institutional and financial backing to scale up low-carbon nickel extraction technologies to reduce the industry's carbon footprint.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Green steel revolution: navigating a new frontier in 2025</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/green-steel-revolution-navigating-a-new-frontier-in-2025/</link><description>Sweden is set to produce the world's first zero-carbon emission steel in 2025, marking a historic milestone for the industry. The shift to green steel, driven by hydrogen-based direct reduction iron and scrap-based electric arc furnace technologies, will reshape pricing, markets, and supply chains, though challenges remain around energy costs and infrastructure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Coarse Particle Flotation: Mining Recovery Revolution</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/coarse-particle-flotation-technology-2025-benefits/</link><description>Coarse particle flotation (CPF) technology is transforming mineral processing by enabling efficient recovery of valuable minerals from larger particles, improving sustainability and operational efficiency in mining. The technology reduces energy and water use, minimizes tailings, and is gaining rapid adoption across major mining operations.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>Copper Strengthens as Trade Tensions Ease</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-strengthens-as-trade-tensions-ease/</link><description>Copper prices rose on Friday, supported by signs of easing trade tensions between major economies, providing some relief after recent declines driven by Fed uncertainty and supply dynamics.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Maxus Mining Announces Closing of Flow Through Private Placement</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/6239431</link><description>Maxus Mining closed a flow-through private placement, supporting exploration at its Penny Copper Project in British Columbia. The project has returned high copper values in grab samples, indicating potential for future copper production.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>SMM News Flash: High-Nickel Pig Iron Prices Decline on November 8</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103030296/SMM-News-Flash:-High-Nickel-Pig-Iron-Prices-Decline-on-November-8</link><description>SMM reported that the price range for 8-12% high-nickel pig iron (ex-factory price) declined to 1005~1025 yuan/nickel on November 8, 2025. The drop reflects ongoing market pressures and subdued demand in the nickel sector.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>