<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Metals Industry News Feed</title><link>https://github.com/XrayFinanceDEV/aluminum-news-automation</link><description>Automated news feed for aluminum, steel, copper, and nickel industries</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:17:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CISA mills' daily crude steel output up 6.0 percent in early November 2025, stocks also up</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/cisa-mills-daily-crude-steel-output-up-60-percent-in-early-november-2025-stocks-also-up-1419574.htm</link><description>The China Iron and Steel Association reported a 6.0% increase in average daily crude steel output of large and medium-sized steel enterprises in China during November 1-10, 2025, compared to late October. Finished steel inventories also rose by 5.9% to 15.49 million metric tons as of November 10.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel news and insights about steel market - steel prices - GMK Center</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Recent steel market updates include a 5.4% year-on-year increase in steel production in Spain for the first half of 2025, a 7.6% month-on-month reduction in U.S. rolled steel imports in June, and a 5.8% year-on-year decline in global steel production in June. Additionally, ArcelorMittal temporarily shut down a blast furnace in Poland due to import pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices fell sharply on November 14</title><link>https://www.metal.com/en/newscontent/103621463</link><description>Nickel prices on the SHFE fell sharply, closing at 117,530 yuan/mt, down 1.1% amid market caution triggered by concerns over a hawkish US Federal Reserve and lack of key economic data. Spot nickel prices also declined, with premiums slightly rising despite the overall weak market sentiment. Prices are expected to remain weak in the near term due to uncertainty and divergent Fed views.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel fell to 14,880 USD/T on November 14, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/nickel</link><description>Nickel prices decreased to $14,880 per tonne, down 0.53% from the previous day, continuing a downward trend over the past month and year due to oversupply and muted demand. The price is near a recent low of $15,078, reflecting ongoing market weakness despite Indonesia's large output.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel price hits 4-year low as gloom offsets potential Indonesia cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices dropped to a four-year low around $15,235 per tonne due to a weak outlook from the Federal Reserve and oversupply concerns, despite potential mining cuts in Indonesia. The price decline reflects slower electric vehicle sales and abundant supply, with nickel trending about 8% lower in 2025.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices: Demand Woes Plague Stainless Market</title><link>https://agmetalminer.com/2025/11/14/stainless-mmi-nov2025-nickel-prices/</link><description>Nickel prices and the stainless steel market have softened due to demand challenges emerging from Q3 2025. Indian primary nickel prices slipped slightly, and various surcharges and related metal prices showed modest declines or slow growth, reflecting broader market softness.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Ottawa backs three key mining projects</title><link>https://www.metaltechnews.com</link><description>The Department of Defense has committed up to $10 million in milestone-based funding to advance engineering, drilling, and alloy qualification work at NioCorp Developments Ltd.'s Elk Creek critical minerals project in southeastern Nebraska, supporting development of a domestic scandium supply chain.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>The premium for aluminum in the US spot market has hit a record high</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103615477/</link><description>Since June, the premium for aluminum in the US Midwest spot market surged to a record 88.10 cents per pound ($1,942 per ton) as of last Friday. This reflects tight supply conditions and strong demand in the region.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Steel Holds November Pullback</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/steel</link><description>Steel rebar futures in China fell to around CNY 3,040 per tonne from a two-month high of CNY 3,120 on October 29th, pressured by lower demand and increasing trade protectionism from major Chinese trading partners. Steel exports from China declined 12.5% year-over-year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>AI boom pushes copper toward a supply crunch, BNEF warns</title><link>https://www.mining.com/video/ai-boom-pushes-copper-toward-a-supply-crunch-bnef-warns/</link><description>The rapid expansion of AI data centers is increasing copper demand by an estimated 400,000 tonnes annually, adding pressure to an already tight market impacted by energy transition projects and fragile mine supply. BloombergNEF forecasts copper prices could reach $13,500 per tonne by 2028, highlighting the need for innovation in supply and sustainability.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Inert Anode Aluminum Production: Carbon-Free Future</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/inert-anode-aluminum-production-2025-environmental-breakthrough/</link><description>Inert anode technology is revolutionizing aluminum production by enabling carbon-free processes that could eliminate 400-700 million tonnes of CO₂ emissions annually if widely adopted by 2040-2045. Recent milestones include a commercial-scale 450-kiloampere cell startup at Rio Tinto's Alma smelter. The technology also offers productivity improvements, higher purity aluminum, and integration with renewable energy for near-zero lifecycle emissions.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Ball is making investments to increase its production capacity in India</title><link>https://www.apnnews.com/ball-is-making-investments-to-increase-its-production-capacity-in-india/</link><description>Ball Corporation is investing to expand its aluminum production capacity in India, aiming to meet growing demand and strengthen its market position. This move reflects broader industry trends of capacity growth in emerging markets to support global aluminum consumption.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Inert Anode Aluminum Production: Carbon-Free Future</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/inert-anode-aluminum-production-2025-environmental-breakthrough/</link><description>Inert anode aluminum production technology eliminates 95% of CO2 emissions while boosting manufacturing efficiency by up to 5% above conventional methods. If the technology achieves 50% market penetration by 2040, it could eliminate 400-500 million tonnes of direct process emissions globally.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Emissions-Free Aluminium Smelting Breakthrough Achieved</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/elysis-technology-industrial-smelting-innovation-2025/</link><description>ELYSIS inert anode technology, developed through a partnership between Alcoa Corporation and Rio Tinto, eliminates CO2 emissions in aluminum smelting while generating oxygen instead. The 450 kA commercial-scale cell represents a revolutionary transformation in industrial smelting with applications across automotive, aerospace, and construction sectors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>At COP30: Can-to-Can Recycling Delivers 18% Higher Efficiency and Major Climate Benefits for Aluminium Beverage Cans</title><link>https://international-aluminium.org/at-cop30-can-to-can-recycling-delivers-18-higher-efficiency-and-major-climate-benefits-for-aluminium-beverage-cans/</link><description>Research by Innoval Technology demonstrates that can-to-can recycling increases melt recovery rates by 18% and cuts energy use and greenhouse gas emissions by 15% compared to mixed-alloy recycling. Expanding Deposit Return Systems across the EU and UK by 2030 could deliver an additional 50% reduction in greenhouse gas emissions for aluminum.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>China October crude steel output slides on weather-led restrictions, lower margins</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/china-october-crude-steel-output-slides-on-weather-led-restrictions-lower-margins/</link><description>China's crude steel production in October declined due to weather-related production restrictions and reduced profit margins. These factors contributed to a slowdown in steel output, reflecting ongoing challenges in the Chinese steel industry amid environmental and economic pressures.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Central Yunnan Nonferrous Metals Achieves 200,000 mt Copper Anode Production Milestone</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103047390/Central-Yunnan-Nonferrous-Metals-Achieves-200000-mt-Copper-Anode-Production-Milestone</link><description>Central Yunnan Nonferrous Metals exceeded 200,000 metric tons of copper anode production for the first time, marking a significant production milestone. This achievement represents a major accomplishment in the company's copper refining operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper: Wired for the Future</title><link>https://sprott.com/insights/copper-wired-for-the-future/</link><description>Copper is central to the clean energy transition, with demand projected to reach 61% of global energy use by 2040. The article discusses the supply and demand imbalance, the importance of investment in sustainable mining, and the role of M&amp;A activity in securing future copper supplies.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Ore Concentrate &amp; Gold Copper Concentrate 2025</title><link>https://farmonaut.com/mining/copper-ore-concentrate-gold-copper-concentrate-2025</link><description>Technological innovations in copper concentrate processing are driving sustainability, with closed-loop water systems, reduced emissions, and improved tailings management. Satellite technology and digital solutions are also enhancing efficiency and transparency in mining operations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Live Nickel Price per Metric Ton in USD</title><link>https://goldpricez.com/us/nickel</link><description>The live nickel price per metric ton in USD is updated continuously, reflecting global market movements. Prices are influenced by EV battery demand, stainless steel output, and supply from Indonesia and the Philippines.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>The Market In Numbers - 15 Nov 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/11/15/the-market-in-numbers-15-nov-2025/</link><description>Nickel prices showed a slight decline on November 15, with a 0.06% drop, continuing a trend of weakness over the past week and month. The broader market remains cautious amid ongoing oversupply concerns.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum breakthrough brings Elysis technology closer to market</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/aluminum-breakthrough-brings-elysis-technology-closer-to-market/</link><description>Alcoa Corp. and Rio Tinto Plc’s joint venture Elysis has achieved a technological milestone at a Quebec smelter, demonstrating high-amperage aluminum production with no direct CO2 emissions. The breakthrough brings Elysis’s inert anode technology closer to commercialization, with plans for broader deployment by the end of the decade.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Copper price falls on Fed uncertainty, Codelco supply relief</title><link>https://www.mining.com/copper-price-falls-on-fed-uncertainty-codelco-supply-relief/</link><description>Copper prices declined as much as 2.4% amid uncertainty over US monetary policy and easing concerns about global supply due to expected output increases from Chile's Codelco mine. The dollar's strength and a less dynamic demand outlook, despite recent supply disruptions, contributed to the price drop.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper - Price - Chart - Historical Data - News - Trading Economics</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/copper</link><description>Copper prices fell slightly to $5.04 per pound on November 14, 2025, down 0.21% from the previous day, but remain up 24.43% year-over-year. The market remains cautious due to the recent US government shutdown and weak trade data from China, with speculation that China may impose stricter controls on copper smelting projects to curb overcapacity.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>US Raw Steel Production Down 0.7 Percent - Week 47, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-down-07-percent-week-47-2025-1420051.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending November 15, 2025, was 1.745 million net tons with a capacity utilization rate of 76.2 percent, down 0.7 percent from the previous week. Year-to-date production through November 15, 2025, reached 78.973 million net tons, representing a 3.2 percent increase compared to the same period last year.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>US raw steel production is down 0.7 percent - week 47, 2025</title><link>https://www.steelorbis.com/steel-news/latest-news/us-raw-steel-production-is-down-07-percent-week-47-2025-1420051.htm</link><description>US domestic raw steel production for the week ending November 15, 2025, was 1.745 million net tons, down 0.7% from the previous week, with a capacity utilization rate of 76.2%. Despite the weekly decline, production increased 8.3% compared to the same week last year. Year-to-date production through November 15 rose 3.2% from the previous year, with capacity utilization at 77%.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Prysmian shares rise as Italian cable maker seen as winner amid US copper tariffs</title><link>https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/UK-USA-TRUMP-TARIFFS-PRYSMIAN-8455abd0-fcd3-4332-ab84-5a5ef0d855ca/</link><description>Prysmian shares rose as analysts identified the Italian cable manufacturer as a potential winner from President Trump's proposed 50% copper tariff. The company's vertically integrated copper operations, including sourcing from a Freeport mine in Arizona and operating its own copper rod mill in Texas, give it a competitive advantage over smaller competitors.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News 16.11.2025</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>In Turkey, billet prices increased in late October affecting domestic supplies and imports from Russia, though Russian companies face weak demand outside Turkey. Turkish steel producers have struggled to raise rebar prices despite rising costs of scrap and semi-finished products.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper prices fall as trade tensions and the US government shutdown weigh</title><link>https://energynews.oedigital.com/mineral-resources/2025/10/16/copper-prices-fall-as-trade-tensions-and-the-us-government-shutdown-weigh</link><description>Copper prices dropped 0.7% to $10,566 per metric tonne on the London Metal Exchange amid concerns about manufacturing demand, especially in China, and the ongoing US government shutdown. Despite recent supply disruptions pushing prices to a 16-month high, analysts expect a market surplus for now and caution that Chinese buyers may avoid the market if prices exceed $11,000.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Extraction 2025: Cutting-edge Developments in Copper Mining, Production, and Fabrication</title><link>https://mineconnect.com/event/extraction-2025/</link><description>The Extraction 2025 conference, starting today in Phoenix, Arizona, brings together global leaders to discuss the latest innovations in copper mining, production, and sustainability. The event features sessions on emerging technologies and multidisciplinary approaches to resource extraction and materials innovation.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Eases from 3-Year High</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum futures in the UK fell slightly to $2,860 per tonne on November 14, down 0.67% from the previous day, after hitting a three-year high of $2,915 on November 3. Despite the pullback, prices remain elevated due to supply concerns and China's production limits.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Italy - Factors to watch on November 17</title><link>https://www.tradingview.com/news/reuters.com,2025:newsml_L8N3WQ0KL:0-italy-factors-to-watch-on-november-17/</link><description>The Italian steel pipe maker Tenaris announced on Saturday the second tranche of a $1.2 billion buyback programme. This announcement highlights key market factors to monitor for Italy on November 17, 2025.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>China's crude steel output drops to lowest level in October at 72 million mt</title><link>https://aisusteel.org/en/38061/</link><description>China's crude steel output fell to 72 million metric tons in October 2025, the lowest level recorded for that month, continuing a trend of declining production amid ongoing domestic challenges.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Goldman lowers copper supply forecast on Grasberg disruption, sees deficit in 2025</title><link>https://www.mining.com/goldman-lowers-copper-supply-forecast-on-grasberg-disruption-sees-deficit-in-2025/</link><description>Goldman Sachs has revised its global copper supply forecast downward due to disruptions at Indonesia's Grasberg mine, shifting the 2025 market balance from surplus to deficit. The event underscores the fragility of copper supply chains and the importance of sustainable mining innovations to meet growing demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit 3-Year High: Is It the Next Key Metal in the Clean Energy Shift?</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/aluminum-prices-hit-3-year-high-is-it-the-next-key-metal-in-the-clean-energy-shift/</link><description>Aluminum prices reached a three-year high around $2,800 per tonne due to surging demand from electric vehicles, solar, and grid upgrades. Supply concerns stem from China's power shortages, environmental regulations, and unrest in Guinea affecting bauxite imports. The market shows a premium for low-carbon aluminum, reflecting growing demand for sustainable materials in clean energy sectors.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Surge Amid U.S. Government Reopening Hopes</title><link>https://www.gurufocus.com/news/3198766/aluminum-prices-surge-amid-us-government-reopening-hopes</link><description>Aluminum prices on the London Metal Exchange surged 1.7% to $2,895 per ton, driven by optimism over a potential U.S. government reopening. This optimism has contributed to a rally in aluminum prices amid broader market dynamics.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit New Annual Highs; Market Expected to Stay Strong</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-27999.html</link><description>The aluminum benchmark price on SunSirs stood at RMB 21,920.00 per ton on November 17, marking new annual highs. The market is expected to remain strong amid ongoing supply constraints and demand pressures.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Chuangxin Industries IPO Gains Strong Investor Interest as Subscription Opens</title><link>https://www.acnnewswire.com/press-release/english/103733/chuangxin-industries-ipo-gains-strong-investor-interest-as-subscription-opens</link><description>Chuangxin Industries, specializing in alumina refining and aluminum smelting, has opened its IPO subscription period. The company boasts a low-cost energy structure and high cost efficiency, with an annual designed production capacity of 788.1kt for electrolytic aluminum and 1,200kt for alumina. It plans to expand with a 500kt aluminum smelting facility in Saudi Arabia to leverage low-cost natural gas and strategic export routes.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>The primary processing sector shows initial signs of marginal weakening; national aluminium ingot inventory buildup of 25,000 tonnes</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/press-release/the-primary-processing-sector-shows-initial-signs-of-marginal-weakening-monday-national-aluminium-ingot-inventory-buildup-of-25-000-tonnes-116226</link><description>The primary aluminum processing sector is showing early signs of marginal weakening with a national aluminum ingot inventory increase of 25,000 tonnes. This suggests some softening in demand or production adjustments in the aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>A slide to USD 2,832.5/t &amp; an 825t stock drop raise fresh questions for the LME aluminium prices</title><link>https://www.alcircle.com/news/a-slide-to-usd-2-832-5-t-an-825t-stock-drop-raise-fresh-questions-for-the-lme-aluminium-prices-116225</link><description>Aluminum rod production is undergoing a wave of maintenance shutdowns affecting nearly 800,000 tonnes of capacity in November. This production cut wave is contributing to price volatility and raising questions about supply dynamics in the aluminum market.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Aluminum Prices Hit New Annual Highs; Market Expected to Remain Volatile at Elevated Levels in Q4</title><link>https://www.sunsirs.com/uk/detail_news-27999.html</link><description>Aluminum prices have reached new annual highs amid ongoing supply concerns and market volatility. The market is expected to remain volatile at elevated price levels through the fourth quarter of 2025.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Green aluminium could make EVs even cleaner for just €25 – study</title><link>https://www.transportenvironment.org/articles/green-aluminium-could-make-evs-even-cleaner-for-just-eur25-study</link><description>A study highlights the potential for green aluminum, produced with low-carbon methods, to significantly reduce emissions in electric vehicles by 2040. Europe’s cleaner electricity grid offers a competitive advantage for green aluminum production, which could add as little as €25 to the price of a car while cutting CO2 emissions equivalent to removing 900,000 fossil fuel cars from the road.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Global Iron and Steel Prices and News</title><link>https://www.steelradar.com/en/</link><description>SteelRadar provides comprehensive coverage of global iron and steel exchanges with price indices and market analysis across Turkey, China, Europe, and North America for both 1-month and 2-month futures contracts.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Middle East Iron and Steel Conference Highlights in Dubai</title><link>https://www.fastmarkets.com/insights/five-key-topics-middle-east-iron-and-steel-2025-conference/</link><description>The Middle East Iron and Steel 2025 Conference in Dubai highlighted major regional projects, including Algeria’s Tosyali working on green hydrogen-powered DRI operations. Steel demand in the Middle East is projected to reach 62.5 million tpy in 2026, with production expected to rise over 14% by 2027.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Steel News and Insights about Steel Market</title><link>https://gmk.center/en/news/</link><description>Recent updates include a 7.6% month-on-month drop in US rolled steel imports, a 5.4% year-on-year increase in Spain’s steel production, and a 5.8% year-on-year fall in global steel production in June. ArcelorMittal has suspended plans for a DRI plant in Dunkirk, and the EU hot-rolled coil market is stabilizing near its price bottom.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto Partners With Calix To Test Low-emissions Steel Making</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/rio-tinto-partners-with-calix-to-test-low-1571328/</link><description>Rio Tinto has partnered with Calix to build the Zesty Green Iron Demonstration Plant, aiming to produce up to 30,000 tonnes per year of hydrogen direct reduced iron (H2-DRI) or HBI. The project is supported by a grant from the Australian Renewable Energy Agency and is part of efforts to decarbonize steel production.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World Steel News Standard</title><link>https://metalexpert.com/en/latestissue?select=MK_WSNPLUS&amp;issue=3986</link><description>Steel futures rose slightly on Friday due to signs of lower supply, while iron ore prices held steady and coking coal prices continued to fall. The market remains sensitive to supply-side developments and global demand trends.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>World Steel Association Updates on Steel Production and Sustainability</title><link>https://worldsteel.org</link><description>World crude steel production for September 2025 was 141.8 million tonnes, a 1.6% decrease from the previous year. The association released updated sustainability indicators and policy papers focusing on emissions reduction and capacity replacement in the steel industry.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto partners with Calix to test low-emissions steel making in Western Australia, pauses BioIron</title><link>https://www.riotinto.com/en/news/releases/2025/rio-tinto-partners-with-calix-to-test-low-emissions-steel-making-in-western-australia-pauses-bioiron</link><description>Rio Tinto has partnered with Calix to test the Zesty low-emissions steel-making technology in Western Australia, pausing its BioIron project for further development. The Zesty process uses electric heating and hydrogen reduction to produce reduced-emissions iron, compatible with lower-grade Pilbara ores.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>From sewer to furnace: how wastewater sludge is greening steel production</title><link>https://cyprus-mail.com/2025/11/17/from-sewer-to-furnace-how-wastewater-sludge-is-greening-steel-production</link><description>EU-funded researchers are converting wastewater sludge into biocoal and green hydrogen to help reduce the environmental impact of steel production. This innovative approach supports the industry’s shift toward more sustainable raw materials and processes.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Green Steel: Europe's Recycling Challenge In A World Of Tariffs And Cheap Imports</title><link>https://www.eurasiareview.com/17112025-green-steel-europes-recycling-challenge-in-a-world-of-tariffs-and-cheap-imports/</link><description>Europe faces challenges in scaling green steel production due to global tariffs and competition from cheap imports. The article discusses the importance of recycling and policy support to advance sustainable steel technologies in the region.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Regesta Group sponsors Steel Budgets 2025</title><link>https://www.regestaitalia.eu/en/regesta-group-at-steel-budgets-2025-digital-and-sustainability-for-the-steel-industry/</link><description>The Steel Budgets 2025 event in Italy focuses on digitalization and sustainability in the steel industry, highlighting tools for monitoring sustainability data and ensuring compliance with European CO₂ emissions regulations. The event brings together industry leaders to discuss future trends and innovations.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Expectations for US Fed Interest Rate Cut Weakened, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Last Friday [SMM Copper Morning Meeting Minutes]</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103622835/Expectations-for-US-Fed-Interest-Rate-Cut-Weakened-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Last-Friday-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>Copper prices fluctuated on Friday, closing lower at $10,824/mt on the LME, as expectations for a US Fed interest rate cut weakened and the dollar index rebounded. Spot prices in Shanghai showed a slight premium increase, while imported copper prices remained flat. Market sentiment was cautious due to ongoing divisions within the Fed and recent ethics issues.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Price Gets Boost From Positive News</title><link>https://www.recyclingtoday.com/news/copper-price-gets-boost-from-positive-news/</link><description>COMEX copper futures settled at $3.74 per pound on November 17, with LME three-month copper also showing positive movement. The market received a boost from favorable news, reflecting ongoing strength in copper prices despite recent volatility.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>White Cliff Minerals Danvers Copper Project Expansion</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/white-cliff-minerals-danvers-copper-expansion-2025/</link><description>White Cliff Minerals announced a major expansion at its Danvers copper project, with the mineralised strike length increasing by 153% to over 950 metres and confirmed continuity beyond 400 metres depth. New modelling shows thicker and higher-grade zones, indicating significant upside potential before formal resource re-estimation. The company plans systematic development milestones through 2025, including JORC resource estimation and expanded drilling campaigns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Marimaca Copper's oxide project passes environmental hurdle</title><link>https://www.mining.com/marimaca-coppers-oxide-project-passes-environmental-hurdle/</link><description>Marimaca Copper's oxide deposit project received environmental approval, moving it closer to construction planned for the second half of 2026. The project aims to produce about 50,000 tonnes of copper cathodes annually over 13 years using an optimized heap-leach operation with minimal environmental impact. Additionally, drilling at the Pampa Medina satellite deposit shows promising high-grade copper continuity, supporting the company's long-term growth strategy.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>USGS adds copper: American Pacific sees projects boost</title><link>https://www.canadianminingjournal.com/news/usgs-adds-copper-american-pacific-sees-projects-boost/</link><description>Copper was added to the U.S. Geological Survey's 2025 critical minerals list, highlighting its strategic importance for domestic supply chains. American Pacific Mining emphasized that this inclusion supports advancement of its copper projects in Montana and Alaska, with increased government focus on funding and permitting critical minerals projects. This move is expected to bolster investment and development of U.S. copper assets amid national security concerns.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Cyprium operations progress as copper redevelopment advances</title><link>https://kalkinemedia.com/au/news/basic-materials/cyprium-operations-progress-as-copper-redevelopment-advances</link><description>Cyprium Metals reported progress in its copper redevelopment operations, advancing its projects as part of ongoing efforts to increase copper production. The update highlights operational milestones and development activities aimed at enhancing copper output, reflecting positive momentum in the company's copper sector initiatives.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Los Andes Copper at 121 Mining Investment London</title><link>https://losandescopper.com/news/2025/los-andes-copper-at-121-mining-investment-london-1/</link><description>Los Andes Copper Ltd. announced its participation in the 121 Mining Investment London event, showcasing its Vizcachitas Project in Chile. The company is focused on advancing this large copper-molybdenum porphyry deposit toward production, emphasizing its strategic location and infrastructure advantages. The event provides a platform to engage with investors and highlight the project's potential as one of the largest copper deposits in the Americas outside major company control.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Nickel Prices Continued to Decline on November 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103623987/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-Prices-Continued-to-Decline-on-November-17-Central-Bank-Conducted-800-Billion-Yuan-in-Reverse-Repo-Operations</link><description>Nickel prices continued to decline on November 17, with the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaging 118,700 yuan/mt, down 900 yuan/mt from the previous day. The market remains under pressure amid ongoing oversupply concerns and weak demand.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Hits 4-Year Low as Gloom Offsets Potential Indonesia Cuts</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nickel-price-hits-4-year-low-as-gloom-offsets-potential-indonesia-cuts/</link><description>Nickel prices fell to a four-year low on November 17, dropping 1.8% to $15,235 per ton on the LME, as weak global demand and a stronger US dollar outweighed hopes of supply cuts from Indonesia. The metal has declined about 8% this year due to oversupply and slowing EV sales.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>The Monday Report - 17 November 2025</title><link>https://fnarena.com/index.php/2025/11/17/the-monday-report-17-november-2025/</link><description>Nickel prices dropped 1.17% on November 17, trading at $6.66 per pound, as part of a broader decline in industrial metals. The market was affected by a stronger dollar and weak manufacturing data from China.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Drops: A Temporary Setback or a Long-Term Trend?</title><link>https://carboncredits.com/nickel-price-takes-a-hit-a-temporary-setback-or-a-long-term-trend/</link><description>Nickel prices have recently declined due to market recalibrations and strategic decisions by global players, including liquidation of long positions and a stronger US dollar. Analysts expect oversupply to continue restraining prices in the near term.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM Nickel Sulphate Daily Review - November 17th</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103624333/%5BSMM-Nickel-Sulphate-Daily-Review%5D-November-17th:-Trading-Relatively-Sluggish-Mid-Month-Nickel-Salt-Prices-Slightly-Decline</link><description>On November 17, the SMM battery-grade nickel sulphate index price was 28,199 yuan/mt, with prices slightly declining amid sluggish trading. The market remains cautious due to ongoing supply-demand imbalances.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>IWIP to invest $2 billion in renewables at Weda Bay nickel hub</title><link>https://www.petromindo.com/news/article/iwip-to-invest-2-billion-in-renewables-at-weda-bay-nickel-hub</link><description>PT Indonesia Weda Bay Industrial Park (IWIP) announced a $2 billion investment in renewable energy at its Weda Bay nickel hub, aiming to accelerate the use of clean energy and support sustainable nickel production in Indonesia.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Mining with integrity to advance sustainable nickel downstreaming</title><link>https://sumsel.antaranews.com/berita/804769/mining-with-integrity-to-advance-sustainable-nickel-downstreaming</link><description>The article highlights efforts to promote sustainable nickel downstreaming in Indonesia, emphasizing responsible mining practices and the importance of integrity in advancing the country's nickel industry.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>SMM #1 refined nickel price down on November 17</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103623958/</link><description>The SMM #1 refined nickel price was reported at 116,500-120,900 yuan/mt on November 17, averaging 118,700 yuan/mt, a decrease of 900 yuan/mt from the previous day, reflecting continued downward pressure in the nickel market.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>TECH Project high-grade nickel is primed to fuel the global green transition</title><link>https://www.innovationnewsnetwork.com/tech-project-high-grade-nickel-is-primed-to-fuel-the-global-green-transition/32893/</link><description>Queensland Pacific Metals' TECH Project aims to become a leading source of high-grade, ethically derived nickel for lithium-ion batteries, supporting the global green transition. The project uses the environmentally friendly DNi Process, which recycles over 98% of nitric acid, requires no tailings dam, and produces minimal waste, targeting carbon-negative and sustainable nickel production.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Aluminum fell to 2,846 USD/T on November 17, 2025</title><link>https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/aluminum</link><description>Aluminum prices declined 0.49% to $2,846 per tonne on November 17, 2025, though prices remain up 2.60% over the past month and 8.96% compared to the same time last year. The commodity has historically reached an all-time high of $4,103 in March 2022, with current prices tracking near three-year highs amid ongoing supply concerns.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>Russia's Aluminium Giant Rusal Shuts Key Plant as China's Low-Cost Silicon Crushes Industry</title><link>https://united24media.com/latest-news/chinas-cheap-silicon-crushes-russias-industry-rusal-forced-to-close-flagship-factory-13516</link><description>Russia's largest silicon producer, the Kremniy factory owned by Rusal, will halt operations on January 1, 2026, due to collapsing demand for Russian silicon as cheaper Chinese imports flood the market. The shutdown is part of a broader wave of production cuts across Russian heavy industry, with at least ten major companies implementing reduced schedules or closures due to weak domestic demand and falling exports.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>US Fed's Hawkish Remarks Drive Stainless Steel Below Recent Lows</title><link>https://www.metal.com/Finished-Steel</link><description>Stainless steel futures broke below nearly five-year lows to reach 12,310 yuan/mt during Friday's night session, affected by weakened expectations for US Federal Reserve interest rate cuts. Stainless steel mills have lowered prices and are actively shipping goods to boost sales amid the market downturn.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Manufacturing in New York state jumps in November</title><link>https://www.steelmarketupdate.com/2025/11/17/manufacturing-in-new-york-state-jumps-in-november/</link><description>Manufacturing activity in New York state increased slightly from November 3-10, with firms forecasting improved business conditions despite a dip in optimism. Steel production dipped last week but remained above the year-to-date weekly average. Employment and hours worked rose modestly, while supply availability worsened slightly and input price increases slowed.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Rio Tinto's Green Steelmaking Pivot from BioIron to Zesty Technology</title><link>https://discoveryalert.com.au/rio-tinto-green-steelmaking-challenge-2025/</link><description>Rio Tinto is shifting its green steelmaking focus from BioIron to hydrogen-based Zesty technology, investing $35 million to advance sustainable steel production. The company aims for a 95% reduction in carbon emissions compared to traditional blast furnaces, leveraging renewable agricultural waste and zero reliance on metallurgical coal. This pragmatic approach balances near-term commercial deployment with long-term innovation, positioning Rio Tinto as a leader in green steel.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>BASF and ExxonMobil Join Forces to Advance Low-Emission Hydrogen Through Methane Pyrolysis Technology</title><link>https://www.basf.com/basf/www/global/en/media/news-releases/2025/11/p-25-233</link><description>BASF and ExxonMobil are collaborating to develop methane pyrolysis technology that produces low-emission hydrogen and solid carbon, which can be used in steel manufacturing among other industries. A demonstration plant in Texas will validate the technology at scale, aiming to reduce the carbon footprint of hydrogen production and support green transformations in chemical and steel sectors.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>SSAB Teams Up With EAB for Green Steel</title><link>https://www.aist.org/steel-news</link><description>SSAB and EAB have partnered to supply fossil-free steel, including SSAB Zero™, for use in warehouse fittings, doors, and steel buildings. This collaboration supports the green steel transition by promoting the use of sustainable steel products in construction and infrastructure.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Comex Copper Settles 0.98% Lower at $5.0000 — Data Talk</title><link>https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202511176772/comex-copper-settles-098-lower-at-50000-data-talk</link><description>Front Month Comex Copper for November delivery lost 4.95 cents per pound, or 0.98%, settling at $5.0000. This marked the largest one-day dollar and percentage decline recently, reflecting market reactions to economic data and uncertainty.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Policy change in Argentina may boost Copper mining</title><link>https://www.argusmedia.com/en/news-and-insights/latest-market-news/2755103-policy-change-in-argentina-may-boost-copper-mining</link><description>Argentina's President Javier Milei is considering policy changes that could enhance copper mining activities in the country. The article also mentions Rio Tinto's ongoing low-emission iron projects and production updates from other miners, highlighting a significant production decrease due to a plant shutdown in October.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Lara Exploration Announces Filing of the Preliminary Economic Assessment for its Planalto Copper-Gold Project in Brazil</title><link>https://laraexploration.com/news/2025/lara-exploration-announces-filing-of-the-preliminary-economic-assessment-for-its-planalto-copper-gold-project-in-brazil/</link><description>Lara Exploration filed a Preliminary Economic Assessment for its Planalto copper-gold project in Brazil, estimating production of 560 kt of copper and 111 koz of gold over an 18-year mine life. The project aims to produce a clean chalcopyrite concentrate with potential for metallurgical improvements and power cost reductions.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>One and One Green Technologies INC Reports Strong First Half 2025 Results</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/11/17/3189572/0/en/One-and-One-Green-Technologies-INC-Reports-Strong-First-Half-2025-Results.html</link><description>One and One Green Technologies reported a 51% revenue increase and 60% net income growth in the first half of 2025, driven by expansion in green technology solutions including sustainable copper processing. The company's strong performance highlights the growing market for environmentally friendly copper technology innovations.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>World's top aluminium producer adds markups as Trump tariffs drive consumer costs</title><link>https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/companies-markets/energy-commodities/worlds-top-aluminium-producer-adds-markups-trump-tariffs-drive-consumer-costs</link><description>Rio Tinto Group is imposing surcharges on aluminium shipments to the US, ranging from one to three cents above the Midwest premium, translating to an extra $2,006 per tonne on top of the raw metal price. The price for aluminium delivered to the US reached a record high last week as stockpiles shrink, with the surcharge reflecting how deeply Trump's 50% import duty has disrupted the market structure. US warehouses used by the London Metal Exchange have no aluminium inventory remaining after the last 125 tonnes were withdrawn in October.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>SMM Flash News: Secondary Aluminum Ingot Social Inventory Dips by 71 mt on Nov 18</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103625109/SMM-Flash-News:-Secondary-Aluminum-Ingot-Social-Inventory-Dips-by-71-mt-on-Nov-18</link><description>Secondary aluminum ingot social inventory decreased by 71 metric tons on November 18, 2025, reflecting current market dynamics in aluminum supply and inventory levels.</description><category>aluminum</category></item><item><title>JSW Steel Ltd: Live Stock Update and Price as of November 18, 2025</title><link>https://www.angelone.in/live-blog/jsw-steel-ltd-18-nov-2025-500228</link><description>JSW Steel Ltd stock price decreased by 0.28%, with the current market value at ₹1,166.00 per share as investors assess the stock's performance.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Chinese steel production remains weak despite rising iron ore imports</title><link>https://cyprusshippingnews.com/2025/11/18/bimco-shipping-number-of-the-week-91/</link><description>Chinese steel production fell 3% year-on-year during Q3 2025 and may have remained weak entering Q4, despite a 7% increase in iron ore imports leading to record-high portside inventories. The property sector crisis continues to suppress domestic steel demand, and the World Steel Association forecasts a 1% decrease in Chinese steel demand for 2026. Rising trade barriers are expected to slow export growth.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>New EU tariffs on steel and Chinese export controls on rare earths</title><link>https://www.wr.no/en/news/new-eu-tariffs-on-steel-and-chinese-export-controls-on-rare-earths</link><description>The EU Commission announced proposed measures to reduce tariff-free steel imports by 47% and increase out-of-quota duties to 50%, alongside enhanced traceability requirements to prevent circumvention. A final decision on ferroalloy restrictions, critical for steel production, is expected on November 18, 2025, reflecting ongoing trade tensions impacting steel capacity and supply chains.</description><category>steel</category></item><item><title>Copper slips as macro concerns, firmer dollar weigh</title><link>https://www.hellenicshippingnews.com/copper-slips-as-macro-concerns-firmer-dollar-weigh/</link><description>Copper prices fell on Monday, weighed down by a slightly firmer dollar and broader macroeconomic concerns. Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange dropped 0.5% to $10,802.50 per metric ton amid cautious market sentiment.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper slips as macro concerns, firmer dollar weigh - Markets</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/40392923</link><description>Benchmark three-month copper on the London Metal Exchange was down 0.5 percent at $10,802.50 per metric ton in official open outcry trading. The decline was attributed to a firmer dollar and ongoing macroeconomic worries affecting demand outlook.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>The Narrative Around Copper Has Not Changed</title><link>https://www.admis.com/the-narrative-around-copper-has-not-changed/</link><description>Copper prices fell as a slightly firmer dollar and broader macro concerns weighed on prices, with LME copper down 0.5% at $10,802. Markets remain focused on upcoming US economic data for clues on Federal Reserve policy and economic activity. Chinese industrial data has been disappointing, though infrastructure and green energy investments support long-term demand.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Copper Ore Bridge Accident in DRC Kills 49, LME Copper Fluctuated and Closed Lower Overnight</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103625020/Copper-Ore-Bridge-Accident-in-DRC-Kills-49-LME-Copper-Fluctuated-and-Closed-Lower-Overnight-%5BSMM-Copper-Morning-Meeting-Minutes%5D</link><description>A tragic copper ore bridge accident in the Democratic Republic of Congo resulted in 49 deaths. Meanwhile, LME copper prices fluctuated overnight, opening at $10,796/mt and closing lower at $10,766.5/mt, with limited supply arrivals and weak downstream demand impacting the market.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Shooting for Canada's next discovery: Star Copper</title><link>https://mining.com.au/shooting-for-canadas-next-discovery-star-copper/</link><description>Star Copper is advancing its copper-gold porphyry discovery in British Columbia, Canada, with recent drilling extending mineralization north and west of the Star Main target. The company plans a 2026 program focusing on step-outs and deeper testing to define the project's larger scale potential.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Ivanhoe Mines Extends Birthday Wishes to President of South Africa Ahead of the Formal Opening of the Platreef Mine</title><link>https://www.newsfilecorp.com/release/274788/Ivanhoe-Mines-Extends-Birthday-Wishes-to-President-of-South-Africa-Cyril-Ramaphosa-Ahead-of-the-Formal-Opening-of-the-Platreef-Mine-on-November-18-2025</link><description>Ivanhoe Mines announced the formal opening of the Platreef mine, a multi-metal project including copper, in South Africa. The company is also exploring for copper in several regions including the Western Forelands and other international locations, highlighting its growth ambitions in copper exploration.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Buenaventura to Host Investor Day on November 18, 2025 in New York</title><link>https://investingnews.com/buenaventura-to-host-investor-day-on-november-18-2025-in-new-york/</link><description>Compañía de Minas Buenaventura, Peru's largest publicly traded precious and base metals company, announced its upcoming Investor Day event. The company operates several mines in Peru and holds a significant stake in Sociedad Minera Cerro Verde, a major Peruvian copper producer.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>Economic Impact Study (2025 11 18 Gunnison Cu Corp Red Cloud)</title><link>https://www.marketscreener.com/news/gunnison-copper-corporate-presentationgunnison-project-ni-43-101-technical-reportjohnson-camp-mine-ce7d5edadf8bf623</link><description>Gunnison Copper Corp. released information related to its economic impact study and corporate presentation, focusing on its copper projects. The company is listed on the TSX and is advancing its copper exploration and development activities.</description><category>copper</category></item><item><title>[SMM Nickel Midday Review] Nickel prices plummeted on November 18 breaking through multiple key support levels</title><link>https://news.metal.com/newscontent/103626220/%5BSMM-Nickel-Midday-Review%5D-Nickel-prices-plummeted-on-November-18-breaking-through-multiple-key-support-levels</link><description>On November 18, the SMM #1 refined nickel price averaged 116,950 yuan/mt, down 1,750 yuan/mt from the previous day. The SHFE nickel contract fell 1.66%, breaking the 116,000 yuan/mt support level amid hawkish US Fed signals and high market inventory, suggesting short-term weakness in nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel Price Collapse Forces Market Repricing as Oversupply &amp; Weak Demand Challenge Producers</title><link>https://www.cruxinvestor.com/posts/nickel-price-collapse-forces-market-repricing-as-oversupply-weak-demand-challenge-producers</link><description>Nickel prices have fallen to around US$15,000/t in mid-2025, down 10% year-over-year, with 32% of production offline due to margin stress. Oversupply persists with a forecasted 198,000t surplus in 2025 and record inventories, driven by Indonesian output despite quotas. Trade tariffs and policy shifts are causing supply chain realignment, creating pricing bifurcation and long-term market restructuring.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel futures at LME rebound on Nov 18</title><link>https://www.yieh.com/en/News/nickel-futures-at-lme-rebound-on-nov-18/151328</link><description>On November 18, nickel spot price at the London Metal Exchange rose by US$194/ton to US$15,486/ton. Meanwhile, LME nickel inventory increased by 4,722 tons to 159,146 tons, indicating a rebound in nickel futures prices despite high stock levels.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nickel pivot sparks legal debate in mining sector</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/11/18/nickel-pivot-sparks-legal-debate-in-mining-sector</link><description>Indonesia's government faces legal debate over new nickel mining policies aimed at addressing global nickel surplus and curbing new market entrants. The policy shift focuses on downstream production of higher-value nickel products, raising investment thresholds and impacting existing license holders. Indonesia and China contribute 75% of global supply, with Indonesia seen as a key factor in declining global nickel prices.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>FLASH: Nickel Industries Q3 2025 nickel production up 2.38% Quarter-on-Quarter</title><link>https://www.mysteel.net/news/5104342-flash-nickel-industries-q3-2025-nickel-production-up-238-quarter-on-quarter</link><description>Nickel Industries Limited reported a 2.38% increase in nickel production for Q3 2025, reaching 31,148 tonnes. The company's RKEF projects saw a 1.29% rise in nickel pig iron output, while the HPAL projects also contributed to growth despite ongoing maintenance at one facility.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Nornickel maintains 2025 nickel production forecast</title><link>https://www.mining.com/web/nornickel-maintains-2025-nickel-production-forecast-2/</link><description>Nornickel reported an 18% increase in nickel production for Q3 2025, reaching 54,000 metric tons, and maintained its annual forecast at 196,000–204,000 metric tons. The rise was attributed to higher volumes of processed raw materials after seasonal disruptions.</description><category>nickel</category></item><item><title>Tenaris Acquires isOplus Oil and Gas Division in $10M Deal, Expands Pipe Coating Business</title><link>https://www.pipeline-journal.net/news/tenaris-acquires-isoplus-oil-and-gas-division-10m-deal-expands-pipe-coating-business</link><description>Tenaris acquired the oil and gas division of isOplus for $10 million, rebranding it as Tenaris Coating Italy. This acquisition enhances Tenaris's capabilities in anti-corrosion coatings for pipelines, aiming to reduce delivery times, maintain quality, and lower environmental impact with coating operations in Italy and other countries.</description><category>general</category></item><item><title>The future of EU steel research – How to foster EU steel leadership</title><link>https://www.estep.eu/events/the-future-of-eu-steel-research-how-to-foster-steel-leadership</link><description>An upcoming event will focus on groundbreaking steel technologies, sustainability strategies, and challenges facing the EU steel industry. Topics include low to zero emission steel production and circularity, aiming to disseminate steel R&amp;D projects and foster EU leadership in sustainable steel innovation.</description><category>steel</category></item></channel></rss>